<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">10719784</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2000</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2006</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1081-1206</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>84</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2000</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of allergy, asthma &amp; immunology : official publication of the American College of Allergy, Asthma, &amp; Immunology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparison of three commercial ultrasonic nebulizers.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>255</StartPage>
          <EndPage>261</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>255-61</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The clinical acceptance of the initial ultrasonic nebulizers was impeded by their production of significant quantities of droplets larger than the respirable range that could have resulted in poor pulmonary deposition of nebulized medications. Subsequent modifications in the design of ultrasonic nebulizers have occurred. Overall nebulizer performance characteristics of the newer ultrasonic devices have not been evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Three commercially available ultrasonic nebulizers (DeVilbiss-Pulmosonic, Omron-Microair, Rhône Poulenc-Rorer-Fisoneb) were studied to compare the aerosol output characteristics.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The parameters studied were total volume output (TVO), time to nebulize total output (TTO), percent of droplets with volume diameters in the respirable range (PDVRR, 1 to 5 microm), albuterol concentration during nebulization, and the total drug delivered. All nebulizers were filled with 2.5 mL of saline and 0.5 mL of albuterol nebulizer solution. Three units from each manufacturer, each from a different lot, were evaluated in duplicate.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The nebulizer with the largest volume output was the Omron (mean 2.94 mL), which also demonstrated the longest nebulization time (mean 10.3 min). The DeVilbiss and Rhône Poulenc-Rorer units delivered smaller volumes (mean 2.5 mL, 2.4 mL, respectively) but nebulized more rapidly (mean 2.21 min, 3.54 min, respectively). The Omron nebulizer generated the highest PDVRR with a mean of 38%. The DeVilbiss had a mean PDVRR of 16% and the Rhône Poulenc-Rorer a mean PDVRR of 21%. The majority of droplets from all three machines had a volume diameter smaller than the respirable range, ie, in the 0.5 to 1.0 microm range (Omron-60%, DeVilbiss-83%, Rhône Poulenc-Rorer-79%). For all three nebulizers there appeared to be no concentrating or diluting effect during nebulization implying that equal quantities of albuterol and diluent were delivered. The Rhône Poulenc-Rorer units demonstrated the greatest unit-to-unit variability with respect to TVO while the Omron units demonstrated the greatest unit to unit variability with respect to TTO.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We conclude that several improvements in the design of ultrasonic nebulizers have resulted in the reduction of the size of the droplets generated. Our evaluation of the three commercially available ultrasonic nebulizers revealed that the majority of droplets generated were within or below the respirable range. There was no concentrating or diluting effect during nebulization for all three nebulizers. The output characteristics of the three devices differ and this will effect the delivery time as well as amount of drug delivered to the lungs.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Katial</LastName>
            <ForeName>R K</ForeName>
            <Initials>RK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Allergy and Immunology, Walter Reed Army Medical Center, Washington, DC 20307, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Reisner</LastName>
            <ForeName>C</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Buchmeier</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bartelson</LastName>
            <ForeName>B B</ForeName>
            <Initials>BB</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nelson</LastName>
            <ForeName>H S</ForeName>
            <Initials>HS</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9503580</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1081-1206</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000336">Aerosols</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000336" MajorTopicYN="N">Aerosols</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009330" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nebulizers and Vaporizers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015656" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Mechanics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014464" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonic Therapy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2000</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2000</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2000</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10719784</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1081-1206(10)62763-9</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1081-1206(10)62763-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
