<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">17915571</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2008</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1128-2460</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>26</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2007</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Acta myologica : myopathies and cardiomyopathies : official journal of the Mediterranean Society of Myology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Acta Myol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>McArdle disease: molecular genetic update.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>53</StartPage>
          <EndPage>57</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>53-7</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>McArdle disease or Glycogenosis type V is an autosomal recessive metabolic disorder caused by a deficiency of the muscle isoform of glycogen phosphorylase (myophosphorylase, PYGM), the specific skeletal muscle enzyme that initiates glycogen breakdown. Since the first clinical description by Brian McArdle in 1951, several patients have been identified worldwide and significant advances have been made in the study of molecular genetics of the disease. Molecular heterogeneity has been demonstrated by the identification to date of more than 65 mutations in the PYGM gene.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Andreu</LastName>
            <ForeName>A L</ForeName>
            <Initials>AL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dept. Patologia Mitocondrial i Neuromuscular, Centre d'Investigacions en Bioquímica i Biología Molecular (CIBBIM), Institut de Recerca Vall d'Hebron, Barcelona, Spain. aandreu@ir.vhebron.net</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nogales-Gadea</LastName>
            <ForeName>G</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cassandrini</LastName>
            <ForeName>D</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arenas</LastName>
            <ForeName>J</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bruno</LastName>
            <ForeName>C</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>OMIM</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>232600</AccessionNumber>
              <AccessionNumber>608455</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Acta Myol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9811169</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1128-2460</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.4.1.-</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D024982">Glycogen Phosphorylase, Muscle Form</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D024982" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycogen Phosphorylase, Muscle Form</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006012" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycogen Storage Disease Type V</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="N">enzymology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="N">enzymology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020641" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Single Nucleotide</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2007</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2008</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2007</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17915571</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2949323</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DiMauro S, Andreu AL, Bruno C, et al. Myophosphorylase Deficiency (Glycogenosis Type V; McArdle Disease). Curr Mol Med 2002;2:189-96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11949935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haller RG, Vissing J. Spontaneous “second wind” and glucose-induced second “second wind” in McArdle disease: oxidative mechanisms. Arch Neurol 2002;59:1395-402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12223025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsujino S, Shanske S, Di Mauro S. Molecular genetic heterogeneity of myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease). N Engl J Med 1993;329:241-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8316268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isackson PJ, Tarnopolsky M, Vladutiu GD. A novel mutation in the PYGM gene in a family with pseudo-dominant transmission of McArdle disease. Mol Genet Metab 2005;85:239-42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15979037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DiMauro S, Tsujino S. Nonlysosomal glycogenoses. In: Engel AG, Franzini-Amstrong C, eds. Myology. New York: McGraw-Hill; 1995. p. 1554-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Browner MF, Fletterick RJ. Phosphorylase: a biological transducer. Trends Biochem Sci 1992;17:66-71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1566331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebo RV, Gorin F, Fletterick RJ, et al. High-resolution chromosome sorting and DNA spot-blot analysis assign McArdle’s syndrome to chromosome 11. Science 1984;225:57-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6587566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartram C, Edwards RH, Clague J, et al. McArdle’s disease: a rare frameshift mutation in exon 1 of the muscle glycogen phosphorylase gene. Biochim Biophys Acta 1994;1226:341-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8054367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsujino S, Shanske S, Goto Y, et al. Two mutations, one novel and one frequently observed, in Japanese patients with McArdle’s disease. Hum Mol Genet 1994;3:1005-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7951211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsujino S, Shanske S, Nonaka I, et al. Three new mutations in patients with myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle disease). Am J Hum Genet 1994;54:44-52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1918063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8279469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugie H, Sugie Y, Ito M, et al. Genetic analysis of Japanese patients with myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease): single-codon deletion in exon 17 is the predominant mutation. Clin Chim Acta 1995;236:81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7664468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsujino S, Shanske S, Martinuzzi A. Two novel missense mutations (E654K, L396P) in Caucasian patients with myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease). Hum Mutat 1995;6:276-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8535454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsujino S, Shanske S, Nonaka I, et al. The molecular genetic basis of myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease). Muscle Nerve 1995;3:23-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7603523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinuzzi A, Tsujino S, Vergani L, et al. Molecular characterization of myophosphorylase deficiency in a group of patients from northern Italy. J Neurol Sci 1996;137:14-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9120482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iyengar S, Kalinsky H, Weiss S, et al. Homozygosity by descent for a rare mutation in the myophosphorylase gene is associated with variable phenotypes in a Druze family with McArdle disease. J Med Genet 1997;34:391-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1050946</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9152836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubisch C, Wicklein EM, Jentsch TJ. Molecular diagnosis of McArdle disease: revised genomic structure of the myophosphorylase gene and identification of a novel mutation. Hum Mutat 1998;12:27-32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9633816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vorgerd M, Kubisch C, Burwinkel B, et al. Mutation analysis in myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease). Ann Neurol 1998;43:326-31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9506549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreu AL, Bruno C, Tamburino L, et al. A new mutation in the myophosphorylase gene (Asn684Tyr) in a Spanish patient with McArdle’s disease. Neuromuscul Disord 1999;9:171-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10382911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruno C, Tamburino L, Kawashima N, et al. A nonsense mutation in the myophosphorylase gene in a Japanese family with McArdle’s disease. Neuromuscul Disord 1999;9:34-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10063833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruno C, Lofberg M, Tamburino L, et al. Molecular characterization of McArdle’s disease in two large Finnish families. J Neurol Sci 1999;165:121-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10450796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gamez J, Fernandez R, Bruno C, et al. A new mutation in the regulatory domain of the myophosphorylase gene affecting protein dimer contact. Muscle Nerve 1999;22:1136-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10417800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruno C, Di Mauro S, Lombes A, et al. Molecular study in a large series of French patients with McArdle’s disease. J Neurol 2000;274:120-1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin MA, Rubio JC, Campos Y, et al. Two homozygous mutations (R193W and 794/795 delAA) in the myophosphorylase gene in a patient with McArdle’s disease. Hum Mutat 2000;15:294.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10679948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin MA, Rubio JC, Campos Y, et al. A homozygous missense mutation (A659D) in the myophosphorylase gene in a Spanish patient with McArdle’s disease. Neuromuscul Disord 2000;10:447-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10899452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubio JC, Martin MA, Campos Y, et al. A missense mutation W797R in the myophosphorylase gene in a Spanish patient with McArdle’s disease. Muscle Nerve 2000;23:129-31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10590419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubio JC, Martin MA, Campos Y, et al. A missense mutation T487N in the myophosphorylase gene in a Spanish patient with McArdle’s disease. Neuromuscul Disord 2000;10:138-40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10714589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deschauer M, Opalka JR, Lindner A, et al. A novel nonsense mutation (R269X) in the myophosphorylase gene in a patient with McArdle disease. Mol Genet Metab 2001;74:489-91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11749054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin MA, Rubio JC, Garcia A, et al. Resolution of a mispaired secondary structure intermediate could account for a novel micro-insertion/deletion (387 insA/del 8 bp) in the PYGM gene causing McArdle’s disease. Clin Genet 2001;59:48-51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11168025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin MA, Rubio JC, Buchbinder J, et al. Molecular heterogeneity of myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease): a genotype-phenotype correlation study. Ann Neurol 2001;50:574-81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruno C, Lanzillo R, Biedi C, et al. Two new mutations in the myophosphorylase gene in Italian patients with McArdle’s disease. Neuromuscul Disord 2002;12:498-500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12031624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadjigeorgiou GM, Papadimitriou A, Musumeci O, et al. A new stop codon mutation (Y52X) in the myophosphorylase gene in a Greek patient with McArdle’s disease. J Neurol Sci 2002;194:83-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadjigeorgiou GM, Sadeh M, Musumeci O, et al. Molecular genetic study of myophosphorylase deficiency (McArdle’s disease) in two Yemenite-Jewish families. Neuromuscul Disord 2002;12:824-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12398832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deschauer M, Hertel K, Zierz S. Two novel mutations in the myophosphorylase gene in a patient with McArdle disease. Muscle Nerve 2003;27:105-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12508303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gamez J, Rubio JC, Martin MA, et al. Two novel mutations in the muscle glycogen phosphorylase gene in McArdle’s disease. Muscle Nerve 2003;28:380-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12929201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mancuso M, Filosto M, Tsujino S, et al. Muscle glycogenosis and mitochondrial hepatopathy in an infant with mutations in both the myophosphorylase and deoxyguanosine kinase genes. Arch Neurol 2003;60:1445-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14568816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin MA, Rubio JC, Wevers RA, et al. Molecular analysis of myophosphorylase deficiency in Dutch patients with McArdle’s disease. Ann Hum Genet 2004;68:17-22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14748827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quintans B, Sanchez-Andrade A, Tejeira S, et al. A new rare mutation (691delCC/InsAAA) in exon 17 of the PYGM gene causing McArdle disease. Arch Neurol 2004;61:1108-10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15262743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paradas C, Fernandez-Cadenas I, Gallardo E, et al. Variable presentation of the clinical phenotype of McArdle’s disease in a kindred harbouring a novel compound genotype in the muscle glycogen phosphorylase gene. Neurosci Lett 2005;391:28-31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16154688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruno C, Cassandrini D, Martinuzzi A, et al. McArdle disease: the mutation spectrum of PYGM in a large Italian cohort. Hum Mutat 2006;27:718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16786513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubio JC, Lucia A, Fernandez-Cadenas I, et al. Novel mutation in the PYGM gene resulting in McArdle disease. Arch Neurol 2006;63:1782-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17172620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez-Cadenas I, Andreu AL, Gamez J, et al. Splicing mosaic of the myophosphorylase gene due to a silent mutation in McArdle disease. Neurology 2003;61:1432-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14638972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>den Dunnen JT, Paalman MH. Standardizing mutation nomenclature: why bother? Hum Mutat 2003;22:181-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12938082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>el-Schahawi M, Tsujino S, Shanske S, et al. Diagnosis of McArdle’s disease by molecular genetic analysis of blood. Neurology 1996;47:579-80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8757044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinuzzi A, Sartori E, Fanin M, et al. Phenotype modulators in myophosphorylase deficiency. Ann Neurol 2003;53:497-502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12666117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
