<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">18090816</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2008</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1529-4242</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>120</Volume>
            <Issue>7 Suppl 1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2007</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Plastic and reconstructive surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Plast Reconstr Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Breast implants and breast cancer: a review of incidence, detection, mortality, and survival.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>70S</StartPage>
          <EndPage>80S</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>70S-80S</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/01.prs.0000286577.70026.5d</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Soon after breast implants were commercially introduced over 30 years ago, questions about potential carcinogenicity were raised. Animal experiments dating back to the mid-twentieth century demonstrated that foreign body implantation of many materials, including silicone, can induce sarcomas. Indeed, female breast cancer incidence rates in the United States have increased substantially over that period. Of the several published studies from various countries that have formally investigated the risk of breast cancer among augmentation mammaplasty patients, none show any evidence of increased risk. In fact, most find lower than expected risk, some with statistically significant reductions. Similarly, breast cancer mortality among these patients is generally found to be below that expected of other similar women. Delayed detection of breast cancer is a concern for these patients because implants can interfere with mammography. However, using indicators such as stage at diagnosis and tumor size, current research shows that augmentation patients do not experience delayed detection. Furthermore, several comparisons of post-breast cancer survival of augmented versus nonaugmented patients have found no significant differences. In summary, breast implants are not associated with an increased risk of breast cancer incidence or death, and these patients do not experience delayed detection or poorer post-breast cancer survival.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Deapen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dennis</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Los Angeles, Calif. From the Department of Preventive Medicine, Keck School of Medicine, University of Southern California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Plast Reconstr Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>1306050</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0032-1052</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018427" MajorTopicYN="N">Breast Implants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012509" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcoma</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <NumberOfReferences>86</NumberOfReferences>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2007</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2008</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2007</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18090816</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.prs.0000286577.70026.5d</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006534-200712001-00012</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oppenheimer, B. S., Oppenheimer, E. T., Danishefsky, I., et al. Further studies of polymers as carcinogenic agents in animals. Cancer Res. 15: 333, 1955.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz, A. W., and Erich, J. B. Experimental study of polyvinylformal (Ivalon) sponge as a substitute for tissue. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 25: 1, 1960.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown, J. B., Ohlwiler, D. A., and Fryer, M. P. Investigation of and use of dimethyl siloxanes, halogenated carbons and polyvinyl alcohol as subcutaneous prostheses. Ann. Surg. 152: 334, 1960.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bryson, G., and Bischoff, F. Silicate-induced neoplasms. Prog. Exp. Tumor Res. 9: 77, 1967.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lilla, J. A., and Vistnes, L. M. Long-term study of reactions to various silicone breast implants in rabbits. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 57: 637, 1976.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brand, K. G., and Brand, I. Risk assessment of carcinogenesis at implantation sites. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 66: 591, 1980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoopes, J. E., Edgerton, M. T., Jr., and Shelley, W. Organic synthetics for augmentation mammaplasty: Their relation to breast cancer. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 39: 263, 1967.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowers, D. G., Jr., and Radlauer, C. B. Breast cancer after prophylactic subcutaneous mastectomies and reconstruction with silastic prostheses. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 44: 541, 1969.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benavent, W. J. Treatment of bilateral breast carcinomas in a patient with silicone-gel breast implants: Case report. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 51: 588, 1973.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris, H. I. Survey of breast implants from the point of view of carcinogenesis. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 28: 81, 1961.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Cholnoky, T. Augmentation mammaplasty: Survey of complications in 10,941 patients by 265 surgeons. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 45: 573, 1970.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deapen, D. M., Pike, M. C., Casagrande, J. T., et al. The relationship between breast cancer and augmentation mammaplasty: An epidemiologic study. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 77: 361, 1986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deapen, D. M., and Brody, G. S. Augmentation mammaplasty and breast cancer: A 5-year update of the Los Angeles study. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 89: 660, 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deapen, D. M., Bernstein, L., and Brody, G. S. Are breast implants anticarcinogenic? A 14-year follow-up of the Los Angeles Study. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 99: 1346, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deapen, D. M., Hirsch, E. M., and Brody, G. S. Cancer risk among Los Angeles women with cosmetic breast implants. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 119: 1987, 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berkel, H., Birdsell, D. C., and Jenkins, H. Breast augmentation: A risk factor for breast cancer? N. Engl. J. Med. 326: 1649, 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bryant, H., and Brasher, P. Breast implants and breast cancer: Reanalysis of a linkage study. N. Engl. J. Med. 332: 1535, 1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin, J. K., Fraumeni, J. F., Jr., Olsen, J., et al. Re: Breast implants, cancer, and systemic sclerosis. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 86: 1424, 1994.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friis, S., McLaughlin, J. K., Mellemkjaer, L., et al. Breast implants and cancer risk in Denmark. Int. J. Cancer 71: 956, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellemkjaer, L., Kjoller, K., Friis, S., et al. Cancer occurrence after cosmetic breast implantation in Denmark. Int. J. Cancer 88: 301, 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friis, S., Holmich, L. R., McLaughlin, J. K., et al. Cancer risk among Danish women with cosmetic breast implants. Int. J. Cancer 118: 998, 2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin, J. K., Fraumeni, J. F., Jr., Nyren, O., et al. Silicone breast implants and risk of cancer? J.A.M.A. 273: 116, 1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin, J. K., Nyren, O., Blot, W. J., et al. Cancer risk among women with cosmetic breast implants: A population-based cohort study in Sweden. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 90: 156, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin, J. K., Lipworth, L., Fryzek, J. P., et al. Long-term cancer risk among Swedish women with cosmetic breast implants: An update of a nationwide study. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 98: 557, 2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kern, K. A., Flannery, J. T., and Kuehn, P. G. Carcinogenic potential of silicone breast implants: A Connecticut statewide study. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 100: 737, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, A. J., Black, R. J., Sarhadi, N. S., et al. Silicone gel-filled breast implants and connective tissue diseases. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 101: 261, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinton, L. A., Lubin, J. H., Burich, M. C., et al. Breast cancer following augmentation mammoplasty (United States). Cancer Causes Control 11: 819, 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pukkala, E., Boice, J. D., Jr., Hovi S. L., et al. Incidence of breast and other cancers among Finnish women with cosmetic breast implants, 1970–1999. J. Long Term Eff. Med. Implants 12: 271, 2002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brisson, J., Holowaty, E. J., Villeneuve, P. J., et al. Cancer incidence in a cohort of Ontario and Quebec women having bilateral breast augmentation. Int. J. Cancer 118: 2854, 2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malone, K. E., Stanford, J. L., Daling, J. R., et al. Implants and breast cancer. Lancet 339: 1365, 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinton, L. A., Malone, K. E., Coates, R. J., et al. Breast enlargement and reduction: Results from a breast cancer case-control study. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 97: 269, 1996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rintala, A. E., and Svinhufvud, U. M. Effect of augmentation mammaplasty on mammography and thermography. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 54: 390, 1974.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein, M. J., Handel, N., Gamagami, P., et al. Breast cancer in women after augmentation mammoplasty. Arch. Surg. 123: 681, 1988.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gumucio, C. A., Pin, P., Young, V. L., et al. The effect of breast implants on the radiographic detection of microcalcification and soft-tissue masses. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 84: 772, 1989.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leibman, A. J., and Kruse, B. Breast cancer: Mammographic and sonographic findings after augmentation mammoplasty. Radiology 174: 195, 1990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein, M. J., Gierson, E. D., Gamagami, P., et al. Breast cancer diagnosis and prognosis in women augmented with silicone gel-filled implants. Cancer 66: 97, 1990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein, M. J., Handel, N., and Gamagami, P. The effect of silicone-gel-filled implants on mammography. Cancer 68: 1159, 1991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monsees, B., and Destouet, J. Mammography in aesthetic and reconstructive breast surgery. Perspect. Plast. Surg. 5: 103, 1991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Douglas, K. P., Bluth, E. I., Sauter, E. R., et al. Roentgenographic evaluation of the augmented breast. South. Med. J. 84: 49, 1991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein, M. J., Handel, N., Gamagami, P., et al. Breast cancer diagnosis and prognosis in women following augmentation with silicone gel-filled prostheses. Eur. J. Cancer 28: 635, 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Handel, N., Silverstein, M. J., Gamagami, P., et al. Factors affecting mammographic visualization of the breast after augmentation mammaplasty. J.A.M.A. 268: 1913, 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayes, H., Jr., Vandergrift, J., and Diner, W. Mammography and breast implants. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 92: 209, 1993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leibman, A. J., and Kruse, B. D. Imaging of breast cancer after augmentation mammoplasty. Ann. Plast. Surg. 30: 111, 1993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fajardo, L. L., Harvey, J. A., McAleese, K. A., et al. Breast cancer diagnosis in women with subglandular silicone gel-filled augmentation implants. Radiology 194: 859, 1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skinner, K. A., Silberman, H., Dougherty, W., et al. Breast cancer after augmentation mammoplasty. Ann. Surg. Oncol. 8: 138, 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deapen, D., Hamilton, A., Bernstein, L., et al. Breast cancer stage at diagnosis and survival among patients with prior breast implants. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 105: 535, 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birdsell, D. C., Jenkins, H., and Berkel, H. Breast cancer diagnosis and survival in women with and without breast implants. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 92: 795, 1993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark, C. P., III, Peters, G. N., and O’Brien, K. M. Cancer in the augmented breast: Diagnosis and prognosis. Cancer 72: 2170, 1993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cahan, A. C., Ashikari, R., Pressman, P., et al. Breast cancer after breast augmentation with silicone implants. Ann. Surg. Oncol. 2: 121, 1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmich, L. R., Mellemkjaer, L., Gunnarsdottir, K. A., et al. Stage of breast cancer at diagnosis among women with cosmetic breast implants. Br. J. Cancer 88: 832, 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Handel, N., and Silverstein, M. J. Breast cancer diagnosis and prognosis in augmented women. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 118: 587, 2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgiade, G. S., Riefkohl, R., Cox, E., et al. Long-term clinical outcome of immediate reconstruction after mastectomy. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 76: 415, 1985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petit, J. Y., Le, M., Rietjens, M., et al. Does long-term exposure to gel-filled silicone implants increase the risk of relapse after breast cancer? Tumori 84: 525, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koot, V. C., Peeters, P. H., Granath, F., et al. Total and cause specific mortality among Swedish women with cosmetic breast implants: Prospective study. B.M.J. 326: 527, 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinton, L. A., Lubin, J. H., Burich, M. C., et al. Mortality among augmentation mammoplasty patients. Epidemiology 12: 321, 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le, G. M., O’Malley, C. D., Glaser, S. L., et al. Breast implants following mastectomy in women with early-stage breast cancer: Prevalence and impact on survival. Breast Cancer Res. 7: R184, 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobsen, P. H., Holmich, L. R., McLaughlin, J. K., et al. Mortality and suicide among Danish women with cosmetic breast implants. Arch. Intern. Med. 164: 2450, 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villeneuve, P. J., Holowaty, E. J., Brisson, J., et al. Mortality among Canadian women with cosmetic breast implants. Am. J. Epidemiol. 164: 334, 2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoshaw, S. J., Klein, P. J., Clark, B. D., et al. Breast implants and cancer: Causation, delayed detection, and survival. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 107: 1393, 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreyfuss, D. A., Singh, S., Dowlatshahi, K., et al. Silicone implants as an anticarcinogen. Surg. Forum 38: 587, 1987.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramasastry, S. S., Weinstein, L. W., Zerbe, A., et al. Regression of local and distant tumor growth by tissue expansion: An experimental study of mammary carcinoma 13,762 in rats. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 87: 1, 1991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su, C. W., Dreyfuss, D. A., Krizek, T. J., et al. Silicone implants and the inhibition of cancer. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 96: 513, 1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, L. S., Daling, J. R., Voigt, L. F., et al. Characteristics of women with and without breast augmentation. J.A.M.A. 277: 1612, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fryzek, J. P., Weiderpass, E., Signorello, L. B., et al. Characteristics of women with cosmetic breast augmentation surgery compared with breast reduction surgery patients and women in the general population of Sweden. Ann. Plast. Surg. 45: 349, 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kjoller, K., Holmich, L. R., Fryzek, J. P., et al. Characteristics of women with cosmetic breast implants compared with women with other types of cosmetic surgery and population-based controls in Denmark. Ann. Plast. Surg. 50: 6, 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breiting, V. B., Holmich, L. R., Brandt, B., et al. Long-term health status of Danish women with silicone breast implants. Plast. Reconstr. Surg. 114: 217, 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albanes, D., and Winick, M. Are cell number and cell proliferation risk factors for cancer? J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 80: 772, 1988.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trichopoulos, D., and Lipman, R. D. Mammary gland mass and breast cancer risk. Epidemiology 3: 523, 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valaoras, V. G., MacMahon, B., Trichopoulos, D., et al. Lactation and reproductive histories of breast cancer patients in greater Athens, 1965-67. Int. J. Cancer 4: 350, 1969.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirohata, T., Nomura, A. M., and Kolonel, L. N. Breast size and cancer. B.M.J. 2: 641, 1977.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soini, I. Risk factors of breast cancer in Finland. Int. J. Epidemiol. 6: 365, 1977.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolonel, L. N., Nomura, A. M., Lee, J., et al. Anthropometric indicators of breast cancer risk in postmenopausal women in Hawaii. Nutr. Cancer 8: 247, 1986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tavani, A., Pregnolato, A., La Vecchia, C., et al. Breast size and breast cancer risk. Eur. J. Cancer Prev. 5: 337, 1996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kusano, A. S., Trichopoulos, D., Terry, K. L., et al. A prospective study of breast size and premenopausal breast cancer incidence. Int. J. Cancer 118: 2031, 2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Safety of polyurethane-covered breast implants. Expert Panel on the Safety of Polyurethane-covered Breast Implants. C.M.A.J. 145: 1125, 1991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute of Medicine, National Academy of Sciences. Safety of Silicone Implants. Washington, D.C.: Institute of Medicine, National Academy of Sciences, 1999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IARC. IARC Monographs on the Evaluation of Carcinogenic Risks to Humans: Surgical Implants and Other Foreign Bodies. Lyon: IARC, 1999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Health Canada. It’s Your Health: Breast Implants. Ottawa, Ontario: Health Canada, Health Protection Branch, 1988.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sturrock, R. D., Batchelor, J. R., Harpwood, V., et al. Silicone Gel Breast Implants: The Report of the Independent Review Group. Cambridge, England: Jill Rogers Associates, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Therapeutic Goods Administration. Breast Implant Information Booklet, 2nd Ed. Woden, Australia: Therapeutic Goods Administration, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Committee on Quality Assurance and Medical Devices in Plastic Surgery. Consensus Declaration on Breast Implants. EQUAM-Consensus Conference, Regensburg, Germany, July 2–4, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman, B. G., Brown, S. L., Bright, R. A., et al. Reported complications of silicone gel breast implants: An epidemiologic review. Ann. Intern. Med. 124: 744, 1996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinton, L. A., and Brown, S. L. Breast implants and cancer. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 89: 1341, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerszten, K., and Gerszten, P. C. Silicone breast implants: An oncologic perspective. Oncology 12: 1427, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edelman, D. A., Grant, S., and van Os, W. A. Breast cancer and silicone breast implants. Int. J. Gynaecol. Obstet. 47: 295, 1994.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
