<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">18398280</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2008</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0256-4947</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2008</Year>
              <Season>Mar-Apr</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of Saudi medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Saudi Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Drug-eluting stents: insights into safety and indications.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>114</StartPage>
          <EndPage>119</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>114-9</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Currently, more than 4 million patients receive drug-eluting stents worldwide. Despite recent studies and editorials that have stirred controversy and generated tremendous publicity in the lay press related to the safety of drug-eluting stents for the treatment of coronary artery disease, enthusiasm for drug-eluting stents remains high. Drug-eluting stents decrease the need for repeat revascularization, but exhibit delayed endothelialization compared with bare metal stents. Adverse late vessel wall remodeling and inflammation have also been attributed to the drug/polymer coating. Recent registry analysis data suggesting an increased risk of late or very late thrombosis with drug-eluting stents in routine clinical practice compared with previous clinical trial experience has led to concerns regarding the long-term safety of these devices. Clearly, there are many benefits to drug-eluting stents, which are an excellent and appropriate revascularization treatment for many patients with substantial reduction of restenosis compared with bare-metal stents. There is a need for understanding the benefits and risks of these devices in order to use them optimally and reduce likelihood of thrombosis. This review sheds some light on the risks and benefits of drug-eluting stents, and puts this treatment in perspective compared with alternative revascularization treatment options for obstructive coronary artery disease. The important take-home message is that the risks of drug-eluting stent thrombosis versus bare-metal stent thrombosis may have been overstated by some studies.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hassan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Walid</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Medicine, King Faisal Specialist Hospital and Research Centre, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. hassanw@kfshrc.edu.sa</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Saudi Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8507355</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0256-4947</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003324" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Artery Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054855" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug-Eluting Stents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009204" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardial Revascularization</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018579" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Selection</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013927" MajorTopicYN="N">Thrombosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2008</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2008</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2008</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18398280</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6074518</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5144/0256-4947.2008.114</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">07-416</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfisterer M, Brunner-La Rocca HP, Buser PT, et al.  Late clinical events after clopidogrel discontinuation may limit the benefit of drug-eluting stents. An observational study of drug-eluting versus bare-metal stents. Am College Cardiol. 2006;48:2584–2591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17174201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camenzind E. Safety of drug-eluting stents: A meta-analysis of 1st generation DES programs. Oral Presentation at World Cardiology Congress; 2006; Barcelona, Spain. 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nordmann AJ, Briel M, Bucher HC. Mortality in randomized controlled trials comparing drug-eluting vs. bare metal stents in coronary artery disease: A meta-analysis. Eur Heart J. 2006;27:2784–2814.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17020889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morice M-C, Serruys PW, Sousa E, et al.  A randomized comparison of a sirolimus-eluting stent with a standard stent for coronary revascularization. N Engl J Med. 2002;346:1773–1780.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12050336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fitzerald PJ, Holmes DR, O’Shaughnessy C, et al.  for the SIRIUS Investigators. Sirolimus-eluting stents versus standard stents in patients with stenosis in a native coronary artery. N Engl J Med. 2003;349:1315–1323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14523139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone GW, Ellis SG, Cox DA, et al.  for the TAXUS-IV Investigators. One-year clinical results with the slow-release, polymer-based, paclitaxel-eluting TAXUS stent: The TAXUS-IV trial. Circulation. 2004;109:1942–1947.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15078803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CYPHER(r) stent: Evaluation of benefits and risks.  Available from:  www.cordis.com/active/crdus/en_US/html/cordis/downloads/155_5056_1_ARC_Overview.pdf. [AUTHOR[AUTHOR: This is a URL for a Powerpoint presentation. Can you provide published references instead?]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cutlip DE. Stent thrombosis after drug-eluting stenting: Impact of a new standard definition on clinical trial results.  Available from:  www.tctmd.com/csportal/appmanager/tctmd/tct2006?_nfpb=true;&amp;_pageLabel=TCT2006Content&amp;hdCon=1462891&amp;srcId=1&amp;destId=78. [AUTHOR: This link does not work. Can you provide another citation, maybe Mauri et al. Stent thrombosis in randomized clinical trials of drug-eluting stents. N Engl J Med 2007;356:1020–9]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marroquin OC, Selzer F, Mulukutla SR, et al.  A comparison of bare-metal and drug-eluting stents for off-label indications. N Engl J Med. 2008;358(4):342–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2761092</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18216354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandhu G, Doyle B, Singh, et al.  Frequency, etiology, treatment, and outcomes of drug-eluting stent thrombosis during one year of follow-up. Am J Cardiol. 2007;99(4):465–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17293185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ong AT, McFadden EP, Regar E, et al.  Late angiographic stent thrombosis (LAST) events with drug-eluting stents. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;245:2088–2092.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15963413</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuchulakanti PK, Chu WW, Torguson R, et al.  Correlates and long-term outcomes of angiographically proven stent thrombosis with sirolimus- and paclitaxel-eluting stents. Circulation. 2006;113:1108–1113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urban P, Gershlick AH, Guagliumi G, et al.  Safety of coronary sirolimus-eluting stents in daily clinical practice: one-year follow-up of the e-Cypher registry, Circulation. 2006;113:1434–1441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16534015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joner M, Finn AV, Farb A, et al.  Pathology of drug-eluting stents in humans: Delayed healing and late thrombotic risk. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;48:193–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16814667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cutlip DE, Baim DS, Ho KK, et al.  Stent thrombosis in the modern era: A pooled analysis of multicenter coronary stent trials. Circulation. 2001;106:1753–1755.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11306525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheneau E, Leborne L, Mintz GS, et al.  Predictors of subacute stent thrombosis: Results of a systematic ultrasound study. Circulation. 2003;108:43–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujii K, Carlier SG, Mintz GS, et al.  Stent underexpansion and residual reference segment stenosis are related to stent thrombosis after sirolimuseluting stent implantation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;45:995–998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15808753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finn AV, Kolodgie FD, Harnek J, et al.  Differential response of delayed healing and persistent inflammation at sites of overlapping sirolimus- or paclitaxel-eluting stents. Circulation. 2005;112(2):270–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15998681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wenaweser P. Late coronary stent thrombosis of DESs in routine clinical practice. Oral Presentation at the World Cardiology Congress; 2006; Barcelona, Spain. 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sousa JE, Serruys PW, Costa MA. New frontiers in cardiology: drug-eluting stents: Part I. Circulation. 2003;107:2274–2279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12732594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virmani R, Guagliumi G, Farb A, et al.  Localized hypersensitivity and late coronary thrombosis secondary to a sirolimus-eluting stent: should we be cautious? Circulation. 2004;109:701–705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14744976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ako J, Morino Y, Honda Y, et al.  Late incomplete stent apposition after sirolimus-eluting stent implantation: a serial intravascular ultrasound analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;46:1002–1005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16168282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taniuchi M, Kurz HI, Lasala JM. Randomized comparison of ticlopidine and clopidogrel after intracoronary stent implantation in a broad patient population. Circulation. 2001;104:539–543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11479250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta V, Aravamuthan BR, Baskerville S, et al.  Reduction of subacute stent thrombosis (SAT) using heparin-coated stents in a large-scale, real world registry. J Invasive Cardiol. 2004;16:304–310.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serruys PW, Unger F, Sousa JE, et al.  Comparison of coronary-artery bypass surgery and stenting for the treatment of multivessel disease. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:1117–1124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11297702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang F, Stouffer GA, Waxman S, Uretsky BF. Late coronary stent thrombosis: Early vs. late stent thrombosis in the stent era. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2002;55:142–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11835636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heller L, Shemwell KC, Hug K. Late stent thrombosis in the absence of prior brachytherapy. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2001;53:23–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11329213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wenaweser P, Rey C, Eberli FR, et al.  Stent thrombosis following bare-metal stent implantation: Success of emergency percutaneous coronary intervention and predictors of adverse outcome. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:1180–1187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15728650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serruys PW, Ong AT, Morice MC, et al.  Arterial revascularization therapies study. II. Sirolimus-eluting stents for the treatment of patients with multivessel de novo coronary artery lesions. EuroInterv. 2005:147–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19758896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno R, Fernandez C, Hernandez R, et al.  Drug-eluting stent thrombosis. Results from a pooled analysis including 10 randomized studies. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;45:954–959.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15766835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams DO, Abbott D, Kip KE for the DEScover Investigators. Outcomes of 6906 patients undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention in the era of drug-eluting stents. Report of the DEScover registry. Circulation. 2006;114:2154–2162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17060386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen MS, John JM, Chew DP, Lee DS, Ellis SG, Bhatt DL. Bare metal stent restenosis is not a benign entity. Am Heart J. 2006;151:1260–1264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16781233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desai N, Cohen EA, Naylor D, et al.  A randomized comparison of radial artery and saphenousvein coronary bypass grafts. N Engl J Med. 2004;351(22):2302–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15564545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widimsky P, Straka Z, Stros P, et al.  One-year coronary bypass graft patency: A randomized comparison between off-pump and on-pump surgery angiographic results of the PRAGUE- 4 Trial. Circulation. 2004;110:3418–3423.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15557371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>PREVENT IV Investigators. Efficacy and safety of edifoligide, an E2F transcription factor decoy, for prevention of vein graft failure following coronary artery bypass graft surgery-PREVENT IV: A randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2005;294:2446–2454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16287955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
