<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">19352540</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2009</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-7270</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2009</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Acta biochimica et biophysica Sinica</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Acta Biochim Biophys Sin (Shanghai)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Regulation of TGF-beta signaling by Smad7.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>263</StartPage>
          <EndPage>272</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>263-72</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Transforming growth factor (TGF)-beta is a pleiotropic cytokine regulating a variety of cellular processes such as cell growth, differentiation, apoptosis, migration, cell adhesion, and immune response. In the well-understood classical TGF-beta signaling pathway, TGF-beta activates Smad signalling via its two cell surface receptors such as TbetaRII and ALK5/TbetaRI, leading to Smad-mediated transcriptional regulation. In addition, TGF-beta may also activate other signaling pathways like mitogen-activated protein kinase, PI3K, etc. The signaling of TGF-beta is finely regulated at different levels. Inhibitory Smads, including Smad6 and Smad7, are key regulators of TGF-beta/bone morphogenetic protein (BMP) signaling by negative feedback loops. They can form stable complexes with activated type I receptors and thereby blocking the phosphorylation of R-Smads, or recruit ubiquitin E3 ligases, such as Smurf1/2, resulting in the ubiquitination and degradation of the activated type I receptors. Besides, these inhibitory Smad proteins also inhibit TGF-beta/BMP signaling in the nucleus by interacting with transcriptional repressors, such as histone deacetylases, Hoxc-8, and CtBP, or disrupting the formation of the TGF-beta-induced functional Smad-DNA complexes. Smad7 is in turn regulated by different stimuli, including TGF-beta, IFN-gamma, TNF-alpha as well as ultraviolet and TPA, and mediates the crosstalk between TGF-beta and other signaling pathways. Deregulation of Smad7 expression has been associated with various human diseases, such as tissue fibrosis, inflammatory disease as well as carcinogenesis. Overexpression of Smad7 has been shown to antagonize TGF-beta-mediated fibrosis, carcinogenesis, and inflammation, suggesting a therapeutic potential of Smad7 to treat these diseases.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaohua</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Biomembrane and Membrane Biotechnology, Department of Biological Sciences and Biotechnology, Tsinghua University, Beijing 100084, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ziying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yeguang</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Acta Biochim Biophys Sin (Shanghai)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101206716</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1672-9145</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051906">Smad7 Protein</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016212">Transforming Growth Factor beta</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.12.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D020929">Mitogen-Activated Protein Kinase Kinases</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004789" MajorTopicYN="N">Enzyme Activation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005786" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020929" MajorTopicYN="N">Mitogen-Activated Protein Kinase Kinases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Biological</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010766" MajorTopicYN="N">Phosphorylation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051906" MajorTopicYN="N">Smad7 Protein</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016212" MajorTopicYN="N">Transforming Growth Factor beta</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2009</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2009</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2009</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19352540</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7110000</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/abbs/gmp018</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derynck R, Akhurst RJ. Differentiation plasticity regulated by TGF-beta family proteins in development and disease. Nat Cell Biol. 2007;9:1000–1004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Massague J. TGFbeta in cancer. Cell. 2008;134:215–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3512574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18662538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li MO, Flavell RA. TGF-beta: a master of all T cell trades. Cell. 2008;134:392–404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3677783</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18692464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunes I, Gleizes PE, Metz CN, Rifkin DB. Latent transforming growth factor-beta binding protein domains involved in activation and transglutaminase-dependent cross-linking of latent transforming growth factor-beta. J Cell Biol. 1997;136:1151–1163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2132473</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9060478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ten Dijke P, Arthur HM. Extracellular control of TGFbeta signalling in vascular development and disease. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8:857–869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17895899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Y, Massague J. Mechanisms of TGF-beta signaling from cell membrane to the nucleus. Cell. 2003;113:685–700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12809600</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown KA, Pietenpol JA, Moses HL. A tale of two proteins: differential roles and regulation of Smad2 and Smad3 in TGF-beta signaling. J Cell Biochem. 2007;101:9–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17340614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang RH, Li C, Xu X, Zheng Y, Xiao C, Zerfas P, Cooperman S, et al.  A role of SMAD4 in iron metabolism through the positive regulation of hepcidin expression. Cell Metab. 2005;2:399–409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao X, Nicholls JM, Chen YG. Severe acute respiratory syndrome-associated coronavirus nucleocapsid protein interacts with Smad3 and modulates transforming growth factor-beta signaling. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:3272–3280.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740907</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18055455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He W, Dorn DC, Erdjument-Bromage H, Tempst P, Moore MA, Massague J. Hematopoiesis controlled by distinct TIF1gamma and Smad4 branches of the TGF-beta pathway. Cell. 2006;125:929–941.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16751102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee MK, Pardoux C, Hall MC, Lee PS, Warburton D, Qing J, Smith SM, et al.  TGF-beta activates Erk MAP kinase signalling through direct phosphorylation of ShcA. EMBO J. 2007;26:3957–3967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1994119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17673906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sorrentino A, Thakur N, Grimsby S, Marcusson A, von Bulow V, Schuster N, Zhang S, et al.  The type I TGF-beta receptor engages TRAF6 to activate TAK1 in a receptor kinase-independent manner. Nat Cell Biol. 2008;10:1199–1207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18758450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamashita M, Fatyol K, Jin C, Wang X, Liu Z, Zhang YE. TRAF6 mediates Smad-independent activation of JNK and p38 by TGF-beta. Mol Cell. 2008;31:918–924.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18922473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanyu A, Ishidou Y, Ebisawa T, Shimanuki T, Imamura T, Miyazono K. The N domain of Smad7 is essential for specific inhibition of transforming growth factor-beta signaling. J Cell Biol. 2001;155:1017–1027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2150897</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mochizuki T, Miyazaki H, Hara T, Furuya T, Imamura T, Watabe T, Miyazono K. Roles for the MH2 domain of Smad7 in the specific inhibition of transforming growth factor-beta superfamily signaling. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:31568–31574.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15148321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Fei T, Zhang L, Zhang R, Chen F, Ning Y, Han Y, et al.  Smad7 antagonizes transforming growth factor beta signaling in the nucleus by interfering with functional Smad-DNA complex formation. Mol Cell Biol. 2007;27:4488–4499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1900056</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17438144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi X, Chen F, Yu J, Xu Y, Zhang S, Chen YG, Fang X. Study of interaction between Smad7 and DNA by single-molecule force spectroscopy. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2008;377:1284–1287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18992714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayashi H, Abdollah S, Qiu Y, Cai J, Xu YY, Grinnell BW, Richardson MA, et al.  The MAD-related protein Smad7 associates with the TGF-beta receptor and functions as an antagonist of TGF-beta signaling. Cell. 1997;89:1165–1173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9215638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itoh S, ten Dijke P. Negative regulation of TGF-beta receptor/Smad signal transduction. Curr Opin Cell Biol. 2007;19:176–184.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17317136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi W, Sun C, He B, Xiong W, Shi X, Yao D, Cao X. GADD34-PP1c recruited by Smad7 dephosphorylates TGF-beta type I receptor. J Cell Biol. 2004;164:291–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2172339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14718519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valdimarsdottir G, Goumans MJ, Itoh F, Itoh S, Heldin CH, ten Dijke P. Smad7 and protein phosphatase 1alpha are critical determinants in the duration of TGF-beta/ALK1 signaling in endothelial cells. BMC Cell Biol. 2006;7:16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1479810</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16571110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hata A, Lagna G, Massague J, Hemmati-Brivanlou A. Smad6 inhibits BMP/Smad1 signaling by specifically competing with the Smad4 tumor suppressor. Genes Dev. 1998;12:186–197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC316444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9436979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai S, Cao X. A nuclear antagonistic mechanism of inhibitory Smads in transforming growth factor-beta signaling. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:4176–4182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11711531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai S, Shi X, Yang X, Cao X. Smad6 as a transcriptional corepressor. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:8267–8270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ichijo T, Voutetakis A, Cotrim AP, Bhattachryya N, Fujii M, Chrousos GP, Kino T. The Smad6-histone deacetylase 3 complex silences the transcriptional activity of the glucocorticoid receptor: potential clinical implications. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:42067–42077.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16249187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin X, Liang YY, Sun B, Liang M, Shi Y, Brunicardi FC, Feng XH. Smad6 recruits transcription corepressor CtBP to repress bone morphogenetic protein-induced transcription. Mol Cell Biol. 2003;23:9081–9093.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC309600</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14645520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Datta PK, Moses HL. STRAP and Smad7 synergize in the inhibition of transforming growth factor beta signaling. Mol Cell Biol. 2000;20:3157–3167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC85610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10757800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lallemand F, Seo SR, Ferrand N, Pessah M, L'Hoste S, Rawadi G, Roman-Roman S, et al.  AIP4 restricts transforming growth factor-beta signaling through a ubiquitination-independent mechanism. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:27645–27653.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15946939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koinuma D, Shinozaki M, Komuro A, Goto K, Saitoh M, Hanyu A, Ebina M, et al.  Arkadia amplifies TGF-beta superfamily signaling through degradation of Smad7. EMBO J. 2003;22:6458–6470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC291827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14657019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu W, Rui H, Wang J, Lin S, He Y, Chen M, Li Q, et al.  Axin is a scaffold protein in TGF-beta signaling that promotes degradation of Smad7 by Arkadia. EMBO J. 2006;25:1646–1658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1440825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16601693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim BC, Lee HJ, Park SH, Lee SR, Karpova TS, McNally JG, Felici A, et al.  Jab1/CSN5, a component of the COP9 signalosome, regulates transforming growth factor beta signaling by binding to Smad7 and promoting its degradation. Mol Cell Biol. 2004;24:2251–2262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC355855</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Song K, Krebs TL, Yang J, Danielpour D. Smad7 is inactivated through a direct physical interaction with the LIM protein Hic-5/ARA55. Oncogene. 2008;27:6791–6805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285457</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18762808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrigno O, Lallemand F, Verrecchia F, L'Hoste S, Camonis J, Atfi A, Mauviel A. Yes-associated protein (YAP65) interacts with Smad7 and potentiates its inhibitory activity against TGF-beta/Smad signaling. Oncogene. 2002;21:4879–4884.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12118366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kowanetz M, Lonn P, Vanlandewijck M, Kowanetz K, Heldin CH, Moustakas A. TGF-beta induces SIK to negatively regulate type I receptor kinase signaling. J Cell Biol. 2008;182:655–662.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2518705</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18725536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inamoto S, Iwata S, Inamoto T, Nomura S, Sasaki T, Urasaki Y, Hosono O, et al.  Crk-associated substrate lymphocyte type regulates transforming growth factor-beta signaling by inhibiting Smad6 and Smad7. Oncogene. 2007;26:893–904.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16909115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YG, Liu F, Massague J. Mechanism of TGF-beta receptor inhibition by FKBP12. EMBO J. 1997;16:3866–3876.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1170011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9233797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamaguchi T, Kurisaki A, Yamakawa N, Minakuchi K, Sugino H. FKBP12 functions as an adaptor of the Smad7-Smurf1 complex on activin type I receptor. J Mol Endocrinol. 2006;36:569–579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16720724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kume S, Haneda M, Kanasaki K, Sugimoto T, Araki S, Isshiki K, Isono M, et al.  SIRT1 inhibits transforming growth factor beta-induced apoptosis in glomerular mesangial cells via Smad7 deacetylation. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:151–158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17098745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simonsson M, Heldin CH, Ericsson J, Gronroos E. The balance between acetylation and deacetylation controls Smad7 stability. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:21797–21803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15831498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gronroos E, Hellman U, Heldin CH, Ericsson J. Control of Smad7 stability by competition between acetylation and ubiquitination. Mol Cell. 2002;10:483–493.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12408818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stopa M, Anhuf D, Terstegen L, Gatsios P, Gressner AM, Dooley S. Participation of Smad2, Smad3, and Smad4 in transforming growth factor beta (TGF-beta)-induced activation of Smad7. The TGF-beta response element of the promoter requires functional Smad binding element and E-box sequences for transcriptional regulation. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:29308–29317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10887185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hua X, Miller ZA, Benchabane H, Wrana JL, Lodish HF. Synergism between transcription factors TFE3 and Smad3 in transforming growth factor-beta-induced transcription of the Smad7 gene. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:33205–33208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodin G, Ahgren A, ten Dijke P, Heldin CH, Heuchel R. Efficient TGF-beta induction of the Smad7 gene requires cooperation between AP-1, Sp1, and Smad proteins on the mouse Smad7 promoter. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:29023–29030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10843994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Q, Wei X, Zhu T, Zhang M, Shen R, Xing L, O'Keefe RJ, et al.  Bone morphogenetic protein 2 activates Smad6 gene transcription through bone-specific transcription factor Runx2. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:10742–10748.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636961</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17215250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ku M, Howard S, Ni W, Lagna G, Hata A. OAZ regulates bone morphogenetic protein signaling through Smad6 activation. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:5277–5287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denissova NG, Liu F. Repression of endogenous Smad7 by Ski. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:28143–28148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15128733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park SH. Fine tuning and cross-talking of TGF-beta signal by inhibitory Smads. J Biochem Mol Biol. 2005;38:9–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15715940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quan T, He T, Voorhees JJ, Fisher GJ. Ultraviolet irradiation induces Smad7 via induction of transcription factor AP-1 in human skin fibroblasts. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:8079–8085.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15579469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong S, Lim S, Li AG, Lee C, Lee YS, Lee EK, Park SH, et al.  Smad7 binds to the adaptors TAB2 and TAB3 to block recruitment of the kinase TAK1 to the adaptor TRAF2. Nat Immunol. 2007;8:504–513.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17384642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi KC, Lee YS, Lim S, Choi HK, Lee CH, Lee EK, Hong S, et al.  Smad6 negatively regulates interleukin 1-receptor-Toll-like receptor signaling through direct interaction with the adaptor Pellino-1. Nat Immunol. 2006;7:1057–1065.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16951688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazars A, Lallemand F, Prunier C, Marais J, Ferrand N, Pessah M, Cherqui G, et al.  Evidence for a role of the JNK cascade in Smad7-mediated apoptosis. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:36797–36803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11477069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edlund S, Bu S, Schuster N, Aspenstrom P, Heuchel R, Heldin NE, ten Dijke P, et al.  Transforming growth factor-beta1 (TGF-beta1)-induced apoptosis of prostate cancer cells involves Smad7-dependent activation of p38 by TGF-beta-activated kinase 1 and mitogen-activated protein kinase kinase 3. Mol Biol Cell. 2003;14:529–544.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12589052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwai T, Murai J, Yoshikawa H, Tsumaki N. Smad7 inhibits chondrocyte differentiation at multiple steps during endochondral bone formation and down-regulates p38 MAPK pathways. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:27154–27164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18644788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edlund S, Landstrom M, Heldin CH, Aspenstrom P. Smad7 is required for TGF-beta-induced activation of the small GTPase Cdc42. J Cell Sci. 2004;117:1835–1847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15075243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edlund S, Lee SY, Grimsby S, Zhang S, Aspenstrom P, Heldin CH, Landstrom M. Interaction between Smad7 and beta-catenin: importance for transforming growth factor beta-induced apoptosis. Mol Cell Biol. 2005;25:1475–1488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC548008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15684397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han G, Li AG, Liang YY, Owens P, He W, Lu S, Yoshimatsu Y, et al.  Smad7-induced beta-catenin degradation alters epidermal appendage development. Dev Cell. 2006;11:301–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang Y, Liu Z, Zhao L, Clemens TL, Cao X. Smad7 stabilizes beta-catenin binding to E-cadherin complex and promotes cell-cell adhesion. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:23956–23963.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2527110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18593713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanchez-Capelo A. Dual role for TGF-beta1 in apoptosis. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2005;16:15–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15733830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohgushi M, Kuroki S, Fukamachi H, O'Reilly LA, Kuida K, Strasser A, Yonehara S. Transforming growth factor beta-dependent sequential activation of Smad, Bim, and caspase-9 mediates physiological apoptosis in gastric epithelial cells. Mol Cell Biol. 2005;25:10017–10028.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1280259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuster N, Krieglstein K. Mechanisms of TGF-beta-mediated apoptosis. Cell Tissue Res. 2002;307:1–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11810309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanders KC. Smad3 as a mediator of the fibrotic response. Int J Exp Pathol. 2004;85:47–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2517464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15154911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W, Koka V, Lan HY. Transforming growth factor-beta and Smad signalling in kidney diseases. Nephrology (Carlton) 2005;10:48–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15705182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lan HY. Smad7 as a therapeutic agent for chronic kidney diseases. Front Biosci. 2008;13:4984–4992.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18508563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang B, Omar A, Angelovska T, Drobic V, Rattan SG, Jones SC, Dixon IM. Regulation of collagen synthesis by inhibitory Smad7 in cardiac myofibroblasts. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2007;293:H1282–H1290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shull MM, Ormsby I, Kier AB, Pawlowski S, Diebold RJ, Yin M, Allen R, et al.  Targeted disruption of the mouse transforming growth factor-beta 1 gene results in multifocal inflammatory disease. Nature. 1992;359:693–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3889166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1436033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li MO, Sanjabi S, Flavell RA. Transforming growth factor-beta controls development, homeostasis, and tolerance of T cells by regulatory T cell-dependent and -independent mechanisms. Immunity. 2006;25:455–471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li MO, Wan YY, Sanjabi S, Robertson AK, Flavell RA. Transforming growth factor-beta regulation of immune responses. Annu Rev Immunol. 2006;24:99–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16551245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteleone G, Pallone F, MacDonald TT. Smad7 in TGF-beta-mediated negative regulation of gut inflammation. Trends Immunol. 2004;25:513–517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15364052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteleone G, Kumberova A, Croft NM, McKenzie C, Steer HW, MacDonald TT. Blocking Smad7 restores TGF-beta1 signaling in chronic inflammatory bowel disease. J Clin Invest. 2001;108:601–609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC209401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11518734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteleone G, Mann J, Monteleone I, Vavassori P, Bremner R, Fantini M, Del Vecchio Blanco G, et al.  A failure of transforming growth factor-beta1 negative regulation maintains sustained NF-kappaB activation in gut inflammation. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:3925–3932.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14600158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W, Huang XR, Li AG, Liu F, Li JH, Truong LD, Wang XJ, et al.  Signaling mechanism of TGF-beta1 in prevention of renal inflammation: role of Smad7. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2005;16:1371–1383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng YY, Hou CC, Wang W, Huang XR, Lan HY. Blockade of NF-kappaB activation and renal inflammation by ultrasound-mediated gene transfer of Smad7 in rat remnant kidney. Kidney Int Suppl. 2005;94:S83–S91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15752249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broderick P, Carvajal-Carmona L, Pittman AM, Webb E, Howarth K, Rowan A, Lubbe S, et al.  A genome-wide association study shows that common alleles of SMAD7 influence colorectal cancer risk. Nat Genet. 2007;39:1315–1317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17934461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin JJ, Selander K, Chirgwin JM, Dallas M, Grubbs BG, Wieser R, Massague J, et al.  TGF-beta signaling blockade inhibits PTHrP secretion by breast cancer cells and bone metastases development. J Clin Invest. 1999;103:197–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC407876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javelaud D, Mohammad KS, McKenna CR, Fournier P, Luciani F, Niewolna M, Andre J, et al.  Stable overexpression of Smad7 in human melanoma cells impairs bone metastasis. Cancer Res. 2007;67:2317–2324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17332363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javelaud D, Delmas V, Moller M, Sextius P, Andre J, Menashi S, Larue L, et al.  Stable overexpression of Smad7 in human melanoma cells inhibits their tumorigenicity in vitro and in vivo. Oncogene. 2005;24:7624–7629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16007121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerutti JM, Ebina KN, Matsuo SE, Martins L, Maciel RM, Kimura ET. Expression of Smad4 and Smad7 in human thyroid follicular carcinoma cell lines. J Endocrinol Invest. 2003;26:516–521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12952364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowdy SC, Mariani A, Reinholz MM, Keeney GL, Spelsberg TC, Podratz KC, Janknecht R. Overexpression of the TGF-beta antagonist Smad7 in endometrial cancer. Gynecol Oncol. 2005;96:368–373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15661223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikula M, Proell V, Fischer AN, Mikulits W. Activated hepatic stellate cells induce tumor progression of neoplastic hepatocytes in a TGF-beta dependent fashion. J Cell Physiol. 2006;209:560–567.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2900580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16883581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azuma H, Ehata S, Miyazaki H, Watabe T, Maruyama O, Imamura T, Sakamoto T, et al.  Effect of Smad7 expression on metastasis of mouse mammary carcinoma JygMC(A) cells. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2005;97:1734–1746.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fidler IJ. Blockade of the TGF-beta superfamily by Smad7 breaking a link in the metastatic chain. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2005;97:1714–1715.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16333022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halder SK, Beauchamp RD, Datta PK. Smad7 induces tumorigenicity by blocking TGF-beta-induced growth inhibition and apoptosis. Exp Cell Res. 2005;307:231–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15922743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleeff J, Ishiwata T, Maruyama H, Friess H, Truong P, Buchler MW, Falb D, et al.  The TGF-beta signaling inhibitor Smad7 enhances tumorigenicity in pancreatic cancer. Oncogene. 1999;18:5363–5372.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10498890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, Lee J, Cooley M, Bhogte E, Hartley S, Glick A. Smad7 but not Smad6 cooperates with oncogenic ras to cause malignant conversion in a mouse model for squamous cell carcinoma. Cancer Res. 2003;63:7760–7768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14633701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niemann C, Owens DM, Hulsken J, Birchmeier W, Watt FM. Expression of DeltaNLef1 in mouse epidermis results in differentiation of hair follicles into squamous epidermal cysts and formation of skin tumours. Development. 2002;129:95–109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11782404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bornstein S, Hoot K, Han GW, Lu SL, Wang XJ. Distinct roles of individual Smads in skin carcinogenesis. Mol Carcinog. 2007;46:660–664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17477360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
