<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301487</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK1310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="sms">Smith-Magenis Syndrome</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Ann CM</ForeName><Initials>ACM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chair Emeritus, PRISMS Professional Advisory Board Head, SMS Research Team Office of the Clinical Director National Human Genome Research Institute National Institutes of Health Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boyd</LastName><ForeName>Kerry E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry &amp; Behavioural Neurosciences McMaster University Hamilton, Ontario, Canada</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brennan</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech, Language, &amp; Hearing Sciences University of Colorado Boulder, Colorado</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charles</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics Division of Developmental-Behavioral Pediatrics Medical University of South Carolina Charleston, South Carolina</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elsea</LastName><ForeName>Sarah H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular and Human Genetics Baylor College of Medicine Houston, Texas</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finucane</LastName><ForeName>Brenda M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism &amp; Developmental Medicine Institute Geisinger Lewisburg Lewisburg, Pennsylvania</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foster</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology St Louis Children's Hospital St Louis, Missouri</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gropman</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's National Health System Washington, DC</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girirajan</LastName><ForeName>Santhosh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology Pennsylvania State University University Park, Pennsylvania</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haas-Givler</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism &amp; Developmental Medicine Institute Geisinger Lewisburg Lewisburg, Pennsylvania</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Smith-Magenis syndrome (SMS) is characterized by distinctive physical features (particularly coarse facial features that progress with age), developmental delay, cognitive impairment, behavioral abnormalities, sleep disturbance, and childhood-onset abdominal obesity. Infants have feeding difficulties, failure to thrive, hypotonia, hyporeflexia, prolonged napping or need to be awakened for feeds, and generalized lethargy. The majority of individuals function in the mild-to-moderate range of intellectual disability. The behavioral phenotype, including significant sleep disturbance, stereotypies, and maladaptive and self-injurious behaviors, is generally not recognized until age 18 months or older and continues to change until adulthood. Sensory issues are frequently noted; these may include avoidant behavior, as well as repetitive seeking of textures, sounds, and experiences. Toileting difficulties are common. Significant anxiety is common as are problems with executive functioning, including inattention, distractibility, hyperactivity, and impulsivity. Maladaptive behaviors include frequent outbursts / temper tantrums, attention-seeking behaviors, opposition, aggression, and self-injurious behaviors including self-hitting, self-biting, skin picking, inserting foreign objects into body orifices (polyembolokoilamania), and yanking fingernails and/or toenails (onychotillomania). Among the stereotypic behaviors described, the spasmodic upper-body squeeze or "self-hug" seems to be highly associated with SMS. An underlying developmental asynchrony, specifically emotional maturity delayed beyond intellectual functioning, may also contribute to maladaptive behaviors in people with SMS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of SMS is established in a proband who has suggestive clinical findings and either a heterozygous deletion at chromosome 17p11.2 that includes <i>RAI1</i> or a heterozygous intragenic <i>RAI1</i> pathogenic variant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Early-childhood intervention programs; individualized special education for school-aged children; speech/language, physical, occupational, and behavior therapy and vocational training support later in life. Affected individuals may also benefit from monitored trials of psychotropic medication to increase attention and/or decrease hyperactivity, and therapeutic management of sleep disorders. Standard treatment for epilepsy, obesity, gastroesophageal reflux disease, constipation, hypercholesterolemia, palatal anomalies, scoliosis, ophthalmologic issues, recurrent otitis media, hearing loss, cardiac anomalies, renal anomalies, mild immunodeficiency, hypothyroidism, and growth hormone deficiency. Individuals with a 17p11.2 deletion that includes <i>FLCN</i> may require management of features of Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome (BHD). Respite care and psychosocial support for family members are recommended. <i>Surveillance:</i> Annual multidisciplinary evaluations for general health and well-being and to plan for educational and vocational or other individualized interventions. In particular, periodic neurodevelopmental assessments and/or consultation with a developmental pediatrician to monitor progress and refer for additional services, evaluations, or support. School-aged children should have periodic comprehensive evaluation to give input to the individualized education program. Annual otolaryngology, audiology, and ophthalmology evaluations. Measurement of growth parameters and nutritional status at each visit. Monitor for the development and/or progression of seizures and scoliosis. Annual fasting lipid profile, screening urinalysis for occult urinary tract infections, and thyroid function tests. Annual family psychosocial assessments are also recommended to assess support for caregivers and sibs. Repeat quantitative immunoglobulins / vaccine titers as clinically indicated. Surveillance for complications of BHD in those with a 17p11.2 deletion that includes <i>FLCN.</i> <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid:</i> When starting a new medication, care should be taken to track sleep and behavior changes over several days or weeks to monitor for potential side effects (e.g., increased appetite, weight gain) and adverse reactions and/or to determine potential efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">SMS is caused by a heterozygous deletion of or a heterozygous pathogenic variant in RAI1 on chromosome 17p11.2. The majority of 17p11.2 deletions are <i>de novo</i>, while deleterious variants in <i>RAI1</i> can be <i>de novo</i> or inherited. Complex familial chromosome rearrangements leading to del(17)(p11.2) and SMS occur but are rare. Although SMS usually occurs as the result of a <i>de novo</i> deletion of 17p11.2, rare instances of vertical transmission from an affected parent to a child, parental germline mosaicism, and complex familial chromosome rearrangements leading to del(17)(p11.2) and SMS have been reported. If the SMS-related genetic alteration has been identified in an affected family member, prenatal testing for a pregnancy at increased risk and preimplantation genetic testing are possible. In the rare instance of a complex familial chromosome rearrangement, prenatal testing is possible for a pregnancy at increased risk using prenatal chromosomal microarray analysis (CMA) and sequencing on fetal cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorder">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">del(17)(p11.2)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">del(17)(p11.2)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retinoic acid-induced protein 1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RAI1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smith-Magenis Syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2001</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><ItemList ListType="Synonyms"><Item>del(17)(p11.2)</Item></ItemList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acquaviva F, Sana ME, Della Monica M, Pinelli M, Postorivo D, Fontana P, Falco MT, Nardone AM, Lonardo F, Iascone M, Scarano G. First evidence of Smith Magenis syndrome in mother and daughter due to a novel RAI mutation. Am J Med Genet A. 2017;173:231–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaimo JT, Hahn NH, Mullegama SV, Elsea SH. Dietary regimens modify early onset of obesity in mice haploinsufficient for Rai1. PLoS One. 2014;9:e105077. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25127133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allanson JE, Greenberg F, Smith AC. The face of Smith-Magenis syndrome: a subjective and objective study. J Med Genet. 1999;36:394–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10353786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arron K, Oliver C, Moss J, Berg K, Burbidge C. The prevalence and phenomenology of self-injurious and aggressive behaviour in genetic syndromes. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2011;55:109–20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi W, Saifi GM, Shaw CJ, Walz K, Fonseca P, Wilson M, Potocki L, Lupski JR. Mutations of RAI1, a PHD-containing protein, in nondeletion patients with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Hum Genet. 2004;115:515–24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15565467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boone PM, Reiter RJ, Glaze DG, Tan DX, Lupski JR, Potocki L. Abnormal circadian rhythm of melatonin in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients with RAI1 point mutations. Am J Med Genet A. 2011;155A:2024–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21739587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreau EA, Johnson KP, Jackman AR, Blancato J, Huizing M, Bendavid C, Jones M, Chandrasekharappa SC, Lewy AJ, Smith AC, Magenis RE. Review of disrupted sleep patterns in Smith-Magenis syndrome and normal melatonin secretion in a patient with an atypical interstitial 17p11.2 deletion. Am J Med Genet A. 2009;149A:1382–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19530184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brendal MA, Carmen C, Brewer CC, King KA, Zalewski CK, Finucane BM, Introne W. Smith ACM. Auditory phenotype of Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2017;60:1076–87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5548078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns B, Schmidt K, Williams SR, Kim S, Girirajan S, Elsea SH. Rai1 haploinsufficiency causes reduced Bdnf expression resulting in hyperphagia, obesity and altered fat distribution in mice and humans with no evidence of metabolic syndrome. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:4026–42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell IM, Yuan B, Robberecht C, Pfundt R, Szafranski P, McEntagart ME, Nagamani SC, Erez A, Bartnik M, Wiśniowiecka-Kowalnik B, Plunkett KS, Pursley AN, Kang SH, Bi W, Lalani SR, Bacino CA, Vast M, Marks K, Patton M, Olofsson P, Patel A, Veltman JA, Cheung SW, Shaw CA, Vissers LE, Vermeesch JR, Lupski JR, Stankiewicz P. Parental somatic mosaicism is underrecognized and influences recurrence risk of genomic disorders. Am J Hum Genet. 2014;95:173–82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Mora P, Encina CA, Canales CP, Cao L, Molina J, Kairath P, Young JI, Walz K. Functional and cellular characterization of human Retinoic Acid Induced 1 (RAI1) mutations associated with Smith-Magenis Syndrome. BMC Mol Biol. 2010;11:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20738874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhry AP, Schwartz C, Singh AS. Stroke after cardiac surgery. Tex Heart Inst J. 2007;34:247–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1894707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17622381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KS, Manian P, Koeuth T, Potocki L, Zhao Q, Chinault AC, Lee CC, Lupski JR. Homologous recombination of a flanking repeat gene cluster is a mechanism for a common contiguous gene deletion syndrome. Nat Genet. 1997;17:154–63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9326934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chik CL, Rollag MD, Duncan WC, Smith AC. Diagnostic utility of daytime salivary melatonin levels in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2010;152A:96–101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou IC, Tsai FJ, Yu MT, Tsai CH. Smith-Magenis syndrome with bilateral vesicoureteral reflux: a case report. J Formos Med Assoc. 2002;101:726–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12517050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claes P, Liberton DK, Daniels K, Rosana KM, Quillen EE, Pearson LN, McEvoy B, Bauchet M, Zaidi AA, Yao W, Tang H, Barsh GS, Absher DM, Puts DA, Rocha J, Beleza S, Pereira RW, Baynam G, Suetens P, Vandermeulen D, Wagner JK, Boster JS, Shriver MD. Modeling 3D facial shape from DNA. PLoS Genet. 2014;10:e1004224. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3961191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24651127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardour L, Verleyen P, Lesage K, Holvoet M, Devriendt K. Bilateral renal tumors in an adult man with Smith-Magenis syndrome: the role of the FLCN gene. Eur J Med Genet. 2016;59:499–501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leersnyder H, Claustrat B, Munnich A, Verloes A. Circadian rhythm disorder in a rare disease: Smith-Magenis syndrome. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2006;252:88–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16723183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leersnyder H, De Blois MC, Claustrat B, Romana S, Albrecht U, Von Kleist-Retzow JC, Delobel B, Viot G, Lyonnet S, Vekemans M, Munnich A. Inversion of the circadian rhythm of melatonin in the Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Pediatr. 2001;139:111–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denny AD, Weik LD, Lubinsky MS, Wyatt DT. Lethal adrenal aplasia in an infant with Smith-Magenis syndrome, deletion 17p11.2. J Dysmorph Clin Genet. 1992;6:175–9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diessler S, Kostic C, Arsenijevic Y, Kawasaki A, Franken P. Rai1 frees mice from the repression of active wake behaviors by light. Elife. 2017;6:e23292. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28548639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubourg C, Bonnet-Brilhault F, Toutain A, Mignot C, Jacquette A, Dieux A, Gérard M, Beaumont-Epinette M-P, Julia S, Isidor B, Rossi IM, Odent S, Bendavid C, Barthélémy C, Verloes A, David V. Identification of nine new RAI1-truncating mutations in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients without 17p11.2 deletions. Mol Syndromol. 2014;5:57–64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3977224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan WC, Gropman A, Morse R, Krasnewich D, Smith ACM. Good babies sleeping poorly: insufficient sleep in infants with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Hum Genet. 2003;73 suppl:A896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykens EM, Smith AC. Distinctiveness and correlates of maladaptive behaviour in children and adolescents with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 1998;42:481–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10030444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelman EA, Girirajan S, Finucane B, Patel PI, Lupski JR, Smith AC, Elsea SH. Gender, genotype, and phenotype differences in Smith-Magenis syndrome: a meta-analysis of 105 cases. Clin Genet. 2007;71:540–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17539903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falco M, Amabile S, Acquaviva F. RAI1 gene mutations: mechanisms of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Appl Clin Genet. 2017;10:85–94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan YS, Farrell SA. Prenatal diagnosis of interstitial deletion of 17(p11.2p11.2) (Smith-Magenis syndrome) Am J Med Genet. 1994;49:253–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8116679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane B, Dirrigl KH, Simon EW. Characterization of self-injurious behaviors in children and adults with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Ment Retard. 2001;106:52–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11246713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane B, Haas-Givler B. Smith-Magenis syndrome: genetic basis and clinical implications. J Ment Health Res Intel Disab. 2009;2:134–48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane B, Savatt JM, Shimelis H, Girirajan S, Myers SM. Birt-Hogg-Dubé symptoms in Smith-Magenis syndrome include pediatric-onset pneumothorax. Am J Med Genet A. 2021;185:1922–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33666332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster RH, Kozachek S, Stern M, Elsea SH. Caring for the caregivers: an investigation of factors related to well-being among parents caring for a child with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Genet Couns. 2010;19:187–98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20151318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girirajan S, Elsas Ii LJ, Devriendt KH, Elsea SH. RAI1 variations in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients without 17p11.2 deletions. J Med Genet. 2005;42:820–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girirajan S, Mendoza-Londono R, Vlangos CN, Dupuis L, Nowak NJ, Bunyan DJ, Hatchwell E, Elsea SH. Smith-Magenis syndrome and Moyamoya disease in a patient with del(17) (p11.2p13.1). Am J Med Genet. 2007;143A:999–1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17431895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg F, Guzzetta V, Montes de Oca-Luna R, Magenis RE, Smith AC, Richter SF, Kondo I, Dobyns WB, Patel PI, Lupski JR. Molecular analysis of the Smith-Magenis syndrome: a possible contiguous-gene syndrome associated with del(17)(p11.2). Am J Hum Genet. 1991;49:1207–18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1686451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1746552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg F, Lewis RA, Potocki L, Glaze D, Parke J, Killian J, Murphy MA, Williamson D, Brown F, Dutton R, McCluggage C, Friedman E, Sulek M, Lupski JR. Multi-disciplinary clinical study of Smith-Magenis syndrome (deletion 17p11.2). Am J Med Genet. 1996;62:247–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8882782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropman AL, Duncan WC, Smith AC. Neurologic and developmental features of the Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2). Pediatr Neurol. 2006;34:337–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16647992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropman AL, Elsea S, Duncan WC, Jr, Smith AC. New developments in Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2). Curr Opin Neurol. 2007;20:125–34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17351481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildenbrand HL, Smith AC. Analysis of the sensory profile in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. 2012;32:48–65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21599572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodapp RM, Fidler DJ, Smith AC. Stress and coping in families of children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 1998;42:331–40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9828063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang WH, Guenthner CJ, Xu J, Nguyen T, Schwarz LA, Wilkinson AW, Gozani O, Chang HY, Shamloo M, Luo L. Molecular and neural functions of Rai1, the causal gene for Smith-Magenis syndrome. Neuron. 2016;92:392–406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5098476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27693255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itoh M, Hayashi M, Hasegawa T, Shimohira M, Kohyama J. Systemic growth hormone corrects sleep disturbance in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Brain Dev. 2004;26:484–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laje G, Bernert R, Morse R, Pao M, Smith AC. Pharmacological treatment of disruptive behavior in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2010a;154C:463–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3022344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20981776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laje G, Morse R, Richter W, Ball J, Pao M, Smith AC. Autism spectrum features in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2010b;154C:456–62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20981775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SC, Wolters PL, Smith AC. Adaptive and maladaptive behavior in children with Smith-Magenis Syndrome. J Autism Dev Disord. 2006;36:541–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16570214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers SM, Challman TD, Bock GH. End-stage renal failure in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2007;143A:1922–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17603799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nováková M, Nevsímalová S, Príhodová I, Sládek M, Sumová A. Alteration of the circadian clock in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012;97:E312–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22162479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JP, Moeschler JB, Davies WS, Patel PI, Mohandas TK. Smith-Magenis syndrome resulting from a de novo direct insertion of proximal 17q into 17p11.2. Am J Med Genet. 1998;77:23–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9557889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins T, Rosenberg JM, Le Coz C, Alaimo JT, Trofa M, Mullegama SV, Antaya RJ, Jyonouchi S, Elsea SH, Utz PJ, Meffre E, Romberg N. Smith-Magenis syndrome patients often display antibody deficiency but not other immune pathologies. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2017;5:1344–50.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5591748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28286158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymeropoulos CM, Brooks J, Czeisler EL, Fisher MA, Gibson MM, Kite K, Smieszek SP, Xiao C, Elsea SH, Birznieks G, Polymeropoulos MH. Tasimelteon safely and effectively improves sleep in Smith-Magenis syndrome: a double-blind randomized trial followed by an open-label extension. Genet Med. 2021;23:2426–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34316024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Bi W, Treadwell-Deering D, Carvalho CM, Eifert A, Friedman EM, Glaze D, Krull K, Lee JA, Lewis RA, Mendoza-Londono R, Robbins-Furman P, Shaw C, Shi X, Weissenberger G, Withers M, Yatsenko SA, Zackai EH, Stankiewicz P, Lupski JR. Characterization of Potocki-Lupski syndrome (dup(17)(p11.2p11.2)) and delineation of a dosage-sensitive critical interval that can convey an autism phenotype. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;80:633–49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17357070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Chen KS, Park SS, Osterholm DE, Withers MA, Kimonis V, Summers AM, Meschino WS, Anyane-Yeboa K, Kashork CD, Shaffer LG, Lupski JR. Molecular mechanism for duplication 17p11.2- the homologous recombination reciprocal of the Smith-Magenis microdeletion. Nat Genet. 2000a;24:84–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10615134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Glaze D, Tan DX, Park SS, Kashork CD, Shaffer LG, Reiter RJ, Lupski JR. Circadian rhythm abnormalities of melatonin in Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Med Genet. 2000b;37:428–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10851253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Shaw CJ, Stankiewicz P, Lupski JR. Variability in clinical phenotype despite common del(17)(p11.2p11.2) chromosomal deletion in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Genet Med. 2003;5:430–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14614393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin NG, Huang B (2007) Prenatal diagnosis of 10 cases with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Cytogenet Genome Res. 116:324 (A10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rive Le Gouard N, Jacquinet A, Ruaud L, Deleersnyder H, Ageorges F, Gallard J, Lacombe D, Odent S, Mikaty M, Manouvrier-Hanu S, Ghoumid J, Geneviève D, Lehman N, Philip N, Edery P, Héron D, Rastel C, Chancenotte S, Thauvin-Robinet C, Faivre L, Perrin L, Verloes A. Smith-Magenis syndrome: clinical and behavioral characteristics in a large retrospective cohort. Clin Genet. 2021;99:519–28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33368193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt LS, Linehan WM. Molecular genetics and clinical features of Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome. Nat Rev Urol. 2015;12:558–69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5119524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26334087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slager RE, Newton TL, Vlangos CN, Finucane B, Elsea SH. Mutations in RAI1 associated with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Nat Genet. 2003;33:466–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12652298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloneem J, Oliver C, Udwin O, Woodcock KA. Prevalence, phenomenology, aetiology and predictors of challenging behaviour in Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2011;55:138–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21199049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Duncan WC. Smith-Magenis syndrome: a developmental disorder with circadian dysfunction. In: Butler MG, Meaney FJ, eds. Genetics of Developmental Disabilities. Boca Raton, LA: Taylor &amp; Francis Group; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Dykens E, Greenberg F. Sleep disturbance in Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17 p11.2). Am J Med Genet. 1998;81:186–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9613860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Gropman AL. Smith-Magenis Syndrome. In: Cassidy S &amp; Allanson J, eds. Management of Genetic Syndromes. 4 ed. New York, NY: Wiley-Blackwell. 2021;863-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Gropman AL, Bailey-Wilson JE, Goker-Alpan O, Elsea SH, Blancato J, Lupski JR, Potocki L. Hypercholesterolemia in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome: del (17) (p11.2p11.2). Genet Med. 2002;4:118–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12180145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Magenis RE, Elsea SH. Overview of Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Assoc Genet Technol. 2005;31:163–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16354942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, McGavran L, Robinson J, Waldstein G, Macfarlane J, Zonona J, Reiss J, Lahr M, Allen L, Magenis E. Interstitial deletion of (17)(p11.2p11.2) in nine patients. Am J Med Genet. 1986;24:393–414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2425619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Pletcher BA, Spilka J, Blancato J, Meck J. First report of two siblings with SMS due to maternal mosaicism. Poster session 829/C. New Orleans, LA: American Society of Human Genetics 56th Annual Meeting; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ACM, Fleming LR, Piskorski AM, Amin A, Phorphutkul C, delaMonte S, Stopa E, Introne W, Vilboux T, Duncan F, Pellegrino J, Braddock B, Middelton LA, Vocke C, Linehan WM. Deletion of 17p11.2 encompasses FLCN with increased risk of Birt-Hogg-Dubé in Smith Magenis syndrome: recommendation for cancer screening. Poster session. San Diego: American Society of Human Genetics Meeting; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ACM, Morse RS, Introne W, Duncan WC., Jr Twenty-four-hour motor activity and body temperature patterns suggest altered central circadian timekeeping in Smith-Magenis syndrome, a neurodevelopmental disorder. Am J Med Genet A. 2019;179:224–36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadoni E, Colapietro P, Bozzola M, Marseglia GL, Repossi L, Danesino C, Larizza L, Maraschio P. Smith-Magenis syndrome and growth hormone deficiency. Eur J Pediatr. 2004;163:353–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15138811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruyt K, Braam W, Smits M, Curfs LMG. Sleep complaints and the 24-h melatonin level in individuals with Smith-Magenis syndrome: assessment for effective intervention. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2016;22:928–35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6492880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27743421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir R, Kennedy A, Elsea SH, Dickinson AJ. Retinoic acid induced-1 (Rai1) regulates craniofacial and brain development in Xenopus. Mech Dev. 2014;133:91–104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DG, Jacques SM, Flore LA, Feldman B, Evans MI, Qureshi F. Prenatal diagnosis of Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2). Fetal Diagn Ther. 2000;15:335–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11111213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomona N, Smith AC, Guadagnini JP, Hart TC. Craniofacial and dental phenotype of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2006;140:2556–61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17001665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong HT, Dudding T, Blanchard CL, Elsea SH. Frameshift mutation hotspot identified in Smith-Magenis syndrome: case report and review of literature. BMC Med Genet. 2010;11:142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2964533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20932317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira GH, Rodriguez JD, Carmona-Mora P, Cao L, Gamba BF, Carvalho DR, de Rezende Duarte A, Santos SR. de Souza DH2, DuPont BR, Walz K, Moretti-Ferreira D, Srivastava AK. Detection of classical 17p11.2 deletions, an atypical deletion and RAI1 alterations in patients with features suggestive of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Eur J Hum Genet. 2012;20:148–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21897445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilboux T, Ciccone C, Blancato JK, Cox GF, Deshpande C, Introne WJ, Gahl WA, Smith AC, Huizing M. Molecular analysis of the retinoic acid induced 1 gene (RAI1) in patients with suspected Smith-Magenis syndrome without the 17p11.2 deletion. PLoS One. 2011;6:e22861. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlangos CN, Yim DK, Elsea SH. Refinement of the Smith-Magenis syndrome critical region to approximately 950kb and assessment of 17p11.2 deletions. Are all deletions created equally? Mol Genet Metab. 2003;79:134–41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12809645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolters PL, Gropman AL, Martin SC, Smith MR, Hildenbrand HL, Brewer CC, Smith ACM. Neurodevelopment of children under three years with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Pediatr Neurol. 2009;41:250–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2785222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19748044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang SP, Bidichandani SI, Figuera LE, Juyal RC, Saxon PJ, Baldini A, Patel PI. Molecular analysis of deletion (17)(p11.2p11.2) in a family segregating a 17p paracentric inversion: implications for carriers of paracentric inversions. Am J Hum Genet. 1997;60:1184–93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1712444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9150166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zori RT, Lupski JR, Heju Z, Greenberg F, Killian JM, Gray BA, Driscoll DJ, Patel PI, Zackowski JL. Clinical, cytogenetic, and molecular evidence for an infant with Smith- Magenis syndrome born from a mother having a mosaic 17p11.2p12 deletion. Am J Med Genet. 1993;47:504–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8256814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301487</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK1310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="sms">Smith-Magenis Syndrome</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Ann CM</ForeName><Initials>ACM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chair Emeritus, PRISMS Professional Advisory Board Head, SMS Research Team Office of the Clinical Director National Human Genome Research Institute National Institutes of Health Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boyd</LastName><ForeName>Kerry E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry &amp; Behavioural Neurosciences McMaster University Hamilton, Ontario, Canada</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brennan</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Speech, Language, &amp; Hearing Sciences University of Colorado Boulder, Colorado</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charles</LastName><ForeName>Jane</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics Division of Developmental-Behavioral Pediatrics Medical University of South Carolina Charleston, South Carolina</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elsea</LastName><ForeName>Sarah H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Molecular and Human Genetics Baylor College of Medicine Houston, Texas</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finucane</LastName><ForeName>Brenda M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism &amp; Developmental Medicine Institute Geisinger Lewisburg Lewisburg, Pennsylvania</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Foster</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology St Louis Children's Hospital St Louis, Missouri</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gropman</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's National Health System Washington, DC</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Girirajan</LastName><ForeName>Santhosh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry &amp; Molecular Biology Pennsylvania State University University Park, Pennsylvania</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haas-Givler</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Autism &amp; Developmental Medicine Institute Geisinger Lewisburg Lewisburg, Pennsylvania</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Smith-Magenis syndrome (SMS) is characterized by distinctive physical features (particularly coarse facial features that progress with age), developmental delay, cognitive impairment, behavioral abnormalities, sleep disturbance, and childhood-onset abdominal obesity. Infants have feeding difficulties, failure to thrive, hypotonia, hyporeflexia, prolonged napping or need to be awakened for feeds, and generalized lethargy. The majority of individuals function in the mild-to-moderate range of intellectual disability. The behavioral phenotype, including significant sleep disturbance, stereotypies, and maladaptive and self-injurious behaviors, is generally not recognized until age 18 months or older and continues to change until adulthood. Sensory issues are frequently noted; these may include avoidant behavior, as well as repetitive seeking of textures, sounds, and experiences. Toileting difficulties are common. Significant anxiety is common as are problems with executive functioning, including inattention, distractibility, hyperactivity, and impulsivity. Maladaptive behaviors include frequent outbursts / temper tantrums, attention-seeking behaviors, opposition, aggression, and self-injurious behaviors including self-hitting, self-biting, skin picking, inserting foreign objects into body orifices (polyembolokoilamania), and yanking fingernails and/or toenails (onychotillomania). Among the stereotypic behaviors described, the spasmodic upper-body squeeze or "self-hug" seems to be highly associated with SMS. An underlying developmental asynchrony, specifically emotional maturity delayed beyond intellectual functioning, may also contribute to maladaptive behaviors in people with SMS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of SMS is established in a proband who has suggestive clinical findings and either a heterozygous deletion at chromosome 17p11.2 that includes <i>RAI1</i> or a heterozygous intragenic <i>RAI1</i> pathogenic variant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Early-childhood intervention programs; individualized special education for school-aged children; speech/language, physical, occupational, and behavior therapy and vocational training support later in life. Affected individuals may also benefit from monitored trials of psychotropic medication to increase attention and/or decrease hyperactivity, and therapeutic management of sleep disorders. Standard treatment for epilepsy, obesity, gastroesophageal reflux disease, constipation, hypercholesterolemia, palatal anomalies, scoliosis, ophthalmologic issues, recurrent otitis media, hearing loss, cardiac anomalies, renal anomalies, mild immunodeficiency, hypothyroidism, and growth hormone deficiency. Individuals with a 17p11.2 deletion that includes <i>FLCN</i> may require management of features of Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome (BHD). Respite care and psychosocial support for family members are recommended. <i>Surveillance:</i> Annual multidisciplinary evaluations for general health and well-being and to plan for educational and vocational or other individualized interventions. In particular, periodic neurodevelopmental assessments and/or consultation with a developmental pediatrician to monitor progress and refer for additional services, evaluations, or support. School-aged children should have periodic comprehensive evaluation to give input to the individualized education program. Annual otolaryngology, audiology, and ophthalmology evaluations. Measurement of growth parameters and nutritional status at each visit. Monitor for the development and/or progression of seizures and scoliosis. Annual fasting lipid profile, screening urinalysis for occult urinary tract infections, and thyroid function tests. Annual family psychosocial assessments are also recommended to assess support for caregivers and sibs. Repeat quantitative immunoglobulins / vaccine titers as clinically indicated. Surveillance for complications of BHD in those with a 17p11.2 deletion that includes <i>FLCN.</i> <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid:</i> When starting a new medication, care should be taken to track sleep and behavior changes over several days or weeks to monitor for potential side effects (e.g., increased appetite, weight gain) and adverse reactions and/or to determine potential efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">SMS is caused by a heterozygous deletion of or a heterozygous pathogenic variant in RAI1 on chromosome 17p11.2. The majority of 17p11.2 deletions are <i>de novo</i>, while deleterious variants in <i>RAI1</i> can be <i>de novo</i> or inherited. Complex familial chromosome rearrangements leading to del(17)(p11.2) and SMS occur but are rare. Although SMS usually occurs as the result of a <i>de novo</i> deletion of 17p11.2, rare instances of vertical transmission from an affected parent to a child, parental germline mosaicism, and complex familial chromosome rearrangements leading to del(17)(p11.2) and SMS have been reported. If the SMS-related genetic alteration has been identified in an affected family member, prenatal testing for a pregnancy at increased risk and preimplantation genetic testing are possible. In the rare instance of a complex familial chromosome rearrangement, prenatal testing is possible for a pregnancy at increased risk using prenatal chromosomal microarray analysis (CMA) and sequencing on fetal cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorder">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="sms" sec="sms.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">del(17)(p11.2)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">del(17)(p11.2)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retinoic acid-induced protein 1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RAI1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smith-Magenis Syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2001</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><ItemList ListType="Synonyms"><Item>del(17)(p11.2)</Item></ItemList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Acquaviva F, Sana ME, Della Monica M, Pinelli M, Postorivo D, Fontana P, Falco MT, Nardone AM, Lonardo F, Iascone M, Scarano G. First evidence of Smith Magenis syndrome in mother and daughter due to a novel RAI mutation. Am J Med Genet A. 2017;173:231–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alaimo JT, Hahn NH, Mullegama SV, Elsea SH. Dietary regimens modify early onset of obesity in mice haploinsufficient for Rai1. PLoS One. 2014;9:e105077. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25127133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allanson JE, Greenberg F, Smith AC. The face of Smith-Magenis syndrome: a subjective and objective study. J Med Genet. 1999;36:394–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10353786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arron K, Oliver C, Moss J, Berg K, Burbidge C. The prevalence and phenomenology of self-injurious and aggressive behaviour in genetic syndromes. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2011;55:109–20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bi W, Saifi GM, Shaw CJ, Walz K, Fonseca P, Wilson M, Potocki L, Lupski JR. Mutations of RAI1, a PHD-containing protein, in nondeletion patients with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Hum Genet. 2004;115:515–24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15565467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boone PM, Reiter RJ, Glaze DG, Tan DX, Lupski JR, Potocki L. Abnormal circadian rhythm of melatonin in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients with RAI1 point mutations. Am J Med Genet A. 2011;155A:2024–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21739587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreau EA, Johnson KP, Jackman AR, Blancato J, Huizing M, Bendavid C, Jones M, Chandrasekharappa SC, Lewy AJ, Smith AC, Magenis RE. Review of disrupted sleep patterns in Smith-Magenis syndrome and normal melatonin secretion in a patient with an atypical interstitial 17p11.2 deletion. Am J Med Genet A. 2009;149A:1382–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19530184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brendal MA, Carmen C, Brewer CC, King KA, Zalewski CK, Finucane BM, Introne W. Smith ACM. Auditory phenotype of Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Speech Lang Hear Res. 2017;60:1076–87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5548078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns B, Schmidt K, Williams SR, Kim S, Girirajan S, Elsea SH. Rai1 haploinsufficiency causes reduced Bdnf expression resulting in hyperphagia, obesity and altered fat distribution in mice and humans with no evidence of metabolic syndrome. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19:4026–42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell IM, Yuan B, Robberecht C, Pfundt R, Szafranski P, McEntagart ME, Nagamani SC, Erez A, Bartnik M, Wiśniowiecka-Kowalnik B, Plunkett KS, Pursley AN, Kang SH, Bi W, Lalani SR, Bacino CA, Vast M, Marks K, Patton M, Olofsson P, Patel A, Veltman JA, Cheung SW, Shaw CA, Vissers LE, Vermeesch JR, Lupski JR, Stankiewicz P. Parental somatic mosaicism is underrecognized and influences recurrence risk of genomic disorders. Am J Hum Genet. 2014;95:173–82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Mora P, Encina CA, Canales CP, Cao L, Molina J, Kairath P, Young JI, Walz K. Functional and cellular characterization of human Retinoic Acid Induced 1 (RAI1) mutations associated with Smith-Magenis Syndrome. BMC Mol Biol. 2010;11:63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20738874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhry AP, Schwartz C, Singh AS. Stroke after cardiac surgery. Tex Heart Inst J. 2007;34:247–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1894707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17622381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen KS, Manian P, Koeuth T, Potocki L, Zhao Q, Chinault AC, Lee CC, Lupski JR. Homologous recombination of a flanking repeat gene cluster is a mechanism for a common contiguous gene deletion syndrome. Nat Genet. 1997;17:154–63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9326934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chik CL, Rollag MD, Duncan WC, Smith AC. Diagnostic utility of daytime salivary melatonin levels in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2010;152A:96–101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou IC, Tsai FJ, Yu MT, Tsai CH. Smith-Magenis syndrome with bilateral vesicoureteral reflux: a case report. J Formos Med Assoc. 2002;101:726–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12517050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claes P, Liberton DK, Daniels K, Rosana KM, Quillen EE, Pearson LN, McEvoy B, Bauchet M, Zaidi AA, Yao W, Tang H, Barsh GS, Absher DM, Puts DA, Rocha J, Beleza S, Pereira RW, Baynam G, Suetens P, Vandermeulen D, Wagner JK, Boster JS, Shriver MD. Modeling 3D facial shape from DNA. PLoS Genet. 2014;10:e1004224. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3961191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24651127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dardour L, Verleyen P, Lesage K, Holvoet M, Devriendt K. Bilateral renal tumors in an adult man with Smith-Magenis syndrome: the role of the FLCN gene. Eur J Med Genet. 2016;59:499–501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leersnyder H, Claustrat B, Munnich A, Verloes A. Circadian rhythm disorder in a rare disease: Smith-Magenis syndrome. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2006;252:88–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16723183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leersnyder H, De Blois MC, Claustrat B, Romana S, Albrecht U, Von Kleist-Retzow JC, Delobel B, Viot G, Lyonnet S, Vekemans M, Munnich A. Inversion of the circadian rhythm of melatonin in the Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Pediatr. 2001;139:111–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denny AD, Weik LD, Lubinsky MS, Wyatt DT. Lethal adrenal aplasia in an infant with Smith-Magenis syndrome, deletion 17p11.2. J Dysmorph Clin Genet. 1992;6:175–9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diessler S, Kostic C, Arsenijevic Y, Kawasaki A, Franken P. Rai1 frees mice from the repression of active wake behaviors by light. Elife. 2017;6:e23292. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5464769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28548639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubourg C, Bonnet-Brilhault F, Toutain A, Mignot C, Jacquette A, Dieux A, Gérard M, Beaumont-Epinette M-P, Julia S, Isidor B, Rossi IM, Odent S, Bendavid C, Barthélémy C, Verloes A, David V. Identification of nine new RAI1-truncating mutations in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients without 17p11.2 deletions. Mol Syndromol. 2014;5:57–64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3977224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan WC, Gropman A, Morse R, Krasnewich D, Smith ACM. Good babies sleeping poorly: insufficient sleep in infants with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Hum Genet. 2003;73 suppl:A896.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dykens EM, Smith AC. Distinctiveness and correlates of maladaptive behaviour in children and adolescents with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 1998;42:481–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10030444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelman EA, Girirajan S, Finucane B, Patel PI, Lupski JR, Smith AC, Elsea SH. Gender, genotype, and phenotype differences in Smith-Magenis syndrome: a meta-analysis of 105 cases. Clin Genet. 2007;71:540–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17539903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falco M, Amabile S, Acquaviva F. RAI1 gene mutations: mechanisms of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Appl Clin Genet. 2017;10:85–94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan YS, Farrell SA. Prenatal diagnosis of interstitial deletion of 17(p11.2p11.2) (Smith-Magenis syndrome) Am J Med Genet. 1994;49:253–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8116679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane B, Dirrigl KH, Simon EW. Characterization of self-injurious behaviors in children and adults with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Ment Retard. 2001;106:52–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11246713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane B, Haas-Givler B. Smith-Magenis syndrome: genetic basis and clinical implications. J Ment Health Res Intel Disab. 2009;2:134–48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finucane B, Savatt JM, Shimelis H, Girirajan S, Myers SM. Birt-Hogg-Dubé symptoms in Smith-Magenis syndrome include pediatric-onset pneumothorax. Am J Med Genet A. 2021;185:1922–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33666332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster RH, Kozachek S, Stern M, Elsea SH. Caring for the caregivers: an investigation of factors related to well-being among parents caring for a child with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Genet Couns. 2010;19:187–98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20151318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girirajan S, Elsas Ii LJ, Devriendt KH, Elsea SH. RAI1 variations in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients without 17p11.2 deletions. J Med Genet. 2005;42:820–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girirajan S, Mendoza-Londono R, Vlangos CN, Dupuis L, Nowak NJ, Bunyan DJ, Hatchwell E, Elsea SH. Smith-Magenis syndrome and Moyamoya disease in a patient with del(17) (p11.2p13.1). Am J Med Genet. 2007;143A:999–1008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17431895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg F, Guzzetta V, Montes de Oca-Luna R, Magenis RE, Smith AC, Richter SF, Kondo I, Dobyns WB, Patel PI, Lupski JR. Molecular analysis of the Smith-Magenis syndrome: a possible contiguous-gene syndrome associated with del(17)(p11.2). Am J Hum Genet. 1991;49:1207–18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1686451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1746552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg F, Lewis RA, Potocki L, Glaze D, Parke J, Killian J, Murphy MA, Williamson D, Brown F, Dutton R, McCluggage C, Friedman E, Sulek M, Lupski JR. Multi-disciplinary clinical study of Smith-Magenis syndrome (deletion 17p11.2). Am J Med Genet. 1996;62:247–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8882782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropman AL, Duncan WC, Smith AC. Neurologic and developmental features of the Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2). Pediatr Neurol. 2006;34:337–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16647992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gropman AL, Elsea S, Duncan WC, Jr, Smith AC. New developments in Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2). Curr Opin Neurol. 2007;20:125–34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17351481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hildenbrand HL, Smith AC. Analysis of the sensory profile in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. 2012;32:48–65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21599572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodapp RM, Fidler DJ, Smith AC. Stress and coping in families of children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 1998;42:331–40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9828063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang WH, Guenthner CJ, Xu J, Nguyen T, Schwarz LA, Wilkinson AW, Gozani O, Chang HY, Shamloo M, Luo L. Molecular and neural functions of Rai1, the causal gene for Smith-Magenis syndrome. Neuron. 2016;92:392–406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5098476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27693255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itoh M, Hayashi M, Hasegawa T, Shimohira M, Kohyama J. Systemic growth hormone corrects sleep disturbance in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Brain Dev. 2004;26:484–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laje G, Bernert R, Morse R, Pao M, Smith AC. Pharmacological treatment of disruptive behavior in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2010a;154C:463–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3022344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20981776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laje G, Morse R, Richter W, Ball J, Pao M, Smith AC. Autism spectrum features in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2010b;154C:456–62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20981775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin SC, Wolters PL, Smith AC. Adaptive and maladaptive behavior in children with Smith-Magenis Syndrome. J Autism Dev Disord. 2006;36:541–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16570214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers SM, Challman TD, Bock GH. End-stage renal failure in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2007;143A:1922–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17603799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nováková M, Nevsímalová S, Príhodová I, Sládek M, Sumová A. Alteration of the circadian clock in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2012;97:E312–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22162479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JP, Moeschler JB, Davies WS, Patel PI, Mohandas TK. Smith-Magenis syndrome resulting from a de novo direct insertion of proximal 17q into 17p11.2. Am J Med Genet. 1998;77:23–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9557889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins T, Rosenberg JM, Le Coz C, Alaimo JT, Trofa M, Mullegama SV, Antaya RJ, Jyonouchi S, Elsea SH, Utz PJ, Meffre E, Romberg N. Smith-Magenis syndrome patients often display antibody deficiency but not other immune pathologies. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2017;5:1344–50.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5591748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28286158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polymeropoulos CM, Brooks J, Czeisler EL, Fisher MA, Gibson MM, Kite K, Smieszek SP, Xiao C, Elsea SH, Birznieks G, Polymeropoulos MH. Tasimelteon safely and effectively improves sleep in Smith-Magenis syndrome: a double-blind randomized trial followed by an open-label extension. Genet Med. 2021;23:2426–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8629754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34316024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Bi W, Treadwell-Deering D, Carvalho CM, Eifert A, Friedman EM, Glaze D, Krull K, Lee JA, Lewis RA, Mendoza-Londono R, Robbins-Furman P, Shaw C, Shi X, Weissenberger G, Withers M, Yatsenko SA, Zackai EH, Stankiewicz P, Lupski JR. Characterization of Potocki-Lupski syndrome (dup(17)(p11.2p11.2)) and delineation of a dosage-sensitive critical interval that can convey an autism phenotype. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;80:633–49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17357070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Chen KS, Park SS, Osterholm DE, Withers MA, Kimonis V, Summers AM, Meschino WS, Anyane-Yeboa K, Kashork CD, Shaffer LG, Lupski JR. Molecular mechanism for duplication 17p11.2- the homologous recombination reciprocal of the Smith-Magenis microdeletion. Nat Genet. 2000a;24:84–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10615134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Glaze D, Tan DX, Park SS, Kashork CD, Shaffer LG, Reiter RJ, Lupski JR. Circadian rhythm abnormalities of melatonin in Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Med Genet. 2000b;37:428–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10851253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potocki L, Shaw CJ, Stankiewicz P, Lupski JR. Variability in clinical phenotype despite common del(17)(p11.2p11.2) chromosomal deletion in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Genet Med. 2003;5:430–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14614393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qin NG, Huang B (2007) Prenatal diagnosis of 10 cases with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Cytogenet Genome Res. 116:324 (A10).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rive Le Gouard N, Jacquinet A, Ruaud L, Deleersnyder H, Ageorges F, Gallard J, Lacombe D, Odent S, Mikaty M, Manouvrier-Hanu S, Ghoumid J, Geneviève D, Lehman N, Philip N, Edery P, Héron D, Rastel C, Chancenotte S, Thauvin-Robinet C, Faivre L, Perrin L, Verloes A. Smith-Magenis syndrome: clinical and behavioral characteristics in a large retrospective cohort. Clin Genet. 2021;99:519–28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33368193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt LS, Linehan WM. Molecular genetics and clinical features of Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome. Nat Rev Urol. 2015;12:558–69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5119524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26334087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slager RE, Newton TL, Vlangos CN, Finucane B, Elsea SH. Mutations in RAI1 associated with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Nat Genet. 2003;33:466–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12652298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloneem J, Oliver C, Udwin O, Woodcock KA. Prevalence, phenomenology, aetiology and predictors of challenging behaviour in Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2011;55:138–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21199049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Duncan WC. Smith-Magenis syndrome: a developmental disorder with circadian dysfunction. In: Butler MG, Meaney FJ, eds. Genetics of Developmental Disabilities. Boca Raton, LA: Taylor &amp; Francis Group; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Dykens E, Greenberg F. Sleep disturbance in Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17 p11.2). Am J Med Genet. 1998;81:186–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9613860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Gropman AL. Smith-Magenis Syndrome. In: Cassidy S &amp; Allanson J, eds. Management of Genetic Syndromes. 4 ed. New York, NY: Wiley-Blackwell. 2021;863-94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Gropman AL, Bailey-Wilson JE, Goker-Alpan O, Elsea SH, Blancato J, Lupski JR, Potocki L. Hypercholesterolemia in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome: del (17) (p11.2p11.2). Genet Med. 2002;4:118–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12180145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Magenis RE, Elsea SH. Overview of Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Assoc Genet Technol. 2005;31:163–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16354942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, McGavran L, Robinson J, Waldstein G, Macfarlane J, Zonona J, Reiss J, Lahr M, Allen L, Magenis E. Interstitial deletion of (17)(p11.2p11.2) in nine patients. Am J Med Genet. 1986;24:393–414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2425619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AC, Pletcher BA, Spilka J, Blancato J, Meck J. First report of two siblings with SMS due to maternal mosaicism. Poster session 829/C. New Orleans, LA: American Society of Human Genetics 56th Annual Meeting; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ACM, Fleming LR, Piskorski AM, Amin A, Phorphutkul C, delaMonte S, Stopa E, Introne W, Vilboux T, Duncan F, Pellegrino J, Braddock B, Middelton LA, Vocke C, Linehan WM. Deletion of 17p11.2 encompasses FLCN with increased risk of Birt-Hogg-Dubé in Smith Magenis syndrome: recommendation for cancer screening. Poster session. San Diego: American Society of Human Genetics Meeting; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith ACM, Morse RS, Introne W, Duncan WC., Jr Twenty-four-hour motor activity and body temperature patterns suggest altered central circadian timekeeping in Smith-Magenis syndrome, a neurodevelopmental disorder. Am J Med Genet A. 2019;179:224–36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spadoni E, Colapietro P, Bozzola M, Marseglia GL, Repossi L, Danesino C, Larizza L, Maraschio P. Smith-Magenis syndrome and growth hormone deficiency. Eur J Pediatr. 2004;163:353–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15138811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruyt K, Braam W, Smits M, Curfs LMG. Sleep complaints and the 24-h melatonin level in individuals with Smith-Magenis syndrome: assessment for effective intervention. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2016;22:928–35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6492880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27743421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir R, Kennedy A, Elsea SH, Dickinson AJ. Retinoic acid induced-1 (Rai1) regulates craniofacial and brain development in Xenopus. Mech Dev. 2014;133:91–104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DG, Jacques SM, Flore LA, Feldman B, Evans MI, Qureshi F. Prenatal diagnosis of Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2). Fetal Diagn Ther. 2000;15:335–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11111213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomona N, Smith AC, Guadagnini JP, Hart TC. Craniofacial and dental phenotype of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2006;140:2556–61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17001665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong HT, Dudding T, Blanchard CL, Elsea SH. Frameshift mutation hotspot identified in Smith-Magenis syndrome: case report and review of literature. BMC Med Genet. 2010;11:142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2964533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20932317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira GH, Rodriguez JD, Carmona-Mora P, Cao L, Gamba BF, Carvalho DR, de Rezende Duarte A, Santos SR. de Souza DH2, DuPont BR, Walz K, Moretti-Ferreira D, Srivastava AK. Detection of classical 17p11.2 deletions, an atypical deletion and RAI1 alterations in patients with features suggestive of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Eur J Hum Genet. 2012;20:148–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3260931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21897445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilboux T, Ciccone C, Blancato JK, Cox GF, Deshpande C, Introne WJ, Gahl WA, Smith AC, Huizing M. Molecular analysis of the retinoic acid induced 1 gene (RAI1) in patients with suspected Smith-Magenis syndrome without the 17p11.2 deletion. PLoS One. 2011;6:e22861. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlangos CN, Yim DK, Elsea SH. Refinement of the Smith-Magenis syndrome critical region to approximately 950kb and assessment of 17p11.2 deletions. Are all deletions created equally? Mol Genet Metab. 2003;79:134–41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12809645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolters PL, Gropman AL, Martin SC, Smith MR, Hildenbrand HL, Brewer CC, Smith ACM. Neurodevelopment of children under three years with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Pediatr Neurol. 2009;41:250–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2785222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19748044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang SP, Bidichandani SI, Figuera LE, Juyal RC, Saxon PJ, Baldini A, Patel PI. Molecular analysis of deletion (17)(p11.2p11.2) in a family segregating a 17p paracentric inversion: implications for carriers of paracentric inversions. Am J Hum Genet. 1997;60:1184–93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1712444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9150166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zori RT, Lupski JR, Heju Z, Greenberg F, Killian JM, Gray BA, Driscoll DJ, Patel PI, Zackowski JL. Clinical, cytogenetic, and molecular evidence for an infant with Smith- Magenis syndrome born from a mother having a mosaic 17p11.2p12 deletion. Am J Med Genet. 1993;47:504–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8256814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
