<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301288</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK1109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="nf1">Neurofibromatosis 1</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friedman</LastName><ForeName>Jan M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Genetics University of British Columbia Vancouver, Canada</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Neurofibromatosis 1 (NF1) is a multisystem disorder characterized by multiple café au lait macules, intertriginous freckling, multiple cutaneous neurofibromas, and learning disability or behavior problems. About half of people with NF1 have plexiform neurofibromas, but most are internal and not suspected clinically. Plexiform neurofibromas can cause pain, neurologic deficits, and abnormalities of involved or adjacent structures. Less common but potentially more serious manifestations include optic nerve and other central nervous system gliomas, malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors, scoliosis, tibial dysplasia, vasculopathy, and gastrointestinal, endocrine, or pulmonary disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of NF1 is established in a proband with two or more of the characteristic clinical features or one characteristic clinical feature and a heterozygous <i>NF1</i> pathogenic variant.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Referral to specialists for treatment of abnormalities of the eye, central or peripheral nervous system, cardiovascular system, lungs, endocrine system, spine, or long bones; surgical removal of disfiguring or uncomfortable discrete cutaneous or subcutaneous neurofibromas. Surgical treatment of diffuse or large plexiform neurofibromas is possible but may be associated with damage to involved nerves or adjacent tissues and stimulate growth of residual tumor. Complete surgical excision, when possible, of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors is the treatment of choice; chemotherapy may be beneficial in some individuals. Treatment of optic gliomas is generally unnecessary as they are usually asymptomatic and clinically stable. Dystrophic scoliosis often requires surgical management, whereas nondystrophic scoliosis can usually be treated conservatively. Individualized developmental and educational interventions may be beneficial, and methylphenidate treatment often benefits individuals with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. <i>Surveillance:</i> Annual physical examination by a physician familiar with the disorder; ophthalmologic examination annually in children, and regularly but less frequently in adults; developmental assessment of children; regular blood pressure monitoring; MRI for identification and follow up of clinically suspected intracranial or other tumors that are not apparent on physical examination. Begin annual mammography in women at age 30 years with consideration of annual breast MRI in women between ages 30 and 50 years. Individuals with <i>NF1</i> whole-gene deletions, large or growing plexiform neurofibromas or intracranial tumors, symptomatic vascular disease, progressive osseous lesions, or other serious disease manifestations require more frequent targeted follow up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">NF1 is inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. Approximately half of affected individuals have NF1 as the result of a <i>de novo</i> <i>NF1</i> disease-causing variant. Each child of an individual with NF1 has a 50% chance of inheriting the disease-causing variant. Penetrance is close to 100%; thus, a child who inherits an NF1-causing variant is expected to develop features of NF1, but the features may be considerably more (or less) severe in an affected child than in his or her affected parent. Prenatal testing for a pregnancy at increased risk and preimplantation genetic testing are possible if the disease-causing variant in a family is known.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorder">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="nf1" sec="nf1.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NF1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Von Recklinghausen Disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Von Recklinghausen's Neurofibromatosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NF1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Von Recklinghausen Disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Von Recklinghausen's Neurofibromatosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurofibromin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NF1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurofibromatosis 1</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>1998</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><ItemList ListType="Synonyms"><Item>NF1</Item><Item>Von Recklinghausen Disease</Item><Item>Von Recklinghausen's Neurofibromatosis</Item></ItemList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Accetturo M, Bartolomeo N, Stella A. In-silico analysis of NF1 missense variants in clinvar: translating variant predictions into variant interpretation and classification. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7037781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31979111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afridi SK, Leschziner GD, Ferner RE. Prevalence and clinical presentation of headache in a National Neurofibromatosis 1 Service and impact on quality of life. Am J Med Genet A. 2015;167A:2282–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26044068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlawat S, Fayad LM, Khan MS, Bredella MA, Harris GJ, Evans DG, Farschtschi S, Jacobs MA, Chhabra A, Salamon JM, Wenzel R, Mautner VF, Dombi E, Cai W, Plotkin SR, Blakeley JO. Whole Body MRI Committee for the REiNS International Collaboration; REiNS International Collaboration Members 2016. Current whole-body MRI applications in the neurofibromatoses: NF1, NF2, and schwannomatosis. Neurology. 2016;87:S31–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5578359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27527647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albaghdadi M, Thibodeau ML, Lara-Corrales I. Updated approach to patients with multiple café au lait macules. Dermatol Clin. 2022;40:9–23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34799039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Farsi FAH, Al-Alyani OBS, Al-Kumzari A, Al-Saadi T. Systemic review and meta-analysis of the intellectual integrity of children with neurofibromatosis type 1. World Neurosurg. 2022;157:69–74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34648986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allanson JE, Upadhyaya M, Watson GH, Partington M, MacKenzie A, Lahey D, MacLeod H, Sarfarazi M, Broadhead W, Harper PS, et al.  Watson syndrome: is it a subtype of type 1 neurofibromatosis? J Med Genet. 1991;28:752–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1017110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1770531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Sharefi A, Javaid U, Perros P, Ealing J, Truran P, Nag S, Kamaruddin S, Abouglila K, Cains F, Lewis L, James RA. Clinical presentation and outcomes of phaeochromocytomas/paragangliomas in neurofibromatosis type 1. Eur Endocrinol. 2019;15:95–100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31616500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves Júnior SF, Zanetti G, Alves de Melo AS, Souza AS, Jr, Souza LS, de Souza Portes Meirelles G, Irion KL, Hochhegger B, Marchiori E. Neurofibromatosis type 1: State-of-the-art review with emphasis on pulmonary involvement. Respir Med. 2019;149:9–15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson MK, Johnson M, Thornburg L, Halford Z. A review of selumetinib in the treatment of neurofibromatosis type 1-related plexiform neurofibromas. Ann Pharmacother. 2022;56:716–26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34541874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ater JL, Xia C, Mazewski CM, Booth TN, Freyer DR, Packer RJ, Sposto R, Vezina G, Pollack IF. Nonrandomized comparison of neurofibromatosis type 1 and non-neurofibromatosis type 1 children who received carboplatin and vincristine for progressive low-grade glioma: a report from the Children's Oncology Group. Cancer. 2016;122:1928–36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4892942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27061921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avery RA, Katowitz JA, Fisher MJ, Heidary G, Dombi E, Packer RJ, Widemann BC, et al.  Orbital/periorbital plexiform neurofibromas in children with neurofibromatosis type 1: multidisciplinary recommendations for care. Ophthalmology. 2017;124:123–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5173440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin S, Kurtcan S, Alkan A, Guler S, Filiz M, Yilmaz TF, Sahin TU, Aralasmak A. Relationship between the corpus callosum and neurocognitive disabilities in children with NF-1: diffusion tensor imaging features. Clin Imaging. 2016;40:1092–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babovic-Vuksanovic D, Messiaen L, Nagel C, Brems H, Scheithauer B, Denayer E, Mao R, Sciot R, Janowski KM, Schuhmann MU, Claes K, Beert E, Garrity JA, Spinner RJ, Stemmer-Rachamimov A, Gavrilova R, Van Calenbergh F, Mautner V, Legius E. Multiple orbital neurofibromas, painful peripheral nerve tumors, distinctive face and marfanoid habitus: a new syndrome. Eur J Hum Genet. 2012;20:618–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3355267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22258529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacci C, Sestini R, Ammannati F, Bianchini E, Palladino T, Carella M, Melchionda S, Zelante L, Papi L. Multiple spinal ganglioneuromas in a patient harboring a pathogenic NF1 mutation. Clin Genet. 2010;77:293–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19863548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett C, Alon T, Abraham A, Kim RH, McCuaig JM, Kongkham P, Maurice C, Suppiah S, Zadeh G, Bril V. Evidence of small-fiber neuropathy in neurofibromatosis type 1. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:673–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31465118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto-Duarte B, Andrade-Gomes FH, Arriaga MB, Araújo-Pereira M, Cubillos-Angulo JM, Andrade BB. Association between neurofibromatosis type 1 and cerebrovascular diseases in children: a systematic review. PLoS One. 2021;16:e0241096. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33395412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baudou E, Chaix Y. The value of screening tests in children with neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2311–19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32524181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baudou E, Nemmi F, Biotteau M, Maziero S, Assaiante C, Cignetti F, Vaugoyeau M, Audic F, Peran P, Chaix Y. Are morphological and structural MRI characteristics related to specific cognitive impairments in neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) children? Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2020;28:89–100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32893091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayat M, Bayat A. Neurological manifestations of neurofibromatosis: a review. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:2685–90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32358705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekiesińska-Figatowska M, Brągoszewska H, Duczkowski M, Romaniuk-Doroszewska A, Szkudlińska-Pawlak S, Duczkowska A, Mądzik J, Kowalska B, Pęczkowski P. Circle of Willis abnormalities in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Neurol Neurochir Pol. 2014;48:15–20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24636765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellampalli SS, Khanna R. Towards a neurobiological understanding of pain in neurofibromatosis type 1: mechanisms and implications for treatment. Pain. 2019;160:1007–18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6478401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31009417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergoug M, Doudeau M, Godin F, Mosrin C, Vallée B, Bénédetti H. Neurofibromin structure, functions and regulation. Cells. 2020;9:2365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergqvist C, Hemery F, Jannic A, Ferkal S, Wolkenstein P. Lymphoproliferative malignancies in patients with neurofibromatosis 1. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2021;16:230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34011343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergqvist C, Servy A, Valeyrie-Allanore L, Ferkal S, Combemale P, Wolkenstein P, et al.  Neurofibromatosis 1 French national guidelines based on an extensive literature review since 1966. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2020;15:37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6998847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32014052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardo P, Cinalli G, Santoro C. Epilepsy in NF1: a systematic review of the literature. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2333–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettegowda C, Upadhayaya M, Evans DG, Kim A, Mathios D, Hanemann CO, et al.  Genotype-phenotype correlations in neurofibromatosis and their potential clinical use. Neurology. 2021;97:S91–S98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8594005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34230207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bianchessi D, Ibba MC, Saletti V, Blasa S, Langella T, Paterra R, Cagnoli GA, Melloni G, Scuvera G, Natacci F, Cesaretti C, Finocchiaro G, Eoli M. Simultaneous Detection of NF1, SPRED1, LZTR1, and NF2 gene mutations by targeted NGS in an Italian cohort of suspected NF1 patients. Genes (Basel) 2020;11:671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32575496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard G, Lafforgue MP, Lion-François L, Kemlin I, Rodriguez D, Castelnau P, Carneiro M, Meyer P, Rivier F, Barbarot S, Chaix Y, et al.  Systematic MRI in NF1 children under six years of age for the diagnosis of optic pathway gliomas. Study and outcome of a French cohort. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2016;20:275–81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26774135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bottillo I, Torrente I, Lanari V, Pinna V, Giustini S, Divona L, De Luca A, Dallapiccola B. Germline mosaicism in neurofibromatosis type 1 due to a paternally derived multi-exon deletion. Am J Med Genet A. 2010;152A:1467–73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20503322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brahmi M, Thiesse P, Ranchere D, Mognetti T, Pinson S, Renard C, Decouvelaere AV, Blay JY, Combemale P. Diagnostic accuracy of PET/CT-guided percutaneous biopsies for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors in neurofibromatosis type 1 patients. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0138386. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4596851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brena M, Besagni F, Hernandez-Martin A, Tadini G. Clinical features of NF1 in the skin. In: Multidisciplinary Approach to Neurofibromatosis Type 1, in: Gianluca T, Legius E, Brems H (eds). Multidisciplinary approach to neurofibromatosis type 1. Cham, Switzerland : Springer, [2020]. pp. 46-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosseau JP, Liao CP, Le LQ. Translating current basic research into future therapies for neurofibromatosis type 1. Br J Cancer. 2020;123:178–86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7374719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32439933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buske A, Gewies A, Lehmann R, Rüther K, Algermissen B, Nürnberg P, Tinschert S. Recurrent NF1 gene mutation in a patient with oligosymptomatic neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). Am J Med Genet. 1999;86:328–30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10494088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrne S, Connor S, Lascelles K, Siddiqui A, Hargrave D, Ferner RE. Clinical presentation and prognostic indicators in 100 adults and children with neurofibromatosis 1 associated non-optic pathway brain gliomas. J Neurooncol. 2017;133:609–14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28593402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calì F, Chiavetta V, Ruggeri G, Piccione M, Selicorni A, Palazzo D, Bonsignore M, Cereda A, Elia M, Failla P, Figura MG, Fiumara A, Maitz S, Luana Mandarà GM, Mattina T, Ragalmuto A, Romano C, Ruggieri M, Salluzzo R, Saporoso A, Schepis C, Sorge G, Spanò M, Tortorella G, Romano V. Mutation spectrum of NF1 gene in Italian patients with neurofibromatosis type 1 using Ion Torrent PGM™ platform. Eur J Med Genet. 2017;60:93–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27838393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvez S, Levy R, Calvez R, Roux CJ, Grévent D, Purcell Y, Beccaria K, Blauwblomme T, Grill J, Dufour C, Bourdeaut F, Doz F, Robert MP, Boddaert N, Dangouloff-Ros V. Focal areas of high signal intensity in children with neurofibromatosis type 1: expected evolution on MRI. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2020;41:1733–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7583105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32816766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambiaso P, Galassi S, Palmiero M, Mastronuzzi A, Del Bufalo F, Capolino R, Cacchione A, Buonuomo PS, Gonfiantini MV, Bartuli A, Cappa M, Macchiaiolo M. Growth hormone excess in children with neurofibromatosis type-1 and optic glioma. Am J Med Genet A. 2017;173:2353–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28631895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Celik B, Aksoy OY, Bastug F, Poyrazoglu HG. Renal manifestations in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Eur J Pediatr. 2021;180:3477–82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34091747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chauvel-Picard J, Lion-Francois L, Beuriat PA, Paulus C, Szathmari A, Mottolese C, Gleizal A, Di Rocco F. Craniofacial bone alterations in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2391–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32583151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PC, Yin J, Yu HW, Yuan T, Fernandez M, Yung CK, Trinh QM, Peltekova VD, Reid JG, Tworog-Dube E, Morgan MB, Muzny DM, Stein L, McPherson JD, Roberts AE, Gibbs RA, Neel BG, Kucherlapati R. Next-generation sequencing identifies rare variants associated with Noonan syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:11473–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4128129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25049390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chetty SP, Shaffer BL, Norton ME. Management of pregnancy in women with genetic disorders: Part 2: Inborn errors of metabolism, cystic fibrosis, neurofibromatosis type 1, and turner syndrome in pregnancy. Obstet Gynecol Surv. 2011;66:765–76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22192461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chirindel A, Chaudhry M, Blakeley JO, Wahl R. 18F-FDG PET/CT qualitative and quantitative evaluation in neurofibromatosis type 1 patients for detection of malignant transformation: comparison of early to delayed imaging with and without liver activity normalization. J Nucl Med. 2015;56:379–85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25655626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm AK, Anderson VA, Pride NA, Malarbi S, North KN, Payne JM. Social function and autism spectrum disorder in children and adults with neurofibromatosis type 1: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neuropsychol Rev. 2018;28:317–40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm AK, Haebich KM, Pride NA, Walsh KS, Lami F, Ure A, Maloof T, Brignell A, Rouel M, Granader Y, Maier A, Barton B, Darke H, Dabscheck G, Anderson VA, Williams K, North KN, Payne JM. Delineating the autistic phenotype in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Mol Autism. 2022;13:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8729013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34983638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crucis A, Richer W, Brugières L, Bergeron C, Marie-Cardine A, Stephan JL, Girard P, Corradini N, Munzer M, Lacour B, Minard-Colin V, Sarnacki S, Ranchere-Vince D, Orbach D, Bourdeaut F. Rhabdomyosarcomas in children with neurofibromatosis type I: a national historical cohort. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2015;62:1733–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25893277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cui XW, Ren JY, Gu YH, Li QF, Wang ZC. NF1, neurofibromin and gene therapy: prospects of next-generation therapy. Curr Gene Ther. 2020;20:100–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32767931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Amico A, Rosano C, Pannone L, Pinna V, Assunto A, Motta M, Ugga L, Daniele P, Mandile R, Mariniello L, Siano MA, Santoro C, Piluso G, Martinelli S, Strisciuglio P, De Luca A, Tartaglia M, Melis D. Clinical variability of neurofibromatosis 1: A modifying role of cooccurring PTPN11 variants and atypical brain MRI findings. Clin Genet. 2021;100:563–72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34346503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Angelo F, Ceccarelli M, Tala A, Garofano L, Zhang J, Frattini V, Caruso FP, Lewis G, Alfaro KD, Bauchet L, Berzero G, Cachia D, Cangiano M, Capelle L, de Groot J, DiMeco F, Ducray F, Farah W, Finocchiaro G, Goutagny S, Kamiya-Matsuoka C, Lavarino C, Loiseau H, Lorgis V, Marras CE, McCutcheon I, Nam DH, Ronchi S, Saletti V, Seizeur R, Slopis J, Suñol M, Vandenbos F, Varlet P, Vidaud D, Watts C, Tabar V, Reuss DE, Kim SK, Meyronet D, Mokhtari K, Salvador H, Bhat KP, Eoli M, Sanson M, Lasorella A, Iavarone A. The molecular landscape of glioma in patients with neurofibromatosis 1. Nat Med. 2019;25:176–87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Arco F, D'Amico A, Caranci F, Di Paolo N, Melis D, Brunetti A. Cerebrovascular stenosis in neurofibromatosis type 1 and utility of magnetic resonance angiography: our experience and literature review. Radiol Med. 2014;119:415–21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24297593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Luca A, Bottillo I, Sarkozy A, Carta C, Neri C, Bellacchio E, Schirinzi A, Conti E, Zampino G, Battaglia A, Majore S, Rinaldi MM, Carella M, Marino B, Pizzuti A, Digilio MC, Tartaglia M, Dallapiccola B. NF1 gene mutations represent the major molecular event underlying neurofibromatosis-Noonan syndrome. Am J Hum Genet. 2005;77:1092–101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1285166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16380919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBella K, Poskitt K, Szudek J, Friedman JM. Use of "unidentified bright objects" on MRI for diagnosis of neurofibromatosis 1 in children. Neurology. 2000;54:1646–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10762507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Nicola M, Viola F. Ocular manifestations of neurofibromatosis type 1. In: Tadini G, Legius E, Brems H, eds. Multidisciplinary Approach to Neurofibromatosis Type 1. Cham, Switzerland: Springer; 2020:71-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiPaolo DP, Zimmerman RA, Rorke LB, Zackai EH, Bilaniuk LT, Yachnis AT. Neurofibromatosis type 1: pathologic substrate of high-signal-intensity foci in the brain. Radiology. 1995;195:721–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7754001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domon-Archambault V, Gagnon L, Benoît A, Perreault S. Psychosocial features of neurofibromatosis type 1 in children and adolescents. J Child Neurol. 2018;33:225–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29318935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubov T, Toledano-Alhadef H, Chernin G, Constantini S, Cleper R, Ben-Shachar S. High prevalence of elevated blood pressure among children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Pediatr Nephrol. 2016;31:131–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26314566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunnett-Kane V, Burkitt-Wright E, Blackhall FH, Malliri A, Evans DG, Lindsay CR. Germline and sporadic cancers driven by the RAS pathway: parallels and contrasts. Ann Oncol. 2020;31:873–83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7322396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32240795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eby NS, Griffith JL, Gutmann DH, Morris SM. Adaptive functioning in children with neurofibromatosis type 1: relationship to cognition, behavior, and magnetic resonance imaging. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2019;61:972–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejerskov C, Raundahl M, Gregersen PA, Handrup MM. Clinical features and disease severity in patients with mosaic neurofibromatosis type 1: a single-center study and literature review. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2021;16:180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8048193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33853649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekvall S, Sjörs K, Jonzon A, Vihinen M, Annerén G, Bondeson ML. Novel association of neurofibromatosis type 1-causing mutations in families with neurofibromatosis-Noonan syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2014;164A:579–87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elefteriou F, Kolanczyk M, Schindeler A, Viskochil DH, Hock JM, Schorry EK, Crawford AH, Friedman JM, Little D, Peltonen J, Carey JC, Feldman D, Yu X, Armstrong L, Birch P, Kendler DL, Mundlos S, Yang FC, Agiostratidou G, Hunter-Schaedle K, Stevenson DA. Skeletal abnormalities in neurofibromatosis type 1: approaches to therapeutic options. Am J Med Genet A. 2009;149A:2327–38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19764036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eoli M, Saletti V, Finocchiaro G. Neurological malignancies in neurofibromatosis type 1. Curr Opin Oncol. 2019;31:554–61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31436563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans DG, Baser ME, McGaughran J, Sharif S, Howard E, Moran A. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours in neurofibromatosis 1. J Med Genet. 2002;39:311–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12011145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans DG, Howard E, Giblin C, Clancy T, Spencer H, Huson SM, Lalloo F. Birth incidence and prevalence of tumor-prone syndromes: estimates from a UK family genetic register service. Am J Med Genet A. 2010;152A:327–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20082463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans DG, Kallionpää RA, Clementi M, Trevisson E, Mautner VF, Howell SJ, Lewis L, Zehou O, Peltonen S, Brunello A, Harkness EF, Wolkenstein P, Peltonen J. Breast cancer in neurofibromatosis 1: survival and risk of contralateral breast cancer in a five country cohort study. Genet Med. 2020;22:398–406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7000349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans DG, O'Hara C, Wilding A, Ingham SL, Howard E, Dawson J, Moran A, Scott-Kitching V, Holt F, Huson SM. Mortality in neurofibromatosis 1: in North West England: an assessment of actuarial survival in a region of the UK since 1989. Eur J Hum Genet. 2011;19:1187–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferner RE, Gutmann DH. Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1): diagnosis and management. Handb Clin Neurol. 2013;115:939–55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filopanti M, Verga U, Ulivieri FM, Giavoli C, Rodari G, Arosio M, Natacci F, Spada A. Trabecular bone score (TBS) and bone metabolism in patients affected with type 1 neurofibromatosis (NF1). Calcif Tissue Int. 2019;104:207–13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher MJ, Jones DTW, Li Y, Guo X, Sonawane PS, Waanders AJ, Phillips JJ, Weiss WA, Resnick AC, Gosline S, Banerjee J, Guinney J, Gnekow A, Kandels D, Foreman NK, Korshunov A, Ryzhova M, Massimi L, Gururangan S, Kieran MW, Wang Z, Fouladi M, Sato M, Øra I, Holm S, Markham SJ, Beck P, Jäger N, Wittmann A, Sommerkamp AC, Sahm F, Pfister SM, Gutmann DH. Integrated molecular and clinical analysis of low-grade gliomas in children with neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). Acta Neuropathol. 2021;141:605–17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fjermestad KW, Nyhus L, Kanavin ØJ, Heiberg A, Hoxmark LB. Health survey of adults with neurofibromatosis 1 compared to population study controls. J Genet Couns. 2018;27:1102–10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29429039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foiadelli T, Naso M, Licari A, Orsini A, Magistrali M, Trabatti C, Luzzi S, Mosconi M, Savasta S, Marseglia GL. Advanced pharmacological therapies for neurofibromatosis type 1-related tumors. Acta Biomed. 2020;91:101–14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7975824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32608378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich RE, Nuding MA. Optic pathway glioma and cerebral focal abnormal signal intensity in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1: characteristics, treatment choices and follow-up in 134 affected individuals and a brief review of the literature. Anticancer Res. 2016;36:4095–121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27466519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin R, Watson AL, Largaespada DA, Ratner N, Osum S, Moertel CL. Neurofibromatosis in the era of precision medicine: development of MEK inhibitors and recent successes with selumetinib. Curr Oncol Rep. 2021;23:45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33721151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>García-Romero MT, Parkin P, Lara-Corrales I. Mosaic Neurofibromatosis Type 1: A Systematic Review. Pediatr Dermatol. 2016;33:9–17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gianluca T, Legius E, Brems H (eds). Multidisciplinary approach to neurofibromatosis type 1 Cham, Switzerland : Springer, [2020] 313 pages.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giugliano T, Santoro C, Torella A, Del Vecchio Blanco F, Grandone A, Onore ME, Melone MAB, Straccia G, Melis D, Piccolo V, Limongelli G, Buono S, Perrotta S, Nigro V, Piluso G. Clinical and genetic findings in children with neurofibromatosis type 1, Legius syndrome, and other related neurocutaneous disorders. Genes (Basel) 2019;10:580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6722641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31370276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glombova M, Petrak B, Lisy J, Zamecnik J, Sumerauer D, Liby P. Brain gliomas, hydrocephalus and idiopathic aqueduct stenosis in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Brain Dev. 2019;41:678–90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gross AM, Dombi E, Widemann BC. Current status of MEK inhibitors in the treatment of plexiform neurofibromas. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2443–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32607696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber LM, Erickson D, Babovic-Vuksanovic D, Thompson GB, Young WF, Jr, Bancos I. Pheochromocytoma and paraganglioma in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2017;86:141–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27460956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutmann DH, Ferner RE, Listernick RH, Korf BR, Wolters PL, Johnson KJ. Neurofibromatosis type 1. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas-Lude K, Heimgärtner M, Winter S, Mautner VF, Krägeloh-Mann I, Lidzba K. Motor dysfunction in NF1: Mediated by attention deficit or inherent to the disorder? Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2018;22:164–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29111114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannah-Shmouni F, Stratakis CA. Growth hormone excess in neurofibromatosis 1. Genet Med. 2019;21:1254–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heervä E, Huilaja L, Leinonen P, Peltonen S, Peltonen J. Follow-up of six patients with neurofibromatosis 1-related osteoporosis treated with alendronate for 23 months. Calcif Tissue Int. 2014;94:608–12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24390519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heervä E, Koffert A, Jokinen E, Kuorilehto T, Peltonen S, Aro HT, Peltonen J. A controlled register-based study of 460 neurofibromatosis 1 patients: increased fracture risk in children and adults over 41 years of age. J Bone Miner Res. 2012;27:2333–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22692994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higham CS, Dombi E, Rogiers A, Bhaumik S, Pans S, Connor SEJ, Miettinen M, Sciot R, Tirabosco R, Brems H, Baldwin A, Legius E, Widemann BC, Ferner RE. The characteristics of 76 atypical neurofibromas as precursors to neurofibromatosis 1 associated malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Neuro Oncol. 2018;20:818–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5961015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29409029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirabaru K, Matsuo M. Neurological comorbidity in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Pediatr Int. 2018;60:70–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28796925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell SJ, Hockenhull K, Salih Z, Evans DG. Increased risk of breast cancer in neurofibromatosis type 1: current insights. Breast Cancer (Dove Med Press) 2017;9:531–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5573065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28860858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh HY, Fung HC, Wang CJ, Chin SC, Wu T. Epileptic seizures in neurofibromatosis type 1 are related to intracranial tumors but not to neurofibromatosis bright objects. Seizure. 2011;20:606–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huson SM, Compston DA, Clark P, Harper PS. A genetic study of von Recklinghausen neurofibromatosis in south east Wales. I. Prevalence, fitness, mutation rate, and effect of parental transmission on severity. J Med Genet. 1989;26:704–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1015740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2511318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannuzzi S, Albaret JM, Chignac C, Faure-Marie N, Barry I, Karsenty C, Chaix Y. Motor impairment in children with Neurofibromatosis type 1: effect of the comorbidity with language disorders. Brain Dev. 2016;38:181–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26321374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jalabert M, Ferkal S, Souberbielle JC, Sbidian E, Mageau A, Eymard F, Le Corvoisier P, Allanore L, Chevalier X, Wolkenstein P, Guignard S. Bone status according to neurofibromatosis type 1 phenotype: a descriptive study of 60 women in France. Calcif Tissue Int. 2021;108:738–45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33558959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ji J, Shimony J, Gao F, McKinstry RC, Gutmann DH. Optic nerve tortuosity in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Pediatr Radiol. 2013;43:1336–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23636538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia F, Wang G, Sun J, Liu X. Combined anterior-posterior versus posterior-only spinal fusion in treating dystrophic neurofibromatosis scoliosis with modern instrumentation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Spine Surg. 2021;34:132–42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32969869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jutant EM, Girerd B, Jaïs X, Savale L, O'Connell C, Perros F, Sitbon O, Humbert M, Montani D. Pulmonary hypertension associated with neurofibromatosis type 1. Eur Respir Rev. 2018;27:180053. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jutant EM, Jaïs X, Girerd B, Savale L, Ghigna MR, Perros F, Mignard X, Jevnikar M, Bourlier D, Prevot G, Tromeur C, Bauer F, Bergot E, Dauphin C, Favrolt N, Traclet J, Soumagne T, De Groote P, Chabanne C, Magro P, Bertoletti L, Gueffet JP, Chaouat A, Goupil F, Moceri P, Borie R, Fadel E, Wolkenstein P, Brillet PY, Simonneau G, Sitbon O, Humbert M, Montani D. Phenotype and outcomes of pulmonary hypertension associated with neurofibromatosis type 1. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020;202:843–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32437637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kallionpää RA, Uusitalo E, Leppävirta J, Pöyhönen M, Peltonen S, Peltonen J. Prevalence of neurofibromatosis type 1 in the Finnish population. Genet Med. 2018;20:1082–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29215653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaspiris A, Savvidou OD, Vasiliadis ES, Hadjimichael AC, Melissaridou D, Iliopoulou-Kosmadaki S, Iliopoulos ID, Papadimitriou E, Chronopoulos E. Current aspects on the pathophysiology of bone metabolic defects during progression of scoliosis in neurofibromatosis type 1. J Clin Med. 2022;11:444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8781800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35054138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Cooper DN. Classification of NF1 microdeletions and its importance for establishing genotype/phenotype correlations in patients with NF1 microdeletions. Hum Genet. 2021;140:1635–49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8553723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Kluwe L, Salamon J, Well L, Farschtschi S, Rosenbaum T, Mautner VF. Clinical characterization of children and adolescents with NF1 microdeletions. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2297–310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32533297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenborg L, Andersen EW, Duun-Henriksen AK, Jepsen JRM, Doser K, Dalton SO, Bidstrup PE, Krøyer A, Frederiksen LE, Johansen C, Østergaard JR, Hove H, Sørensen SA, Riccardi VM, Mulvihill JJ, Winther JF. Psychiatric disorders in individuals with neurofibromatosis 1 in Denmark: A nationwide register-based cohort study. Am J Med Genet A. 2021;185:3706–16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34327813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenborg L, Duun-Henriksen AK, Dalton SO, Bidstrup PE, Doser K, Rugbjerg K, Pedersen C, Krøyer A, Johansen C, Andersen KK, Østergaard JR, Hove H, Sørensen SA, Riccardi VM, Mulvihill JJ, Winther JF. Multisystem burden of neurofibromatosis 1 in Denmark: registry- and population-based rates of hospitalizations over the life span. Genet Med. 2020;22:1069–78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32107470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinori M, Armarnik S, Listernick R, Charrow J, Zeid JL. Neurofibromatosis type 1-associated optic pathway glioma in children: a follow-up of 10 years or more. Am J Ophthalmol. 2021;221:91–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32283094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinerman RA. Radiation-sensitive genetically susceptible pediatric sub-populations. Pediatr Radiol. 2009;39 Suppl 1:S27–31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2656401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klose A, Peters H, Hoffmeyer S, Buske A, Lüder A, Hess D, Lehmann R, Nürnberg P, Tinschert S. Two independent mutations in a family with neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1). Am J Med Genet. 1999;83:6–12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10076878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kluwe L, Friedrich RE, Farschtschi SC, Hagel C, Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Mautner VF. Null phenotype of neurofibromatosis type 1 in a carrier of a heterozygous atypical NF1 deletion due to mosaicism. Hum Mutat. 2020;41:1226–31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32248581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koczkowska M, Callens T, Chen Y, Gomes A, Hicks AD, Sharp A, Johns E, Uhas KA, Armstrong L, Bosanko KA, Babovic-Vuksanovic D, Baker L, Basel DG, Bengala M, Bennett JT, Chambers C, Clarkson LK, Clementi M, Cortés FM, Cunningham M, D'Agostino MD, Delatycki MB, Digilio MC, Dosa L, Esposito S, Fox S, Freckmann ML, Fauth C, Giugliano T, Giustini S, Goetsch A, Goldberg Y, Greenwood RS, Griffis C, Gripp KW, Gupta P, Haan E, Hachen RK, Haygarth TL, Hernández-Chico C, Hodge K, Hopkin RJ, Hudgins L, Janssens S, Keller K, Kelly-Mancuso G, Kochhar A, Korf BR, Lewis AM, Liebelt J, Lichty A, Listernick RH, Lyons MJ, Maystadt I, Martinez Ojeda M, McDougall C, McGregor LK, Melis D, Mendelsohn N, Nowaczyk MJM, Ortenberg J, Panzer K, Pappas JG, Pierpont ME, Piluso G, Pinna V, Pivnick EK, Pond DA, Powell CM, Rogers C, Ruhrman Shahar N, Rutledge SL, Saletti V, Sandaradura SA, Santoro C, Schatz UA, Schreiber A, Scott DA, Sellars EA, Sheffer R, Siqveland E, Slopis JM, Smith R, Spalice A, Stockton DW, Streff H, Theos A, Tomlinson GE, Tran G, Trapane PL, Trevisson E, Ullrich NJ, Van den Ende J, Schrier Vergano SA, Wallace SE, Wangler MF, Weaver DD, Yohay KH, Zackai E, Zonana J, Zurcher V, Claes KBM, Eoli M, Martin Y, Wimmer K, De Luca A, Legius E, Messiaen LM. Clinical spectrum of individuals with pathogenic NF1 missense variants affecting p.Met1149, p.Arg1276, and p.Lys1423: genotype-phenotype study in neurofibromatosis type 1. Hum Mutat. 2020;41:299–315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6973139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koczkowska M, Chen Y, Callens T, Gomes A, Sharp A, Johnson S, Hsiao MC, Chen Z, Balasubramanian M, Barnett CP, Becker TA, Ben-Shachar S, Bertola DR, Blakeley JO, Burkitt-Wright EMM, Callaway A, Crenshaw M, Cunha KS, Cunningham M, D'Agostino MD, Dahan K, De Luca A, Destrée A, Dhamija R, Eoli M, Evans DGR, Galvin-Parton P, George-Abraham JK, Gripp KW, Guevara-Campos J, Hanchard NA, Hernández-Chico C, Immken L, Janssens S, Jones KJ, Keena BA, Kochhar A, Liebelt J, Martir-Negron A, Mahoney MJ, Maystadt I, McDougall C, McEntagart M, Mendelsohn N, Miller DT, Mortier G, Morton J, Pappas J, Plotkin SR, Pond D, Rosenbaum K, Rubin K, Russell L, Rutledge LS, Saletti V, Schonberg R, Schreiber A, Seidel M, Siqveland E, Stockton DW, Trevisson E, Ullrich NJ, Upadhyaya M, van Minkelen R, Verhelst H, Wallace MR, Yap YS, Zackai E, Zonana J, Zurcher V, Claes K, Martin Y, Korf BR, Legius E, Messiaen LM. Genotype-phenotype correlation in NF1: evidence for a more severe phenotype associated with missense mutations affecting NF1 codons 844-848. Am J Hum Genet. 2018;102:69–87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5777934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongkriangkai AM, King C, Martin LJ, Wakefield E, Prada CE, Kelly-Mancuso G, Schorry EK. Substantial pain burden in frequency, intensity, interference and chronicity among children and adults with neurofibromatosis Type 1. Am J Med Genet A. 2019;179:602–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnatry R, Zhukova N, Guerreiro Stucklin AS, Pole JD, Mistry M, Fried I, Ramaswamy V, Bartels U, Huang A, Laperriere N, Dirks P, Nathan PC, Greenberg M, Malkin D, Hawkins C, Bandopadhayay P, Kieran MW, Manley PE, Bouffet E, Tabori U. Clinical and treatment factors determining long-term outcomes for adult survivors of childhood low-grade glioma: a population-based study. Cancer. 2016;122:1261–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26970559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar MG, Emnett RJ, Bayliss SJ, Gutmann DH. Glomus tumors in individuals with neurofibromatosis type 1. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2014;71:44–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24685357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry JP, Schertz KL, Chiang YJ, Bhalla AD, Yi M, Keung EZ, Scally CP, Feig BW, Hunt KK, Roland CL, Guadagnolo A, Bishop AJ, Lazar AJ, Slopis JM, McCutcheon IE, Torres KE. Comparison of cancer prevalence in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1 at an academic cancer center vs in the general population from 1985 to 2020. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4:e210945. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7974640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33734413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lázaro C, Gaona A, Lynch M, Kruyer H, Ravella A, Estivill X. Molecular characterization of the breakpoints of a 12-kb deletion in the NF1 gene in a family showing germ-line mosaicism. Am J Hum Genet. 1995;57:1044–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1801366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7485153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legius E, Brems H. Genetic basis of neurofibromatosis type 1 and related conditions, including mosaicism. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2285–95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32601904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legius E, Messiaen L, Wolkenstein P, Pancza P, Avery RA, Berman Y, Blakeley J, Babovic-Vuksanovic D, Cunha KS, Ferner R, Fisher MJ, Friedman JM, Gutmann DH, Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Korf BR, Mautner VF, Peltonen S, Rauen KA, Riccardi V, Schorry E, Stemmer-Rachamimov A, Stevenson DA, Tadini G, Ullrich NJ, Viskochil D, Wimmer K, Yohay K, Huson SM, Evans DG, Plotkin SR, et al.  Revised diagnostic criteria for neurofibromatosis type 1 and Legius syndrome: an international consensus recommendation. Genet Med. 2021;23:1506–13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legius E, Wu R, Eyssen M, Marynen P, Fryns JP, Cassiman JJ. Encephalocraniocutaneous lipomatosis with a mutation in the NF1 gene. J Med Genet. 1995;32:316–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1050386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7643367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leier A, Bedwell DM, Chen AT, Dickson G, Keeling KM, Kesterson RA, Korf BR, Marquez Lago TT, Müller UF, Popplewell L, Zhou J, Wallis D. Mutation-directed therapeutics for neurofibromatosis type i. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids. 2020;20:739–53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7225739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32408052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leppävirta J, Kallionpää RA, Uusitalo E, Vahlberg T, Pöyhönen M, Peltonen J, Peltonen S. Congenital anomalies in neurofibromatosis 1: a retrospective register-based total population study. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2018;13:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5769274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29335026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin AE, Birch PH, Korf BR, Tenconi R, Niimura M, Poyhonen M, Armfield Uhas K, Sigorini M, Virdis R, Romano C, Bonioli E, Wolkenstein P, Pivnick EK, Lawrence M, Friedman JM. Cardiovascular malformations and other cardiovascular abnormalities in neurofibromatosis 1. Am J Med Genet. 2000;95:108–17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin N, Baird L, Koss M, Kopecky KE, Gone E, Ullrich NJ, Scott RM, Smith ER. Discovery of asymptomatic moyamoya arteriopathy in pediatric syndromic populations: radiographic and clinical progression. Neurosurg Focus. 2011;31:E6. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lion-François L, Gueyffier F, Mercier C, Gérard D, Herbillon V, Kemlin I, Rodriguez D, Ginhoux T, Peyric E, Coutinho V, Bréant V, des Portes V, Pinson S, Combemale P, Kassaï B, et al.  The effect of methylphenidate on neurofibromatosis type 1: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover trial. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2014;9:142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4172829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25205361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liy-Wong C, Mohammed J, Carleton A, Pope E, Parkin P, Lara-Corrales I. The relationship between neurofibromatosis type 1, juvenile xanthogranuloma, and malignancy: A retrospective case-control study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;76:1084–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28189268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly KI, Blakeley JO. The diagnosis and management of neurofibromatosis type 1. Med Clin North Am. 2019;103:1035–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31582003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madden JR, Rush SZ, Stence N, Foreman NK, Liu AK. Radiation-induced gliomas in 2 pediatric patients with neurofibromatosis type 1: case study and summary of the literature. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2014;36:e105–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24136023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjanska A, Galazka P, Wysocki M, Styczynski J. New frontiers in therapy of peripheral nerve sheath tumors in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1: latest evidence and clinical implications. Anticancer Res. 2020;40:1817–31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32234870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin E, Coert JH, Flucke UE, Slooff WM, van de Sande MAJ, van Noesel MM, Grünhagen DJ, Wijnen MHWA, Verhoef C. Neurofibromatosis-associated malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors in children have a worse prognosis: a nationwide cohort study. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2020;67:e28138. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31889416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maruoka R, Takenouchi T, Torii C, Shimizu A, Misu K, Higasa K, Matsuda F, Ota A, Tanito K, Kuramochi A, Arima Y, Otsuka F, Yoshida Y, Moriyama K, Niimura M, Saya H, Kosaki K. The use of next-generation sequencing in molecular diagnosis of neurofibromatosis type 1: a validation study. Genet Test Mol Biomarkers. 2014;18:722–35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4216997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25325900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masocco M, Kodra Y, Vichi M, Conti S, Kanieff M, Pace M, Frova L, Taruscio D. Mortality associated with neurofibromatosis type 1: a study based on Italian death certificates (1995-2006). Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2011;6:11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21439034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mautner VF, Granström S, Leark RA. Impact of ADHD in adults with neurofibromatosis type 1: associated psychological and social problems. J Atten Disord. 2015;19:35–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22786884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEwing RL, Joelle R, Mohlo M, Bernard JP, Hillion Y, Ville Y. Prenatal diagnosis of neurofibromatosis type 1: sonographic and MRI findings. Prenat Diagn. 2006;26:1110–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Méni C, Sbidian E, Moreno JC, Lafaye S, Buffard V, Goldzal S, Wolkenstein P, Valeyrie-Allanore L. Treatment of neurofibromas with a carbon dioxide laser: a retrospective cross-sectional study of 106 patients. Dermatology. 2015;230:263–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25662097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messiaen L, Vogt J, Bengesser K, Fu C, Mikhail F, Serra E, Garcia-Linares C, Cooper DN, Lazaro C, Kehrer-Sawatzki H. Mosaic type-1 NF1 microdeletions as a cause of both generalized and segmental neurofibromatosis type-1 (NF1). Hum Mutat. 2011;32:213–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21280148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messiaen L, Yao S, Brems H, Callens T, Sathienkijkanchai A, Denayer E, Spencer E, Arn P, Babovic-Vuksanovic D, Bay C, Bobele G, Cohen BH, Escobar L, Eunpu D, Grebe T, Greenstein R, Hachen R, Irons M, Kronn D, Lemire E, Leppig K, Lim C, McDonald M, Narayanan V, Pearn A, Pedersen R, Powell B, Shapiro LR, Skidmore D, Tegay D, Thiese H, Zackai EH, Vijzelaar R, Taniguchi K, Ayada T, Okamoto F, Yoshimura A, Parret A, Korf B, Legius E. Clinical and mutational spectrum of neurofibromatosis type 1-like syndrome. JAMA. 2009;302:2111–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19920235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DT, Freedenberg D, Schorry E, Ullrich NJ, Viskochil D, Korf BR, et al.  Health supervision for children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Pediatrics. 2019;19:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31010905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miraglia E, Moliterni E, Iacovino C, Roberti V, Laghi A, Moramarco A, Giustini S. Cutaneous manifestations in neurofibromatosis type 1. Clin Ter. 2020;171:e371–e377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mladenov KV, Spiro AS, Krajewski KL, Stücker R, Kunkel P. Management of spinal deformities and tibial pseudarthrosis in children with neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF-1). Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2409–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8346390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32613421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo J, Moye SL, McKay RM, Le LQ. Neurofibromin and suppression of tumorigenesis: beyond the GAP. Oncogene. 2022;41:1235–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9063229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monroe CL, Dahiya S, Gutmann DH. Dissecting clinical heterogeneity in neurofibromatosis type 1. Annu Rev Pathol. 2017;12:53–74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moramarco A, Giustini S, Nofroni I, Mallone F, Miraglia E, Iacovino C, Calvieri S, Lambiase A. Near-infrared imaging: an in vivo, non-invasive diagnostic tool in neurofibromatosis type 1. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2018;256:307–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moramarco A, Mallone F, Sacchetti M, Lucchino L, Miraglia E, Roberti V, Lambiase A, Giustini S. Hyperpigmented spots at fundus examination: a new ocular sign in Neurofibromatosis Type I. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2021;16:147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33757576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moramarco A, Miraglia E, Mallone F, Roberti V, Iacovino C, Bruscolini A, Giustolisi R, Giustini S. Retinal microvascular abnormalities in neurofibromatosis type 1. Br J Ophthalmol. 2019;103:1590–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris SM, Acosta MT, Garg S, Green J, Huson S, Legius E, North KN, Payne JM, Plasschaert E, Frazier TW, Weiss LA, Zhang Y, Gutmann DH, Constantino JN. Disease burden and symptom structure of autism in neurofibromatosis type 1: a study of the International NF1-ASD Consortium Team (INFACT). JAMA Psychiatry. 2016;73:1276–84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5298203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27760236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhopadhyay S, Maitra A, Choudhury S. Selumetinib: the first ever approved drug for neurofibromatosis-1 related inoperable plexiform neurofibroma. Curr Med Res Opin. 2021;37:789–94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33683166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy ES, Xie H, Merchant TE, Yu JS, Chao ST, Suh JH. Review of cranial radiotherapy-induced vasculopathy. J Neurooncol. 2015;122:421–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25670390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen R, Dombi E, Widemann BC, Solomon J, Fuensterer C, Kluwe L, Friedman JM, Mautner VF. Growth dynamics of plexiform neurofibromas: a retrospective cohort study of 201 patients with neurofibromatosis 1. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2012;7:75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3524754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23035791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen R, Jett K, Harris GJ, Cai W, Friedman JM, Mautner VF. Benign whole body tumor volume is a risk factor for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors in neurofibromatosis type 1. J Neurooncol. 2014;116:307–13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24166582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen R, Mir TS, Kluwe L, Jett K, Kentsch M, Mueller G, Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Friedman JM, Mautner VF. Cardiac characterization of 16 patients with large NF1 gene deletions. Clin Genet. 2013;84:344–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niemeyer CM, Flotho C. Juvenile myelomonocytic leukemia: who's the driver at the wheel? Blood. 2019;133:1060–70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning X, Farschtschi S, Jones A, Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Mautner VF, Friedman JM. Growth in neurofibromatosis 1 microdeletion patients. Clin Genet. 2016;89:351–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26111455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida T, Tsujimoto M, Takahashi T, Hirota S, Blay JY, Wataya-Kaneda M. Gastrointestinal stromal tumors in Japanese patients with neurofibromatosis type I. J Gastroenterol. 2016;51:571–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4880630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26511941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishida Y, Ikuta K, Ito S, Urakawa H, Sakai T, Koike H, Ito K, Imagama S. Limitations and benefits of FDG-PET/CT in NF1 patients with nerve sheath tumors: a cross-sectional/longitudinal study. Cancer Sci. 2021;112:1114–22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33415792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozarslan B, Russo T, Argenziano G, Santoro C, Piccolo V. cutaneous findings in neurofibromatosis type 1. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13:463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7865571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33530415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer RJ, Iavarone A, Jones DTW, Blakeley JO, Bouffet E, Fisher MJ, Hwang E, Hawkins C, Kilburn L, MacDonald T, Pfister SM, Rood B, Rodriguez FJ, Tabori U, Ramaswamy V, Zhu Y, Fangusaro J, Johnston SA, Gutmann DH. Implications of new understandings of gliomas in children and adults with NF1: report of a consensus conference. Neuro Oncol. 2020;22:773–84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7283027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32055852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Packer RJ, Vezina G. New treatment modalities in NF-related neuroglial tumors. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2377–84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32601903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacot L, Burin des Roziers C, Laurendeau I, Briand-Suleau A, Coustier A, Mayard T, Tlemsani C, Faivre L, Thomas Q, Rodriguez D, Blesson S, Dollfus H, Muller YG, Parfait B, Vidaud M, Gilbert-Dussardier B, Yardin C, Dauriat B, Derancourt C, Vidaud D, Pasmant E. One NF1 mutation may conceal another. Genes (Basel) 2019;10:633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacot L, Vidaud D, Sabbagh A, Laurendeau I, Briand-Suleau A, Coustier A, Maillard T, Barbance C, Morice-Picard F, Sigaudy S, Glazunova OO, Damaj L, Layet V, Quelin C, Gilbert-Dussardier B, Audic F, Dollfus H, Guerrot AM, Lespinasse J, Julia S, Vantyghem MC, Drouard M, Lackmy M, Leheup B, Alembik Y, Lemaire A, Nitschké P, Petit F, Dieux Coeslier A, Mutez E, Taieb A, Fradin M, Capri Y, Nasser H, Ruaud L, Dauriat B, Bourthoumieu S, Geneviève D, Audebert-Bellanger S, Nizon M, Stoeva R, Hickman G, Nicolas G, Mazereeuw-Hautier J, Jannic A, Ferkal S, Parfait B, Vidaud M, Wolkenstein P, Pasmant E, et al.  Severe phenotype in patients with large deletions of NF1. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13:2963.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8231977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34199217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paley D. Congenital pseudarthrosis of the tibia: biological and biomechanical considerations to achieve union and prevent refracture. J Child Orthop. 2019;13:120–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardej SK, Glad DM, Casnar CL, Janke KM, Klein-Tasman BP. Longitudinal investigation of early motor development in neurofibromatosis type 1. J Pediatr Psychol. 2022;47:180–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34664663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmeggiani A, Boiani F, Capponi S, Duca M, Angotti M, Pignataro V, Sacrato L, Spinardi L, Vara G, Maltoni L, Cecconi I, Pastore Trossello M, Franzoni E. Neuropsychological profile in Italian children with neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) and their relationships with neuroradiological data: Preliminary results. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2018;22:822–30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29802023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrozzani R, Pilotto E, Clementi M, Frizziero L, Leonardi F, Convento E, Miglionico G, Pulze S, Perrini P, Trevisson E, Cassina M, Midena E. Retinal vascular abnormalities in a large cohort of patients affected by neurofibromatosis type 1: a study using optical coherence tomography angiography. Retina. 2018;38:585–93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28248826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasmant E, Parfait B, Luscan A, Goussard P, Briand-Suleau A, Laurendeau I, Fouveaut C, Leroy C, Montadert A, Wolkenstein P, Vidaud M, Vidaud D. Neurofibromatosis type 1 molecular diagnosis: what can NGS do for you when you have a large gene with loss of function mutations? Eur J Hum Genet. 2015;23:596–601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4402624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25074460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel NB, Stacy GS. Musculoskeletal manifestations of neurofibromatosis type 1. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2012;199:W99-106. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22733937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne JM, Pickering T, Porter M, Oates EC, Walia N, Prelog K, North KN. Longitudinal assessment of cognition and T2-hyperintensities in NF1: an 18-year study. Am J Med Genet A. 2014;164A:661–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Payne JM, Walsh KS, Pride NA, Haebich KM, Maier A, Chisholm A, Glad DM, Casnar CL, Rouel M, Lorenzo J, Del Castillo A, North KN, Klein-Tasman B. Social skills and autism spectrum disorder symptoms in children with neurofibromatosis type 1: evidence for clinical trial outcomes. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2020;62:813–19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32181506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pecoraro A, Arehart E, Gallentine W, Radtke R, Smith E, Pizoli C, Kansagra S, Abdelnour E, McLendon R, Mikati MA. Epilepsy in neurofibromatosis type 1. Epilepsy Behav. 2017;73:137–41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28633092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philpott C, Tovell H, Frayling IM, Cooper DN, Upadhyaya M. The NF1 somatic mutational landscape in sporadic human cancers. Hum Genomics. 2017;11:13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5480124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28637487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinna V, Daniele P, Calcagni G, Mariniello L, Criscione R, Giardina C, Lepri FR, Hozhabri H, Alberico A, Cavone S, Morella AT, Mandile R, Annunziata F, Di Giosaffatte N, D'Asdia MC, Versacci P, Capolino R, Strisciuglio P, Giustini S, Melis D, Digilio MC, Tartaglia M, Marino B, De Luca A. Prevalence, type, and molecular spectrum of NF1 mutations in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1 and congenital heart disease. Genes (Basel) 2019;10:675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770533</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31487937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinna V, Lanari V, Daniele P, Consoli F, Agolini E, Margiotti K, Bottillo I, Torrente I, Bruselles A, Fusilli C, Ficcadenti A, Bargiacchi S, Trevisson E, Forzan M, Giustini S, Leoni C, Zampino G, Digilio MC, Dallapiccola B, Clementi M, Tartaglia M, De Luca A. p. Arg1809Cys substitution in neurofibromin is associated with a distinctive NF1 phenotype without neurofibromas. Eur J Hum Genet. 2015;23:1068–71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4795103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25370043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prada CE, Hufnagel RB, Hummel TR, Lovell AM, Hopkin RJ, Saal HM, Schorry EK. The use of magnetic resonance imaging screening for optic pathway gliomas in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. J Pediatr. 2015;167:851–6.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9100836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26233602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pride N, Payne JM, Webster R, Shores EA, Rae C, North KN. Corpus callosum morphology and its relationship to cognitive function in neurofibromatosis type 1. J Child Neurol. 2010;25:834–41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20142468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rad E, Tee AR. Neurofibromatosis type 1: fundamental insights into cell signalling and cancer. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2016;52:39–46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramirez E, Morris SM, Turner TN, Gutmann DH. Familial lipomas without classic neurofibromatosis-1 caused by a missense germline NF1 mutation. Neurol Genet. 2021;7:e582. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8054955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33884301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen SA, Friedman JM. NF1 gene and neurofibromatosis 1. Am J Epidemiol. 2000;151:33–40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10625171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riccardi C, Perrone L, Napolitano F, Sampaolo S, Melone MAB. Understanding the biological activities of vitamin D in type 1 neurofibromatosis: new insights into disease pathogenesis and therapeutic design. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12:2965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7602022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33066259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodari G, Scuvera G, Ulivieri FM, Profka E, Menni F, Saletti V, Esposito S, Bergamaschi S, Ferrante E, Eller-Vainicher C, Esposito S, Arosio M, Giavoli C. Progressive bone impairment with age and pubertal development in neurofibromatosis type I. Arch Osteoporos. 2018;13:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojnueangnit K, Xie J, Gomes A, Sharp A, Callens T, Chen Y, Liu Y, Cochran M, Abbott MA, Atkin J, Babovic-Vuksanovic D, Barnett CP, Crenshaw M, Bartholomew DW, Basel L, Bellus G, Ben-Shachar S, Bialer MG, Bick D, Blumberg B, Cortes F, David KL, Destree A, Duat-Rodriguez A, Earl D, Escobar L, Eswara M, Ezquieta B, Frayling IM, Frydman M, Gardner K, Gripp KW, Hernández-Chico C, Heyrman K, Ibrahim J, Janssens S, Keena BA, Llano-Rivas I, Leppig K, McDonald M, Misra VK, Mulbury J, Narayanan V, Orenstein N, Galvin-Parton P, Pedro H, Pivnick EK, Powell CM, Randolph L, Raskin S, Rosell J, Rubin K, Seashore M, Schaaf CP, Scheuerle A, Schultz M, Schorry E, Schnur R, Siqveland E, Tkachuk A, Tonsgard J, Upadhyaya M, Verma IC, Wallace S, Williams C, Zackai E, Zonana J, Lazaro C, Claes K, Korf B, Martin Y, Legius E, Messiaen L. High incidence of Noonan syndrome features including short stature and pulmonic stenosis in patients carrying NF1 missense mutations affecting p.Arg1809: genotype-phenotype correlation. Hum Mutat. 2015;36:1052–63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5049609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26178382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy A, Barbarot S, Charbonnier V, Gayet-Delacroix M, Stalder JF, Roulin JL, Le Gall D. Examining the frontal subcortical brain vulnerability hypothesis in children with neurofibromatosis type 1: Are T2-weighted hyperintensities related to executive dysfunction? Neuropsychology. 2015;29:473–84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25365565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggieri M, Polizzi A, Spalice A, Salpietro V, Caltabiano R, D'Orazi V, Pavone P, Pirrone C, Magro G, Platania N, Cavallaro S, Muglia M, Nicita F. The natural history of spinal neurofibromatosis: a critical review of clinical and genetic features. Clin Genet. 2015;87:401–10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25211147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabbagh A, Pasmant E, Imbard A, Luscan A, Soares M, Blanché H, Laurendeau I, Ferkal S, Vidaud M, Pinson S, Bellanné-Chantelot C, Vidaud D, Parfait B, Wolkenstein P. NF1 molecular characterization and neurofibromatosis type I genotype-phenotype correlation: the French experience. Hum Mutat. 2013;34:1510–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23913538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salamon J, Papp L, Tóth Z, Laqmani A, Apostolova I, Adam G, Mautner VF, Derlin T. Nerve sheath tumors in neurofibromatosis type 1: assessment of whole-body metabolic tumor burden using F-18-FDG PET/CT. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0143305. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26625155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellmer L, Farschtschi S, Marangoni M, Heran MK, Birch P, Wenzel R, Friedman JM, Mautner VF. Non-optic glioma in adults and children with neurofibromatosis 1. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2017;12:34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5312522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellmer L, Marangoni M, Farschtschi S, Heran MK, Birch P, Wenzel R, Mautner VF, Friedman JM. Serial MRIs provide novel insight into natural history of optic pathway gliomas in patients with neurofibromatosis 1. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2018;13:62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5913802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29685181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seminog OO, Goldacre MJ. Risk of benign tumours of nervous system, and of malignant neoplasms, in people with neurofibromatosis: population-based record-linkage study. Br J Cancer. 2013;108:193–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3553528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23257896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Serra E, Gel B, Fernández-Rodríguez J, Lázaro C. Genomics of peripheral nerve sheath tumors associated with neurofibromatosis type 1. In: Tadini G, Legius E, Brems H, eds. Multidisciplinary Approach to Neurofibromatosis Type 1. Cham, Switzerland: Springer; 2020:118-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharif S, Ferner R, Birch JM, Gillespie JE, Gattamaneni HR, Baser ME, Evans DG. Second primary tumors in neurofibromatosis 1 patients treated for optic glioma: substantial risks after radiotherapy. J Clin Oncol. 2006;24:2570–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16735710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma MR, Puj KS, Salunke AA, Pandya SJ, Gandhi JS, Parikh AR. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor with analysis of various prognostic factors: a single-institutional experience. J Cancer Res Ther. 2021;17:106–13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33723140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shofty B, Ben Sira L, Constantini S. Neurofibromatosis 1-associated optic pathway gliomas. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2351–61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32524182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivasubramanian R, Meyers KE. Hypertension in children and adolescents with turner syndrome (TS), neurofibromatosis 1 (NF1), and Williams syndrome (WS). Curr Hypertens Rep. 2021;23:18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33779870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solares I, Viñal D, Morales-Conejo M, Rodriguez-Salas N, Feliu J. Novel molecular targeted therapies for patients with neurofibromatosis type 1 with inoperable plexiform neurofibromas: a comprehensive review. ESMO Open. 2021;6:100223. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34388689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorrentino U, Bellonzi S, Mozzato C, Brasson V, Toldo I, Parrozzani R, Clementi M, Cassina M, Trevisson E. Epilepsy in NF1: epidemiologic, genetic, and clinical features. A monocentric retrospective study in a cohort of 784 patients. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13:6336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8699608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34944956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spinnato P, Facchini G, Tetta C, Lotrecchiano L, Colangeli M, Bazzocchi A, Albisinni U, Cutrera R, Tomà P, Bartoloni A. Neurofibromatosis type-1-associated diffuse lung disease in children. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2019;54:1760–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31411009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenson PD, Mort M, Ball EV, Chapman M, Evans K, Azevedo L, Hayden M, Heywood S, Millar DS, Phillips AD, Cooper DN. The Human Gene Mutation Database (HGMD®): optimizing its use in a clinical diagnostic or research setting. Hum Genet. 2020;139:1197–207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson DA, Viskochil DH, Schorry EK, Crawford AH, D'Astous J, Murray KA, Friedman JM, Armstrong L, Carey JC. The use of anterolateral bowing of the lower leg in the diagnostic criteria for neurofibromatosis type 1. Genet Med. 2007;9:409–12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3244139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17666887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart DR, Korf BR, Nathanson KL, Stevenson DA, Yohay K. Care of adults with neurofibromatosis type 1: a clinical practice resource of the American College of Medical Genetics and Genomics (ACMG). Genet Med. 2018;20:671–82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Summers MA, Quinlan KG, Payne JM, Little DG, North KN, Schindeler A. Skeletal muscle and motor deficits in neurofibromatosis type 1. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2015;15:161–70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5133719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26032208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry AR, Barker FG, 2nd, Leffert L, Bateman BT, Souter I, Plotkin SR. Neurofibromatosis type 1 and pregnancy complications: a population-based study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2013;209:46.e1–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terry AR, Jordan JT, Schwamm L, Plotkin SR. Increased risk of cerebrovascular disease among patients with neurofibromatosis type 1: population-based approach. Stroke. 2016;47:60–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26645253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tezol O, Balcı Y, Alakaya M, Gundogan B, Cıtak EC. Bone densitometry measurements in children with neurofibromatosis Type 1 using quantitative computed tomography. Singapore Med J. 2021 Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34005845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toledano-Alhadef H, Mautner VF, Gugel I, Zipfel J, Haas-Lude K, Constantini S, Schuhmann MU. Role, function and challenges of multidisciplinary centres for rare diseases exemplified for neurofibromatosis type 1 syndrome. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2279–84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32514759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touzé R, Manassero A, Bremond-Gignac D, Robert MP. Long-term follow-up of choroidal abnormalities in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2021;49:516–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevisson E, Forzan M, Salviati L, Clementi M. Neurofibromatosis type 1 in two siblings due to maternal germline mosaicism. Clin Genet. 2014;85:386–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23621909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevisson E, Morbidoni V, Forzan M, Daolio C, Fumini V, Parrozzani R, Cassina M, Midena E, Salviati L, Clementi M. The Arg1038Gly missense variant in the NF1 gene causes a mild phenotype without neurofibromas. Mol Genet Genomic Med. 2019;7:e616. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang DS, Murphy ES, Merchant TE. Radiation therapy for optic pathway and hypothalamic low-grade gliomas in children. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2017;99:642–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29280458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uehara M, Nakamura Y, Takahashi J, Kamimura M, Isobe F, Yamaguchi T, Kosho T, Uchiyama S, Suzuki T, Kato H. Efficacy of denosumab therapy for neurofibromatosis type 1 with osteoporosis and history of fractures: a case report. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2018;14:1243–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upadhyaya M, Majounie E, Thompson P, Han S, Consoli C, Krawczak M, Cordeiro I, Cooper DN. Three different pathological lesions in the NF1 gene originating de novo in a family with neurofibromatosis type 1. Hum Genet. 2003;112:12–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12483293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uusitalo E, Leppävirta J, Koffert A, Suominen S, Vahtera J, Vahlberg T, Pöyhönen M, Peltonen J, Peltonen S. Incidence and mortality of neurofibromatosis: a total population study in Finland. J Invest Dermatol. 2015;135:904–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25354145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uusitalo E, Rantanen M, Kallionpää RA, Pöyhönen M, Leppävirta J, Ylä-Outinen H, Riccardi VM, Pukkala E, Pitkäniemi J, Peltonen S, Peltonen J. Distinctive cancer associations in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34:1978–86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26926675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vagge A, Nelson LB, Capris P, Traverso CE. Choroidal freckling in pediatric patients affected by neurofibromatosis type 1. J Pediatr Ophthalmol Strabismus. 2016;53:271–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27637020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valentin T, Le Cesne A, Ray-Coquard I, Italiano A, Decanter G, Bompas E, Isambert N, Thariat J, Linassier C, Bertucci F, Bay JO, Bellesoeur A, Penel N, Le Guellec S, Filleron T, Chevreau C. Management and prognosis of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors: the experience of the French Sarcoma Group (GSF-GETO). Eur J Cancer. 2016;56:77–84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26824706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Der Gucht A, Zehou O, Djelbani-Ahmed S, Valeyrie-Allanore L, Ortonne N, Brugières P, Wolkenstein P, Luciani A, Rahmouni A, Sbidian E, Itti E. Metabolic tumour burden measured by 18F-FDG PET/CT predicts malignant transformation in patients with neurofibromatosis Type-1. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0151809. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4795780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26987124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Minkelen R, van Bever Y, Kromosoeto JN, Withagen-Hermans CJ, Nieuwlaat A, Halley DJ, van den Ouweland AM. A clinical and genetic overview of 18 years neurofibromatosis type 1 molecular diagnostics in the Netherlands. Clin Genet. 2014;85:318–27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23656349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varan A, Şen H, Aydın B, Yalçın B, Kutluk T, Akyüz C. Neurofibromatosis type 1 and malignancy in childhood. Clin Genet. 2016;89:341–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26073032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virdis R, Street ME, Bandello MA, Tripodi C, Donadio A, Villani AR, Cagozzi L, Garavelli L, Bernasconi S. Growth and pubertal disorders in neurofibromatosis type 1. J Pediatr Endocrinol Metab. 2003;16 Suppl 2:289–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12729406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogel AC, Gutmann DH, Morris SM. Neurodevelopmental disorders in children with neurofibromatosis type 1. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2017;59:1112–16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28845518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Merker VL, Park ER, Plotkin SR. Quality of life among children and adolescents with neurofibromatosis 1: a systematic review of the literature. J Neurooncol. 2015;122:219–28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25663248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Well L, Döbel K, Kluwe L, Bannas P, Farschtschi S, Adam G, Mautner VF, Salamon J. Genotype-phenotype correlation in neurofibromatosis type-1: NF1 whole gene deletions lead to high tumor-burden and increased tumor-growth. PLoS Genet. 2021;17:e1009517. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8099117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33951044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Well L, Jaeger A, Kehrer-Sawatzki H, Farschtschi S, Avanesov M, Sauer M, de Sousa MT, Bannas P, Derlin T, Adam G, Mautner VF, Salamon JM. The effect of pregnancy on growth-dynamics of neurofibromas in Neurofibromatosis type 1. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0232031. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7188260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32343738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilding A, Ingham SL, Lalloo F, Clancy T, Huson SM, Moran A, Evans DG. Life expectancy in hereditary cancer predisposing diseases: an observational study. J Med Genet. 2012;49:264–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22362873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winter N, Dohrn MF, Wittlinger J, Loizides A, Gruber H, Grimm A. Role of high-resolution ultrasound in detection and monitoring of peripheral nerve tumor burden in neurofibromatosis in children. Childs Nerv Syst. 2020;36:2427–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang YD, Jiang F, Li DZ. Neurofibromatosis type 1 due to possible maternal mosaicism in a family with two affected siblings. Congenit Anom (Kyoto) 2020;60:156–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32352596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zessis NR, Gao F, Vadlamudi G, Gutmann DH, Hollander AS. Height growth impairment in children with neurofibromatosis type 1 is characterized by decreased pubertal growth velocity in both sexes. J Child Neurol. 2018;33:762–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Tong H, Fu X, Zhang Y, Liu J, Cheng R, Liang J, Peng J, Sun Z, Liu H, Zhang F, Lu W, Li M, Yao Z. Molecular characterization of NF1 and neurofibromatosis type 1 genotype-phenotype correlations in a Chinese population. Sci Rep. 2015;5:11291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4460887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26056819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
