<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301457</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK1280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="pc">Pachyonychia Congenita</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Frances JD</ForeName><Initials>FJD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pachyonychia Congenita Project, School of Life Sciences, University of Dundee, Dundee, Scotland, United Kingdom</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hansen</LastName><ForeName>C David</ForeName><Initials>CD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hull</LastName><ForeName>Peter R</ForeName><Initials>PR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Clinical Dermatology and Cutaneoous Science, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaspar</LastName><ForeName>Roger L</ForeName><Initials>RL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Transderm, Inc, Santa Cruz, California</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McLean</LastName><ForeName>WH Irwin</ForeName><Initials>WHI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biological Chemistry and Drug Discovery, School of Life Sciences, University of Dundee, Dundee, Scotland, United Kingdom</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O’Toole</LastName><ForeName>Edel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Cutaneous Research, Barts &amp; the London School of Medicine and Dentistry, Queen Mary University of London, London, England, United Kingdom</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sprecher</LastName><ForeName>Eli</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Tel Aviv Medical Center, Tel Aviv, Israel</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Pachyonychia congenita (PC) is characterized by hypertrophic nail dystrophy, painful palmoplantar keratoderma and blistering, oral leukokeratosis, pilosebaceous cysts (including steatocystoma and vellus hair cysts), palmoplantar hyperhydrosis, and follicular keratoses on the trunk and extremities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">PC is diagnosed by clinical findings and/or by the identification of a heterozygous pathogenic variant in one of the five keratin genes known to cause PC: <i>KRT6A</i>, <i>KRT6B</i>, <i>KRT6C</i>, <i>KRT16</i>, and <i>KRT17</i>.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Pain from the palmoplantar keratoderma may be reduced somewhat by limiting friction and trauma to the feet by minimizing walking or standing, reducing hydration of the stratum corneum by using wicking socks and ventilated footwear, selecting comfortable shoes, and maintaining ideal body weight. Foot care includes paring down of hyperkeratotic areas and topical therapies for hyperkeratosis (emollients and lotions containing keratolyics). Care of thickened nails often requires the use of surgical or razor blades or sanders such as a Dremel<sup>®</sup> tool. Troublesome nails removed surgically frequently grow back in some form. Good oral hygiene and brushing gently with a soft toothbrush can improve thick, white patches on the tongue and oral mucosa. Secondary fungal and bacterial infections that require treatment are common; cysts usually do not require treatment but can be incised and drained if infected or painful. Bottle-fed infants with leukokeratosis may need a soft nipple with an enlarged opening. Rarely, young children with laryngeal thickening/growths need emergency surgery to reestablish the airway; however, surgery may exacerbate the condition. <i>Prevention of secondary complications:</i> Attention to pre- and post-grooming hygiene to prevent infection; a "bleach bath" regimen using a mild bleach solution can help prevent infections. <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid:</i> High temperatures and high humidity may worsen the condition.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">Pachyonychia congenita is inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. Approximately 30% of cases appear to be caused by a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant. A single case of germline mosaicism has been reported. The offspring of an affected individual have a 50% chance of inheriting the disorder. If the pathogenic variant has been identified in an affected family member, prenatal testing for a pregnancy at increased risk is possible.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorders">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.References">References</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="pc" sec="pc.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Keratin, type I cytoskeletal 16</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Keratin, type I cytoskeletal 17</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Keratin, type II cytoskeletal 6A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Keratin, type II cytoskeletal 6B</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Keratin, type II cytoskeletal 6C</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KRT16</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KRT17</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KRT6A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KRT6B</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KRT6C</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pachyonychia Congenita</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2006</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Covello SP, Smith FJD, Sillevis Smitt JH, Paller AS, Munro CS, Jonkman MF, Uitto J, McLean WHI. Keratin 17 mutations cause either steatocystoma multiplex or pachyonychia congenita type 2. Br J Dermatol. 1998;139:475–80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9767294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeKlotz CMC, Schwartz ME, Milstone LM. Nail removal in pachyonychia congenita: patient-reported survey outcomes. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;76:990–2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28411774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchatelet S, Guibbal L, de Veer S, Fraitag S, Nitschké P, Zarhrate M, Bodemer C, Hovnanian A. Olmsted syndrome with erythromelalgia caused by recessive transient receptor potential vanilloid 3 mutations. Br J Dermatol. 2014;171:675–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24606194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eliason MJ, Leachman SA, Feng BJ, Schwartz ME, Hansen CD. A review of the clinical phenotype of 254 patients with genetically confirmed pachyonychia congenita. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2012;67:680–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22264670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng YG, Xiao SX, Ren XR, Wang WQ, Liu A, Pan M. Keratin 17 mutation in pachyonychia congenita type 2 with early onset sebaceous cysts. Br J Dermatol. 2003;148:452–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12653736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu T, Leachman SA, Wilson NJ, Smith FJD, Schwartz ME, Tang JY. Genotype-phenotype correlations among pachyonychia congenita patients with K16 mutations. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:1025–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21160496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg I, Fruchter D, Meilick A, Schwartz ME, Sprecher E. Best treatment practices for pachyonychia congenita. JEADV. 2014;28:279–85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23363249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>González-Ramos J, Sendagorta-Cudós E, González-López G, Mayor-Ibarguren A, Feltes-Ochoa R, Herranz-Pinto P. Efficacy of botulinum toxin in pachyonychia congenita type 1: report of two new cases. Dermatol Ther. 2016;29:32–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber R, Edlinger M, Kaspar RL, Hansen CD, Leachman S, Milstone LM, Smith FJ, Sidoroff A, Fritsch PO, Schmuth M. An appraisal of oral retinoids in the treatment of pachyonychia congenita. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2012;66:e193–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21601946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hale GI, Wilson NJ, Smith FJ, Wylie G, Schwartz ME, Zamiri M. Mutations in GJB6 causing phenotype resembling pachyonychia congenita. Br J Dermatol. 2015;172:1447–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25385569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickerson RP, Leake D, Pho LN, Leachman SA, Kaspar RL. Rapamycin selectively inhibits expression of an inducible keratin (K6a) in human keratinocytes and improves symptoms in pachyonychia congenita patients. J Dermatol Sci. 2009;56:82–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19699613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickerson RP, Smith FJD, Reeves RE, Contag CH, Leake D, Leachman SA, Milstone LM, McLean WHI, Kaspar RL. Single-nucleotide-specific siRNA targeting in a dominant-negative skin model. J Invest Dermatol. 2008;128:594–605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17914454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasparis C, Reid D, Wilson NJ, Okur V, Cole C, Hansen CD, Bosse K, Betz RC, Khan M, Smith FJD. Isolated recessive nail dysplasia caused by FZD6 mutations: report of three families and review of the literature. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2016;41:884–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5132090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27786367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leachman SA, Hickerson RP, Hull PR, Smith FJD, Milstone LM, Lane EB, Bale SJ, Roop DR, McLean WHI, Kaspar RL. Therapeutic siRNAs for dominant genetic skin disorders including pachyonychia congenita. J Dermatol Sci. 2008;51:151–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2587483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18495438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leachman SA, Hickerson RP, Schwartz ME, Bullough EE, Hutcherson SL, Boucher KM, Hansen CD, Eliason MJ, Srivatsa GS, Kornbrust DJ, Smith FJD, McLean WHI, Milstone LM, Kaspar RL. First-in-human mutation-targeted siRNA phase Ib trial of an inherited skin disorder. Mol Ther. 2010;18:442–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2839285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19935778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leachman SA, Kaspar RL, Fleckman P, Florell SR, Smith FJD, McLean WHI, Lunny DP, Milstone LM, van Steensel MA, Munro CS, O'Toole EA, Celebi JT, Kansky A, Lane EB. Clinical and pathological features of pachyonychia congenita. J Investig Dermatol Symp Proc. 2005;10:3–17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16250204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao H, Sayers JM, Wilson NJ, Irvine AD, Mellerio JE, Baselga E, Bayliss SJ, Uliana V, Fimiani M, Lane EB, McLean WHI, Leachman SA, Smith FJD. A spectrum of mutations in keratins K6a, K16 and K17 causing pachyonychia congenita. J Dermatol Sci. 2007;48:199–205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17719747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Z, Chen Q, Lee M, Cao X, Zhang J, Ma D, Chen L, Hu X, Wang H, Wang X, Zhang P, Liu X, Guan L, Tang Y, Yang H, Tu P, Bu D, Zhu X, Wang K, Li R, Yang Y. Exome sequencing reveals mutations in TRPV3 as a cause of Olmsted syndrome. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;90:558–64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3309189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22405088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovgren ML, McAleer MA, Irvine AD, Wilson NJ, Tavadia S, Schwartz ME, Cole C, Sandilands A, Smith FJD, Zamiri M. Mutations in desmoglein 1 cause diverse inherited palmoplantar keratoderma phenotypes: implications for genetic screening. Br J Dermatol. 2017;176:1345–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5485079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27534273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLean WHI, Hansen CD, Eliason M, Smith FJD. The phenotypic and molecular genetic features of pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:1015–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21430705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan B, Byrnes K, Schwartz M, Hansen CD, Campbell CM, Krupiczojc M, Caterina MJ, Polydefkis M. Peripheral neuropathic changes in pachyonychia congenita. Pain. 2016;157:2843–53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27776012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pho LN, Smith FJD, Konecki D, Bale S, McLean WHI, Cohen B, Eliason M, Leachman SA. Paternal germ cell mosaicism in autosomal dominant pachyonychia congenita. Arch Dermatol. 2011;147:1077–80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohler E, Mamai O, Hirst J, Zamiri M, Horn H, Nomura T, Irvine AD, Moran B, Wilson NJ, Smith FJD, Goh CS, Sandilands A, Cole C, Barton GJ, Evans AT, Shimizu H, Akiyama M, Suehiro M, Konohana I, Shboul M, Teissier S, Boussofara L, Denguezli M, Saad A, Gribaa M, Dopping-Hepenstal PJ, McGrath JA, Brown SJ, Goudie DR, Reversade B, Munro CS, McLean WHI. Haploinsufficiency for AAGAB causes clinically heterogeneous forms of punctate palmoplantar keratoderma. Nat Genet. 2012;44:1272–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz ME, Zimmerman GM, Smith FJD, Sprecher E. Pachyonychia Congenita Project: a partnership of patient and medical professional. J Derm Nurses Association. 2013;5:42–47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S, Boen M, Kenner-Bell B, Schwartz M, Rademaker A, Paller AS. Pachyonychia congenita in pediatric patients: natural history, features, and impact. JAMA Dermatol. 2014;150:146–53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24132595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaunhurst KM, Hogendorf AM, Smith FJD, Lingala B, Schwartz ME, Cywinska-Bernas A, Zeman KJ, Tang JY. Pachyonychia congenita patients with mutations in KRT6A have more extensive disease compared with patients who have mutations in KRT16. Br J Dermatol. 2012;166:875–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22098151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szeverenyi I, Cassidy AJ, Chung CW, Lee BT, Common JE, Ogg SC, Chen H, Sim SY, Goh WL, Ng KW, Simpson JA, Chee LL, Eng GH, Li B, Lunny DP, Chuon D, Venkatesh A, Khoo KH, McLean WHI, Lim YP, Lane EB. The human intermediate filament database: comprehensive information on a gene family involved in many human diseases. Hum Mutat. 2008;29:351–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18033728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swartling C, Karlqvist M, Hymnelius K, Weis J, Vahlquist A. Botulinum toxin in the treatment of sweat-worsened foot problems in patients with epidermolysis bullosa simplex and pachyonychia congenita. Br J Dermatol. 2010;163:1072–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20618323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swartling C, Vahlquist A. Treatment of pachyonychia congenita with plantar injections of botulinum toxin. Br J Dermatol. 2006;154:763–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16536826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis T, Poole CD, Hoggart B. Can skin disease cause neuropathic pain? A study in pachyonychia congenita. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2016;41:26–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26358843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson NJ, Cole C, Milstone LM, Kiszewski AE, Hansen CD, O'Toole EA, Schwartz ME, McLean WHI, Smith FJD. Expanding the phenotypic spectrum of Olmsted syndrome. J Invest Dermatol. 2015;135:2879–83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4652067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26067147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson NJ, Hansen CD, Azkur D, Kocabas CN, Metin A, Coskun Z, Schwartz ME, Hull PR, McLean WHI, Smith FJD. Recessive mutations in the gene encoding frizzled 6 cause twenty nail dystrophy--expanding the differential diagnosis for pachyonychia congenita. J Dermatol Sci. 2013;70:58–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23374899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson NJ, Leachman SA, Hansen CD, McMullan AC, Milstone LM, Schwartz ME, McLean WHI, Hull PR, Smith FJD. A large mutational study in pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:1018–24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21326300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson NJ, Messenger AG, Leachman SA, O'Toole EA, Lane EB, McLean WHI, Smith FJD. Keratin K6c mutations cause focal palmoplantar keratoderma. J Invest Dermatol. 2010;130:425–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19609311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson NJ, O'Toole E, Milstone LM, Hansen CD, Shepherd AA, Al-Asadi E, Schwartz ME, McLean WHI, Sprecher E, Smith FJD. The molecular genetic analysis of the expanding pachyonychia congenita case collection. Br J Dermatol. 2014;171:343–55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4282083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24611874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao Y, Gartner U, Smith FJD, McLean WHI. Statins downregulate K6a promoter activity: a possible therapeutic avenue for pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:1045–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21390048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
