<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301774</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK9674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia"><i>PRICKLE1</i>-Related Disorders</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mastrangelo</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Neurology and Psychiatry Unit Department of Human Neuroscience Sapienza Università di Roma Rome, Italy</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caputi</LastName><ForeName>Caterina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Neurology and Psychiatry Unit Department of Human Neuroscience Sapienza Università di Roma Rome, Italy</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esposito</LastName><ForeName>Dario</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Neurology and Psychiatry Unit Department of Human Neuroscience Sapienza Università di Roma Rome, Italy</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leuzzi</LastName><ForeName>Vincenzo</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Neurology and Psychiatry Unit Department of Human Neuroscience Sapienza Università di Roma Rome, Italy</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Individuals with biallelic <i>PRICKLE1-</i>related disorders typically present with progressive myoclonus epilepsy (PME) with ataxia characterized by myoclonic seizures (lightning-like jerks), generalized convulsive seizures, varying degrees of neurologic regression mainly presenting with ataxia, and mild cognitive impairment or normal cognition. Onset of symptoms is between ages five and ten years. Action myoclonus may affect the limbs or bulbar muscles, while spontaneous myoclonus may occasionally involve facial muscles. Dysarthria may also be an early feature of this condition. The main seizure types are myoclonic or tonic-clonic with frequent nocturnal occurrence. Individuals with heterozygous <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variants have presented with non-PME seizures (isolated myoclonic seizures, juvenile myoclonic epilepsy), myoclonic epilepsy, developmental delay, intellectual disability, autism spectrum disorder, and/or central nervous system malformations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of a <i>PRICKLE1</i>-related disorder is established in a proband with suggestive findings and biallelic or heterozygous pathogenic variant(s) in <i>PRICKLE1</i> identified by molecular genetic testing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Occupational therapy, psychomotricity/physical therapy, and speech therapy for ataxia and neurodevelopmental impairment; adaptive devices as needed to maintain or improve independence in mobility and feeding; anti-seizure medications as needed, such as valproic acid, clonazepam, zonisamide, and levetiracetam. <i>Surveillance:</i> Neurologic examination every six months; developmental assessment and evaluation of school performance and emotional status every six to 12 months as needed based on age. <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid:</i> Phenytoin, carbamezapine, oxycarbazpine, gabapentin, pregabalin, tiagabine, and vigabatrin may worsen myoclonic seizures.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING"><i>PRICKLE1</i>-related PME with ataxia is associated with biallelic homozygous or compound heterozygous <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variants and inherited in an autosomal recessive manner. <i>PRICKLE1</i>-related phenotypes associated with a heterozygous <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variant are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. <i>Autosomal recessive inheritance.</i> If both parents of a proband with <i>PRICKLE1</i>-related PME with ataxia are known to be heterozygous for a <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variant, each sib of an affected individual has at conception a 25% chance of being affected, a 50% chance of being heterozygous, and a 25% chance of inheriting neither of the familial <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variants. <i>Autosomal dominant inheritance.</i> An individual with an autosomal dominant <i>PRICKLE1</i>-related disorder may have the disorder as the result of a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant or a pathogenic variant inherited from a parent. Each child of an individual with a heterozygous <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variant has a 50% chance of inheriting the pathogenic variant. Once the <i>PRICKLE1</i> pathogenic variant(s) have been identified in an affected family member, prenatal testing for a pregnancy at increased risk and preimplantation genetic testing for <i>PRICKLE1</i>-related disorders are possible.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.GeneReview_Scope"><i>GeneReview</i> Scope</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Di">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="me-ataxia" sec="me-ataxia.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1-Related Progressive Myoclonic Epilepsy (PME) with Ataxia (Epilepsy, Progressive Myoclonic 1B [EPM1B])</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1-Related Non-PME Seizures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1-Related Myoclonic Seizures, Developmental Delay, Mild Intellectual Disability, and Autism Spectrum Disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1-Related Distal Symmetric Polyneuropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1-Related Central Nervous System Malformations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prickle-like protein 1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PRICKLE1-Related Disorders</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Algahtani H, Al-Hakami F, Al-Shehri M, Shirah B, Al-Qahtani MH, Abdulkareem AA, Naseer MI. A very rare form of autosomal dominant progressive myoclonus epilepsy caused by a novel variant in the PRICKLE1 gene. Seizure. 2019;69:133–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31035234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassuk AG, Sherr EH. A de novo mutation in PRICKLE1 in fetal agenesis of the corpus callosum and polymicrogyria. J Neurogenet. 2015;29:174–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4813514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26727662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosoi CM, Capra V, Allache R, Trinh VQ, De Marco P, Merello E, Kibar Z. Identification and characterization of novel rare mutations in the planar cell polarity gene PRICKLE1 in human neural tube defects. Hum Mutat. 2011;32:1371–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3217084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21901791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldridge R, Iivanainen M, Stern R, Koerber T, Wilder BJ. "Baltic" myoclonus epilepsy: hereditary disorder of childhood made worse by phenytoin. Lancet. 1983;2:838–42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6137660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Shanti H, Daoud A, Sadoon AA, Leal SM, Chen S, Lee K, Spiegel R. A distinct autosomal recessive ataxia maps to chromosome 12 in an inbred family from Jordan. Brain Dev. 2006;28:353–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6143173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16376507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hata Y, Yoshida K, Nishida N. Sudden unexpected death with rare compound heterozygous variants in PRICKLE1. Neurogenetics. 2019;20:39–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30564977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jónsson H, Sulem P, Kehr B, Kristmundsdottir S, Zink F, Hjartarson E, Hardarson MT, Hjorleifsson KE, Eggertsson HP, Gudjonsson SA, Ward LD, Arnadottir GA, Helgason EA, Helgason H, Gylfason A, Jonasdottir A, Jonasdottir A, Rafnar T, Frigge M, Stacey SN, Th Magnusson O, Thorsteinsdottir U, Masson G, Kong A, Halldorsson BV, Helgason A, Gudbjartsson DF, Stefansson K. Parental influence on human germline de novo mutations in 1,548 trios from Iceland. Nature. 2017;549:519–22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28959963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Lin C, Whitaker DT, Bakeri H, Bulgakov OV, Liu P, Lei J, Dong L, Li T, Swaroop A. Prickle1 is expressed in distinct cell populations of the central nervous system and contributes to neuronal morphogenesis. Hum Mol Genet. 2013;22:2234–46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3652420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23420014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastrangelo M, Tolve M, Martinelli M, Di Noia SP, Parrini E, Leuzzi V. PRICKLE1-related early onset epileptic encephalopathy. Am J Med Genet A. 2018;176:2841–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Epilepsies: diagnosis and management – do not do recommendation [NICE Guideline CG137]. Available online. 2016. Accessed 3-31-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Organization for Rare Disorders. Progressive Myoclonus Epilepsy. Available online. 1990. Accessed 3-31-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pehlivan D, Beck CR, Okamoto Y, Harel T, Akdemir ZHC, Jhangiani SN, Lupski JR. The role of combined SNV and CNV burden in patients with distal symmetric polyneuropathy. Genet Med. 2016;18:443–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5322766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahbari R, Wuster A, Lindsay SJ, Hardwick RJ, Alexandrov LB, Turki SA, Dominiczak A, Morris A, Porteous D, Smith B, Stratton MR, Hurles ME, et al.  Timing, rates and spectra of human germline mutation. Nat Genet. 2016;48:126–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26656846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenson PD, Mort M, Ball EV, Chapman M, Evans K, Azevedo L, Hayden M, Heywood S, Millar DS, Phillips AD, Cooper DN. The Human Gene Mutation Database (HGMD®): optimizing its use in a clinical diagnostic or research setting. Hum Genet. 2020;139:1197–207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straussberg R, Basel-Vanagaite L, Kivity S, Dabby R, Cirak S, Nurnberg P, Voit T, Mahajnah M, Inbar D, Saifi GM, Lupski JR, Delague V, Megarbane A, Richter A, Leshinsky E, Berkovic SF. An autosomal recessive cerebellar ataxia syndrome with upward gaze palsy, neuropathy, and seizures. Neurology. 2005;64:142–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tao H, Manak JR, Sowers L, Mei X, Kiyonari H, Abe T, Dahdaleh NS, Yang T, Wu S, Chen S, Fox MH, Gurnett C, Montine T, Bird T, Shaffer LG, Rosenfeld JA, McConnell J, Madan-Khetarpal S, Berry-Kravis E, Griesbach H, Saneto RP, Scott MP, Antic D, Reed J, Boland R, Ehaideb SN, El-Shanti H, Mahajan VB, Ferguson PJ, Axelrod JD, Lehesjoki AE, Fritzsch B, Slusarski DC, Wemmie J, Ueno N, Bassuk AG. Mutations in prickle orthologs cause seizures in flies, mice, and humans. Am J Hum Genet. 2011;88:138–49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3035715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21276947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Todd BP, Bassuk AG. A de novo mutation in PRICKLE1 associated with myoclonic epilepsy and autism spectrum disorder. J Neurogenet. 2018;32:313–15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6251753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29790814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
