<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301494</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK1318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="gefs"><i>SCN1A</i> Seizure Disorders</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>Ian O</ForeName><Initials>IO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Director, Comprehensive Epilepsy Program Nicklaus Children's Hospital Miami, Florida</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sotero de Menezes</LastName><ForeName>Marcio A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Director, Genetic Epilepsy Clinic and TSC Clinic Pediatric Neuroscience Center Swedish Neuroscience Institute Seattle, Washington</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS"><i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorders encompass a spectrum that ranges from simple febrile seizures and generalized epilepsy with febrile seizures plus (GEFS+) at the mild end to Dravet syndrome and intractable childhood epilepsy with generalized tonic-clonic seizures (ICE-GTC) at the severe end. Phenotypes with intractable seizures including Dravet syndrome are often associated with cognitive decline. Less commonly observed phenotypes include myoclonic astatic epilepsy (MAE), Lennox-Gastaut syndrome, infantile spasms, epilepsy with focal seizures, and vaccine-related encephalopathy and seizures. The phenotype of <i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorders can vary even within the same family.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of an <i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorder is established in a proband by identification of a heterozygous pathogenic variant in <i>SCN1A</i> by molecular genetic testing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations</i>: Care is best provided by a physician (e.g., pediatric epileptologist) familiar with the pharmacotherapy for this disorder. Seizure control is critical to prevent permanent injury and death. Anti-seizure medication (ASM): clobazam (can be used for treatment of seizures in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome); stiripentol, benzodiazepines, cannabidiol, topiramate, levetiracetam, valproic acid, and ethosuximide. Levetiracetam is often effective, but may make seizures worse in some individuals. Phenobarbital is effective but poorly tolerated because of its effects on cognition. Use of the ketogenic diet to decrease seizure frequency has been beneficial in some affected individuals. Parents are advised to take a CPR course. Routine seizure and personal safety education is indicated. <i>Prevention of secondary complications</i>: Use of protective helmets by individuals with atonic seizures or myoclonic-astatic epilepsy. Good sleep hygiene should be encouraged. Persons with epilepsy should be made aware of motor vehicle driving laws. <i>Surveillance</i>: Serial neuropsychological evaluation for neurologic, cognitive, and behavioral deterioration; EEG monitoring for new or different seizure types; polysomnography should be considered if obstructive or central sleep apnea is suspected. <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid</i>: AEDs: carbamazepine, lamotrigine, and vigabatrin, which can induce or increase myoclonic seizures; phenytoin, which can induce choreoathetosis; rufinamide may exacerbate seizures as well; acetaminophen, which is hepatotoxic. Activities in which a sudden loss of consciousness could lead to injury or death (e.g., bathing, swimming, driving, or working/playing at heights). Sleep deprivation, which can exacerbate seizures, should be avoided. <i>Pregnancy management</i>: Pregnant women should receive counseling regarding the risks and benefits of the use of anti-seizure medication during pregnancy; the advantages and disadvantages of increasing maternal periconceptional folic acid supplementation to 4,000 µg daily; the effects of pregnancy on anticonvulsant metabolism; and the effect of pregnancy on maternal seizure control.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING"><i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorders are inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. A proband with an <i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorder may have an inherited or a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant. The proportion of cases caused by <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variants varies by phenotype: the percentage of probands with an <i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorder and an affected parent decreases as the severity of the phenotype in the proband increases; thus, most <i>SCN1A</i>-related severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy (<i>SCN1A</i>-SMEI) and ICE-GTC are the result of a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant. Each child of an individual with an <i>SCN1A</i> seizure disorder has a 50% chance of inheriting the pathogenic variant; however, the risk of developing seizures is less than 100% because of reduced penetrance. Prenatal diagnosis for pregnancies at increased risk is possible if the pathogenic variant in the family is known.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.GeneReview_Scope">GeneReview Scope</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorde">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="gefs" sec="gefs.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Severe Myoclonic Epilepsy in Infancy (SMEI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Generalized Epilepsy with Febrile Seizures Plus (GEFS+)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simple Febrile Seizures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intractable Childhood Epilepsy with Generalized Tonic-Clonic Seizures (ICE-GTC)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intractable Infantile Partial Seizures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myoclonic-Astatic Epilepsy (MAE)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCN1A-Related Dravet Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium channel protein type 1 subunit alpha</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCN1A</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SCN1A Seizure Disorders</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2007</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aljaafari D, Fasano A, Nascimento FA, Lang AE, Andrade DM. Adult motor phenotype differentiates Dravet syndrome from Lennox-Gastaut syndrome and links SCN1A to early onset parkinsonian features. Epilepsia. 2017;58:e44–e48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28186331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrade DM, Hamani C, Lozano AM, Wennberg RA. Dravet syndrome and deep brain stimulation: seizure control after 10 years of treatment. Epilepsia. 2010;51:1314–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19919661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arzimanoglou A, Guerrini R, Aicardi J. Aicardi's Epilepsy in Children. 3 ed. Philadephia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azmanov DN, Zhelyazkova S, Dimova PS, Radionova M, Bojinova V, Florez L, Smith SJ, Tournev I, Jablensky A, Mulley J, Scheffer I, Kalaydjieva L, Sander JW. Mosaicism of a missense SCN1A mutation and Dravet syndrome in a Roma/Gypsy family. Epileptic Disord. 2010;12:117–24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20562086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayat A, Hjalgrim H, Moller RS. The incidence of SCN1A-related Dravet syndrome in Denmark is 1:22,000: a population-based study from 2004 to 2009. Epilepsia. 2015;56:e36–e39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25778844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergamaschi MM, Queiroz RH, Zuardi AW, Crippa JA. Safety and side effects of cannabidiol, a Cannabis sativa constituent. Curr Drug Saf. 2011;6:237–49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22129319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkovic SF, Harkin L, McMahon JM, Pelekanos JT, Zuberi SM, Wirrell EC, Gill DS, Iona X, Mulley JC, Scheffer IE. De-novo mutations of the sodium channel gene SCN1A in alleged vaccine encephalopathy: a retrospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5:488–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16713920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boles RG, Pober BR, Gibson LH, Willis CR, McGrath J, Roberts DJ, Yang-Feng TL. Deletion of chromosome 2q24-q31 causes characteristic digital anomalies: case report and review. Am J Med Genet. 1995;55:155–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7717414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanni P, Malcarne M, Moro F, Veggiotti P, Buti D, Ferrari AR, Parrini E, Mei D, Volzone A, Zara F, Heron SE, Bordo L, Marini C, Guerrini R. Generalized epilepsy with febrile seizures plus (GEFS+): clinical spectrum in seven Italian families unrelated to SCN1A, SCN1B, and GABRG2 gene mutations. Epilepsia. 2004;45:149–58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14738422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunklaus A, Ellis R, Reavey E, Forbes GH, Zuberi SM. Prognostic, clinical and demographic features in SCN1A mutation-positive Dravet syndrome. Brain. 2012;135:2329–36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22719002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caraballo RH, Cersósimo R, De los Santos C. Levetiracetam-induced seizure aggravation associated with continuous spikes and waves during slow sleep in children with refractory epilepsies. Epileptic Disord. 2010;12:146–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catterall WA. From ionic currents to molecular mechanisms: the structure and function of voltage-gated sodium channels. Neuron. 2000;26:13–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10798388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catterall WA, Kalume F, Oakley JC. NaV1.1 channels and epilepsy. J Physiol. 2010;588:1849–59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20194124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceulemans B, Boel M, Claes L, Dom L, Willekens H, Thiry P, Lagae L. Severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy: toward an optimal treatment. J Child Neurol. 2004a;19:516–21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15526956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceulemans B, Boel M, Leyssens K, Van Rossem C, Neels P, Jorens PG, Lagae L. Successful use of fenfluramine as an add-on treatment for Dravet syndrome. Epilepsia. 2012;53:1131–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22554283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceulemans B, Schoonjans AS, Marchau F, Lagae L, Paelinck BP. Five-year extended follow-up status of 10 patients with Dravet syndrome treated with fenﬂuramine. Epilepsia. 2016;57:e129–34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27197941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceulemans BP, Claes LR, Lagae LG. Clinical correlations of mutations in the SCN1A gene: from febrile seizures to severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy. Pediatr Neurol. 2004b;30:236–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15087100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chipaux M, Villeneuve N, Sabouraud P, Desguerre I, Boddaert N, Depienne C, Chiron C, Dulac O, Nabbout R. Unusual consequences of status epilepticus in Dravet syndrome. Seizure. 2010;19:190–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20172746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiron C, Marchand MC, Tran A, Rey E, d'Athis P, Vincent J, Dulac O, Pons G. Stiripentol in severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy: a randomised placebo-controlled syndrome-dedicated trial. STICLO study group. Lancet. 2000;356:1638–42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11089822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppola G, Capovilla G, Montagnini A, Romeo A, Spano M, Tortorella G, Veggiotti P, Viri M, Pascotto A. Topiramate as add-on drug in severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy: an Italian multicenter open trial. Epilepsy Res. 2002;49:45–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11948006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curia G, Biagini G, Perucca E, Avoli M. Lacosamide: a new approach to target voltage-gated sodium currents in epileptic disorders. CNS Drugs. 2009;23:555–68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4878900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19552484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depienne C, Trouillard O, Gourfinkel-An I, Saint-Martin C, Bouteiller D, Graber D, Barthez-Carpentier MA, Gautier A, Villeneuve N, Dravet C, Livet MO, Rivier-Ringenbach C, Adam C, Dupont S, Baulac S, Héron D, Nabbout R, Leguern E. Mechanisms for variable expressivity of inherited SCN1A mutations causing Dravet syndrome. J Med Genet. 2010;47:404–10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20522430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depienne C, Trouillard O, Saint-Martin C, Gourfinkel-An I, Bouteiller D, Carpentier W, Keren B, Abert B, Gautier A, Baulac S, Arzimanoglou A, Cazeneuve C, Nabbout R, LeGuern E. Spectrum of SCN1A gene mutations associated with Dravet syndrome: analysis of 333 patients. J Med Genet. 2009;46:183–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18930999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devinsky O, Cross JH, Laux L, Marsh E, Miller I, Nabbout R, Scheffer IE, Thiele EA, Wright S, et al.  Trial of cannabidiol for drug-resistant seizures in the Dravet syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2017;376:2011–20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dichgans M, Freilinger T, Eckstein G, Babini E, Lorenz-Depiereux B, Biskup S, Ferrari MD, Herzog J, van den Maagdenberg AM, Pusch M, Strom TM. Mutation in the neuronal voltage-gated sodium channel SCN1A in familial hemiplegic migraine. Lancet. 2005;366:371–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16054936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dravet C, Bureau M, Oguni H, Fukuyama Y, Cokar O. Severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy. In: Roger J, Bureau M, Dravet C, Genton P, Tassinari CA, Wolf P, eds. Epileptic Syndromes in Infancy, Childhood and Adolescence. 3 ed. Eastleigh, UK: John Libbey; 2002:81-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dressler A, Stöcklin B, Reithofer E, Benninger F, Freilinger M, Hauser E, Reiter-Fink E, Seidl R, Trimmel-Schwahofer P, Feucht M. Long-term outcome and tolerability of the ketogenic diet in drug-resistant childhood epilepsy--the Austrian experience. Seizure. 2010;19:404–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20598586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escayg A, Goldin AL. Sodium channel SCN1A and epilepsy: mutations and mechanisms. Epilepsia. 2010;51:1650–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2937162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20831750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara T. Clinical spectrum of mutations in SCN1A gene: severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy and related epilepsies. Epilepsy Res. 2006;70 Suppl 1:S223–30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16806826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujiwara T, Sugawara T, Mazaki-Miyazaki E, Takahashi Y, Fukushima K, Watanabe M, Hara K, Morikawa T, Yagi K, Yamakawa K, Inoue Y. Mutations of sodium channel alpha subunit type 1 (SCN1A) in intractable childhood epilepsies with frequent generalized tonic-clonic seizures. Brain. 2003;126:531–46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12566275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuma G, Oguni H, Shirasaka Y, Watanabe K, Miyajima T, Yasumoto S, Ohfu M, Inoue T, Watanachai A, Kira R, Matsuo M, Muranaka H, Sofue F, Zhang B, Kaneko S, Mitsudome A, Hirose S. Mutations of neuronal voltage-gated Na+ channel alpha 1 subunit gene SCN1A in core severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy (SMEI) and in borderline SMEI (SMEB). Epilepsia. 2004;45:140–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14738421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller RW, Snoddy HD, Robertson DW. Mechanisms of effects of D-fenfluramine on brain serotonin metabolism in rats: uptake inhibition versus release. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1988;30:715–21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2463643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaily E, Anttonen AK, Valanne L, Liukkonen E, Träskelin AL, Polvi A, Lommi M, Muona M, Eriksson K, Lehesjoki AE. Dravet syndrome: new potential genetic modifiers, imaging abnormalities, and ictal findings. Epilepsia. 2013;54:1577–85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23808377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennaro E, Santorelli FM, Bertini E, Buti D, Gaggero R, Gobbi G, Lini M, Granata T, Freri E, Parmeggiani A, Striano P, Veggiotti P, Cardinali S, Bricarelli FD, Minetti C, Zara F. Somatic and germline mosaicisms in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2006;341:489–93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16430863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gennaro E, Veggiotti P, Malacarne M, Madia F, Cecconi M, Cardinali S, Cassetti A, Cecconi I, Bertini E, Bianchi A, Gobbi G, Zara F. Familial severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy: truncation of Nav1.1 and genetic heterogeneity. Epileptic Disord. 2003;5:21–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12773292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goeggel Simonetti B, Rieubland C, Courage C, Strozzi S, Tschumi S, Gallati S, Lemke JR. Duplication of the sodium channel gene cluster on 2q24 in children with early onset epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2012;53:2128–34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23016767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grosso S, Orrico A, Galli L, Di Bartolo R, Sorrentino V, Balestri P. SCN1A mutation associated with atypical Panayiotopoulos syndrome. Neurology. 2007;69:609–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17679682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrini R, Dravet C, Genton P, Belmonte A, Kaminska A, Dulac O. Lamotrigine and seizure aggravation in severe myoclonic epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1998;39:508–12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9596203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harkin LA, McMahon JM, Iona X, Dibbens L, Pelekanos JT, Zuberi SM, Sadleir LG, Andermann E, Gill D, Farrell K, Connolly M, Stanley T, Harbord M, Andermann F, Wang J, Batish SD, Jones JG, Seltzer WK, Gardner A, Sutherland G, Berkovic SF, Mulley JC, Scheffer IE. The spectrum of SCN1A-related infantile epileptic encephalopathies. Brain. 2007;130:843–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17347258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hattori J, Ouchida M, One J, Miyake S, Maniwa S, Mimaki N, Ohtsuka Y, Ohmori I. A screening test for the prediction of Dravet syndrome before one year of age. Epilepsia. 2008;49:626–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18076640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heron SE, Scheffer IE, Iona X, Zuberi SM, Birch R, McMahon JM, Bruce CM, Berkovic SF, Mulley JC. De novo SCN1A mutations in Dravet syndrome and related epileptic encephalopathies are largely of paternal origin. J Med Genet. 2010;47:137–41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19589774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn CS, Ater SB, Hurst DL. Carbamazepine-exacerbated epilepsy in children and adolescents. Pediatr Neurol. 1986;2:340–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3508708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannetti P, Parisi P, Spalice A, Ruggieri M, Zara F. Addition of verapamil in the treatment of severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy. Epilepsy Res. 2009;85:89–95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19303743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanai K, Hirose S, Oguni H, Fukuma G, Shirasaka Y, Miyajima T, Wada K, Iwasa H, Yasumoto S, Matsuo M, Ito M, Mitsudome A, Kaneko S. Effect of localization of missense mutations in SCN1A on epilepsy phenotype severity. Neurology. 2004;63:329–34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kimura K, Sugawara T, Mazaki-Miyazaki E, Hoshino K, Nomura Y, Tateno A, Hachimori K, Yamakawa K, Segawa M. A missense mutation in SCN1A in brothers with severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy (SMEI) inherited from a father with febrile seizures. Brain Dev. 2005;27:424–30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16122630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingston JH, Cross JH, Mclellan A, Birch R, Zuberi SM. A novel inherited mutation in the voltage sensor region of SCN1A is associated with Panayiotopoulos syndrome in siblings and generalized epilepsy with febrile seizures plus. J Child Neurol. 2009;24:503–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19339291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madia F, Striano P, Gennaro E, Malacarne M, Paravidino R, Biancheri R, Budetta M, Cilio MR, Gaggero R, Pierluigi M, Minetti C, Zara F. Cryptic chromosome deletions involving SCN1A in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy. Neurology. 2006;67:1230–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17030758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malow BA, Levy K, Maturen K, Bowes R. Obstructive sleep apnea is common in medically refractory epilepsy patients. Neurology. 2000;55:1002–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11061259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantegazza M, Gambardella A, Rusconi R, Schiavon E, Annesi F, Cassulini RR, Labate A, Carrideo S, Chifari R, Canevini MP, Canger R, Franceschetti S, Annesi G, Wanke E, Quattrone A. Identification of an Nav1.1 sodium channel (SCN1A) loss-of-function mutation associated with familial simple febrile seizures. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102:18177–82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1312393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16326807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marini C, Mei D, Temudo T, Ferrari AR, Buti D, Dravet C, Dias AI, Moreira A, Calado E, Seri S, Neville B, Narbona J, Reid E, Michelucci R, Sicca F, Cross HJ, Guerrini R. Idiopathic epilepsies with seizures precipitated by fever and SCN1A abnormalities. Epilepsia. 2007;48:1678–85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17561957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marini C, Scheffer IE, Nabbout R, Mei D, Cox K, Dibbens LM, McMahon JM, Iona X, Carpintero RS, Elia M, Cilio MR, Specchio N, Giordano L, Striano P, Gennaro E, Cross JH, Kivity S, Neufeld MY, Afawi Z, Andermann E, Keene D, Dulac O, Zara F, Berkovic SF, Guerrini R, Mulley JC. SCN1A duplications and deletions detected in Dravet syndrome: implications for molecular diagnosis. Epilepsia. 2009;50:1670–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19400878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIntosh AM, McMahon J, Dibbens LM, Iona X, Mulley JC, Scheffer IE, Berkovic SF. Effects of vaccination on onset and outcome of Dravet syndrome: a retrospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:592–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20447868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meador KJ, Baker GA, Browning N, Clayton-Smith J, Combs-Cantrell DT, Cohen M, Kalayjian LA, Kanner A, Liporace JD, Pennell PB, Privitera M, Loring DW, et al.  Cognitive function at 3 years of age after fetal exposure to antiepileptic drugs. N Engl J Med. 2009;360:1597–605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2737185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng H, Xu HQ, Yu L, Lin GW, He N, Su T, Shi YW, Li B, Wang J, Liu XR, Tang B, Long YS, Yi YH, Liao WP. The SCN1A mutation database: updating information and analysis of the relationships among genotype, functional alteration, and phenotype. Hum Mutat. 2015;36:573–80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25754450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulley JC, Nelson P, Guerrero S, Dibbens L, Iona X, McMahon JM, Harkin L, Schouten J, Yu S, Berkovic SF, Scheffer IE. A new molecular mechanism for severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy: exonic deletions in SCN1A. Neurology. 2006;67:1094–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17000989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulley JC, Scheffer IE, Petrou S, Dibbens LM, Berkovic SF, Harkin LA. SCN1A mutations and epilepsy. Hum Mutat. 2005;25:535–42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15880351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabbout R, Copioli C, Chipaux M, Chemaly N, Desguerre I, Dulac O, Chiron C. Ketogenic diet also benefits Dravet syndrome patients receiving stiripentol: a prospective pilot study. Epilepsia. 2011;52:e54–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21569025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nabbout R, Gennaro E, Dalla Bernardina B, Dulac O, Madia F, Bertini E, Capovilla G, Chiron C, Cristofori G, Elia M, Fontana E, Gaggero R, Granata T, Guerrini R, Loi M, La Selva L, Lispi ML, Matricardi A, Romeo A, Tzolas V, Valseriati D, Veggiotti P, Vigevano F, Vallee L, Dagna Bricarelli F, Bianchi A, Zara F. Spectrum of SCN1A mutations in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy. Neurology. 2003;60:1961–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolai J, Gunning B, Leroy PL, Ceulemans B, Vles JS. Acute hepatic injury in four children with Dravet syndrome: valproic acid, topiramate or acetaminophen? Seizure. 2008;17:92–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17697789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolan K, Camfield CS, Camfield PR. Coping with a child with Dravet syndrome: insights from families. J Child Neurol. 2008;23:690–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18344453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohmori I, Ouchida M, Kobayashi K, Jitsumori Y, Inoue T, Shimizu K, Matsui H, Ohtsuka Y, Maegaki Y. Rasmussen encephalitis associated with SCN 1 A mutation. Epilepsia. 2008a;49:521–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18031552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohmori I, Ouchida M, Kobayashi K, Jitsumori Y, Mori A, Michiue H, Nishiki T, Ohtsuka Y, Matsui H. CACNA1A variants may modify the epileptic phenotype of Dravet syndrome. Neurobiol Dis. 2013;50:209–17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23103419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohmori I, Ouchida M, Miki T, Mimaki N, Kiyonaka S, Nishiki T, Tomizawa K, Mori Y, Matsui H. A. CACNB4 mutation shows that altered Ca(v)2.1 function may be a genetic modifier of severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy. Neurobiol Dis. 2008b;32:349–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18755274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumura A, Yamamoto T, Shimojima K, Honda Y, Abe S, Ikeno M, Shimizu T. Refractory neonatal epilepsy with a de novo duplication of chromosome 2q24.2q24.3. Epilepsia. 2011;52:e66–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21692795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira S, Vieira JP, Barroca F, Roll P, Carvalhas R, Cau P, Sequeira S, Genton P, Szepetowski P. Severe epilepsy, retardation, and dysmorphic features with a 2q deletion including SCN1A and SCN2A. Neurology. 2004;63:191–2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15249644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescucci C, Caselli R, Grosso S, Mencarelli MA, Mari F, Farnetani MA, Piccini B, Artuso R, Bruttini M, Priolo M, Zuffardi O, Gimelli S, Balestri P, Renieri A. 2q24-q31 deletion: report of a case and review of the literature. Eur J Med Genet. 2007;50:21–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17088112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quilichini PP, Chiron C, Ben-Ari Y, Gozlan H. Stiripentol, a putative antiepileptic drug, enhances the duration of opening of GABA-A receptor channels. Epilepsia. 2006;47:704–16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16650136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragona F, Granata T, Dalla Bernardina B, Offredi F, Darra F, Battaglia D, Morbi M, Brazzo D, Cappelletti S, Chieffo D, De Giorgi I, Fontana E, Freri E, Marini C, Toraldo A, Specchio N, Veggiotti P, Vigevano F, Guerrini R, Guzzetta F, Dravet C. Cognitive development in Dravet syndrome: a retrospective, multicenter study of 26 patients. Epilepsia. 2011;52:386–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21269283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieder SA, Chauhan A, Singh U, Nagarkatti M, Nagarkatti P. Cannabinoid-induced apoptosis in immune cells as a pathway to immunosuppression. Immunobiology. 2010;215:598–605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19457575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rilstone JJ, Coelho FM, Minassian BA, Andrade DM. Dravet syndrome: seizure control and gait in adults with different SCN1A mutations. Epilepsia. 2012;53:1421–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22780858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riva D, Vago C, Pantaleoni C, Bulgheroni S, Mantegazza M, Franceschetti S. Progressive neurocognitive decline in two children with Dravet syndrome, de novo SCN1A truncations and different epileptic phenotypes. Am J Med Genet A. 2009;149A:2339–45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19764027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodda JM, Scheffer IE, McMahon JM, Berkovic SF, Graham HK. Progressive gait deterioration in adolescents with Dravet syndrome. Arch Neurol. 2012;69:873–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22409937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roger J, Bureau M, Dravet C, Genton P, Tassinari CA, Wolf P. Epileptic Syndromes in Infancy, Childhood and Adolescence. 3 ed. Eastleigh, UK: John Libbey; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito Y, Oguni H, Awaya Y, Hayashi K, Osawa M. Phenytoin-induced choreoathetosis in patients with severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy. Neuropediatrics. 2001;32:231–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11748493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samrén EB, van Duijn CM, Koch S, Hiilesmaa VK, Klepel H, Bardy AH, Mannagetta GB, Deichl AW, Gaily E, Granström ML, Meinardi H, Grobbee DE, Hofman A, Janz D, Lindhout D. Maternal use of antiepileptic drugs and the risk of major congenital malformations: a joint European prospective study of human teratogenesis associated with maternal epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1997;38:981–90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9579936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selmer KK, Lund C, Brandal K, Undlien DE, Brodtkorb E. SCN1A mutation screening in adult patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome features. Epilepsy Behav. 2009;16:555–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Andermann E, Whitehouse WP, Harvey AS, Keene DL, Seni MH, Crossland KM, Andermann F, Berkovic SF, Scheffer IE. Severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy: extended spectrum of GEFS+? Epilepsia. 2001;42:837–44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11488881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Striano P, Mancardi MM, Biancheri R, Madia F, Gennaro E, Paravidino R, Beccaria F, Capovilla G, Dalla Bernardina B, Darra F, Elia M, Giordano L, Gobbi G, Granata T, Ragona F, Guerrini R, Marini C, Mei D, Longaretti F, Romeo A, Siri L, Specchio N, Vigevano F, Striano S, Tortora F, Rossi A, Minetti C, Dravet C, Gaggero R, Zara F. Brain MRI findings in severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy and genotype-phenotype correlations. Epilepsia. 2007;48:1092–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17381446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suls A, Claeys KG, Goossens D, Harding B, Van Luijk R, Scheers S, Deprez L, Audenaert D, Van Dyck T, Beeckmans S, Smouts I, Ceulemans B, Lagae L, Buyse G, Barisic N, Misson JP, Wauters J, Del-Favero J, De Jonghe P, Claes LR. Microdeletions involving the SCN1A gene may be common in SCN1A-mutation-negative SMEI patients. Hum Mutat. 2006;27:914–20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16865694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suls A, Velizarova R, Yordanova I, Deprez L, Van Dyck T, Wauters J, Guergueltcheva V, Claes LR, Kremensky I, Jordanova A, De Jonghe P. Four generations of epilepsy caused by an inherited microdeletion of the SCN1A gene. Neurology. 2010;75:72–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20484682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takayanagi M, Haginoya K, Umehara N, Kitamura T, Numata Y, Wakusawa K, Hino-Fukuyo N, Mazaki E, Yamakawa K, Ohura T, Ohtake M. Acute encephalopathy with a truncation mutation in the SCN1A gene: a case report. Epilepsia. 2010;51:1886–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20491869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanabe T, Awaya Y, Matsuishi T, Iyoda K, Nagai T, Kurihara M, Yamamoto K, Minagawa K, Maekawa K. Management of and prophylaxis against status epilepticus in children with severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy (SMEI; Dravet syndrome)--a nationwide questionnaire survey in Japan. Brain Dev. 2008;30:629–35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18424028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanh TN, Chiron C, Dellatolas G, Rey E, Pons G, Vincent J, Dulac O. Arch Pediatr. 2002;9:1120–7. [Long-term efficacy and tolerance of stiripentaol in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy (Dravet's syndrome)]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12503502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tro-Baumann B, von Spiczak S, Lotte J, Bast T, Haberlandt E, Sassen R, Freund A, Leiz S, Stephani U, Boor R, Holthausen H, Helbig I, Kluger G. A retrospective study of the relation between vaccination and occurrence of seizures in Dravet syndrome. Epilepsia. 2011;52:175–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21219303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbeek NE, van der Maas NAT, Jansen FE, van Kempen MJA, Lindhout D, Brilstra EH. Prevalence of SCN1A-related Dravet syndrome among children reported with seizures following vaccination: a population-based ten-year cohort study. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e65758. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3675088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23762420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace RH, Hodgson BL, Grinton BE, Gardiner RM, Robinson R, Rodriguez-Casero V, Sadleir L, Morgan J, Harkin LA, Dibbens LM, Yamamoto T, Andermann E, Mulley JC, Berkovic SF, Scheffer IE. Sodium channel alpha1-subunit mutations in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy and infantile spasms. Neurology. 2003;61:765–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14504318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss LA, Escayg A, Kearney JA, Trudeau M, MacDonald BT, Mori M, Reichert J, Buxbaum JD, Meisler MH. Sodium channels SCN1A, SCN2A and SCN3A in familial autism. Mol Psychiatry. 2003;8:186–94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12610651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirrell EC, Laux L, Donner E, Jette N, Knupp K, Meskis MA, Miller I, Sullivan J, Welborn M, Berg AT. Optimizing the diagnosis and management of Dravet syndrome: recommendations from a North American consensus panel. Pediatr Neurol. 2017;68:18–34.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28284397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirrell EC, Laux L, Franz DN, Sullivan J, Saneto RP, Morse RP, Devinsky O, Chugani H, Hernandez A, Hamiwka L, Mikati MA, Valencia I, Le Guern ME, Chancharme L, de Menezes MS. Stiripentol in Dravet syndrome: results of a retrospective U.S. study. Epilepsia. 2013;54:1595–604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23848835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu YW, Sullivan J, McDaniel SS, Meisler MH, Walsh EM, Li SX, Kuzniewicz MW. Incidence of Dravet syndrome in a US population. Pediatrics. 2015;136:e1310–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4621800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26438699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Hua Y, Zhang W, Xu J, Xu L, Gao F, Jiang P. Variable epilepsy phenotypes associated with heterozygous mutation in the SCN9A gene: report of two cases. Neurol Sci. 2018;39:1113–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29500686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshitomi S, Takahashi Y, Ishizuka M, Yamaguchi T, Watanabe A, Nasu H, Ueda Y, Ohtani H, Ikeda H, Imai K, Shigematsu H, Inoue Y, Tanahashi Y, Aiba K, Ohta H, Shimada S, Yamamoto T. Three patients manifesting early infantile epileptic spasms associated with 2q24.3 microduplications. Brain Dev. 2015;37:874–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25843248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu FH, Mantegazza M, Westenbroek RE, Robbins CA, Kalume F, Burton KA, Spain WJ, McKnight GS, Scheuer T, Catterall WA. Reduced sodium current in GABAergic interneurons in a mouse model of severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy. Nat Neurosci. 2006;9:1142–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16921370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu MJ, Shi YW, Gao MM, Deng WY, Liu XR, Chen L, Long YS, Yi YH, Liao WP. Milder phenotype with SCN1A truncation mutation other than SMEI. Seizure. 2010;19:443–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20630778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuberi SM, Brunklaus A, Birch R, Reavey E, Duncan J, Forbes GH. Genotype-phenotype associations in SCN1A-related epilepsies. Neurology. 2011;76:594–600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21248271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
