<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">20301638</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK1465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="phs">Pallister-Hall Syndrome</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Biesecker</LastName><ForeName>Leslie G</ForeName><Initials>LG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Genomics and Metabolic Genetics Branch National Human Genome Research Institute National Institutes of Health Bethesda, Maryland</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Pallister-Hall syndrome (referred to as PHS in this entry) is characterized by a spectrum of anomalies ranging from polydactyly, asymptomatic bifid epiglottis, and hypothalamic hamartoma at the mild end to laryngotracheal cleft with neonatal lethality at the severe end. Individuals with mild PHS may be incorrectly diagnosed as having isolated postaxial polydactyly type A. Individuals with PHS can have pituitary insufficiency and may die as neonates from undiagnosed and untreated adrenal insufficiency.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of Pallister-Hall syndrome can be established in a proband with both hypothalamic hamartoma and mesoaxial polydactyly. Identification of a heterozygous pathogenic variant in <i>GLI3</i> confirms the diagnosis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Urgent treatment for endocrine abnormalities, especially cortisol deficiency; management of epiglottic abnormalities depending on the abnormality and the extent of respiratory compromise. Bifid epiglottis, the most common abnormality, typically does not need treatment. Standard treatment of anal atresia or stenosis; symptomatic treatment of seizures; elective repair of polydactyly; developmental intervention or special education for developmental delays. <i>Prevention of secondary complications:</i> Biopsy or resection of hypothalamic hamartoma may result in complications and lifelong need for hormone replacement; seizures may begin or worsen with use of stimulants for attention deficit disorder. <i>Surveillance:</i> During childhood, annual developmental assessment and annual medical evaluation to assess growth and monitor for signs of precocious puberty.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">Pallister-Hall syndrome is inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. Individuals with PHS may have an affected parent or may have the disorder as the result of a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant. About 25% of individuals have a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant. Persons with a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant are generally more severely affected than those with a family history of PHS. The risk to offspring of an affected individual is 50%. Prenatal testing for pregnancies at increased risk is possible if the pathogenic variant in the family is known. The reliability of ultrasound examination for prenatal diagnosis is unknown.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.GeneReview_Scope"><i>GeneReview</i> Scope</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorder">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="phs" sec="phs.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sub-Pallister-Hall Syndrome (Sub-PHS)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptional activator GLI3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GLI3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pallister-Hall Syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2000</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2017</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Azzam A, Lerner DM, Peters KF, Wiggs E, Rosenstein DL, Biesecker LG. Psychiatric and neuropsychological characterization of Pallister-Hall syndrome. Clin Genet. 2005;67:87–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15617553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biesecker LG. What you can learn from one gene: GLI3. J Med Genet. 2006;43:465–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2564530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16740916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake J, Hu D, Cain JE, Rosenblum ND. Urogenital development in Pallister-Hall syndrome is disrupted in a cell-lineage-specific manner by constitutive expression of GLI3 repressor. Hum Mol Genet. 2016;25:437–47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26604140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borthen I, Gilhus NE. Pregnancy complications in patients with epilepsy. Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol. 2012;24:78–83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22327733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreau EA, Liow K, Frattali CM, Wiggs E, Turner JT, Feuillan P, Sato S, Patsalides A, Patronas N, Biesecker LG, Theodore WH. Hypothalamic hamartomas and seizures: distinct natural history of isolated and Pallister-Hall syndrome cases. Epilepsia. 2005;46:42–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15660767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Démurger F, Ichkou A, Mougou-Zerelli S, Le Merrer M, Goudefroye G, Delezoide AL, Quélin C, Manouvrier S, Baujat G, Fradin M, Pasquier L, Megarbané A, Faivre L, Baumann C, Nampoothiri S, Roume J, Isidor B, Lacombe D, Delrue MA, Mercier S, Philip N, Schaefer E, Holder M, Krause A, Laffargue F, Sinico M, Amram D, André G, Liquier A, Rossi M, Amiel J, Giuliano F, Boute O, Dieux-Coeslier A, Jacquemont ML, Afenjar A, Van Maldergem L, Lackmy-Port-Lis M, Vincent-Delorme C, Chauvet ML, Cormier-Daire V, Devisme L, Geneviève D, Munnich A, Viot G, Raoul O, Romana S, Gonzales M, Encha-Razavi F, Odent S, Vekemans M, Attie-Bitach T. New insights into genotype-phenotype correlation for GLI3 mutations. Eur J Hum Genet. 2015;23:92–102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4266745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24736735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everman D. The polydactylies. In: Stevenson RE, Hall JG, eds. Human Malformations and Related Anomalies. 2 ed. Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press; 2006:937-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston JJ, Olivos-Glander I, Killoran C, Elson E, Turner JT, Peters KF, Abbott MH, Aughton DJ, Aylsworth AS, Bamshad MJ, Booth C, Curry CJ, David A, Dinulos MB, Flannery DB, Fox MA, Graham JM, Grange DK, Guttmacher AE, Hannibal MC, Henn W, Hennekam RC, Holmes LB, Hoyme HE, Leppig KA, Lin AE, Macleod P, Manchester DK, Marcelis C, Mazzanti L, McCann E, McDonald MT, Mendelsohn NJ, Moeschler JB, Moghaddam B, Neri G, Newbury-Ecob R, Pagon RA, Phillips JA, Sadler LS, Stoler JM, Tilstra D, Walsh Vockley CM, Zackai EH, Zadeh TM, Brueton L, Black GC, Biesecker LG. Molecular and clinical analyses of Greig cephalopolysyndactyly and Pallister-Hall syndromes: robust phenotype prediction from the type and position of GLI3 mutations. Am J Hum Genet. 2005;76:609–22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1199298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15739154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnston JJ, Sapp JC, Turner JT, Amor D, Aftimos S, Aleck KA, Bocian M, Bodurtha JN, Cox GF, Curry CJ, Day R, Donnai D, Field M, Fujiwara I, Gabbett M, Gal M, Graham JM, Hedera P, Hennekam RC, Hersh JH, Hopkin RJ, Kayserili H, Kidd AM, Kimonis V, Lin AE, Lynch SA, Maisenbacher M, Mansour S, McGaughran J, Mehta L, Murphy H, Raygada M, Robin NH, Rope AF, Rosenbaum KN, Schaefer GB, Shealy A, Smith W, Soller M, Sommer A, Stalker HJ, Steiner B, Stephan MJ, Tilstra D, Tomkins S, Trapane P, Tsai AC, Van Allen MI, Vasudevan PC, Zabel B, Zunich J, Black GC, Biesecker LG. Molecular analysis expands the spectrum of phenotypes associated with GLI3 mutations. Hum Mutat. 2010;31:1142–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2947617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20672375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang S, Graham JM, Jr, Olney AH, Biesecker LG. GLI3 frameshift mutations cause autosomal dominant Pallister-Hall syndrome. Nat Genet. 1997;15:266–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9054938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kübler K, Klingmüller D, Gembruch U, Merz WM. High-risk pregnancy management in women with hypopituitarism. J Perinatol. 2009;29:89–95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19177043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng D, Johnston JJ, Turner JT, Boudreau EA, Wiggs EA, Theodore WH, Biesecker LG. Gonadal mosaicism in severe Pallister-Hall syndrome. Am J Med Genet. 2004;124A:296–302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14708104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radhakrishna U, Bornholdt D, Scott HS, Patel UC, Rossier C, Engel H, Bottani A, Chandal D, Blouin JL, Solanki JV, Grzeschik KH, Antonarakis SE. The phenotypic spectrum of GLI3 morphopathies includes autosomal dominant preaxial polydactyly type-IV and postaxial polydactyly type- A/B; No phenotype prediction from the position of GLI3 mutations. Am J Hum Genet. 1999;65:645–55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1377970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10441570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarma AK, Khandker N, Kurczewski L, Brophy GM. Medical management of epileptic seizures: challenges and solutions. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2016;12:467–85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4771397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26966367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens CA, Ledbetter JC. Significance of bifid epiglottis. Am J Med Genet A. 2005;134:447–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15782417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace RH, Freeman JL, Shouri MR, Izzillo PA, Rosenfeld JV, Mulley JC, Harvey AS, Berkovic SF. Somatic mutations in GLI3 can cause hypothalamic hamartoma and gelastic seizures. Neurology. 2008;70:653–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
