<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">20346817</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2010</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>375</Volume>
            <Issue>9720</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2010</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>27</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Environmental health in China: progress towards clean air and safe water.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1110</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1119</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1110-9</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)60062-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Environmental risk factors, especially air and water pollution, are a major source of morbidity and mortality in China. Biomass fuel and coal are burned for cooking and heating in almost all rural and many urban households, resulting in severe indoor air pollution that contributes greatly to the burden of disease. Many communities lack access to safe drinking water and sanitation, and thus the risk of waterborne disease in many regions is high. At the same time, China is rapidly industrialising with associated increases in energy use and industrial waste. Although economic growth from industrialisation has improved health and quality of life indicators, it has also increased the release of chemical toxins into the environment and the rate of environmental disasters, with severe effects on health. Air quality in China's cities is among the worst in the world, and industrial water pollution has become a widespread health hazard. Moreover, emissions of climate-warming greenhouse gases from energy use are rapidly increasing. Global climate change will inevitably intensify China's environmental health troubles, with potentially catastrophic outcomes from major shifts in temperature and precipitation. Facing the overlap of traditional, modern, and emerging environmental dilemmas, China has committed substantial resources to environmental improvement. The country has the opportunity to address its national environmental health challenges and to assume a central role in the international effort to improve the global environment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junfeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Medicine and Dentistry of New Jersey, School of Public Health, Piscataway, NJ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mauzerall</LastName>
            <ForeName>Denise L</ForeName>
            <Initials>DL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tong</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Song</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ezzati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Majid</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Remais</LastName>
            <ForeName>Justin V</ForeName>
            <Initials>JV</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>K01 AI091864</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P30 ES005022</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ES</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P30ES 05022</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ES</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AI068854</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AI050038</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000397" MajorTopicYN="Y">Air Pollution</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057231" MajorTopicYN="N">Climate Change</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004782" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environmental Health</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D052918" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Restoration and Remediation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017752" MajorTopicYN="N">Greenhouse Effect</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011640" MajorTopicYN="Y">Public Policy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Pollution</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest statement</b>. We declare that we have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20346817</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS636903</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4210128</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(10)60062-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(10)60062-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Bank. From poor areas to poor people: China’s evolving poverty reduction agenda. Washington, DC: World Bank; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prüss-Ustün A, Corvalán C.  Preventing disease through healthy environments. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>HEI. Health Effects of Outdoor Air Pollution in Developing Countries of Asia. Boston, MA: Health Effects Institute; 2004.  Report No.: Special Report 15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MEP. Bulletin of China's Environmental Conditions. Beijing: Ministry of Environmental Protection; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO. China country profile. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2009. Quantification of the disease burden attributable to environmental risk factors.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez A, Mathers C, Ezzati M, Murray C, Jamison D.  Global burden of disease and risk factors. New York: Oxford University Press; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang S, Meng Q, Chen L, Bekedam H, Evans T, Whitehead M. Tackling the challenges to health equity in China. Lancet. 2008 Oct 25;372(9648):1493–1501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18930531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Smith KR. Household air pollution from coal and biomass fuels in china: measurements, health impacts, and interventions. Environ Health Perspect. 2007 Jun;115(6):848–855.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1892127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17589590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NBSC. China Statistical Yearbook. Beijing: National Bureau of Statistics of China; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MoH. 2007 Health Yearbook. Beijing: Ministry of Health; 2007. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang XY, Tao FB, Xiao DL, Lee H, Deen J, Gong J, et al.  Trend and disease burden of bacillary dysentery in China (1991–2000) Bulletin of the World Health Organization. 2006 Jul;84(7):561–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2627389</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16878230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X, Mauzerall DL. Evaluating Impacts of Air Pollution in China on Public Health: Implications for Future Air Pollution and Energy Policies. Atmospheric Environment. 2006;40(9):1706–1721.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pope CA, III, Burnett RT, Thun MJ, Calle EE, Krewski D, Ito K, et al.  Lung Cancer, Cardiopulmonary Mortality and Long-Term Exposure to Fine Particulate Air Pollution. J Amer Med Assoc. 2002;287(9):1132–1141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4037163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11879110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dockery DW, Pope CA, III, Xu X, Spengler JD, Ware JH, Fay ME, et al.  An association between air pollution and mortality in six U.S. cities. The New England Journal of Medicine. 1993;329(24):1753–1759.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8179653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO-UNDP. Environment and People's Health in China. Geneva: WHO; 2001. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NAS. Toxicological Effects of Methylmercury. Washington D.C: National Academy of Sciences, The National Academies Press; 2000. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Mauzerall DL, Horowitz LW. Evaluating Inter-continental transport of fine aerosols : (2) Global Health Impacts. Atmospheric Environment. 2009b</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saikawa E, Naik V, Horowitz LW, Liu JF, Mauzerall DL. Present and potential future contributions of sulfate, black and organic carbon aerosols from China to global air quality, premature mortality and, radiative forcing. Atmospheric Environment. 2009 Jun;43(17):2814–2822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou XN, Yang GJ, Yang K, Wang XH, Hong QB, Sun LP, et al.  Potential impact of climate change on schistosomiasis transmission in China. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2008 Feb;78(2):188–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell-Lendrum D, Corvalan C. Climate change and developing-country cities: implications for environmental health and equity. J Urban Health. 2007 May;84(3 Suppl):i109–i117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1891643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17393341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IPCC. Geneva, Switzerland: 2008. Climate Change 2007: Synthesis Report. Contribution of Working Groups I, II and III to the Fourth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S, Zhou Y, Wang X, Wang D, Lu J, Zheng J, et al.  Biomass fuels are the probable risk factor for chronic obstructive pulmonary disease in rural South China. Thorax. 2007 Oct;62(10):889–897.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2094241</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17483137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhuang P, Zou B, Li NY, Li ZA. Heavy metal contamination in soils and food crops around Dabaoshan mine in Guangdong, China: implication for human health. Environ Geochem Health. 2009 Feb 13;</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19214759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bao QS, Lu CY, Song H, Wang M, Ling W, Chen WQ, et al.  Behavioural development of school-aged children who live around a multi-metal sulphide mine in Guangdong province, China: a cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2009;9:217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2717083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19573251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu X, Cook S, Salazar MA. Internal migration and health in China. Lancet. 2008 Nov 15;372(9651):1717–1719.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18930533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jia ZW, Jia XW, Liu YX, Dye C, Chen F, Chen CS, et al.  Spatial analysis of tuberculosis cases in migrants and permanent residents, Beijing, 2000–2006. Emerg Infect Dis. 2008 Sep;14(9):1413–1419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2603090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18760008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shao M, Tang XY, Zhang YH, Li WJ. Air and surface water pollution of city clusters in China: current situation and challenges. Frontiers in Ecology and the Environment. 2006;7(4):353–361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parrish DD, Zhu T. Climate change. Clean air for megacities. Science. 2009 Oct 30;326(5953):674–675.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19900921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang XP, Mauzerall DL. Characterizing distributions of surface ozone and its impact on grain production in China, Japan and South Korea: 1990 and 2020. Atmospheric Environment. 2004 Aug;38(26):4383–4402.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacyna EG, Pacyna JM, Steenhuisen F, Wilson S. Global anthropogenic mercury emission inventory for 2000. Atmospheric Environment. 2006;40(22):4048–4063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDIAC. Carbon Dioxide Information Analysis Center.  [cited 2009 August 10];2009  Available from:  http://cdiac.ornl.gov/trends/emis/tre_prc.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West JJ, Fiore AM, Horowitz LW, Mauzerall DL. Global health benefits of mitigating ozone pollution with methane emission controls. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006 Mar 14;103(11):3988–3993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1449633</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16537473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bond TC, Streets DG, Yarber KF, Nelson SM, Woo JH, Klimont Z. A technology-based global inventory of black and organic carbon emissions from combustion. Journal of Geophysical Research-Atmospheres. 2004 Jul 24;109(D14) -.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie J, Liebenthal A, Warford JJ, Dixon JA, Wang M, Gao S, et al.   Addressing China's water scarcity: recommendations for selected water resource management issues. Washington DC: World Bank; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu KS, Huo X, Zhu GH. Relationships between esophageal cancer and spatial environment factors by using Geographic Information System. Sci Total Environ. 2008 Apr 15;393(2–3):219–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18243281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Bank. Cost of Pollution in China: Economic Estimates of Physical Damages. Washington, DC: World Bank; 2007. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang R, Li H-x, Wu X, Fan F, Sun B, Wang Z, et al.  Current situation analysis on China's rural drinking water quality. Journal of Environmental Health. 2009;26(1):3–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang S, Yang C, Zhong B, Qiu D. Re-emerging schistosomiasis in hilly and mountainous areas of Sichuan, China. Bull World Health Organ. 2006 Feb;84(2):139–144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2626530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16501732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AH. Hexavalent chromium, yellow water, and cancer: a convoluted saga. Epidemiology. 2008 Jan;19(1):24–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18091414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SEPA. State of the Environment Report. Beijing, China: State Environmental Protection Administration; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OECD. Environmental Performance Reviews: China. Beijing, China: Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development; 2007. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L. Investigation on drinking water safety in China in 2006. Journal of Environmental Health. 2007;24(8):595–597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gleick P.  The World's Water 2008–2009: The Biennial Report on Freshwater Resources. Washington D.C: Island Press; 2008. China and Water; p. 402.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chorus I, Bartram J, editors. Toxic cyanobacteria in water: a Guide to their public health consequences, monitoring and management. London: E&amp;FN Spon; 1999. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ezzati M, Singer B, Kammen D. Towards an integrated framework for development-environment policy: the dynamics of environmental Kuznets curves. World Development. 2001;29(8):1421–1434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gakidou E, Oza S, Vidal Fuertes C, Li AY, Lee DK, Sousa A, et al.  Improving child survival through environmental and nutritional interventions: the importance of targeting interventions toward the poor. Jama. 2007 Oct 24;298(16):1876–1887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17954539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health. National Environment and Health Action Plan (2007–2015) Beijing, China: 2007. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedley AJ, Wong CM, Thach TQ, Ma S, Lam TH, Anderson HR. Cardiorespiratory and all-cause mortality after restrictions on sulphur content of fuel in Hong Kong: an intervention study. Lancet. 2002 Nov 23;360(9346):1646–1652.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12457788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNEP. The Songhua River Spill, China, Field Mission Report. Paris, France: United Nations Environment Programme, Division of Technology, Industry and Economics; 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Zhu T, Zheng J, Zhang RY, Zhang SQ, Xie XX, et al.   Atmos Chem Phys. Use of a mobile laboratory to evaluate changes in on-road air pollutants during the Beijing 2008 Summer Olympics. in press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
