<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">20375353</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2010</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-6618</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2010</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical microbiology reviews</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Microbiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Molecular pathogenesis of infections caused by Legionella pneumophila.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>274</StartPage>
          <EndPage>298</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>274-98</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/CMR.00052-09</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The genus Legionella contains more than 50 species, of which at least 24 have been associated with human infection. The best-characterized member of the genus, Legionella pneumophila, is the major causative agent of Legionnaires' disease, a severe form of acute pneumonia. L. pneumophila is an intracellular pathogen, and as part of its pathogenesis, the bacteria avoid phagolysosome fusion and replicate within alveolar macrophages and epithelial cells in a vacuole that exhibits many characteristics of the endoplasmic reticulum (ER). The formation of the unusual L. pneumophila vacuole is a feature of its interaction with the host, yet the mechanisms by which the bacteria avoid classical endosome fusion and recruit markers of the ER are incompletely understood. Here we review the factors that contribute to the ability of L. pneumophila to infect and replicate in human cells and amoebae with an emphasis on proteins that are secreted by the bacteria into the Legionella vacuole and/or the host cell. Many of these factors undermine eukaryotic trafficking and signaling pathways by acting as functional and, in some cases, structural mimics of eukaryotic proteins. We discuss the consequences of this mimicry for the biology of the infected cell and also for immune responses to L. pneumophila infection.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Newton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hayley J</ForeName>
            <Initials>HJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Melbourne, Grattan Street, Parkville, Victoria 3010, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Desmond K Y</ForeName>
            <Initials>DK</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>van Driel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ian R</ForeName>
            <Initials>IR</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hartland</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elizabeth L</ForeName>
            <Initials>EL</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Microbiol Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8807282</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0893-8512</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016680" MajorTopicYN="N">Genome, Bacterial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016952" MajorTopicYN="N">Legionella pneumophila</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007877" MajorTopicYN="N">Legionnaires' Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20375353</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2863363</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00052-09</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">23/2/274</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abu Kwaik, Y. 1996. The phagosome containing Legionella pneumophila within the protozoan Hartmannella vermiformis is surrounded by the rough endoplasmic reticulum. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 62:2022-2028.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167980</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8787400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abu Kwaik, Y., L. Y. Gao, O. S. Harb, and B. J. Stone. 1997. Transcriptional regulation of the macrophage-induced gene (gspA) of Legionella pneumophila and phenotypic characterization of a null mutant. Mol. Microbiol. 24:629-642.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9179855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abu-Zant, A., S. Jones, R. Asare, J. Suttles, C. Price, J. Graham, and Y. A. Kwaik. 2007. Anti-apoptotic signalling by the Dot/Icm secretion system of L. pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 9:246-264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16911566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akhter, A., M. A. Gavrilin, L. Frantz, S. Washington, C. Ditty, D. Limoli, C. Day, A. Sarkar, C. Newland, J. Butchar, C. B. Marsh, M. D. Wewers, S. Tridandapani, T. D. Kanneganti, and A. O. Amer. 2009. Caspase-7 activation by the Nlrc4/Ipaf inflammasome restricts Legionella pneumophila infection. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19343209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khodor, S., S. Kalachikov, I. Morozova, C. T. Price, and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2009. The PmrA/PmrB two-component system of Legionella pneumophila is a global regulator required for intracellular replication within macrophages and protozoa. Infect. Immun. 77:374-386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612241</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18936184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khodor, S., C. T. Price, F. Habyarimana, A. Kalia, and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2008. A Dot/Icm-translocated ankyrin protein of Legionella pneumophila is required for intracellular proliferation within human macrophages and protozoa. Mol. Microbiol. 70:908-923.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18811729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allan, B. B., B. D. Moyer, and W. E. Balch. 2000. Rab1 recruitment of p115 into a cis-SNARE complex: programming budding COPII vesicles for fusion. Science 289:444-448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10903204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allard, K. A., J. Dao, P. Sanjeevaiah, K. McCoy-Simandle, C. H. Chatfield, D. S. Crumrine, D. Castignetti, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2009. Purification of legiobactin and importance of this siderophore in lung infection by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 77:2887-2895.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2708552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19398549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allard, K. A., V. K. Viswanathan, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2006. lbtA and lbtB are required for production of the Legionella pneumophila siderophore legiobactin. J. Bacteriol. 188:1351-1363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1367248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16452417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alli, O. A., L. Y. Gao, L. L. Pedersen, S. Zink, M. Radulic, M. Doric, and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2000. Temporal pore formation-mediated egress from macrophages and alveolar epithelial cells by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 68:6431-6440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97730</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11035756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altman, E., and G. Segal. 2008. The response regulator CpxR directly regulates expression of several Legionella pneumophila icm/dot components as well as new translocated substrates. J. Bacteriol. 190:1985-1996.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258895</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18192394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amer, A., L. Franchi, T. D. Kanneganti, M. Body-Malapel, N. Ozoren, G. Brady, S. Meshinchi, R. Jagirdar, A. Gewirtz, S. Akira, and G. Nunez. 2006. Regulation of Legionella phagosome maturation and infection through flagellin and host Ipaf. J. Biol. Chem. 281:35217-35223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16984919</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amer, A. O. 2010. Modulation of caspases and their non-apoptotic functions by Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 12:140-147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19863553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amer, A. O., and M. S. Swanson. 2005. Autophagy is an immediate macrophage response to Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 7:765-778.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1584279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15888080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anand, C. M., A. R. Skinner, A. Malic, and J. B. Kurtz. 1983. Interaction of L. pneumophilia and a free living amoeba (Acanthamoeba palestinensis). J. Hyg. (Lond.) 91:167-178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2129387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6358342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrews, H. L., J. P. Vogel, and R. R. Isberg. 1998. Identification of linked Legionella pneumophila genes essential for intracellular growth and evasion of the endocytic pathway. Infect. Immun. 66:950-958.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC108001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9488381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aragon, V., S. Kurtz, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2001. Legionella pneumophila major acid phosphatase and its role in intracellular infection. Infect. Immun. 69:177-185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11119504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aragon, V., S. Kurtz, A. Flieger, B. Neumeister, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2000. Secreted enzymatic activities of wild-type and pilD-deficient Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 68:1855-1863.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aragon, V., O. Rossier, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2002. Legionella pneumophila genes that encode lipase and phospholipase C activities. Microbiology 148:2223-2231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12101309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Archer, K. A., L. Alexopoulou, R. A. Flavell, and C. R. Roy. 2009. Multiple MyD88-dependent responses contribute to pulmonary clearance of Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 11:21-36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2752851</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18782351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Archer, K. A., and C. R. Roy. 2006. MyD88-dependent responses involving Toll-like receptor 2 are important for protection and clearance of Legionella pneumophila in a mouse model of Legionnaires' disease. Infect. Immun. 74:3325-3333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1479235</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16714560</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asare, R., and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2007. Early trafficking and intracellular replication of Legionella longbeachaea within an ER-derived late endosome-like phagosome. Cell. Microbiol. 9:1571-1587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17309675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aurell, H., J. Etienne, F. Forey, M. Reyrolle, P. Girardo, P. Farge, B. Decludt, C. Campese, F. Vandenesch, and S. Jarraud. 2003. Legionella pneumophila serogroup 1 strain Paris: endemic distribution throughout France. J. Clin. Microbiol. 41:3320-3322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12843082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachman, M. A., and M. S. Swanson. 2001. RpoS co-operates with other factors to induce Legionella pneumophila virulence in the stationary phase. Mol. Microbiol. 40:1201-1214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11401723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachman, M. A., and M. S. Swanson. 2004. The LetE protein enhances expression of multiple LetA/LetS-dependent transmission traits by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 72:3284-3293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC415668</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baine, W. B. 1985. Cytolytic and phospholipase C activity in Legionella species. J. Gen. Microbiol. 131:1383-1391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4045420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandyopadhyay, P., S. Liu, C. B. Gabbai, Z. Venitelli, and H. M. Steinman. 2007. Environmental mimics and the Lvh type IVA secretion system contribute to virulence-related phenotypes of Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 75:723-735.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1828514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17101653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerji, S., P. Aurass, and A. Flieger. 2008. The manifold phospholipases A of Legionella pneumophila—identification, export, regulation, and their link to bacterial virulence. Int. J. Med. Microbiol. 298:169-181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18178130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerji, S., M. Bewersdorff, B. Hermes, N. P. Cianciotto, and A. Flieger. 2005. Characterization of the major secreted zinc metalloprotease-dependent glycerophospholipid:cholesterol acyltransferase, PlaC, of Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 73:2899-2909.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1087370</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15845496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banga, S., P. Gao, X. Shen, V. Fiscus, W. X. Zong, L. Chen, and Z. Q. Luo. 2007. Legionella pneumophila inhibits macrophage apoptosis by targeting pro-death members of the Bcl2 protein family. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 104:5121-5126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1829273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17360363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barker, J., M. R. Brown, P. J. Collier, I. Farrell, and P. Gilbert. 1992. Relationship between Legionella pneumophila and Acanthamoeba polyphaga: physiological status and susceptibility to chemical inactivation. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 58:2420-2425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC195797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1514790</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartfeld, S., C. Engels, B. Bauer, P. Aurass, A. Flieger, H. Bruggemann, and T. F. Meyer. 2009. Temporal resolution of two-tracked NF-kappaB activation by Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 11:1638-1651.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19573161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baskerville, A., R. B. Fitzgeorge, M. Broster, P. Hambleton, and P. J. Dennis. 1981. Experimental transmission of Legionnaires' disease by exposure to aerosols of Legionella pneumophila. Lancet ii:1389-1390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6118761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beckers, M. C., S. Yoshida, K. Morgan, E. Skamene, and P. Gros. 1995. Natural resistance to infection with Legionella pneumophila: chromosomal localization of the Lgn1 susceptibility gene. Mamm. Genome 6:540-545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8589525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyi, Y., R. Niggeweg, B. Opitz, M. Vogelsgesang, S. Hippenstiel, M. Wilm, and K. Aktories. 2006. Legionella pneumophila glucosyltransferase inhibits host elongation factor 1A. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 103:16953-16958.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1636560</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17068130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyi, Y., M. Stahl, I. Sovkova, P. Kaden, B. Luy, and K. Aktories. 2009. Region of elongation factor 1A1 involved in substrate recognition by Legionella pneumophila glucosyltransferase LGT1—identification of LGT1 as a retaining glucosyltransferase. J. Biol. Chem. 284:20167-20174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2740443</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger, K. H., and R. R. Isberg. 1993. Two distinct defects in intracellular growth complemented by a single genetic locus in Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 7:7-19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8382332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger, K. H., J. J. Merriam, and R. R. Isberg. 1994. Altered intracellular targeting properties associated with mutations in the Legionella pneumophila dotA gene. Mol. Microbiol. 14:809-822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7891566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berk, S. G., G. Faulkner, E. Garduno, M. C. Joy, M. A. Ortiz-Jimenez, and R. A. Garduno. 2008. Packaging of live Legionella pneumophila into pellets expelled by Tetrahymena spp. does not require bacterial replication and depends on a Dot/Icm-mediated survival mechanism. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 74:2187-2199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2292602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18245233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berk, S. G., R. S. Ting, G. W. Turner, and R. J. Ashburn. 1998. Production of respirable vesicles containing live Legionella pneumophila cells by two Acanthamoeba spp. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 64:279-286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC124706</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9435080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhan, U., G. Trujillo, K. Lyn-Kew, M. W. Newstead, X. Zeng, C. M. Hogaboam, A. M. Krieg, and T. J. Standiford. 2008. Toll-like receptor 9 regulates the lung macrophage phenotype and host immunity in murine pneumonia caused by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 76:2895-2904.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2446723</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18426877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhardwaj, N., T. W. Nash, and M. A. Horwitz. 1986. Interferon-gamma-activated human monocytes inhibit the intracellular multiplication of Legionella pneumophila. J. Immunol. 137:2662-2669.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3093580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanchard, D. K., W. E. Stewart II, T. W. Klein, H. Friedman, and J. Y. Djeu. 1987. Cytolytic activity of human peripheral blood leukocytes against Legionella pneumophila-infected monocytes: characterization of the effector cell and augmentation by interleukin 2. J. Immunol. 139:551-556.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3496384</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blander, S. J., R. F. Breiman, and M. A. Horwitz. 1989. A live avirulent mutant Legionella pneumophila vaccine induces protective immunity against lethal aerosol challenge. J. Clin. Invest. 83:810-815.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC303752</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2646318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blander, S. J., and M. A. Horwitz. 1993. Major cytoplasmic membrane protein of Legionella pneumophila, a genus common antigen and member of the hsp 60 family of heat shock proteins, induces protective immunity in a guinea pig model of Legionnaires' disease. J. Clin. Invest. 91:717-723.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC288014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8432872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blander, S. J., and M. A. Horwitz. 1991. Vaccination with Legionella pneumophila membranes induces cell-mediated and protective immunity in a guinea pig model of Legionnaires' disease. Protective immunity independent of the major secretory protein of Legionella pneumophila. J. Clin. Invest. 87:1054-1059.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC329900</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1999485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blander, S. J., and M. A. Horwitz. 1991. Vaccination with the major secretory protein of Legionella induces humoral and cell-mediated immune responses and protective immunity across different serogroups of Legionella pneumophila and different species of Legionella. J. Immunol. 147:285-291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1711078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blander, S. J., and M. A. Horwitz. 1989. Vaccination with the major secretory protein of Legionella pneumophila induces cell-mediated and protective immunity in a guinea pig model of Legionnaires' disease. J. Exp. Med. 169:691-705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2189286</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2926324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bozue, J. A., and W. Johnson. 1996. Interaction of Legionella pneumophila with Acanthamoeba castellanii: uptake by coiling phagocytosis and inhibition of phagosome-lysosome fusion. Infect. Immun. 64:668-673.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173819</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8550225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brand, B. C., A. B. Sadosky, and H. A. Shuman. 1994. The Legionella pneumophila icm locus: a set of genes required for intracellular multiplication in human macrophages. Mol. Microbiol. 14:797-808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7891565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brassinga, A. K., M. F. Hiltz, G. R. Sisson, M. G. Morash, N. Hill, E. Garduno, P. H. Edelstein, R. A. Garduno, and P. S. Hoffman. 2003. A 65-kilobase pathogenicity island is unique to Philadelphia-1 strains of Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 185:4630-4637.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC165780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12867476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brassinga, A. K., J. M. Kinchen, M. E. Cupp, S. R. Day, P. S. Hoffman, and C. D. Sifri. 2010. Caenorhabditisis a metazoan host for Legionella. Cell. Microbiol. 12:343-361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120102</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19863556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner, D. J., A. G. Steigerwalt, and J. E. McDade. 1979. Classification of the Legionnaires' disease bacterium: Legionella pneumophila, genus novum, species nova, of the family Legionellaceae, familia nova. Ann. Intern. Med. 90:656-658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">434652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brieland, J., P. Freeman, R. Kunkel, C. Chrisp, M. Hurley, J. Fantone, and C. Engleberg. 1994. Replicative Legionella pneumophila lung infection in intratracheally inoculated A/J mice. A murine model of human Legionnaires' disease. Am. J. Pathol. 145:1537-1546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1887509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7992856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brieland, J. K., C. Jackson, S. Hurst, D. Loebenberg, T. Muchamuel, R. Debets, R. Kastelein, T. Churakova, J. Abrams, R. Hare, and A. O'Garra. 2000. Immunomodulatory role of endogenous interleukin-18 in gamma interferon-mediated resolution of replicative Legionella pneumophila lung infection. Infect. Immun. 68:6567-6573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97751</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11083766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brieland, J. K., D. G. Remick, P. T. Freeman, M. C. Hurley, J. C. Fantone, and N. C. Engleberg. 1995. In vivo regulation of replicative Legionella pneumophila lung infection by endogenous tumor necrosis factor alpha and nitric oxide. Infect. Immun. 63:3253-3258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173448</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7642253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brieland, J. K., D. G. Remick, M. L. LeGendre, N. C. Engleberg, and J. C. Fantone. 1998. In vivo regulation of replicative Legionella pneumophila lung infection by endogenous interleukin-12. Infect. Immun. 66:65-69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC107859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9423840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brombacher, E., S. Urwyler, C. Ragaz, S. S. Weber, K. Kami, M. Overduin, and H. Hilbi. 2009. Rab1 guanine nucleotide exchange factor SidM is a major phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate-binding effector protein of Legionella pneumophila. J. Biol. Chem. 284:4846-4856.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2643517</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19095644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruggemann, H., A. Hagman, M. Jules, O. Sismeiro, M. A. Dillies, C. Gouyette, F. Kunst, M. Steinert, K. Heuner, J. Y. Coppee, and C. Buchrieser. 2006. Virulence strategies for infecting phagocytes deduced from the in vivo transcriptional program of Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 8:1228-1240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16882028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brumell, J. H., and M. A. Scidmore. 2007. Manipulation of rab GTPase function by intracellular bacterial pathogens. Microbiol. Mol. Biol. Rev. 71:636-652.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2168649</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18063721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burstein, D., T. Zusman, E. Degtyar, R. Viner, G. Segal, and T. Pupko. 2009. Genome-scale identification of Legionella pneumophila effectors using a machine learning approach. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19593377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byrd, T. F., and M. A. Horwitz. 2000. Aberrantly low transferrin receptor expression on human monocytes is associated with nonpermissiveness for Legionella pneumophila growth. J. Infect. Dis. 181:1394-1400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10762570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byrne, B., and M. S. Swanson. 1998. Expression of Legionella pneumophila virulence traits in response to growth conditions. Infect. Immun. 66:3029-3034.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC108309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9632562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cambronne, E. D., and C. R. Roy. 2007. The Legionella pneumophila IcmSW complex interacts with multiple Dot/Icm effectors to facilitate type IV translocation. PLoS Pathog. 3:e188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2134951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18069892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campodonico, E. M., L. Chesnel, and C. R. Roy. 2005. A yeast genetic system for the identification and characterization of substrate proteins transferred into host cells by the Legionella pneumophila Dot/Icm system. Mol. Microbiol. 56:918-933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15853880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Case, C. L., S. Shin, and C. R. Roy. 2009. Asc and Ipaf inflammasomes direct distinct pathways for caspase-1 activation in response to Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 77:1981-1991.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2681768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19237518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cazalet, C., S. Jarraud, Y. Ghavi-Helm, F. Kunst, P. Glaser, J. Etienne, and C. Buchrieser. 2008. Multigenome analysis identifies a worldwide distributed epidemic Legionella pneumophila clone that emerged within a highly diverse species. Genome Res. 18:431-441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2259107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cazalet, C., C. Rusniok, H. Bruggemann, N. Zidane, A. Magnier, L. Ma, M. Tichit, S. Jarraud, C. Bouchier, F. Vandenesch, F. Kunst, J. Etienne, P. Glaser, and C. Buchrieser. 2004. Evidence in the Legionella pneumophila genome for exploitation of host cell functions and high genome plasticity. Nat. Genet. 36:1165-1173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15467720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang, H. R., L. H. Loo, B. G. Kuah, and B. H. Heng. 1995. Comparison of multiplex PCR and culture for detection of legionellae in cooling tower water samples. Southeast Asian J. Trop. Med. Public Health 26:258-262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8629056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charpentier, X., S. P. Faucher, S. Kalachikov, and H. A. Shuman. 2008. Loss of RNase R induces competence development in Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 190:8126-8136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2593228</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18849432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charpentier, X., J. E. Gabay, M. Reyes, J. W. Zhu, A. Weiss, and H. A. Shuman. 2009. Chemical genetics reveals bacterial and host cell functions critical for type IV effector translocation by Legionella pneumophila. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19578436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatfield, C. H., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2007. The secreted pyomelanin pigment of Legionella pneumophila confers ferric reductase activity. Infect. Immun. 75:4062-4070.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17548481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, D. E., S. Podell, J. D. Sauer, M. S. Swanson, and M. H. Saier, Jr. 2008. The phagosomal nutrient transporter (Pht) family. Microbiology 154:42-53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18174124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, J., K. S. de Felipe, M. Clarke, H. Lu, O. R. Anderson, G. Segal, and H. A. Shuman. 2004. Legionella effectors that promote nonlytic release from protozoa. Science 303:1358-1361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14988561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chien, M., I. Morozova, S. Shi, H. Sheng, J. Chen, S. M. Gomez, G. Asamani, K. Hill, J. Nuara, M. Feder, J. Rineer, J. J. Greenberg, V. Steshenko, S. H. Park, B. Zhao, E. Teplitskaya, J. R. Edwards, S. Pampou, A. Georghiou, I. C. Chou, W. Iannuccilli, M. E. Ulz, D. H. Kim, A. Geringer-Sameth, C. Goldsberry, P. Morozov, S. G. Fischer, G. Segal, X. Qu, A. Rzhetsky, P. Zhang, E. Cayanis, P. J. De Jong, J. Ju, S. Kalachikov, H. A. Shuman, and J. J. Russo. 2004. The genomic sequence of the accidental pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Science 305:1966-1968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiu, Y. H., J. B. Macmillan, and Z. J. Chen. 2009. RNA polymerase III detects cytosolic DNA and induces type I interferons through the RIG-I pathway. Cell 138:576-591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2747301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chong, A., C. A. Lima, D. S. Allan, G. K. Nasrallah, and R. A. Garduno. 2009. The purified and recombinant Legionella pneumophila chaperonin alters mitochondrial trafficking and microfilament organization. Infect. Immun. 77:4724-4739.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772529</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19687203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, P. J., and J. P. Vogel. 2000. Bacterial type IV secretion: conjugation systems adapted to deliver effector molecules to host cells. Trends Microbiol. 8:354-360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4847720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10920394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cianciotto, N. P. 2007. Iron acquisition by Legionella pneumophila. Biometals 20:323-331.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17180462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cianciotto, N. P. 2005. Type II secretion: a protein secretion system for all seasons. Trends Microbiol. 13:581-588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16216510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cianciotto, N. P., J. M. Bangsborg, B. I. Eisenstein, and N. C. Engleberg. 1990. Identification of mip-like genes in the genus Legionella. Infect. Immun. 58:2912-2918.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC313586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2387627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cianciotto, N. P., B. I. Eisenstein, C. H. Mody, G. B. Toews, and N. C. Engleberg. 1989. A Legionella pneumophila gene encoding a species-specific surface protein potentiates initiation of intracellular infection. Infect. Immun. 57:1255-1262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC313258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2925251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cianciotto, N. P., and B. S. Fields. 1992. Legionella pneumophila mip gene potentiates intracellular infection of protozoa and human macrophages. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 89:5188-5191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC49255</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1594630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cirillo, J. D., S. L. Cirillo, L. Yan, L. E. Bermudez, S. Falkow, and L. S. Tompkins. 1999. Intracellular growth in Acanthamoeba castellanii affects monocyte entry mechanisms and enhances virulence of Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 67:4427-4434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC96761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10456883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cirillo, J. D., S. Falkow, and L. S. Tompkins. 1994. Growth of Legionella pneumophila in Acanthamoeba castellanii enhances invasion. Infect. Immun. 62:3254-3261.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC302953</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8039895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cirillo, S. L., L. E. Bermudez, S. H. El-Etr, G. E. Duhamel, and J. D. Cirillo. 2001. Legionella pneumophila entry gene rtxA is involved in virulence. Infect. Immun. 69:508-517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97910</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11119544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cirillo, S. L., J. Lum, and J. D. Cirillo. 2000. Identification of novel loci involved in entry by Legionella pneumophila. Microbiology 146(Pt. 6):1345-1359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10846213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clemens, D. L., B. Y. Lee, and M. A. Horwitz. 2000. Deviant expression of Rab5 on phagosomes containing the intracellular pathogens Mycobacterium tuberculosis and Legionella pneumophila is associated with altered phagosomal fate. Infect. Immun. 68:2671-2684.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clemens, D. L., B. Y. Lee, and M. A. Horwitz. 2000. Mycobacterium tuberculosis and Legionella pneumophila phagosomes exhibit arrested maturation despite acquisition of Rab7. Infect. Immun. 68:5154-5166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101766</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10948139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coers, J., R. E. Vance, M. F. Fontana, and W. F. Dietrich. 2007. Restriction of Legionella pneumophila growth in macrophages requires the concerted action of cytokine and Naip5/Ipaf signalling pathways. Cell. Microbiol. 9:2344-2357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17506816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cole, S. T., R. Brosch, J. Parkhill, T. Garnier, C. Churcher, D. Harris, S. V. Gordon, K. Eiglmeier, S. Gas, C. E. Barry III, F. Tekaia, K. Badcock, D. Basham, D. Brown, T. Chillingworth, R. Connor, R. Davies, K. Devlin, T. Feltwell, S. Gentles, N. Hamlin, S. Holroyd, T. Hornsby, K. Jagels, A. Krogh, J. McLean, S. Moule, L. Murphy, K. Oliver, J. Osborne, M. A. Quail, M. A. Rajandream, J. Rogers, S. Rutter, K. Seeger, J. Skelton, R. Squares, S. Squares, J. E. Sulston, K. Taylor, S. Whitehead, and B. G. Barrell. 1998. Deciphering the biology of Mycobacterium tuberculosis from the complete genome sequence. Nature 393:537-544.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9634230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conover, G. M., I. Derre, J. P. Vogel, and R. R. Isberg. 2003. The Legionella pneumophila LidA protein: a translocated substrate of the Dot/Icm system associated with maintenance of bacterial integrity. Mol. Microbiol. 48:305-321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalebroux, Z. D., R. L. Edwards, and M. S. Swanson. 2009. SpoT governs Legionella pneumophila differentiation in host macrophages. Mol. Microbiol. 71:640-658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19040633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debroy, S., V. Aragon, S. Kurtz, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2006. Legionella pneumophila Mip, a surface-exposed peptidylproline cis-trans-isomerase, promotes the presence of phospholipase C-like activity in culture supernatants. Infect. Immun. 74:5152-5160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1594821</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DebRoy, S., J. Dao, M. Soderberg, O. Rossier, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2006. Legionella pneumophila type II secretome reveals unique exoproteins and a chitinase that promotes bacterial persistence in the lung. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 103:19146-19151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1748190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17148602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Buck, E., D. Hoper, E. Lammertyn, M. Hecker, and J. Anne. 2008. Differential 2-D protein gel electrophoresis analysis of Legionella pneumophila wild type and Tat secretion mutants. Int. J. Med. Microbiol. 298:449-461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17723319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Buck, E., I. Lebeau, L. Maes, N. Geukens, E. Meyen, L. Van Mellaert, J. Anne, and E. Lammertyn. 2004. A putative twin-arginine translocation pathway in Legionella pneumophila. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 317:654-661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15063808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Buck, E., L. Maes, E. Meyen, L. Van Mellaert, N. Geukens, J. Anne, and E. Lammertyn. 2005. Legionella pneumophila Philadelphia-1 tatB and tatC affect intracellular replication and biofilm formation. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 331:1413-1420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Felipe, K. S., R. T. Glover, X. Charpentier, O. R. Anderson, M. Reyes, C. D. Pericone, and H. A. Shuman. 2008. Legionella eukaryotic-like type IV substrates interfere with organelle trafficking. PLoS Pathog. 4:e1000117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2475511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18670632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Degtyar, E., T. Zusman, M. Ehrlich, and G. Segal. 2009. A Legionella effector acquired from protozoa is involved in sphingolipids metabolism and is targeted to the host cell mitochondria. Cell. Microbiol. 11:1219-1235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19438520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng, J. C., K. Tateda, X. Zeng, and T. J. Standiford. 2001. Transient transgenic expression of gamma interferon promotes Legionella pneumophila clearance in immunocompetent hosts. Infect. Immun. 69:6382-6390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98773</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11553582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derre, I., and R. R. Isberg. 2004. Legionella pneumophila replication vacuole formation involves rapid recruitment of proteins of the early secretory system. Infect. Immun. 72:3048-3053.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derre, I., and R. R. Isberg. 2005. LidA, a translocated substrate of the Legionella pneumophila type IV secretion system, interferes with the early secretory pathway. Infect. Immun. 73:4370-4380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1168608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15972532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dietrich, W. F., D. M. Damron, R. R. Isberg, E. S. Lander, and M. S. Swanson. 1995. Lgn1, a gene that determines susceptibility to Legionella pneumophila, maps to mouse chromosome 13. Genomics 26:443-450.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7607666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diez, E., S. H. Lee, S. Gauthier, Z. Yaraghi, M. Tremblay, S. Vidal, and P. Gros. 2003. Birc1e is the gene within the Lgn1 locus associated with resistance to Legionella pneumophila. Nat. Genet. 33:55-60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12483212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doleans, A., H. Aurell, M. Reyrolle, G. Lina, J. Freney, F. Vandenesch, J. Etienne, and S. Jarraud. 2004. Clinical and environmental distributions of Legionella strains in France are different. J. Clin. Microbiol. 42:458-460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321724</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doleans-Jordheim, A., M. Akermi, C. Ginevra, C. Cazalet, E. Kay, D. Schneider, C. Buchrieser, D. Atlan, F. Vandenesch, J. Etienne, and S. Jarraud. 2006. Growth-phase-dependent mobility of the lvh-encoding region in Legionella pneumophila strain Paris. Microbiology 152:3561-3568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17159208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorer, M. S., D. Kirton, J. S. Bader, and R. R. Isberg. 2006. RNA interference analysis of Legionella in Drosophila cells: exploitation of early secretory apparatus dynamics. PLoS Pathog. 2:e34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1447669</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16652170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorn, B. R., W. A. Dunn, Jr., and A. Progulske-Fox. 2002. Bacterial interactions with the autophagic pathway. Cell. Microbiol. 4:1-10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11856168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doyle, R. M., N. P. Cianciotto, S. Banvi, P. A. Manning, and M. W. Heuzenroeder. 2001. Comparison of virulence of Legionella longbeachae strains in guinea pigs and U937 macrophage-like cells. Infect. Immun. 69:5335-5344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11500403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doyle, R. M., and M. W. Heuzenroeder. 2002. A mutation in an ompR-like gene on a Legionella longbeachae serogroup 1 plasmid attenuates virulence. Int. J. Med. Microbiol. 292:227-239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12398213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreyfus, L. A. 1987. Virulence associated ingestion of Legionella pneumophila by HeLa cells. Microb. Pathog. 3:45-52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3504217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dumenil, G., T. P. Montminy, M. Tang, and R. R. Isberg. 2004. IcmR-regulated membrane insertion and efflux by the Legionella pneumophila IcmQ protein. J. Biol. Chem. 279:4686-4695.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14625271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn, W. A., Jr. 1990. Studies on the mechanisms of autophagy: formation of the autophagic vacuole. J. Cell Biol. 110:1923-1933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2116114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2351689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards, M. T., N. K. Fry, and T. G. Harrison. 2008. Clonal population structure of Legionella pneumophila inferred from allelic profiling. Microbiology 154:852-864.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18310031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisen, D. P., J. Stubbs, D. Spilsbury, J. Carnie, J. Leydon, and B. P. Howden. 2007. Low mannose-binding lectin complement activation function is associated with predisposition to Legionnaires' disease. Clin. Exp. Immunol. 149:97-102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1942031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17425652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Endeman, H., B. L. Herpers, B. A. de Jong, G. P. Voorn, J. C. Grutters, H. van Velzen-Blad, and D. H. Biesma. 2008. Mannose-binding lectin genotypes in susceptibility to community-acquired pneumonia. Chest 134:1135-1140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18641104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engleberg, N. C., C. Carter, D. R. Weber, N. P. Cianciotto, and B. I. Eisenstein. 1989. DNA sequence of mip, a Legionella pneumophila gene associated with macrophage infectivity. Infect. Immun. 57:1263-1270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC313259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2925252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faulkner, G., S. G. Berk, E. Garduno, M. A. Ortiz-Jimenez, and R. A. Garduno. 2008. Passage through Tetrahymena tropicalis triggers a rapid morphological differentiation in Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 190:7728-7738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2583602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18805971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faulkner, G., and R. A. Garduno. 2002. Ultrastructural analysis of differentiation in Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 184:7025-7041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC135455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12446652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feeley, J. C., R. J. Gibson, G. W. Gorman, N. C. Langford, J. K. Rasheed, D. C. Mackel, and W. B. Baine. 1979. Charcoal-yeast extract agar: primary isolation medium for Legionella pneumophila. J. Clin. Microbiol. 10:437-441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC273193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">393713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman, C. 2005. Pneumonia associated with HIV infection. Curr. Opin. Infect. Dis. 18:165-170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fischer, G., H. Bang, B. Ludwig, K. Mann, and J. Hacker. 1992. Mip protein of Legionella pneumophila exhibits peptidyl-prolyl-cis/trans isomerase (PPlase) activity. Mol. Microbiol. 6:1375-1383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1379319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fitzgeorge, R. B., A. Baskerville, M. Broster, P. Hambleton, and P. J. Dennis. 1983. Aerosol infection of animals with strains of Legionella pneumophila of different virulence: comparison with intraperitoneal and intranasal routes of infection. J. Hyg. (Lond.) 90:81-89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2134197</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6401778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flieger, A., S. Gong, M. Faigle, H. Northoff, and B. Neumeister. 2001. In vitro secretion kinetics of proteins from Legionella pneumophila in comparison to proteins from non-pneumophila species. Microbiology 147:3127-3134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11700363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flieger, A., B. Neumeister, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2002. Characterization of the gene encoding the major secreted lysophospholipase A of Legionella pneumophila and its role in detoxification of lysophosphatidylcholine. Infect. Immun. 70:6094-6106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12379686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flieger, A., K. Rydzewski, S. Banerji, M. Broich, and K. Heuner. 2004. Cloning and characterization of the gene encoding the major cell-associated phospholipase A of Legionella pneumophila, plaB, exhibiting hemolytic activity. Infect. Immun. 72:2648-2658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387885</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fliermans, C. B., W. B. Cherry, L. H. Orrison, S. J. Smith, D. L. Tison, and D. H. Pope. 1981. Ecological distribution of Legionella pneumophila. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 41:9-16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC243633</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7013702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox, J. W., and S. M. Serrano. 2005. Structural considerations of the snake venom metalloproteinases, key members of the M12 reprolysin family of metalloproteinases. Toxicon 45:969-985.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15922769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraser, D. W., D. C. Deubner, D. L. Hill, and D. K. Gilliam. 1979. Nonpneumonic, short-incubation-period legionellosis (Pontiac fever) in men who cleaned a steam turbine condenser. Science 205:690-691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">462175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraser, D. W., T. R. Tsai, W. Orenstein, W. E. Parkin, H. J. Beecham, R. G. Sharrar, J. Harris, G. F. Mallison, S. M. Martin, J. E. McDade, C. C. Shepard, and P. S. Brachman. 1977. Legionnaires' disease: description of an epidemic of pneumonia. N. Engl. J. Med. 297:1189-1197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">335244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedman, H., C. Newton, D. K. Blanchard, T. W. Klein, R. Widen, and K. H. Wong. 1987. Immunogenicity and adjuvanticity of lipopolysaccharide from Legionella pneumophila. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med. 184:191-196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3809173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujita, M., S. Ikegame, E. Harada, H. Ouchi, I. Inoshima, K. Watanabe, S. Yoshida, and Y. Nakanishi. 2008. TNF receptor 1 and 2 contribute in different ways to resistance to Legionella pneumophila-induced mortality in mice. Cytokine 44:298-303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18838275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galka, F., S. N. Wai, H. Kusch, S. Engelmann, M. Hecker, B. Schmeck, S. Hippenstiel, B. E. Uhlin, and M. Steinert. 2008. Proteomic characterization of the whole secretome of Legionella pneumophila and functional analysis of outer membrane vesicles. Infect. Immun. 76:1825-1836.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2346698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18250176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gal-Mor, O., and G. Segal. 2003. Identification of CpxR as a positive regulator of icm and dot virulence genes of Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 185:4908-4919.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC166489</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12897011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gal-Mor, O., and G. Segal. 2003. The Legionella pneumophila GacA homolog (LetA) is involved in the regulation of icm virulence genes and is required for intracellular multiplication in Acanthamoeba castellanii. Microb. Pathog. 34:187-194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12668142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, L. Y., and Y. Abu Kwaik. 1999. Activation of caspase 3 during Legionella pneumophila-induced apoptosis. Infect. Immun. 67:4886-4894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC96823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10456945</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, L. Y., M. Susa, B. Ticac, and Y. Abu Kwaik. 1999. Heterogeneity in intracellular replication and cytopathogenicity of Legionella pneumophila and Legionella micdadei in mammalian and protozoan cells. Microb. Pathog. 27:273-287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10545255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garduno, R. A., E. Garduno, M. Hiltz, and P. S. Hoffman. 2002. Intracellular growth of Legionella pneumophila gives rise to a differentiated form dissimilar to stationary-phase forms. Infect. Immun. 70:6273-6283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130304</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12379706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garduno, R. A., E. Garduno, and P. S. Hoffman. 1998. Surface-associated hsp60 chaperonin of Legionella pneumophila mediates invasion in a HeLa cell model. Infect. Immun. 66:4602-4610.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC108567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9746556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garin, J., R. Diez, S. Kieffer, J. F. Dermine, S. Duclos, E. Gagnon, R. Sadoul, C. Rondeau, and M. Desjardins. 2001. The phagosome proteome: insight into phagosome functions. J. Cell Biol. 152:165-180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11149929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge, J., H. Xu, T. Li, Y. Zhou, Z. Zhang, S. Li, L. Liu, and F. Shao. 2009. A Legionella type IV effector activates the NF-kappaB pathway by phosphorylating the IkappaB family of inhibitors. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 106:13725-13730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728961</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19666608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gebran, S. J., C. Newton, Y. Yamamoto, R. Widen, T. W. Klein, and H. Friedman. 1994. Macrophage permissiveness for Legionella pneumophila growth modulated by iron. Infect. Immun. 62:564-568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC186142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8300214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>George, J. R., L. Pine, M. W. Reeves, and W. K. Harrell. 1980. Amino acid requirements of Legionella pneumophila. J. Clin. Microbiol. 11:286-291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC273381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6769947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerhardt, H., M. J. Walz, M. Faigle, H. Northoff, H. Wolburg, and B. Neumeister. 2000. Localization of Legionella bacteria within ribosome-studded phagosomes is not restricted to Legionella pneumophila. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 192:145-152.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11040443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson, F. C., III, A. O. Tzianabos, and F. G. Rodgers. 1994. Adherence of Legionella pneumophila to U-937 cells, guinea-pig alveolar macrophages, and MRC-5 cells by a novel, complement-independent binding mechanism. Can. J. Microbiol. 40:865-872.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8000965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glockner, G., C. Albert-Weissenberger, E. Weinmann, S. Jacobi, E. Schunder, M. Steinert, J. Hacker, and K. Heuner. 2008. Identification and characterization of a new conjugation/type IVA secretion system (trb/tra) of Legionella pneumophila Corby localized on two mobile genomic islands. Int. J. Med. Microbiol. 298:411-428.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17888731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gobin, I., M. Susa, G. Begic, E. L. Hartland, and M. Doric. 2009. Experimental Legionella longbeachae infection in intratracheally inoculated mice. J. Med. Microbiol. 58:723-730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19429747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goebl, M., and M. Yanagida. 1991. The TPR snap helix: a novel protein repeat motif from mitosis to transcription. Trends Biochem. Sci. 16:173-177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1882418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez-Valero, L., C. Rusniok, and C. Buchrieser. 2009. Legionella pneumophila: population genetics, phylogeny and genomics. Infect. Genet. Evol. 9:727-739.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19450709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Growney, J. D., and W. F. Dietrich. 2000. High-resolution genetic and physical map of the Lgn1 interval in C57BL/6J implicates Naip2 or Naip5 in Legionella pneumophila pathogenesis. Genome Res. 10:1158-1171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC310929</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hacker, J., and G. Fischer. 1993. Immunophilins: structure-function relationship and possible role in microbial pathogenicity. Mol. Microbiol. 10:445-456.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7526121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hales, L. M., and H. A. Shuman. 1999. Legionella pneumophila contains a type II general secretion pathway required for growth in amoebae as well as for secretion of the Msp protease. Infect. Immun. 67:3662-3666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC116561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10377156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hales, L. M., and H. A. Shuman. 1999. The Legionella pneumophila rpoS gene is required for growth within Acanthamoeba castellanii. J. Bacteriol. 181:4879-4889.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10438758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer, B. K., and M. S. Swanson. 1999. Co-ordination of Legionella pneumophila virulence with entry into stationary phase by ppGpp. Mol. Microbiol. 33:721-731.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10447882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer, B. K., E. S. Tateda, and M. S. Swanson. 2002. A two-component regulator induces the transmission phenotype of stationary-phase Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 44:107-118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11967072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawn, T. R., W. R. Berrington, I. A. Smith, S. Uematsu, S. Akira, A. Aderem, K. D. Smith, and S. J. Skerrett. 2007. Altered inflammatory responses in TLR5-deficient mice infected with Legionella pneumophila. J. Immunol. 179:6981-6987.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17982089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawn, T. R., K. D. Smith, A. Aderem, and S. J. Skerrett. 2006. Myeloid differentiation primary response gene (88)- and Toll-like receptor 2-deficient mice are susceptible to infection with aerosolized Legionella pneumophila. J. Infect. Dis. 193:1693-1702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16703513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawn, T. R., A. Verbon, M. Janer, L. P. Zhao, B. Beutler, and A. Aderem. 2005. Toll-like receptor 4 polymorphisms are associated with resistance to Legionnaires' disease. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 102:2487-2489.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC549026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawn, T. R., A. Verbon, K. D. Lettinga, L. P. Zhao, S. S. Li, R. J. Laws, S. J. Skerrett, B. Beutler, L. Schroeder, A. Nachman, A. Ozinsky, K. D. Smith, and A. Aderem. 2003. A common dominant TLR5 stop codon polymorphism abolishes flagellin signaling and is associated with susceptibility to Legionnaires' disease. J. Exp. Med. 198:1563-1572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2194120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14623910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hay, J. C., D. S. Chao, C. S. Kuo, and R. H. Scheller. 1997. Protein interactions regulating vesicle transport between the endoplasmic reticulum and Golgi apparatus in mammalian cells. Cell 89:149-158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9094723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hebert, G. A., C. W. Moss, L. K. McDougal, F. M. Bozeman, R. M. McKinney, and D. J. Brenner. 1980. The rickettsia-like organisms TATLOCK (1943) and HEBA (1959): bacteria phenotypically similar to but genetically distinct from Legionella pneumophila and the WIGA bacterium. Ann. Intern. Med. 92:45-52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6985783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedlund, K. W., V. G. McGann, D. S. Copeland, S. F. Little, and R. G. Allen. 1979. Immunologic protection against the Legionnaires' disease bacterium in the AKR/J. mouse. Ann. Intern. Med. 90:676-679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">434655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heidtman, M., E. J. Chen, M. Y. Moy, and R. R. Isberg. 2009. Large-scale identification of Legionella pneumophila Dot/Icm substrates that modulate host cell vesicle trafficking pathways. Cell. Microbiol. 11:230-248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2744955</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19016775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herpers, B. L., E. P. Yzerman, B. A. de Jong, J. P. Bruin, K. D. Lettinga, S. Kuipers, J. W. Den Boer, E. J. van Hannen, G. T. Rijkers, H. van Velzen-Blad, and B. M. de Jongh. 2009. Deficient mannose-binding lectin-mediated complement activation despite mannose-binding lectin-sufficient genotypes in an outbreak of Legionella pneumophila pneumonia. Hum. Immunol. 70:125-129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19073229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higa, F., J. Fujita, M. Koide, S. Haranaga, and M. Tateyama. 2008. Clinical features of two cases of Legionnaires' disease with persistence of Legionella urinary antigen excretion. Intern. Med. 47:173-178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18239328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilbi, H., G. Segal, and H. A. Shuman. 2001. icm/dot-dependent upregulation of phagocytosis by Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 42:603-617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11722729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch, C., R. Gauss, S. C. Horn, O. Neuber, and T. Sommer. 2009. The ubiquitylation machinery of the endoplasmic reticulum. Nature 458:453-460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horstmann, M., P. Ehses, K. Schweimer, M. Steinert, T. Kamphausen, G. Fischer, J. Hacker, P. Rosch, and C. Faber. 2006. Domain motions of the Mip protein from Legionella pneumophila. Biochemistry 45:12303-12311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17014083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz, M. A. 1983. Cell-mediated immunity in Legionnaires' disease. J. Clin. Invest. 71:1686-1697.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC370373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6345589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz, M. A. 1987. Characterization of avirulent mutant Legionella pneumophila that survive but do not multiply within human monocytes. J. Exp. Med. 166:1310-1328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2189638</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3681188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz, M. A. 1983. Formation of a novel phagosome by the Legionnaires' disease bacterium (Legionella pneumophila) in human monocytes. J. Exp. Med. 158:1319-1331.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2187375</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6619736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz, M. A. 1984. Phagocytosis of the Legionnaires' disease bacterium (Legionella pneumophila) occurs by a novel mechanism: engulfment within a pseudopod coil. Cell 36:27-33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6692469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz, M. A. 1983. The Legionnaires' disease bacterium (Legionella pneumophila) inhibits phagosome-lysosome fusion in human monocytes. J. Exp. Med. 158:2108-2126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2187157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6644240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz, M. A., and F. R. Maxfield. 1984. Legionella pneumophila inhibits acidification of its phagosome in human monocytes. J. Cell Biol. 99:1936-1943.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2113576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6501409</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husmann, L. K., and W. Johnson. 1994. Cytotoxicity of extracellular Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 62:2111-2114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC186476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8168978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huston, W. M., J. Naylor, N. P. Cianciotto, M. P. Jennings, and A. G. McEwan. 2008. Functional analysis of the multi-copper oxidase from Legionella pneumophila. Microbes Infect. 10:497-503.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18403241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingmundson, A., A. Delprato, D. G. Lambright, and C. R. Roy. 2007. Legionella pneumophila proteins that regulate Rab1 membrane cycling. Nature 450:365-369.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17952054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inohara, N., and G. Nunez. 2001. The NOD: a signaling module that regulates apoptosis and host defense against pathogens. Oncogene 20:6473-6481.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11607846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isberg, R. R., T. J. O'Connor, and M. Heidtman. 2009. The Legionella pneumophila replication vacuole: making a cosy niche inside host cells. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 7:13-24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2631402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ivanov, S. S., and C. R. Roy. 2009. Modulation of ubiquitin dynamics and suppression of DALIS formation by the Legionella pneumophila Dot/Icm system. Cell. Microbiol. 11:261-278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19016782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Izu, K., S. Yoshida, H. Miyamoto, B. Chang, M. Ogawa, H. Yamamoto, Y. Goto, and H. Taniguchi. 1999. Grouping of 20 reference strains of Legionella species by the growth ability within mouse and guinea pig macrophages. FEMS Immunol. Med. Microbiol. 26:61-68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10518043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobi, S., and K. Heuner. 2003. Description of a putative type I secretion system in Legionella pneumophila. Int. J. Med. Microbiol. 293:349-358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14695063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James, B. W., W. S. Mauchline, R. B. Fitzgeorge, P. J. Dennis, and C. W. Keevil. 1995. Influence of iron-limited continuous culture on physiology and virulence of Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 63:4224-4230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173600</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7591051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jepras, R. I., R. B. Fitzgeorge, and A. Baskerville. 1985. A comparison of virulence of two strains of Legionella pneumophila based on experimental aerosol infection of guinea-pigs. J. Hyg. (Lond.) 95:29-38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2129515</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4020112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joly, P., P. A. Falconnet, J. Andre, N. Weill, M. Reyrolle, F. Vandenesch, M. Maurin, J. Etienne, and S. Jarraud. 2006. Quantitative real-time Legionella PCR for environmental water samples: data interpretation. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 72:2801-2808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1449029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16597985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kagan, J. C., and C. R. Roy. 2002. Legionella phagosomes intercept vesicular traffic from endoplasmic reticulum exit sites. Nat. Cell Biol. 4:945-954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12447391</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kagan, J. C., M. P. Stein, M. Pypaert, and C. R. Roy. 2004. Legionella subvert the functions of Rab1 and Sec22b to create a replicative organelle. J. Exp. Med. 199:1201-1211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2211909</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15117975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz, S. M., and S. Hashemi. 1982. Electron microscopic examination of the inflammatory response to Legionella pneumophila in guinea pigs. Lab. Invest. 46:24-32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7054588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khelef, N., H. A. Shuman, and F. R. Maxfield. 2001. Phagocytosis of wild-type Legionella pneumophila occurs through a wortmannin-insensitive pathway. Infect. Immun. 69:5157-5161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11447198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kikuchi, T., S. Andarini, H. Xin, K. Gomi, Y. Tokue, Y. Saijo, T. Honjo, A. Watanabe, and T. Nukiwa. 2005. Involvement of fractalkine/CX3CL1 expression by dendritic cells in the enhancement of host immunity against Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 73:5350-5357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1231053</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16113250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King, C. H., E. B. Shotts, Jr., R. E. Wooley, and K. G. Porter. 1988. Survival of coliforms and bacterial pathogens within protozoa during chlorination. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 54:3023-3033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC204422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3223766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirby, J. E., J. P. Vogel, H. L. Andrews, and R. R. Isberg. 1998. Evidence for pore-forming ability by Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 27:323-336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9484888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitsukawa, K., A. Nakamoto, H. Koito, Y. Matsuda, A. Saito, and H. Yamamoto. 1995. Interferon-gamma (IFN-gamma) production by human T lymphocytes upon Legionella pneumophila stimulation in vitro. Clin. Exp. Immunol. 99:76-81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1534145</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7813113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komano, T., T. Yoshida, K. Narahara, and N. Furuya. 2000. The transfer region of IncI1 plasmid R64: similarities between R64 tra and Legionella icm/dot genes. Mol. Microbiol. 35:1348-1359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10760136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubori, T., A. Hyakutake, and H. Nagai. 2008. Legionella translocates an E3 ubiquitin ligase that has multiple U-boxes with distinct functions. Mol. Microbiol. 67:1307-1319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18284575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laguna, R. K., E. A. Creasey, Z. Li, N. Valtz, and R. R. Isberg. 2006. A Legionella pneumophila-translocated substrate that is required for growth within macrophages and protection from host cell death. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 103:18745-18750.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1656969</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17124169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lettinga, K. D., S. Florquin, P. Speelman, R. van Ketel, T. van der Poll, and A. Verbon. 2002. Toll-like receptor 4 is not involved in host defense against pulmonary Legionella pneumophila infection in a mouse model. J. Infect. Dis. 186:570-573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12195388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lettinga, K. D., A. Verbon, G. J. Weverling, J. F. Schellekens, J. W. Den Boer, E. P. Yzerman, J. Prins, W. G. Boersma, R. J. van Ketel, J. M. Prins, and P. Speelman. 2002. Legionnaires' disease at a Dutch flower show: prognostic factors and impact of therapy. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 8:1448-1454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12498662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lettinga, K. D., S. Weijer, P. Speelman, J. M. Prins, T. Van Der Poll, and A. Verbon. 2003. Reduced interferon-gamma release in patients recovered from Legionnaires' disease. Thorax 58:63-67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746454</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12511724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Z., A. S. Dugan, G. Bloomfield, J. Skelton, A. Ivens, V. Losick, and R. R. Isberg. 2009. The amoebal MAP kinase response to Legionella pneumophila is regulated by DupA. Cell Host Microbe 6:253-267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2767185</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19748467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liles, M. R., P. H. Edelstein, and N. P. Cianciotto. 1999. The prepilin peptidase is required for protein secretion by and the virulence of the intracellular pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 31:959-970.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10048038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liles, M. R., T. A. Scheel, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2000. Discovery of a nonclassical siderophore, legiobactin, produced by strains of Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 182:749-757.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC94339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10633110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindsay, D. S., W. H. Abraham, and R. J. Fallon. 1994. Detection of mip gene by PCR for diagnosis of Legionnaires' disease. J. Clin. Microbiol. 32:3068-3069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC264231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7883904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lippmann, J., S. Rothenburg, N. Deigendesch, J. Eitel, K. Meixenberger, V. van Laak, H. Slevogt, P. D. N′Guessan, S. Hippenstiel, T. Chakraborty, A. Flieger, N. Suttorp, and B. Opitz. 2008. IFNbeta responses induced by intracellular bacteria or cytosolic DNA in different human cells do not require ZBP1 (DLM-1/DAI). Cell. Microbiol. 10:2579-2588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18771559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, M., G. M. Conover, and R. R. Isberg. 2008. Legionella pneumophila EnhC is required for efficient replication in tumor necrosis factor alpha-stimulated macrophages. Cell. Microbiol. 10:1906-1923.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2579332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18549456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reference deleted.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lomma, M., L. Gomez Valero, C. Rusniok, and C. Buchrieser. 2009. Legionella pneumophila-host interactions: insights gained from comparative genomics and cell biology. Genome Dyn. 6:170-186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Losick, V. P., and R. R. Isberg. 2006. NF-kappaB translocation prevents host cell death after low-dose challenge by Legionella pneumophila. J. Exp. Med. 203:2177-2189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2118400</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16940169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo, Z. Q., and R. R. Isberg. 2004. Multiple substrates of the Legionella pneumophila Dot/Icm system identified by interbacterial protein transfer. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 101:841-846.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luzio, J. P., B. M. Mullock, P. R. Pryor, M. R. Lindsay, D. E. James, and R. C. Piper. 2001. Relationship between endosomes and lysosomes. Biochem. Soc. Trans. 29:476-480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11498012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lynch, D., N. Fieser, K. Gloggler, V. Forsbach-Birk, and R. Marre. 2003. The response regulator LetA regulates the stationary-phase stress response in Legionella pneumophila and is required for efficient infection of Acanthamoeba castellanii. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 219:241-248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12620627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machner, M. P., and R. R. Isberg. 2007. A bifunctional bacterial protein links GDI displacement to Rab1 activation. Science 318:974-977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17947549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machner, M. P., and R. R. Isberg. 2006. Targeting of host Rab GTPase function by the intravacuolar pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Dev. Cell 11:47-56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16824952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maier, J. K., Z. Lahoua, N. H. Gendron, R. Fetni, A. Johnston, J. Davoodi, D. Rasper, S. Roy, R. S. Slack, D. W. Nicholson, and A. E. MacKenzie. 2002. The neuronal apoptosis inhibitory protein is a direct inhibitor of caspases 3 and 7. J. Neurosci. 22:2035-2043.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6758245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11896143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mampel, J., T. Spirig, S. S. Weber, J. A. Haagensen, S. Molin, and H. Hilbi. 2006. Planktonic replication is essential for biofilm formation by Legionella pneumophila in a complex medium under static and dynamic flow conditions. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 72:2885-2895.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1448985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16597995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mariathasan, S., and D. M. Monack. 2007. Inflammasome adaptors and sensors: intracellular regulators of infection and inflammation. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 7:31-40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17186029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marra, A., S. J. Blander, M. A. Horwitz, and H. A. Shuman. 1992. Identification of a Legionella pneumophila locus required for intracellular multiplication in human macrophages. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 89:9607-9611.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC50181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1409673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marston, B. J., J. F. Plouffe, T. M. File, Jr., B. A. Hackman, S. J. Salstrom, H. B. Lipman, M. S. Kolczak, and R. F. Breiman. 1997. Incidence of community-acquired pneumonia requiring hospitalization. Results of a population-based active surveillance study in Ohio. The Community-Based Pneumonia Incidence Study Group. Arch. Intern. Med. 157:1709-1718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9250232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maruta, K., M. Ogawa, H. Miyamoto, K. Izu, and S. I. Yoshida. 1998. Entry and intracellular localization of Legionella dumoffii in Vero cells. Microb. Pathog. 24:65-73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9480789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsiota-Bernard, P., C. Lefebre, M. Sedqui, P. Cornillet, and M. Guenounou. 1993. Involvement of tumor necrosis factor alpha in intracellular multiplication of Legionella pneumophila in human monocytes. Infect. Immun. 61:4980-4983.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC281272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8225572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matthews, M., and C. R. Roy. 2000. Identification and subcellular localization of the Legionella pneumophila IcmX protein: a factor essential for establishment of a replicative organelle in eukaryotic host cells. Infect. Immun. 68:3971-3982.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101675</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10858211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCusker, K. T., B. A. Braaten, M. W. Cho, and D. A. Low. 1991. Legionella pneumophila inhibits protein synthesis in Chinese hamster ovary cells. Infect. Immun. 59:240-246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC257733</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1987039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDade, J. E., C. C. Shepard, D. W. Fraser, T. R. Tsai, M. A. Redus, and W. R. Dowdle. 1977. Legionnaires' disease: isolation of a bacterium and demonstration of its role in other respiratory disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 297:1197-1203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">335245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moffat, J. F., P. H. Edelstein, D. P. Regula, Jr., J. D. Cirillo, and L. S. Tompkins. 1994. Effects of an isogenic Zn-metalloprotease-deficient mutant of Legionella pneumophila in a guinea-pig pneumonia model. Mol. Microbiol. 12:693-705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8052122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moliner, C., D. Raoult, and P. E. Fournier. 2009. Evidence of horizontal gene transfer between amoeba and bacteria. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 15:178-180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19793120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moliner, C., D. Raoult, and P. E. Fournier. 2009. Evidence that the intra-amoebal Legionella drancourtii acquired a sterol reductase gene from eukaryotes. BMC Res. Notes 2:51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19327142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molmeret, M., and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2002. How does Legionella pneumophila exit the host cell? Trends Microbiol. 10:258-260.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12088652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molmeret, M., O. A. Alli, M. Radulic, M. Susa, M. Doric, and Y. A. Kwaik. 2002. The C-terminus of IcmT is essential for pore formation and for intracellular trafficking of Legionella pneumophila within Acanthamoeba polyphaga. Mol. Microbiol. 43:1139-1150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11918802</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molmeret, M., O. A. Alli, S. Zink, A. Flieger, N. P. Cianciotto, and Y. A. Kwaik. 2002. icmT is essential for pore formation-mediated egress of Legionella pneumophila from mammalian and protozoan cells. Infect. Immun. 70:69-78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC127627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11748165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molmeret, M., S. D. Zink, L. Han, A. Abu-Zant, R. Asari, D. M. Bitar, and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2004. Activation of caspase-3 by the Dot/Icm virulence system is essential for arrested biogenesis of the Legionella-containing phagosome. Cell. Microbiol. 6:33-48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14678329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molofsky, A. B., B. G. Byrne, N. N. Whitfield, C. A. Madigan, E. T. Fuse, K. Tateda, and M. S. Swanson. 2006. Cytosolic recognition of flagellin by mouse macrophages restricts Legionella pneumophila infection. J. Exp. Med. 203:1093-1104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1584282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16606669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molofsky, A. B., L. M. Shetron-Rama, and M. S. Swanson. 2005. Components of the Legionella pneumophila flagellar regulon contribute to multiple virulence traits, including lysosome avoidance and macrophage death. Infect. Immun. 73:5720-5734.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1231111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16113289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molofsky, A. B., and M. S. Swanson. 2003. Legionella pneumophila CsrA is a pivotal repressor of transmission traits and activator of replication. Mol. Microbiol. 50:445-461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monroe, K. M., S. M. McWhirter, and R. E. Vance. 2009. Identification of host cytosolic sensors and bacterial factors regulating the type I interferon response to Legionella pneumophila. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2773930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19936053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris, G. K., C. M. Patton, J. C. Feeley, S. E. Johnson, G. Gorman, W. T. Martin, P. Skaliy, G. F. Mallison, B. D. Politi, and D. C. Mackel. 1979. Isolation of the Legionnaires' disease bacterium from environmental samples. Ann. Intern. Med. 90:664-666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">373549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moyer, B. D., B. B. Allan, and W. E. Balch. 2001. Rab1 interaction with a GM130 effector complex regulates COPII vesicle cis-Golgi tethering. Traffic 2:268-276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11285137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muder, R. R., and V. L. Yu. 2002. Infection due to Legionella species other than L. pneumophila. Clin. Infect. Dis. 35:990-998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12355387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murata, T., A. Delprato, A. Ingmundson, D. K. Toomre, D. G. Lambright, and C. R. Roy. 2006. The Legionella pneumophila effector protein DrrA is a Rab1 guanine nucleotide-exchange factor. Nat. Cell Biol. 8:971-977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16906144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murga, R., T. S. Forster, E. Brown, J. M. Pruckler, B. S. Fields, and R. M. Donlan. 2001. Role of biofilms in the survival of Legionella pneumophila in a model potable-water system. Microbiology 147:3121-3126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11700362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagai, H., E. D. Cambronne, J. C. Kagan, J. C. Amor, R. A. Kahn, and C. R. Roy. 2005. A C-terminal translocation signal required for Dot/Icm-dependent delivery of the Legionella RalF protein to host cells. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 102:826-831.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545534</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15613486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagai, H., J. C. Kagan, X. Zhu, R. A. Kahn, and C. R. Roy. 2002. A bacterial guanine nucleotide exchange factor activates ARF on Legionella phagosomes. Science 295:679-682.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagai, H., and C. R. Roy. 2001. The DotA protein from Legionella pneumophila is secreted by a novel process that requires the Dot/Icm transporter. EMBO J. 20:5962-5970.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC125688</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11689436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nash, T. W., D. M. Libby, and M. A. Horwitz. 1984. Interaction between the Legionnaires' disease bacterium (Legionella pneumophila) and human alveolar macrophages. Influence of antibody, lymphokines, and hydrocortisone. J. Clin. Invest. 74:771-782.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC425231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6470140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naylor, J., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2004. Cytochrome c maturation proteins are critical for in vivo growth of Legionella pneumophila. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 241:249-256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15598540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neild, A. L., and C. R. Roy. 2003. Legionella reveal dendritic cell functions that facilitate selection of antigens for MHC class II presentation. Immunity 18:813-823.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12818162</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neild, A. L., S. Shin, and C. R. Roy. 2005. Activated macrophages infected with Legionella inhibit T cells by means of MyD88-dependent production of prostaglandins. J. Immunol. 175:8181-8190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16339557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neumeister, B., M. Faigle, K. Lauber, H. Northoff, and S. Wesselborg. 2002. Legionella pneumophila induces apoptosis via the mitochondrial death pathway. Microbiology 148:3639-3650.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12427954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton, C. A., I. Perkins, R. H. Widen, H. Friedman, and T. W. Klein. 2007. Role of Toll-like receptor 9 in Legionella pneumophila-induced interleukin-12 p40 production in bone marrow-derived dendritic cells and macrophages from permissive and nonpermissive mice. Infect. Immun. 75:146-151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1828406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17060467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton, H. J., F. M. Sansom, V. Bennett-Wood, and E. L. Hartland. 2006. Identification of Legionella pneumophila-specific genes by genomic subtractive hybridization with Legionella micdadei and identification of lpnE, a gene required for efficient host cell entry. Infect. Immun. 74:1683-1691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1418643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16495539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton, H. J., F. M. Sansom, J. Dao, C. Cazalet, H. Bruggemann, C. Albert-Weissenberger, C. Buchrieser, N. P. Cianciotto, and E. L. Hartland. 2008. Significant role for ladC in initiation of Legionella pneumophila infection. Infect. Immun. 76:3075-3085.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2446704</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18426879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton, H. J., F. M. Sansom, J. Dao, A. D. McAlister, J. Sloan, N. P. Cianciotto, and E. L. Hartland. 2007. Sel1 repeat protein LpnE is a Legionella pneumophila virulence determinant that influences vacuolar trafficking. Infect. Immun. 75:5575-5585.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2168337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17893138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen, T. M., D. Ilef, S. Jarraud, L. Rouil, C. Campese, D. Che, S. Haeghebaert, F. Ganiayre, F. Marcel, J. Etienne, and J. C. Desenclos. 2006. A community-wide outbreak of Legionnaires disease linked to industrial cooling towers—how far can contaminated aerosols spread? J. Infect. Dis. 193:102-111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16323138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ninio, S., J. Celli, and C. R. Roy. 2009. A Legionella pneumophila effector protein encoded in a region of genomic plasticity binds to Dot/Icm-modified vacuoles. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621349</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ninio, S., D. M. Zuckman-Cholon, E. D. Cambronne, and C. R. Roy. 2005. The Legionella IcmS-IcmW protein complex is important for Dot/Icm-mediated protein translocation. Mol. Microbiol. 55:912-926.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15661013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nogueira, C. V., T. Lindsten, A. M. Jamieson, C. L. Case, S. Shin, C. B. Thompson, and C. R. Roy. 2009. Rapid pathogen-induced apoptosis: a mechanism used by dendritic cells to limit intracellular replication of Legionella pneumophila. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2689937</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19521510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Opitz, B., M. Vinzing, V. van Laak, B. Schmeck, G. Heine, S. Gunther, R. Preissner, H. Slevogt, P. D. N′Guessan, J. Eitel, T. Goldmann, A. Flieger, N. Suttorp, and S. Hippenstiel. 2006. Legionella pneumophila induces IFNbeta in lung epithelial cells via IPS-1 and IRF3, which also control bacterial replication. J. Biol. Chem. 281:36173-36179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16984921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otto, G. P., M. Y. Wu, M. Clarke, H. Lu, O. R. Anderson, H. Hilbi, H. A. Shuman, and R. H. Kessin. 2004. Macroautophagy is dispensable for intracellular replication of Legionella pneumophila in Dictyostelium discoideum. Mol. Microbiol. 51:63-72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14651611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan, X., A. Luhrmann, A. Satoh, M. A. Laskowski-Arce, and C. R. Roy. 2008. Ankyrin repeat proteins comprise a diverse family of bacterial type IV effectors. Science 320:1651-1654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2514061</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18566289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pardo, A., M. Selman, and N. Kaminski. 2008. Approaching the degradome in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 40:1141-1155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18207447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearce, M. M., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2009. Legionella pneumophila secretes an endoglucanase that belongs to the family-5 of glycosyl hydrolases and is dependent upon type II secretion. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 300:256-264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2766432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19817866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedro-Botet, M. L., N. Sopena, A. Garcia-Cruz, L. Mateu, M. Garcia-Nunez, C. Rey-Joly, and M. Sabria. 2007. Streptococcus pneumoniae and Legionella pneumophila pneumonia in HIV-infected patients. Scand. J. Infect. Dis. 39:122-128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17366028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plumlee, C. R., C. Lee, A. A. Beg, T. Decker, H. A. Shuman, and C. Schindler. 2009. Interferons direct an effective innate response to Legionella pneumophila infection. J. Biol. Chem. 284:30058-30066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2781560</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19720834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polesky, A. H., J. T. Ross, S. Falkow, and L. S. Tompkins. 2001. Identification of Legionella pneumophila genes important for infection of amoebae by signature-tagged mutagenesis. Infect. Immun. 69:977-987.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11159993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pope, C. D., W. O'Connell, and N. P. Cianciotto. 1996. Legionella pneumophila mutants that are defective for iron acquisition and assimilation and intracellular infection. Infect. Immun. 64:629-636.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8550218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price, C. T., S. Al-Khodor, T. Al-Quadan, M. Santic, F. Habyarimana, A. Kalia, and Y. A. Kwaik. 2009. Molecular mimicry by an F-box effector of Legionella pneumophila hijacks a conserved polyubiquitination machinery within macrophages and protozoa. PLoS Pathog. 5:e1000704.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20041211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Purcell, M., and H. A. Shuman. 1998. The Legionella pneumophila icmGCDJBF genes are required for killing of human macrophages. Infect. Immun. 66:2245-2255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC108188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9573114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragaz, C., H. Pietsch, S. Urwyler, A. Tiaden, S. S. Weber, and H. Hilbi. 2008. The Legionella pneumophila phosphatidylinositol-4 phosphate-binding type IV substrate SidC recruits endoplasmic reticulum vesicles to a replication-permissive vacuole. Cell. Microbiol. 10:2416-2433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18673369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasis, M., and G. Segal. 2009. The LetA-RsmYZ-CsrA regulatory cascade, together with RpoS and PmrA, post-transcriptionally regulates stationary phase activation of Legionella pneumophila Icm/Dot effectors. Mol. Microbiol. 72:995-1010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19400807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ratcliff, R. M., J. A. Lanser, P. A. Manning, and M. W. Heuzenroeder. 1998. Sequence-based classification scheme for the genus Legionella targeting the mip gene. J. Clin. Microbiol. 36:1560-1567.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104877</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raychaudhury, S., J. D. Farelli, T. P. Montminy, M. Matthews, J. F. Menetret, G. Dumenil, C. R. Roy, J. F. Head, R. R. Isberg, and C. W. Akey. 2009. Structure and function of interacting IcmR-IcmQ domains from a type IVb secretion system in Legionella pneumophila. Structure 17:590-601.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19368892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rechnitzer, C., and J. Blom. 1989. Engulfment of the Philadelphia strain of Legionella pneumophila within pseudopod coils in human phagocytes. Comparison with other Legionella strains and species. APMIS 97:105-114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2920101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reeves, M. W., L. Pine, S. H. Hutner, J. R. George, and W. K. Harrell. 1981. Metal requirements of Legionella pneumophila. J. Clin. Microbiol. 13:688-695.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC273860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6785311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren, T., D. S. Zamboni, C. R. Roy, W. F. Dietrich, and R. E. Vance. 2006. Flagellin-deficient Legionella mutants evade caspase-1- and Naip5-mediated macrophage immunity. PLoS Pathog. 2:e18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1401497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16552444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds, H. Y., and H. H. Newball. 1974. Analysis of proteins and respiratory cells obtained from human lungs by bronchial lavage. J. Lab. Clin. Med. 84:559-573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4412011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riboldi-Tunnicliffe, A., B. Konig, S. Jessen, M. S. Weiss, J. Rahfeld, J. Hacker, G. Fischer, and R. Hilgenfeld. 2001. Crystal structure of Mip, a prolylisomerase from Legionella pneumophila. Nat. Struct. Biol. 8:779-783.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11524681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricci, M. L., A. Torosantucci, M. Scaturro, P. Chiani, L. Baldassarri, and M. C. Pastoris. 2005. Induction of protective immunity by Legionella pneumophila flagellum in an A/J. mouse model. Vaccine 23:4811-4820.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16005118</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ridenour, D. A., S. L. Cirillo, S. Feng, M. M. Samrakandi, and J. D. Cirillo. 2003. Identification of a gene that affects the efficiency of host cell infection by Legionella pneumophila in a temperature-dependent fashion. Infect. Immun. 71:6256-6263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC219575</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14573644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ristroph, J. D., K. W. Hedlund, and S. Gowda. 1981. Chemically defined medium for Legionella pneumophila growth. J. Clin. Microbiol. 13:115-119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC273733</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7462408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robey, M., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2002. Legionella pneumophila feoAB promotes ferrous iron uptake and intracellular infection. Infect. Immun. 70:5659-5669.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC128349</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12228295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, C. G., and C. R. Roy. 2006. Attachment and fusion of endoplasmic reticulum with vacuoles containing Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 8:793-805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16611228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodgers, F. G., and F. C. Gibson III. 1993. Opsonin-independent adherence and intracellular development of Legionella pneumophila within U-937 cells. Can. J. Microbiol. 39:718-722.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8364804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers, J., A. B. Dowsett, P. J. Dennis, J. V. Lee, and C. W. Keevil. 1994. Influence of temperature and plumbing material selection on biofilm formation and growth of Legionella pneumophila in a model potable water system containing complex microbial flora. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 60:1585-1592.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8017938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossier, O., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2005. The Legionella pneumophila tatB gene facilitates secretion of phospholipase C, growth under iron-limiting conditions, and intracellular infection. Infect. Immun. 73:2020-2032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1087389</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15784543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossier, O., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2001. Type II protein secretion is a subset of the PilD-dependent processes that facilitate intracellular infection by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 69:2092-2098.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11254562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossier, O., J. Dao, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2009. A type II secreted RNase of Legionella pneumophila facilitates optimal intracellular infection of Hartmannella vermiformis. Microbiology 155:882-890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19246759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossier, O., J. Dao, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2008. The type II secretion system of Legionella pneumophila elaborates two aminopeptidases, as well as a metalloprotease that contributes to differential infection among protozoan hosts. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 74:753-761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2227731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossier, O., S. R. Starkenburg, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2004. Legionella pneumophila type II protein secretion promotes virulence in the A/J. mouse model of Legionnaires' disease pneumonia. Infect. Immun. 72:310-321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC344012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14688110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowbotham, T. J. 1980. Preliminary report on the pathogenicity of Legionella pneumophila for freshwater and soil amoebae. J. Clin. Pathol. 33:1179-1183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1146371</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7451664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadosky, A. B., L. A. Wiater, and H. A. Shuman. 1993. Identification of Legionella pneumophila genes required for growth within and killing of human macrophages. Infect. Immun. 61:5361-5373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC281323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8225610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahr, T., H. Bruggemann, M. Jules, M. Lomma, C. Albert-Weissenberger, C. Cazalet, and C. Buchrieser. 2009. Two small ncRNAs jointly govern virulence and transmission in Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 72:741-762.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888818</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19400772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sansom, F. M., H. J. Newton, S. Crikis, N. P. Cianciotto, P. J. Cowan, A. J. d'Apice, and E. L. Hartland. 2007. A bacterial ecto-triphosphate diphosphohydrolase similar to human CD39 is essential for intracellular multiplication of Legionella pneumophila. Cell. Microbiol. 9:1922-1935.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17388784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sansom, F. M., P. Riedmaier, H. J. Newton, M. A. Dunstone, C. E. Muller, H. Stephan, E. Byres, T. Beddoe, J. Rossjohn, P. J. Cowan, A. J. d'Apice, S. C. Robson, and E. L. Hartland. 2008. Enzymatic properties of an ecto-nucleoside triphosphate diphosphohydrolase from Legionella pneumophila: substrate specificity and requirement for virulence. J. Biol. Chem. 283:12909-12918.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2442346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18337253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santic, M., R. Asare, M. Doric, and Y. Abu Kwaik. 2007. Host-dependent trigger of caspases and apoptosis by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 75:2903-2913.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1932860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17420236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sauer, J. D., M. A. Bachman, and M. S. Swanson. 2005. The phagosomal transporter A couples threonine acquisition to differentiation and replication of Legionella pneumophila in macrophages. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 102:9924-9929.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1174991</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15998735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiavoni, G., C. Mauri, D. Carlei, F. Belardelli, M. C. Pastoris, and E. Proietti. 2004. Type I IFN protects permissive macrophages from Legionella pneumophila infection through an IFN-gamma-independent pathway. J. Immunol. 173:1266-1275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15240719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlossberg, D., and J. Bonoan. 1998. Legionella and immunosuppression. Semin. Respir. Infect. 13:128-131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9643390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, B., J. Rahfeld, A. Schierhorn, B. Ludwig, J. Hacker, and G. Fischer. 1994. A homodimer represents an active species of the peptidyl-prolyl cis/trans isomerase FKBP25mem from Legionella pneumophila. FEBS Lett. 352:185-190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7523184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal, G., M. Purcell, and H. A. Shuman. 1998. Host cell killing and bacterial conjugation require overlapping sets of genes within a 22-kb region of the Legionella pneumophila genome. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 95:1669-1674.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC19142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9465074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal, G., and H. A. Shuman. 1997. Characterization of a new region required for macrophage killing by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 65:5057-5066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC175729</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9393796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sethi, K. K., and H. Brandis. 1983. Direct demonstration and isolation of Legionella pneumophila (serogroup 1) from bathroom water specimens in a hotel. Zentralbl. Bakteriol. Mikrobiol. Hyg. B 177:402-405. (In German.)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6367308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen, X., S. Banga, Y. Liu, L. Xu, P. Gao, I. Shamovsky, E. Nudler, and Z. Q. Luo. 2009. Targeting eEF1A by a Legionella pneumophila effector leads to inhibition of protein synthesis and induction of host stress response. Cell. Microbiol. 11:911-926.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin, S., C. L. Case, K. A. Archer, C. V. Nogueira, K. S. Kobayashi, R. A. Flavell, C. R. Roy, and D. S. Zamboni. 2008. Type IV secretion-dependent activation of host MAP kinases induces an increased proinflammatory cytokine response to Legionella pneumophila. PLoS Pathog. 4:e1000220.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2582680</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19043549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinozawa, Y., T. Matsumoto, K. Uchida, S. Tsujimoto, Y. Iwakura, and K. Yamaguchi. 2002. Role of interferon-gamma in inflammatory responses in murine respiratory infection with Legionella pneumophila. J. Med. Microbiol. 51:225-230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11871617</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shohdy, N., J. A. Efe, S. D. Emr, and H. A. Shuman. 2005. Pathogen effector protein screening in yeast identifies Legionella factors that interfere with membrane trafficking. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 102:4866-4871.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC555709</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15781869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silveira, T. N., and D. S. Zamboni. 2010. Pore formation triggered by Legionella spp. is an Nlrc4 inflammasome-dependent host cell response that precedes pyroptosis. Infect. Immun. 78:1403-1413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2825914</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simonsen, A., R. Lippe, S. Christoforidis, J. M. Gaullier, A. Brech, J. Callaghan, B. H. Toh, C. Murphy, M. Zerial, and H. Stenmark. 1998. EEA1 links PI(3)K function to Rab5 regulation of endosome fusion. Nature 394:494-498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9697774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skaliy, P., and H. V. McEachern. 1979. Survival of the Legionnaires' disease bacterium in water. Ann. Intern. Med. 90:662-663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">434653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soderberg, M. A., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2008. A Legionella pneumophila peptidyl-prolyl cis-trans isomerase present in culture supernatants is necessary for optimal growth at low temperatures. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 74:1634-1638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258609</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18165359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soderberg, M. A., and N. P. Cianciotto. 2010. Mediators of lipid A modification, RNA degradation, and central intermediary metabolism facilitate the growth of Legionella pneumophila at low temperatures. Curr. Microbiol. 60:59-65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2809775</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19768502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soderberg, M. A., J. Dao, S. R. Starkenburg, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2008. Importance of type II secretion for survival of Legionella pneumophila in tap water and in amoebae at low temperatures. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 74:5583-5588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2546640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18621869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soderberg, M. A., O. Rossier, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2004. The type II protein secretion system of Legionella pneumophila promotes growth at low temperatures. J. Bacteriol. 186:3712-3720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC419956</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15175284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sogaard, M., K. Tani, R. R. Ye, S. Geromanos, P. Tempst, T. Kirchhausen, J. E. Rothman, and T. Sollner. 1994. A rab protein is required for the assembly of SNARE complexes in the docking of transport vesicles. Cell 78:937-948.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7923363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spirig, T., A. Tiaden, P. Kiefer, C. Buchrieser, J. A. Vorholt, and H. Hilbi. 2008. The Legionella autoinducer synthase LqsA produces an alpha-hydroxyketone signaling molecule. J. Biol. Chem. 283:18113-18123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2440625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18411263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spitalny, K. C., R. L. Vogt, L. A. Orciari, L. E. Witherell, P. Etkind, and L. F. Novick. 1984. Pontiac fever associated with a whirlpool spa. Am. J. Epidemiol. 120:809-817.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6391156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sporri, R., N. Joller, U. Albers, H. Hilbi, and A. Oxenius. 2006. MyD88-dependent IFN-gamma production by NK cells is key for control of Legionella pneumophila infection. J. Immunol. 176:6162-6171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16670325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Starkenburg, S. R., J. M. Casey, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2004. Siderophore activity among members of the Legionella genus. Curr. Microbiol. 49:203-207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15386105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steele, T. W., J. Lanser, and N. Sangster. 1990. Isolation of Legionella longbeachae serogroup 1 from potting mixes. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 56:49-53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC183249</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1968736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steele, T. W., C. V. Moore, and N. Sangster. 1990. Distribution of Legionella longbeachae serogroup 1 and other legionellae in potting soils in Australia. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 56:2984-2988.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC184887</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2285311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, M., L. Emody, R. Amann, and J. Hacker. 1997. Resuscitation of viable but nonculturable Legionella pneumophila Philadelphia JR32 by Acanthamoeba castellanii. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 63:2047-2053.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC168494</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9143134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, M., and K. Heuner. 2005. Dictyostelium as host model for pathogenesis. Cell. Microbiol. 7:307-314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15679834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, M., K. Heuner, C. Buchrieser, C. Albert-Weissenberger, and G. Glockner. 2007. Legionella pathogenicity: genome structure, regulatory networks and the host cell response. Int. J. Med. Microbiol. 297:577-587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17467337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stetson, D. B., and R. Medzhitov. 2006. Recognition of cytosolic DNA activates an IRF3-dependent innate immune response. Immunity 24:93-103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16413926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart, C. R., O. Rossier, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2009. Surface translocation by Legionella pneumophila: a form of sliding motility that is dependent upon type II protein secretion. J. Bacteriol. 191:1537-1546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2648193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19114479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stout, J. E., and V. L. Yu. 1997. Legionellosis. N. Engl. J. Med. 337:682-687.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9278466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sturgill-Koszycki, S., and M. S. Swanson. 2000. Legionella pneumophila replication vacuoles mature into acidic, endocytic organelles. J. Exp. Med. 192:1261-1272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193360</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11067875</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Susa, M., B. Ticac, T. Rukavina, M. Doric, and R. Marre. 1998. Legionella pneumophila infection in intratracheally inoculated T cell-depleted or -nondepleted A/J. mice. J. Immunol. 160:316-321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9551986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki, Y., Y. Nakabayashi, K. Nakata, J. C. Reed, and R. Takahashi. 2001. X-linked inhibitor of apoptosis protein (XIAP) inhibits caspase-3 and -7 in distinct modes. J. Biol. Chem. 276:27058-27063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11359776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swanson, M. S., and R. R. Isberg. 1995. Association of Legionella pneumophila with the macrophage endoplasmic reticulum. Infect. Immun. 63:3609-3620.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173501</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7642298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szeto, L., and H. A. Shuman. 1990. The Legionella pneumophila major secretory protein, a protease, is not required for intracellular growth or cell killing. Infect. Immun. 58:2585-2592.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC258859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2164510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tachado, S. D., M. M. Samrakandi, and J. D. Cirillo. 2008. Non-opsonic phagocytosis of Legionella pneumophila by macrophages is mediated by phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase. PLoS One 3:e3324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2553182</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18830409</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tateda, K., T. Matsumoto, Y. Ishii, N. Furuya, A. Ohno, S. Miyazaki, and K. Yamaguchi. 1998. Serum cytokines in patients with Legionella pneumonia: relative predominance of Th1-type cytokines. Clin. Diagn. Lab. Immunol. 5:401-403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC104531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9605998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tesh, M. J., and R. D. Miller. 1981. Amino acid requirements for Legionella pneumophila growth. J. Clin. Microbiol. 13:865-869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC273905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6113250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tesh, M. J., S. A. Morse, and R. D. Miller. 1983. Intermediary metabolism in Legionella pneumophila: utilization of amino acids and other compounds as energy sources. J. Bacteriol. 154:1104-1109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC217580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6133845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiaden, A., T. Spirig, P. Carranza, H. Bruggemann, K. Riedel, L. Eberl, C. Buchrieser, and H. Hilbi. 2008. Synergistic contribution of the Legionella pneumophila lqs genes to pathogen-host interactions. J. Bacteriol. 190:7532-7547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2576672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18805977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiaden, A., T. Spirig, S. S. Weber, H. Bruggemann, R. Bosshard, C. Buchrieser, and H. Hilbi. 2007. The Legionella pneumophila response regulator LqsR promotes host cell interactions as an element of the virulence regulatory network controlled by RpoS and LetA. Cell. Microbiol. 9:2903-2920.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17614967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiaden, A., T. Spirig, T. Sahr, M. A. Walti, K. Boucke, C. Buchrieser, and H. Hilbi. 2010. The autoinducer lqsA and cognate sensor kinase lqsS regulate phagocyte interactions, extracellular filaments and a genomic island of Legionella pneumophila. Environ. Microbiol. [Epub ahead of print.] doi:10.1111/j.1462-2920.2010.02167.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-2920.2010.02167.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tilney, L. G., O. S. Harb, P. S. Connelly, C. G. Robinson, and C. R. Roy. 2001. How the parasitic bacterium Legionella pneumophila modifies its phagosome and transforms it into rough ER: implications for conversion of plasma membrane to the ER membrane. J. Cell Sci. 114:4637-4650.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11792828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urwyler, S., E. Brombacher, and H. Hilbi. 2009. Endosomal and secretory markers of the Legionella-containing vacuole. Commun. Integr. Biol. 2:107-109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2686358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19704903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urwyler, S., Y. Nyfeler, C. Ragaz, H. Lee, L. N. Mueller, R. Aebersold, and H. Hilbi. 2009. Proteome analysis of Legionella vacuoles purified by magnetic immunoseparation reveals secretory and endosomal GTPases. Traffic 10:76-87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18980612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VanRheenen, S. M., Z. Q. Luo, T. O'Connor, and R. R. Isberg. 2006. Members of a Legionella pneumophila family of proteins with ExoU (phospholipase A) active sites are translocated to target cells. Infect. Immun. 74:3597-3606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1479236</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16714592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent, C. D., J. R. Friedman, K. C. Jeong, E. C. Buford, J. L. Miller, and J. P. Vogel. 2006. Identification of the core transmembrane complex of the Legionella Dot/Icm type IV secretion system. Mol. Microbiol. 62:1278-1291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17040490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viswanathan, V. K., P. H. Edelstein, C. D. Pope, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2000. The Legionella pneumophila iraAB locus is required for iron assimilation, intracellular infection, and virulence. Infect. Immun. 68:1069-1079.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97250</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10678909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viswanathan, V. K., S. Kurtz, L. L. Pedersen, Y. Abu-Kwaik, K. Krcmarik, S. Mody, and N. P. Cianciotto. 2002. The cytochrome c maturation locus of Legionella pneumophila promotes iron assimilation and intracellular infection and contains a strain-specific insertion sequence element. Infect. Immun. 70:1842-1852.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC127876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11895946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vivian, J. P., P. Riedmaier, H. Ge, J. Le Nours, F. M. Sansom, M. C. J. Wilce, E. Byres, M. Dias, P. J. Cowan, A. J. F. d'Apice, E. L. Hartland, J. Rossjohn, and T. Beddoe. 2010. Crystal structure of a Legionella pneumophilia ecto-triphosphate diphosphohydrolase, a structural and functional homologue of the eukaryotic NTPDases. Structure 18:228-238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20159467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogel, J. P., H. L. Andrews, S. K. Wong, and R. R. Isberg. 1998. Conjugative transfer by the virulence system of Legionella pneumophila. Science 279:873-876.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9452389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voth, D. E., D. Howe, P. A. Beare, J. P. Vogel, N. Unsworth, J. E. Samuel, and R. A. Heinzen. 2009. The Coxiella burnetii ankyrin repeat domain-containing protein family is heterogeneous, with C-terminal truncations that influence Dot/Icm-mediated secretion. J. Bacteriol. 191:4232-4242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19411324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner, C., A. S. Khan, T. Kamphausen, B. Schmausser, C. Unal, U. Lorenz, G. Fischer, J. Hacker, and M. Steinert. 2007. Collagen binding protein Mip enables Legionella pneumophila to transmigrate through a barrier of NCI-H292 lung epithelial cells and extracellular matrix. Cell. Microbiol. 9:450-462.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16953800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe, M., Y. Shimamoto, S. Yoshida, K. Suga, Y. Mizuguchi, O. Kohashi, and M. Yamaguchi. 1993. Intracellular multiplication of Legionella pneumophila in HL-60 cells differentiated by 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 and the effect of interferon gamma. J. Leukoc. Biol. 54:40-46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8336078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watarai, M., I. Derre, J. Kirby, J. D. Growney, W. F. Dietrich, and R. R. Isberg. 2001. Legionella pneumophila is internalized by a macropinocytotic uptake pathway controlled by the Dot/Icm system and the mouse Lgn1 locus. J. Exp. Med. 194:1081-1096.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11602638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber, S. S., C. Ragaz, and H. Hilbi. 2009. The inositol polyphosphate 5-phosphatase OCRL1 restricts intracellular growth of Legionella, localizes to the replicative vacuole and binds to the bacterial effector LpnE. Cell. Microbiol. 11:442-460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19021631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber, S. S., C. Ragaz, K. Reus, Y. Nyfeler, and H. Hilbi. 2006. Legionella pneumophila exploits PI(4)P to anchor secreted effector proteins to the replicative vacuole. PLoS Pathog. 2:e46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1463015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16710455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weeratna, R., D. A. Stamler, P. H. Edelstein, M. Ripley, T. Marrie, D. Hoskin, and P. S. Hoffman. 1994. Human and guinea pig immune responses to Legionella pneumophila protein antigens OmpS and Hsp60. Infect. Immun. 62:3454-3462.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC302978</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7913699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinbaum, D. L., R. R. Benner, J. N. Dowling, A. Alpern, A. W. Pasculle, and G. R. Donowitz. 1984. Interaction of Legionella micdadei with human monocytes. Infect. Immun. 46:68-73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC261422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6480116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weissgerber, P., M. Faigle, H. Northoff, and B. Neumeister. 2003. Investigation of mechanisms involved in phagocytosis of Legionella pneumophila by human cells. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 219:173-179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12620617</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitfield, N. N., B. G. Byrne, and M. S. Swanson. 2010. Mouse macrophages are permissive to motile Legionella species that fail to trigger pyroptosis. Infect. Immun. 78:423-432.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798216</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19841075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wieland, H., F. Goetz, and B. Neumeister. 2004. Phagosomal acidification is not a prerequisite for intracellular multiplication of Legionella pneumophila in human monocytes. J. Infect. Dis. 189:1610-1614.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15116296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wieland, H., S. Ullrich, F. Lang, and B. Neumeister. 2005. Intracellular multiplication of Legionella pneumophila depends on host cell amino acid transporter SLC1A5. Mol. Microbiol. 55:1528-1537.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15720558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wintermeyer, E., B. Ludwig, M. Steinert, B. Schmidt, G. Fischer, and J. Hacker. 1995. Influence of site specifically altered Mip proteins on intracellular survival of Legionella pneumophila in eukaryotic cells. Infect. Immun. 63:4576-4583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7591108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright, E. K., S. A. Goodart, J. D. Growney, V. Hadinoto, M. G. Endrizzi, E. M. Long, K. Sadigh, A. L. Abney, I. Bernstein-Hanley, and W. F. Dietrich. 2003. Naip5 affects host susceptibility to the intracellular pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Curr. Biol. 13:27-36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12526741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu, D., A. P. Joglekar, A. L. Williams, and J. C. Hay. 2000. Subunit structure of a mammalian ER/Golgi SNARE complex. J. Biol. Chem. 275:39631-39639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11035026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaraghi, Z., E. Diez, P. Gros, and A. MacKenzie. 1999. cDNA cloning and the 5′ genomic organization of Naip2, a candidate gene for murine Legionella resistance. Mamm. Genome 10:761-763.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10384056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu, V. L., J. F. Plouffe, M. C. Pastoris, J. E. Stout, M. Schousboe, A. Widmer, J. Summersgill, T. File, C. M. Heath, D. L. Paterson, and A. Chereshsky. 2002. Distribution of Legionella species and serogroups isolated by culture in patients with sporadic community-acquired legionellosis: an international collaborative survey. J. Infect. Dis. 186:127-128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12089674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamboni, D. S., K. S. Kobayashi, T. Kohlsdorf, Y. Ogura, E. M. Long, R. E. Vance, K. Kuida, S. Mariathasan, V. M. Dixit, R. A. Flavell, W. F. Dietrich, and C. R. Roy. 2006. The Birc1e cytosolic pattern-recognition receptor contributes to the detection and control of Legionella pneumophila infection. Nat. Immunol. 7:318-325.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16444259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamboni, D. S., S. McGrath, M. Rabinovitch, and C. R. Roy. 2003. Coxiella burnetii express type IV secretion system proteins that function similarly to components of the Legionella pneumophila Dot/Icm system. Mol. Microbiol. 49:965-976.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12890021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zerial, M., and H. McBride. 2001. Rab proteins as membrane organizers. Nat. Rev. Mol. Cell Biol. 2:107-117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11252952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman, T., G. Aloni, E. Halperin, H. Kotzer, E. Degtyar, M. Feldman, and G. Segal. 2007. The response regulator PmrA is a major regulator of the icm/dot type IV secretion system in Legionella pneumophila and Coxiella burnetii. Mol. Microbiol. 63:1508-1523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17302824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman, T., O. Gal-Mor, and G. Segal. 2002. Characterization of a Legionella pneumophila relA insertion mutant and roles of RelA and RpoS in virulence gene expression. J. Bacteriol. 184:67-75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC134777</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11741845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman, T., G. Yerushalmi, and G. Segal. 2003. Functional similarities between the icm/dot pathogenesis systems of Coxiella burnetii and Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 71:3714-3723.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC161977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12819052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
