<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">20643990</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2010</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-3704</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>153</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2010</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
              <Day>20</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of internal medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Intern Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Narrative review: the systemic capillary leak syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>90</StartPage>
          <EndPage>98</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>90-8</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7326/0003-4819-153-2-201007200-00005</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The systemic capillary leak syndrome (SCLS) is a rare disease of reversible plasma extravasation and vascular collapse accompanied by hemoconcentration and hypoalbuminemia. Its cause is unknown, although it is believed to be a manifestation of transient endothelial dysfunction due to endothelial contraction, apoptosis, injury, or a combination of these. Fewer than 150 cases of SCLS have been reported, but the condition is probably underrecognized because of its nonspecific symptoms and signs and high mortality rate. Patients experience shock and massive edema, often after a nonspecific prodrome of weakness, fatigue, and myalgias, and are at risk for ischemia-induced organ failure, rhabdomyolysis and muscle compartment syndromes, and venous thromboembolism. Shock and edema reverse almost as quickly as they begin, at which time patients are at risk for death from flash pulmonary edema during rapid fluid remobilization. Diagnosis is made clinically and by exclusion of other diseases that cause similar symptoms and signs, most notably sepsis, anaphylaxis, and angioedema. Acute episodes are treated with vasopressor therapy and judicious fluid replacement, possibly with colloid solutions for their osmotic effects, to prevent the sequelae of underperfusion. Between episodes, patients may be treated with theophylline and terbutaline, which clinical experience suggests may reduce the severity and frequency of acute episodes. Prognosis is uncertain, but patients who survive an initial severe SCLS episode are estimated to have a 10-year survival rate greater than 70%. Much remains to be learned about SCLS, and clinicians should consider the diagnosis in patients with unexplained edema, increased hematocrit, and hypotension.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Druey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kirk M</ForeName>
            <Initials>KM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland, and Mayo Clinic College of Medicine, Rochester, Minnesota 20892, USA. kdruey@niaid.nih.gov</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Greipp</LastName>
            <ForeName>Philip R</ForeName>
            <Initials>PR</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>Z99 AI999999</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>ZIA AI001083-01</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>AI001083</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052060">Research Support, N.I.H., Intramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Intern Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0003-4819</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn">
          <RefSource>Ann Intern Med. 2010 Dec 7;153(11):764</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">21135304</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn">
          <RefSource>Ann Intern Med. 2010 Dec 7;153(11):764</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">21135305</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Capillary Leak Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20643990</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS258673</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3017349</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-153-2-201007200-00005</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">153/2/90</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkinson JP, Waldmann TA, Stein SF, et al.  Systemic capillary leak syndrome and monoclonal IgG gammopathy; studies in a sixth patient and a review of the literature. Medicine (Baltimore) 1977;56(3):225–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">870792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarkson B, Thompson D, Horwith M, Luckey EH. Cyclical edema and shock due to increased capillary permeability. Am J Med. 1960;29:193–216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13693909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noble RP, Gregersen MI, Porter PM, Buckman A. Blood Volume in Clinical Shock. I. Mixing Time and Disappearance Rate of T-1824 in Normal Subjects and in Patients in Shock; Determination of Plasma Volume in Man from 10-Minute Sample. J Clin Invest. 1946;25(2):158–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC435551</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16695305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amoura Z, Papo T, Ninet J, et al.  Systemic capillary leak syndrome: report on 13 patients with special focus on course and treatment. Am J Med. 1997;103(6):514–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9428835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawabe S, Saeki T, Yamazaki H, Nagai M, Aoyagi R, Miyamura S. Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Intern Med. 2002;41(3):211–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhir V, Arya V, Malav IC, Suryanarayanan BS, Gupta R, Dey AB. Idiopathic systemic capillary leak syndrome (SCLS): case report and systematic review of cases reported in the last 16 years. Intern Med. 2007;46(12):899–904.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17575386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gousseff M, Amoura Z. Idiopathic capillary leak syndrome. Rev Med Interne. 2009;30(9):754–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19615793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sion-Sarid R, Lerman-Sagie T, Blumkin L, Ben-Ami D, Cohen I, Houri S. Neurologic Involvement in a Child With Systemic Capillary Leak Syndrome. Pediatrics. 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20123768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert M, Launay D, Hachulla E, et al.  High-dose intravenous immunoglobulins dramatically reverse systemic capillary leak syndrome. Crit Care Med. 2008;36(7):2184–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18552679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keller K, Hauge E, Stengaard-Pedersen K. Chronic systemic capillary leak syndrome: a case responding to prednisolone treatment. Scand J Rheumatol. 2009;38(5):400–1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20166237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onal H, Aktuglu-Zeybek C, Altun G, Ozyilmaz I, Alhaj S, Aydin A. Capillary leak syndrome in a 5-month-old infant associated with intractable diarrhoea. Ann Trop Paediatr. 2007;27(1):81–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17469737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lesterhuis WJ, Rennings AJ, Leenders WP, et al.  Vascular endothelial growth factor in systemic capillary leak syndrome. Am J Med. 2009;122(6):e5–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Martino M, Sasso L, Pirozzi F, Bonaduce D. Systemic capillary leak syndrome or Clarkson’s disease: a case report. Intern Emerg Med. 2009;4(4):357–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19526356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowden AM, Rullo OJ, Aziz N, Fasano MB, Chatila T, Ballas ZK. Idiopathic systemic capillary leak syndrome: Novel therapy for acute attacks. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19703708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee YS, Kim SY, Kwon CW, et al.  Two cases of systemic capillary leak syndrome that were treated with pentastarch. Korean J Intern Med. 2007;22(2):130–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2687610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17616032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perry J, Balasubramanian S, Imray C. Systemic capillary leak syndrome resulting in compartment syndrome and the requirement for a surgical airway. Anaesthesia. 2009;64(6):679–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19453323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solomon S, Pefanis A, Papaetis GS, Ginos C, Kythreotis P, Achimastos A. A patient with recurrent episodes of abdominal pain and hypovolemic shock. Am J Emerg Med. 2009;27(6):755, e5–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingegnoli F, Sciascera A, D’Ingianna E, Fantini F. Systemic sclerosis, capillary leak syndrome and nasopharyngeal carcinoma: an unusual association or paraneoplastic manifestations? Rheumatology (Oxford) 2009;48(2):201–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19052056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kjaergaard KD, Rickers H. Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Ugeskr Laeger. 2008;170(41):3251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18940160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dams K, Meersseman W, Verbeken E, Knockaert DC. A 59-year-old man with shock, polycythemia, and an underlying paraproteinemia. Chest. 2007;132(4):1393–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17934127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumura M, Kakuchi Y, Hamano R, et al.  Systemic capillary leak syndrome associated with compartment syndrome. Intern Med. 2007;46(18):1585–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17878647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosadik A, Kettani A, Faroudy M, Sbihi A. Idiopathic capillary leak syndrome: an exceptional aetiology for shock. Ann Fr Anesth Reanim. 2007;26(7–8):715–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17574370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonadies N, Baud P, Peter HJ, Buergi U, Mueller BU. A case report of Clarkson’s disease: If you don’t know it, you’ll miss it. Eur J Intern Med. 2006;17(5):363–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16864014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanghavi R, Aneman A, Parr M, Dunlop L, Champion D. Systemic capillary leak syndrome associated with compartment syndrome and rhabdomyolysis. Anaesth Intensive Care. 2006;34(3):388–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16802499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hollenberg J, Frykman J, Lundberg LG, Forsberg S. A case report of systemic capillary leak syndrome (Clarkson’s disease) Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lions C, Wey PF, Puidupin M, Soubirou JL, Escarment J. Haemodynamic management of Clarkson’s disease: interest of the echocardiographic follow-up. Ann Fr Anesth Reanim. 2007;26(12):1079–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17964113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debourdeau P, Bory P, Zammit C, Pavic M, Colle B. Recurrent unexplained lipothymia: do not forget the capillary leak syndrome. Rev Med Interne. 2007;28(10):711–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17321012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foeldvari I, Waida E, Junker AK. Systemic capillary leak syndrome in a child. J Pediatr. 1995;127(5):739–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7472826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karatzios C, Gauvin F, Egerszegi EP, et al.  Systemic capillary leak syndrome presenting as recurrent shock. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2006;7(4):377–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16738498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cicardi M, Gardinali M, Bisiani G, Rosti A, Allavena P, Agostoni A. The systemic capillary leak syndrome: appearance of interleukin-2-receptor-positive cells during attacks. Ann Intern Med. 1990;113(6):475–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2386338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cicardi M, Berti E, Caputo V, Radice F, Gardinali M, Agostoni A. Idiopathic capillary leak syndrome: evidence of CD8-positive lymphocytes surrounding damaged endothelial cells. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 1997;99(3):417–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9058699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fellows IW, Powell RJ, Toghill PJ, Williams TJ, Cohen GF. Epoprostenol in systemic capillary leak syndrome. Lancet. 1988;2(8620):1143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2903357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinbren I. Spontaneous Periodic Oedema. A New Syndrome. Lancet. 1963;2(7307):544–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14049581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kao NL, Richmond GW, Luskin AT. Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Chest. 1993;104(5):1637–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8222853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwith M, Hagstrom JW, Riggins RC, Luckey EH. Hypovolemic shock and edema due to increased capillary permeability. Jama. 1967;200(2):101–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6071375</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fardet L, Kerob D, Rybojad M, et al.  Idiopathic systemic capillary leak syndrome: cutaneous involvement can be misleading. Dermatology. 2004;209(4):291–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15539891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacox RF, Waterhouse C, Tobin R. Periodic disease associated with muscle destruction. Am J Med. 1973;55(1):105–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4123734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doubek M, Brychtova Y, Tomiska M, Mayer J. Idiopathic systemic capillary leak syndrome misdiagnosed and treated as polycythemia vera. Acta Haematol. 2005;113(2):150–1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15802896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarro C, Garcia-Bragado F, Lima J, Fernandez JM. Muscle biopsy findings in systemic capillary leak syndrome. Hum Pathol. 1990;21(3):297–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2179110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson BR, Lofdahl CG. Ultrastructure of the microvessels in skeletal muscle in a case of systemic capillary leak syndrome. Acta Med Scand. 1979;206(5):413–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">525443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assaly R, Olson D, Hammersley J, et al.  Initial evidence of endothelial cell apoptosis as a mechanism of systemic capillary leak syndrome. Chest. 2001;120(4):1301–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11591575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hinsbergh V, van Nieuw Amerongen G. Intracellular signalling involved in modulating human endothelial barrier function. J Anat. 2002;200(5):525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1570750</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chihara R, Nakamoto H, Arima H, et al.  Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Intern Med. 2002;41(11):953–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12487166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebihara I, Hirayama K, Kaneko S, et al.  Vascular endothelial growth factor and soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1 in septic shock patients treated with direct hemoperfusion with a polymyxin B-immobilized fiber column. Ther Apher Dial. 2008;12(4):285–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18789115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albert C, Garrido N, Mercader A, et al.  The role of endothelial cells in the pathogenesis of ovarian hyperstimulation syndrome. Mol Hum Reprod. 2002;8(5):409–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dispenzieri A, Moreno-Aspitia A, Suarez GA, et al.  Peripheral blood stem cell transplantation in 16 patients with POEMS syndrome, and a review of the literature. Blood. 2004;104(10):3400–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15280195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Witzig TE, Timm M, et al.  Expression of VEGF and its receptors by myeloma cells. Leukemia. 2003;17(10):2025–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14513053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajkumar SV, Dispenzieri A, Kyle RA. Monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance, Waldenstrom macroglobulinemia, AL amyloidosis, and related plasma cell disorders: diagnosis and treatment. Mayo Clin Proc. 2006;81(5):693–703.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16706268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vigneau C, Haymann JP, Khoury N, Sraer JD, Rondeau E. An unusual evolution of the systemic capillary leak syndrome. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2002;17(3):492–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11865098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiraoka E, Matsushima Y, Inomoto-Naribayashi Y, et al.  Systemic capillary leak syndrome associated with multiple myeloma of IgG kappa type. Intern Med. 1995;34(12):1220–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8929655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh K, Madkaikar M, Iyer Y, Pathare A, Jijina F, Mohanty D. Systemic capillary leak syndrome preceding plasma cell leukaemia. Acta Haematol. 2001;106(3):118–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11713377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beermann W, Horstrup KA, Will R. Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Am J Med. 1998;105(6):554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9870846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W, Ewan PW, Lachmann PJ. The paraproteins in systemic capillary leak syndrome. Clin Exp Immunol. 1993;93(3):424–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1554918</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8370170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zivkovic SA, Lacomis D, Lentzsch S. Paraproteinemic neuropathy. Leuk Lymphoma. 2009:1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merlini G, Stone MJ. Dangerous small B-cell clones. Blood. 2006;108(8):2520–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16794250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michiels JJ, Berneman Z, Gadisseur A, et al.  Immune-mediated etiology of acquired von Willebrand syndrome in systemic lupus erythematosus and in benign monoclonal gammopathy: therapeutic implications. Semin Thromb Hemost. 2006;32(6):577–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16977568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzi R, Curci P, Rinaldi E, et al.  Schnitzler’s syndrome: monoclonal gammopathy associated with chronic urticaria. Acta Haematol. 2008;120(1):1–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18612198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cugno M, Castelli R, Cicardi M. Angioedema due to acquired C1-inhibitor deficiency: a bridging condition between autoimmunity and lymphoproliferation. Autoimmun Rev. 2008;8(2):156–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahirkheli NK, Greipp PR. Treatment of the systemic capillary leak syndrome with terbutaline and theophylline. A case series. Ann Intern Med. 1999;130(11):905–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10375339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Airaghi L, Montori D, Santambrogio L, Miadonna A, Tedeschi A. Chronic systemic capillary leak syndrome. Report of a case and review of the literature. J Intern Med. 2000;247(6):731–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10886496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stirling CM, Boulton-Jones JM, Simpson K. Progressive oedema in a 30-year-old. Lancet. 1998;352(9126):450.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9708754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolberg-Stolik OC, Putterman C, Rubinow A, Rivkind AI, Sprung CL. Idiopathic capillary leak syndrome complicated by massive rhabdomyolysis. Chest. 1993;104(1):123–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8325053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Droder RM, Kyle RA, Greipp PR. Control of systemic capillary leak syndrome with aminophylline and terbutaline. Am J Med. 1992;92(5):523–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1580299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doorenbos CJ, van Es A, Valentijn RM, van Es LA. Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Preventive treatment with terbutaline. Neth J Med. 1988;32(3–4):178–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3362269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koga H, Tokunaga Y, Hisamoto T, et al.  Ratio of serum vascular endothelial growth factor to platelet count correlates with disease activity in a patient with POEMS syndrome. Eur J Intern Med. 2002;13(1):70–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11836087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuwabara S, Misawa S, Kanai K, et al.  Thalidomide reduces serum VEGF levels and improves peripheral neuropathy in POEMS syndrome. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79(11):1255–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staak JO, Glossmann JP, Esser JM, Diehl V, Mietz H, Josting A. Thalidomide for systemic capillary leak syndrome. Am J Med. 2003;115(4):332–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12967704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dybowski F, Sepp N, Bergerhausen HJ, Braun J. Successful use of anakinra to treat refractory Schnitzler’s syndrome. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2008;26(2):354–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crouch R, Akhras V, Sarkany R. Schnitzler’s syndrome: successful treatment with anakinra. Australas J Dermatol. 2007;48(3):178–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17680970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lust JA, Lacy MQ, Zeldenrust SR, et al.  Induction of a chronic disease state in patients with smoldering or indolent multiple myeloma by targeting interleukin 1{beta}-induced interleukin 6 production and the myeloma proliferative component. Mayo Clin Proc. 2009;84(2):114–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2664581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19181644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teelucksingh S, Padfield PL, Edwards CR. Systemic capillary leak syndrome. Q J Med. 1990;75(277):515–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2201996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng L, Xu H, Chew TL, et al.  HMG CoA reductase inhibition modulates VEGF-induced endothelial cell hyperpermeability by preventing RhoA activation and myosin regulatory light chain phosphorylation. Faseb J. 2005;19(13):1845–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16160062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Wang JJ, Chen D, et al.  Systemic administration of HMG-CoA reductase inhibitor protects the blood-retinal barrier and ameliorates retinal inflammation in type 2 diabetes. Exp Eye Res. 2009;89(1):71–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19254713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobson JR, Barnard JW, Grigoryev DN, Ma SF, Tuder RM, Garcia JG. Simvastatin attenuates vascular leak and inflammation in murine inflammatory lung injury. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2005;288(6):L1026–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15665042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell’Omo G, Bandinelli S, Penno G, Pedrinelli R, Mariani M. Simvastatin, capillary permeability, and acetylcholine-mediated vasomotion in atherosclerotic, hypercholesterolemic men. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2000;68(4):427–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11061583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gavard J, Gutkind JS. VEGF controls endothelial-cell permeability by promoting the beta-arrestin-dependent endocytosis of VE-cadherin. Nat Cell Biol. 2006;8(11):1223–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17060906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang X, Wu D, Jin H, Stupack D, Wang JY. Induction of cell retraction by the combined actions of Abl-CrkII and Rho-ROCK1 signaling. J Cell Biol. 2008;183(4):711–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2582888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen BM, Beaven MA, Iwaki S, Metcalfe DD, Gilfillan AM. Concurrent inhibition of kit- and FcepsilonRI-mediated signaling: coordinated suppression of mast cell activation. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2008;324(1):128–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17925481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunton VG, Frame MC. Src and focal adhesion kinase as therapeutic targets in cancer. Curr Opin Pharmacol. 2008;8(4):427–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18625340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliceiri BP, Paul R, Schwartzberg PL, Hood JD, Leng J, Cheresh DA. Selective requirement for Src kinases during VEGF-induced angiogenesis and vascular permeability. Mol Cell. 1999;4(6):915–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10635317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gherardi RK, Belec L, Soubrier M, et al.  Overproduction of proinflammatory cytokines imbalanced by their antagonists in POEMS syndrome. Blood. 1996;87(4):1458–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8608236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soubrier M, Sauron C, Souweine B, et al.  Growth factors and proinflammatory cytokines in the renal involvement of POEMS syndrome. Am J Kidney Dis. 1999;34(4):633–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10516342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrara N, Gerber HP, LeCouter J. The biology of VEGF and its receptors. Nat Med. 2003;9(6):669–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12778165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumpers P, David S, Haubitz M, et al.  The Tie2 receptor antagonist Angiopoietin-2 facilitates vascular inflammation in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis. 2008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18930996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang ZY, Duckers HJ, Sullivan NJ, Sanchez A, Nabel EG, Nabel GJ. Identification of the Ebola virus glycoprotein as the main viral determinant of vascular cell cytotoxicity and injury. Nat Med. 2000;6(8):886–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10932225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wahl-Jensen VM, Afanasieva TA, Seebach J, Stroher U, Feldmann H, Schnittler HJ. Effects of Ebola virus glycoproteins on endothelial cell activation and barrier function. J Virol. 2005;79(16):10442–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1182673</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
