<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">20807070</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2010</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1557-8992</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2010</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of child and adolescent psychopharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The immunobiology of Tourette's disorder, pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with Streptococcus, and related disorders: a way forward.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>317</StartPage>
          <EndPage>331</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>317-31</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1089/cap.2010.0043</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) and related conditions including Tourette's disorder (TD) are chronic, relapsing disorders of unknown etiology associated with marked impairment and disability. Associated immune dysfunction has been reported and debated in the literature since the late 80s. The immunologic culprit receiving the most interest has been Group A Streptococcus (GAS), which began to receive attention as a potential cause of neuropsychiatric symptoms, following the investigation of the symptoms reported in Sydenham's chorea (SC) and rheumatic fever, such as motor tics, vocal tics, and both obsessive-compulsive and attention deficit/hyperactivity symptoms. Young children have been described as having a sudden onset of these neuropsychiatric symptoms temporally associated with GAS, but without supporting evidence of rheumatic fever. This presentation of OCD and tics has been termed pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with Streptococcus (PANDAS). Of note, SC, OCD, and TD often begin in early childhood and share common anatomic areas--the basal ganglia of the brain and the related cortical and thalamic sites--adding support to the possibility that these disorders might share a common immunologic and/or genetic vulnerability. Relevant manuscripts were identified through searches of the PsycINFO and MedLine databases using the following keywords: OCD, immune, PANDAS, Sydenham chorea, Tourette's disorder Group A Streptococcus. Articles were also identified through reference lists from research articles and other materials on childhood OCD, PANDAS, and TD between 1966 and December 2010. Considering the overlap of clinical and neuroanatomic findings among these disorders, this review explores evidence regarding the immunobiology as well as the relevant clinical and therapeutic aspects of TD, OCD, and PANDAS.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Murphy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tanya K</ForeName>
            <Initials>TK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Psychiatry, University of South Florida, St Petersburg, Florida 33701, USA. tmurphy@health.usf.edu</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kurlan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roger</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leckman</LastName>
            <ForeName>James</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R25 MH077823</GrantID>
            <Acronym>MH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9105358</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1044-5463</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001289" MajorTopicYN="N">Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020274" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune Diseases of the Nervous System</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009771" MajorTopicYN="N">Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013290" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcal Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020323" MajorTopicYN="N">Tics</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005879" MajorTopicYN="N">Tourette Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807070</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4003464</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2010.0043</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albin RL. Young AB. Penney JB. The functional anatomy of basal ganglia disorders. Trends Neurosci. 1989;12:366–375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2479133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen AJ. Leonard HL. Swedo SE. Case study: A new infection-triggered, autoimmune subtype of pediatric OCD and Tourette's syndrome. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1995;34:307–311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7896671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axley J. Rheumatic chorea controlled with haloperidol. J Pediatr. 1972;81:1216–1217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4643046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayoub EM. Resurgence of rheumatic fever in the United States. The changing picture of a preventable illness. Postgrad Med. 1992;92:133–136. 139–142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1518750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benatar A. Beatty DW. Human DG. Immunological abnormalities in children with acute rheumatic carditis and acute post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis. Int J Cardiol. 1988;21:51–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3220602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berrios X. Quesney F. Morales A. Blazquez J. Bisno AL. Are all recurrences of “pure” Sydenham chorea true recurrences of acute rheumatic fever? J Pediatr. 1985;107:867–872.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3906071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Besser MJ. Ganor Y. Levite M. Dopamine by itself activates either D2, D3 or D1/D5 dopaminergic receptors in normal human T-cells and triggers the selective secretion of either IL-10, TNFalpha or both. J Neuroimmunol. 2005;169:161–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16150496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bisno AL. Brito MO. Collins CM. Molecular basis of group A streptococcal virulence. Lancet Infect Dis. 2003;3:191–200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12679262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bloch MH. Peterson BS. Scahill L. Otka J. Katsovich L. Zhang H, et al.  Adulthood outcome of tic and obsessive-compulsive symptom severity in children with Tourette syndrome. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2006;160:65–69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2291298</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16389213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bloem A. Zenke G. Eichmann K. Emmrich F. Human immune response to group A streptococcal carbohydrate (A-CHO). II. Antigen-independent stimulation of IgM anti-A-CHO production in purified B cells by a monoclonal anti-idiotopic antibody. J Immunol. 1988;140:277–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2447171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bombaci M. Grifantini R. Mora M. Reguzzi V. Petracca R. Meoni E, et al.  Protein array profiling of tic patient sera reveals a broad range, enhanced immune response against Group A Streptococcus antigens. PLoS One. 2009;4:e6332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2709431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19623252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bornstein RA. Stefl ME. Hammond L. A survey of Tourette syndrome patients and their families: The 1987 Ohio Tourette Survey. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 1990;2:275–281.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2136086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brambilla F. Bellodi L. Perna G. Arancio C. Bertani A. Dopamine function in obsessive-compulsive disorder: Growth hormone response to apomorphine stimulation. Biol Psychiatry. 1997;42:889–897.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9359974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronze MS. Dale JB. Epitopes of streptococcal M proteins that evoke antibodies that cross-react with human brain. J Immunol. 1993;151:2820–2828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7689617</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brooks BM. Hart CA. Coleman JW. Differential effects of beta-lactams on human IFN-gamma activity. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2005;56:1122–1125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brooks BM. Thomas AL. Coleman JW. Benzylpenicillin differentially conjugates to IFN-gamma, TNF-alpha, IL-1beta, IL-4 and IL-13 but selectively reduces IFN-gamma activity. Clin Exp Immunol. 2003;131:268–274.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1808618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budman C. Coffey B. Dure L. Gilbert D. Juncos J. Kaplan E, et al.  Regarding antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;58:916–917.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16242121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona F. Orefici G. Group A streptococcal infections and tic disorders in an Italian pediatric population. J Pediatr. 2001;138:71–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona F. Romano A. Cundari G. Ventriglia F. Versacci P. Orefici G. Colour Doppler echocardiography in children with group A streptococcal infection related tic disorders. Indian J Med Res. 2004;119(Suppl):186–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15232192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chappell P. Leckman J. Goodman W. Bissette G. Pauls D. Anderson G, et al.  Elevated cerebrospinal fluid corticotropin-releasing factor in Tourette's syndrome: Comparison to obsessive compulsive disorder and normal controls. Biol Psychiatry. 1996;39:776–783.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8731518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chappell P. Riddle M. Anderson G. Scahill L. Hardin M. Walker D, et al.  Enhanced stress responsivity of Tourette syndrome patients undergoing lumbar puncture. Biol Psychiatry. 1994;36:35–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8080901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charmandari E. Kino T. Souvatzoglou E. Chrousos GP. Pediatric stress: hormonal mediators and human development. Horm Res. 2003;59:161–179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12649570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Church AJ. Cardoso F. Dale RC. Lees AJ. Thompson EJ. Giovannoni G. Anti-basal ganglia antibodies in acute and persistent Sydenham's chorea. Neurology. 2002;59:227–231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12136062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbett BA. Mendoza SP. Baym CL. Bunge SA. Levine S. Examining cortisol rhythmicity and responsivity to stress in children with Tourette syndrome. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2008;33:810–820.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2547137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18487023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crispin JC. Martinez A. Alcocer-Varela J. Quantification of regulatory T cells in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Autoimmun. 2003;21:273–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14599852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham M. Perry H. Autoimmunity and behavior: Sydenham's Chorea and related disorders. Paper presented at the 9th International Congress of Neuroimmunology; Fort Worth, TX. 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czerkinsky C. Prince SJ. Michalek SM. Jackson S. Russell MW. Moldoveanu Z, et al.  IgA antibody-producing cells in peripheral blood after antigen ingestion: Evidence for a common mucosal immune system in humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1987;84:2449–2453.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC304669</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3470804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC. Candler PM. Church AJ. Wait R. Pocock JM. Giovannoni G. Neuronal surface glycolytic enzymes are autoantigen targets in post-streptococcal autoimmune CNS disease. J Neuroimmunol. 2006;172:187–197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16356555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC. Church AJ. Cardoso F. Goddard E. Cox TC. Chong WK, et al.  Poststreptococcal acute disseminated encephalomyelitis with basal ganglia involvement and auto-reactive antibasal ganglia antibodies. Ann Neurol. 2001;50:588–595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC. Heyman I. Giovannoni G. Church AW. Incidence of anti-brain antibodies in children with obsessive-compulsive disorder. Br J Psychiatry. 2005;187:314–319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Kleer IM. Wedderburn LR. Taams LS. Patel A. Varsani H. Klein M, et al.  CD4+CD25 bright regulatory T cells actively regulate inflammation in the joints of patients with the remitting form of juvenile idiopathic arthritis. J Immunol. 2004;172:6435–6443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15128835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denys D. Fluitman S. Kavelaars A. Heijnen C. Westenberg H. Decreased TNF-alpha and NK activity in obsessive-compulsive disorder. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2004;29:945–952.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15177711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diamond A. Kenney C. Jankovic J. Effect of vagal nerve stimulation in a case of Tourette's syndrome and complex partial epilepsy. Mov Disord. 2006;21:1273–1275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16703589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DiFazio MP. Morales J. Davis R. Acute myoclonus secondary to group A beta-hemolytic Streptococcus infection: A PANDAS variant. J Child Neurol. 1998;13:516–518.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9796759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dranitzki Z. Steiner I. PANDAS in siblings: a common risk? Eur J Neurol. 2007;14:e4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17539928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du X. Tang Y. Xu H. Lit L. Walker W. Ashwood P, et al.  Genomic profiles for human peripheral blood T cells, B cells, natural killer cells, monocytes, and polymorphonuclear cells: Comparisons to ischemic stroke, migraine, and Tourette syndrome. Genomics. 2006;87:693–703.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16546348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efstratiou A. Group A streptococci in the 1990s. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2000;45(Suppl):3–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10759357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ercan TE. Ercan G. Severge B. Arpaozu M. Karasu G. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection and obsessive-compulsive disease: a case report. J Child Neurol. 2008;23:338–340.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18079308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrari M. Termine C. Franciotta D. Castiglioni E. Pagani A. Lanzi G, et al.  Dopaminergic receptor D5 mRNA expression is increased in circulating lymphocytes of Tourette syndrome patients. J Psychiatr Res. 2008;43:24–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabbay V. Coffey BJ. Babb JS. Meyer L. Wachtel C. Anam S, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with Streptococcus: Comparison of diagnosis and treatment in the community and at a specialty clinic. Pediatrics. 2008;122:273–278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabbay V. Coffey BJ. Guttman LE. Gottlieb L. Katz Y. Babb JS, et al.  A cytokine study in children and adolescents with Tourette's disorder. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2009;33:967–971.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19427348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey MA. Perlmutter SJ. Allen AJ. Hamburger S. Lougee L. Leonard HL, et al.  A pilot study of penicillin prophylaxis for neuropsychiatric exacerbations triggered by streptococcal infections. Biol Psychiatry. 1999;45:1564–1571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10376116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey MA. Snider LA. Leitman SF. Werden R. Swedo SE. Treatment of Sydenham's chorea with intravenous immunoglobulin, plasma exchange, or prednisone. J Child Neurol. 2005;20:424–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15968928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gause C. Morris C. Vernekar S. Pardo-Villamizar C. Grados MA. Singer HS. Antineuronal antibodies in OCD: Comparisons in children with OCD-only, OCD+chronic tics and OCD+PANDAS. J Neuroimmunol. 2009;214:118–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19628285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gebremariam A. Sydenham's chorea: Risk factors and the role of prophylactic benzathine penicillin G in preventing recurrence. Ann Trop Paediatr. 1999;19:161–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10690256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giedd JN. Rapoport JL. Garvey MA. Perlmutter S. Swedo SE. MRI assessment of children with obsessive-compulsive disorder or tics associated with streptococcal infection. Am J Psychiatry. 2000;157:281–283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10671403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giedd JN. Rapoport JL. Leonard HL. Richter D. Swedo SE. Case study: Acute basal ganglia enlargement and obsessive-compulsive symptoms in an adolescent boy. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1996;35:913–915.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8768351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodman WK. McDougle CJ. Price LH. Riddle MA. Pauls DL. Leckman JF. Beyond the serotonin hypothesis: A role for dopamine in some forms of obsessive compulsive disorder? J Clin Psychiatry. 1990;51(Suppl):36–43. discussion 55–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2199433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallett JJ. Harling-Berg CJ. Knopf PM. Stopa EG. Kiessling LS. Anti-striatal antibodies in Tourette syndrome cause neuronal dysfunction. J Neuroimmunol. 2000;111:195–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11063838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirschtritt ME. Hammond CJ. Luckenbaugh D. Buhle J. Thurm AE. Casey BJ, et al.  Executive and attention functioning among children in the PANDAS subgroup. Child Neuropsychol. 2009;15:179–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18622810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ. Anderson GM. Troost PW. Kallenberg CG. Minderaa RB. Plasma kynurenine and related measures in tic disorder patients. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2007;16(Suppl 1):71–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ. Manson WL. Steenhuis MP. Kallenberg CG. Minderaa RB. Association of common cold with exacerbations in pediatric but not adult patients with tic disorder: A prospective longitudinal study. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2005;15:285–292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15910212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ. Minderaa RB. Kallenberg CG. Lack of effect of intravenous immunoglobulins on tics: A double-blind placebo-controlled study. J Clin Psychiatry. 2004;65:537–542.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15119917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman KL. Hornig M. Yaddanapudi K. Jabado O. Lipkin WI. A murine model for neuropsychiatric disorders associated with group A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection. J Neurosci. 2004;24:1780–1791.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14973249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong JJ. Loiselle CR. Yoon DY. Lee O. Becker KG. Singer HS. Microarray analysis in Tourette syndrome postmortem putamen. J Neurol Sci. 2004;225:57–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15465086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husby G. van de Rijn I. Zabriskie JB. Abdin ZH. Williams RC. Antibodies reacting with cytoplasm of subthalamic and caudate nuclei neurons in chorea and acute rheumatic fever. J Exp Med. 1976;144:1094–1110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2190435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">789810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacob CM. Pastorino AC. Fahl K. Carneiro-Sampaio M. Monteiro RC. Autoimmunity in IgA deficiency: revisiting the role of IgA as a silent housekeeper. J Clin Immunol. 2008;28(Suppl 1):S56–S61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin R. Zheng RY. Huang WW. Xu HQ. Shao B. Chen H, et al.  Epidemiological survey of Tourette syndrome in children and adolescents in Wenzhou of P.R China. Eur J Epidemiol. 2005;20:925–927.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson DR. Kurlan R. Leckman J. Kaplan EL. The human immune response to streptococcal extracellular antigens: Clinical, diagnostic, and potential pathogenetic implications. Clin Infect Dis. 2010;50:481–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20067422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kansy JW. Katsovich L. McIver KS. Pick J. Zabriskie JB. Lombroso PJ, et al.  Identification of pyruvate kinase as an antigen associated with Tourette syndrome. J Neuroimmunol. 2006;181:165–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1853370</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17011640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kantor L. Hewlett GH. Gnegy ME. Enhanced amphetamine- and K+-mediated dopamine release in rat striatum after repeated amphetamine: differential requirements for Ca2+- and calmodulin-dependent phosphorylation and synaptic vesicles. J Neurosci. 1999;19:3801–3808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6782702</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10234012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan EL. Rothermel CD. Johnson DR. Antistreptolysin O and Anti-Deoxyribonuclease B titers: Normal values for children ages 2 to 12 in the United States. Pediatrics. 1998;101:86–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9417157</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karno M. Golding JM. Sorenson SB. Burnam MA. The epidemiology of obsessive-compulsive disorder in five US communities. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1988;45:1094–1099.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3264144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawikova I. Grady BP. Tobiasova Z. Zhang Y. Vojdani A. Katsovich L, et al.  Children with Tourette's syndrome may suffer immunoglobulin A dysgammaglobulinemia: Preliminary report. Biol Psychiatry. 2010;67:679–683.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3974615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20006327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawikova I. Leckman JF. Kronig H. Katsovich L. Bessen DE. Ghebremichael M, et al.  Decreased numbers of regulatory T cells suggest impaired immune tolerance in children with tourette syndrome: a preliminary study. Biol Psychiatry. 2007;61:273–278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khalifa N. von Knorring AL. Prevalence of tic disorders and Tourette syndrome in a Swedish school population. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2003;45:315–319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12729145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiessling LS. Marcotte AC. Culpepper L. Antineuronal antibodies in movement disorders. Pediatrics. 1993;92:39–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8516083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HS. Park H. Cho IY. Paik HD. Park E. Dietary supplementation of probiotic Bacillus polyfermenticus, Bispan strain, modulates natural killer cell and T cell subset populations and immunoglobulin G levels in human subjects. J Med Food. 2006;9:321–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17004893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kipnis J. Cardon M. Avidan H. Lewitus GM. Mordechay S. Rolls A, et al.  Dopamine, through the extracellular signal-regulated kinase pathway, downregulates CD4+CD25+ regulatory T-cell activity: Implications for neurodegeneration. J Neurosci. 2004;24:6133–6143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15240805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirvan CA. Swedo SE. Heuser JS. Cunningham MW. Mimicry and autoantibody-mediated neuronal cell signaling in Sydenham chorea. Nat Med. 2003;9:914–920.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12819778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirvan CA. Swedo SE. Kurahara D. Cunningham MW. Streptococcal mimicry and antibody-mediated cell signaling in the pathogenesis of Sydenham's chorea. Autoimmunity. 2006;39:21–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16455579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korn-Lubetzki I. Brand A. Steiner I. Recurrence of Sydenham chorea: Implications for pathogenesis. Arch Neurol. 2004;61:1261–1264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotby AA. El Badawy N. El Sokkary S. Moawad H. El Shawarby M. Antineuronal antibodies in rheumatic chorea. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 1998;5:836–839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC96212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9801345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krause RM. A half-century of streptococcal research: Then now. Indian J Med Res. 2002;115:215–241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12440194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubera N. Lin AH. Kenis G. Bosmans E. van Bockstaele D. Maes M. Anti-inflammatory effects of antidepressants through suppression of the interferon-gamma/interleukin-10 production ratio. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2001;21:199–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11270917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuelz AK. Hohagen F. Voderholzer U. Neuropsychological performance in obsessive-compulsive disorder: A critical review. Biol Psychol. 2004;65:185–236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14757309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kukreja A. Cost G. Marker J. Zhang C. Sun Z. Lin-Su K, et al.  Multiple immuno-regulatory defects in type-1 diabetes. J Clin Invest. 2002;109:131–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150819</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11781358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R. Johnson D. Kaplan EL. Streptococcal infection and exacerbations of childhood tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: A prospective blinded cohort study. Pediatrics. 2008;121:1188–1197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R. Kaplan EL. The pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection (PANDAS) etiology for tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: Hypothesis or entity? Practical considerations for the clinician. Pediatrics. 2004;113:883–886.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15060240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kushner HI. Kiessling LS. The controversy over the classification of Gilles de la Tourette's syndrome, 1800–1995. Perspect Biol Med. 1996;39:409–435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8657554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langlois M. Force L. Nosologic and clinical revision of Gilles de la Tourette disease evoked by the action of certain neuroloeptics on its course. Rev Neurol. 1965;113:641–645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4379216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF. Katsovich L. Kawikova I. Lin H. Zhang H. Kronig H, et al.  Increased serum levels of interleukin-12 and tumor necrosis factor-alpha in Tourette's syndrome. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;57:667–673.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15780855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leslie DL. Kozma L. Martin A. Landeros A. Katsovich L. King RA, et al.  Neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection: A case-control study among privately insured children. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2008;47:1166–1172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2783578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18724258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H. Katsovich L. Ghebremichael M. Findley DB. Grantz H. Lombroso PJ, et al.  Psychosocial stress predicts future symptom severities in children and adolescents with Tourette syndrome and/or obsessive-compulsive disorder. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2007;48:157–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3073143</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17300554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H. Williams KA. Katsovich L. Findley DB. Grantz H. Lombroso PJ, et al.  Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and psychosocial stress predict future tic and obsessive-compulsive symptom severity in children and adolescents with Tourette syndrome and obsessive-compulsive disorder. Biol Psychiatry. 2009;67:684–691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2843763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lit L. Gilbert DL. Walker W. Sharp FR. A subgroup of Tourette's patients overexpress specific natural killer cell genes in blood: A preliminary report. Am J Med Genet B Neuropsychiatr Genet. 2007;144B:958–963.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17503477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loiselle CR. Lee O. Moran TH. Singer HS. Striatal microinfusion of Tourette syndrome and PANDAS sera: Failure to induce behavioral changes. Mov Disord. 2004;19:390–396.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lougee L. Perlmutter SJ. Nicolson R. Garvey MA. Swedo SE. Psychiatric disorders in first-degree relatives of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections (PANDAS) J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2000;39:1120–1126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10986808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo F. Leckman JF. Katsovich L. Findley D. Grantz H. Tucker DM, et al.  Prospective longitudinal study of children with tic disorders and/or obsessive-compulsive disorder: relationship of symptom exacerbations to newly acquired streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2004;113:e578–e585.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D. Church AJ. Dale RC. Giovannoni G. Antibasal ganglia antibodies and PANDAS. Mov Disord. 2005;20:116–117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15382207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D. Defazio G. Church AJ. Dale RC. Giovannoni G. Robertson MM, et al.  Antineuronal antibody status and phenotype analysis in Tourette's syndrome. Mov Disord. 2007;22:1424–1429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17516471</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D. Defazio G. Giovannoni G. The PANDAS subgroup of tic disorders and childhood-onset obsessive-compulsive disorder. J Psychosom Res. 2009;67:547–557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19913659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matarese G. Carrieri PB. La Cava A. Perna F. Sanna V. De Rosa V, et al.  Leptin increase in multiple sclerosis associates with reduced number of CD4(+)CD25+regulatory T cells. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2005;102:5150–5155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC555982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo M. Tsuchiya K. Hamasaki Y. Singer HS. Restless legs syndrome: Association with streptococcal or mycoplasma infection. Pediatr Neurol. 2004;31:119–121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDonald MI. Towers RJ. Andrews RM. Benger N. Currie BJ. Carapetis JR. Low rates of streptococcal pharyngitis and high rates of pyoderma in Australian aboriginal communities where acute rheumatic fever is hyperendemic. Clin Infect Dis. 2006;43:683–689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16912939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mell LK. Davis RL. Owens D. Association between streptococcal infection and obsessive-compulsive disorder, Tourette's syndrome, and tic disorder. Pediatrics. 2005;116:56–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercadante MT. Busatto GF. Lombroso PJ. Prado L. Rossario-Campos MC. do Valle R, et al.  The psychiatric symptoms of rheumatic fever. Am J Psychiatry. 2000;157:2036–2038.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11097972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miettinen M. Matikainen S. Vuopio-Varkila J. Pirhonen J. Varkila K. Kurimoto M, et al.  Lactobacilli and streptococci induce interleukin-12 (IL-12), IL-18, and gamma interferon production in human peripheral blood mononuclear cells. Infect Immun. 1998;66:6058–6062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC108774</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9826398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mittleman BB. Castellanos FX. Jacobsen LK. Rapoport JL. Swedo SE. Shearer GM. Cerebrospinal fluid cytokines in pediatric neuropsychiatric disease. J Immunol. 1997;159:2994–2999.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9300724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moller JC. Tackenberg B. Heinzel-Gutenbrunner M. Burmester R. Oertel WH. Bandmann O, et al.  Immunophenotyping in Tourette syndrome—A pilot study. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15:749–753.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18484991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteleone P. Catapano F. Fabrazzo M. Tortorella A. Maj M. Decreased blood levels of tumor necrosis factor-alpha in patients with obsessive-compulsive disorder. Neuropsychobiology. 1998;37:182–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9648125</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morer A. Lazaro L. Sabater L. Massana J. Castro J. Graus F. Antineuronal antibodies in a group of children with obsessive-compulsive disorder and Tourette syndrome. J Psychiatr Res. 2008;42:64–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17113107</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morer A. Wookjin C. Henegariu O. Bothwell ALM. Leckman JF. Kawikova I. Elevated expression of MCP-1, IL-2, PTPR-N in basal ganglia of Tourette syndrome cases. Brain Behav Immun. 2010 Mar 1; [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20193755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris CM. Pardo-Villamizar C. Gause CD. Singer HS. Serum autoantibodies measured by immunofluorescence confirm a failure to differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. J Neurol Sci. 2009;276:45–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18823914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morshed SA. Parveen S. Leckman JF. Mercadante MT. Bittencourt Kiss MH. Miguel EC, et al.  Antibodies against neural, nuclear, cytoskeletal, and streptococcal epitopes in children and adults with Tourette's syndrome, Sydenham's chorea, and autoimmune disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2001;50:566–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11690591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy ML. Pichichero ME. Prospective identification and treatment of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with group A streptococcal infection (PANDAS) Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2002;156:356–361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK. Husted DS. Edge PJ.  Preclinical/Clinical Evidence of Central Nervous System Infectious Etiology in PANDAS. In: Walkup J.T., editor; Mink J.W., editor; Hollenbeck P.J., editor. Advances in Neurology: Tourette Syndrome. Vol. 99. Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams Wilkins; 2006. pp. 148–158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16536361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK. Sajid M. Soto O. Shapira N. Edge P. Yang M, et al.  Detecting pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with Streptococcus in children with obsessive-compulsive disorder and tics. Biol Psychiatry. 2004;55:61–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14706426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK. Snider LA. Mutch PJ. Harden E. Zaytoun A. Edge PJ, et al.  Relationship of movements and behaviors to Group A Streptococcus infections in elementary school children. Biol Psychiatry. 2007;61:279–284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17126304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murr C. Gerlach D. Widner B. Dierich MP. Fuchs D. Neopterin production and tryptophan degradation in humans infected by Streptococcus pyogenes. Med Microbiol Immunol (Berl) 2001;189:161–163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11388614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolson R. Swedo SE. Lenane M. Bedwell J. Wudarsky M. Gochman P, et al.  An open trial of plasma exchange in childhood-onset obsessive-compulsive disorder without poststreptococcal exacerbations. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2000;39:1313–1315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11026187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norhagen G. Engstrom PE. Hammarstrom L. Soder PO. Smith CI. Immunoglobulin levels in saliva in individuals with selective IgA deficiency: Compensatory IgM secretion and its correlation with HLA and susceptibility to infections. J Clin Immunol. 1989;9:279–286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2768433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paluck E. Katzenstein D. Frankish CJ. Herbert CP. Milner R. Speert D, et al.  Prescribing practices and attitudes toward giving children antibiotics. Can Fam Physician. 2001;47:521–527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2018393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11281085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavone P. Bianchini R. Parano E. Incorpora G. Rizzo R. Mazzone L, et al.  Anti-brain antibodies in PANDAS versus uncomplicated streptococcal infection. Pediatr Neurol. 2004;30:107–110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14984902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perlmutter SJ. Leitman SF. Garvey MA. Hamburger S. Feldman E. Leonard HL, et al.  Therapeutic plasma exchange and intravenous immunoglobulin for obsessive-compulsive disorder and tic disorders in childhood. Lancet. 1999;354:1153–1158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrin EM. Murphy ML. Casey JR. Pichichero ME. Runyan DK. Miller WC, et al.  Does group A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection increase risk for behavioral and neuropsychiatric symptoms in children? Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2004;158:848–856.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson BS. Leckman JF. Tucker D. Scahill L. Staib L. Zhang H, et al.  Preliminary findings of antistreptococcal antibody titers and basal ganglia volumes in tic, obsessive-compulsive, and attention deficit/hyperactivity disorders. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2000;57:364–372.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittenger C. Krystal JH. Coric V. Glutamate-modulating drugs as novel pharmacotherapeutic agents in the treatment of obsessive-compulsive disorder. NeuroRx. 2006;3:69–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puxley F. Midtsund M. Iosif A. Lask B. PANDAS anorexia nervosa—Endangered, extinct or nonexistent? Int J Eat Disord. 2008;41:15–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17922534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Read SE. Reid HF. Fischetti VA. Poon-King T. Ramkissoon R. McDowell M, et al.  Serial studies on the cellular immune response to streptococcal antigens in acute and convalescent rheumatic fever patients in Trinidad. J Clin Immunol. 1986;6:433–441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3536986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renneberg J. Soderstrom M. Prellner K. Forsgren A. Christensen P. Age-related variations in anti-streptococcal antibody levels. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 1989;8:792–795.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2512149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts-Lewis JM. Welsh MJ. Gnegy ME. Chronic amphetamine treatment increases striatal calmodulin in rats. Brain Res. 1986;384:383–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2946359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothstein JD. Patel S. Regan MR. Haenggeli C. Huang YH. Bergles DE, et al.  Beta-lactam antibiotics offer neuroprotection by increasing glutamate transporter expression. Nature. 2005;433:73–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15635412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabharwal H. Michon F. Nelson D. Dong W. Fuchs K. Manjarrez RC, et al.  Group A Streptococcus (GAS) carbohydrate as an immunogen for protection against GAS infection. J Infect Dis. 2006;193:129–135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16323141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanchez-Carpintero R. Albesa SA. Crespo N. Villoslada P. Narbona J. A preliminary study of the frequency of anti-basal ganglia antibodies and streptococcal infection in attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. J Neurol. 2009;256:1103–1108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19288046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scahill L. Erenberg G. Berlin CM., Jr. Budman C. Coffey BJ. Jankovic J, et al.  Contemporary assessment and pharmacotherapy of Tourette syndrome. NeuroRx. 2006;3:192–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16554257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag A. Gilbert R. Giovannoni G. Robertson MM. Metcalfe C. Ben-Shlomo Y. Streptococcal infection, Tourette syndrome, and OCD: Is there a connection? Neurology. 2009;73:1256–1263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2889814</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19794128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segarra AR. Murphy TK. Cardiac involvement in children with PANDAS. Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry. 2008;47:603–604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sela S. Neeman R. Keller N. Barzilai A. Relationship between asymptomatic carriage of Streptococcus pyogenes and the ability of the strains to adhere to and be internalised by cultured epithelial cells. J Med Microbiol. 2000;49:499–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10847202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selling L. The role of infection in the etiology of tics. Arch Neurol Psychiatry. 1929;22:1163–1171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shet A. Kaplan EL. Clinical use and interpretation of group A streptococcal antibody tests: a practical approach for the pediatrician or primary care physician. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2002;21:420–426. quiz 427–430.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12150180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS. Gause C. Morris C. Lopez P. Serial immune markers do not correlate with clinical exacerbations in pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2008;121:1198–1205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS. Giuliano JD. Zimmerman AM. Walkup JT. Infection: A stimulus for tic disorders. Pediatr Neurol. 2000;22:380–383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10913730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS. Hong JJ. Yoon DY. Williams PN. Serum autoantibodies do not differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. Neurology. 2005;65:1701–1707.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16207842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS. Loiselle CR. Lee O. Minzer K. Swedo S. Grus FH. Anti-basal ganglia antibodies in PANDAS. Mov Disord. 2004;19:406–415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS. PANDAS and immunomodulatory therapy. Lancet. 1999;354:1137–1138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA. Lougee L. Slattery M. Grant P. Swedo SE. Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;57:788–792.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA. Sachdev V. MaCkaronis JE. St. Peter M. Swedo SE. Echocardiographic findings in the PANDAS subgroup. Pediatrics. 2004;114:e748–e751.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15545618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sokol MS. Infection-triggered anorexia nervosa in children: Clinical description of four cases. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2000;10:133–145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10933123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storch EA. Murphy TK. Geffken GR. Mann G. Adkins J. Merlo LJ, et al.  Cognitive-behavioral therapy for PANDAS-related obsessive-compulsive disorder: Findings from a preliminary waitlist controlled open trial. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2006;45:1171–1178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE. Leonard HL. Garvey M. Mittleman B. Allen AJ. Perlmutter S, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: Clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry. 1998;155:264–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE. Leonard HL. Childhood movement disorders and obsessive compulsive disorder. J Clin Psychiatry. 1994;55(Suppl):32–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7915713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tait AS. Butts CL. Sternberg EM. The role of glucocorticoids and progestins in inflammatory, autoimmune, and infectious disease. J Leukoc Biol. 2008;84:924–931.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2538604</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18664528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang Y. Gilbert DL. Glauser TA. Hershey AD. Sharp FR. Blood gene expression profiling of neurologic diseases: a pilot microarray study. Arch Neurol. 2005;62:210–215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15710849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor JR. Morshed SA. Parveen S. Mercadante MT. Scahill L. Peterson BS, et al.  An animal model of Tourette's syndrome. Am J Psychiatry. 2002;159:657–660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11925307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terreri MT. Roja SC. Len CA. Faustino PC. Roberto AM. Hilario MO. Sydenham's chorea—Clinical and evolutive characteristics. Sao Paulo Med J. 2002;120:16–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11836548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomsen PH. Mikkelsen HU. Course of obsessive-compulsive disorder in children and adolescents: a prospective follow-up study of 23 Danish cases. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1995;34:1432–1440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8543510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tucker DM. Leckman JF. Scahill L. Wilf GE. LaCamera R. Cardona L, et al.  A putative poststreptococcal case of OCD with chronic tic disorder, not otherwise specified. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1996;35:1684–1691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8973076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woof JM. Kerr MA. The function of immunoglobulin A in immunity. J Pathol. 2006;208:270–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16362985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaddanapudi K. Hornig M. Serge R. De Miranda J. Baghban A. Villar G, et al.  Passive transfer of Streptococcus-induced antibodies reproduces behavioral disturbances in a mouse model of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection. Mol Psychiatry. 2009;15:712–726.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19668249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
