<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">20936972</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2011</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1545-3278</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>29</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2011</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annual review of immunology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Annu Rev Immunol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Innate antifungal immunity: the key role of phagocytes.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1</StartPage>
          <EndPage>21</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1-21</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1146/annurev-immunol-030409-101229</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Fungal diseases have emerged as significant causes of morbidity and mortality, particularly in immune-compromised individuals, prompting greater interest in understanding the mechanisms of host resistance to these pathogens. Consequently, the past few decades have seen a tremendous increase in our knowledge of the innate and adaptive components underlying the protective (and nonprotective) mechanisms of antifungal immunity. What has emerged from these studies is that phagocytic cells are essential for protection and that defects in these cells compromise the host's ability to resist fungal infection. This review covers the functions of phagocytes in innate antifungal immunity, along with selected examples of the strategies that are used by fungal pathogens to subvert these defenses.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brown</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gordon D</ForeName>
            <Initials>GD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Aberdeen Fungal Group, Section of Immunology and Infection, Division of Applied Medicine, Institute of Medical Sciences, University of Aberdeen, Foresterhill, United Kingdom. gordon.brown@abdn.ac.uk</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>086558</GrantID>
            <Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency>
            <Country>United Kingdom</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Annu Rev Immunol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8309206</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0732-0582</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056704" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive Immunity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005658" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fungi</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057131" MajorTopicYN="N">Immune Evasion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007113" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunity, Innate</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009181" MajorTopicYN="N">Mycoses</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010586" MajorTopicYN="N">Phagocytes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherID Source="NLM">UKMS34637</OtherID>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20936972</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">UKMS34637</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3434799</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-immunol-030409-101229</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park BJ, Wannemuehler KA, Marston BJ, Govender N, Pappas PG, Chiller TM. Estimation of the current global burden of cryptococcal meningitis among persons living with HIV/AIDS. AIDS. 2009;23:525–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19182676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wisplinghoff H, Bischoff T, Tallent SM, Seifert H, Wenzel RP, Edmond MB. Nosocomial bloodstream infections in US hospitals: analysis of 24,179 cases from a prospective nationwide surveillance study. Clin. Infect. Dis. 2004;39:309–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15306996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan J, Wannemuehler KA, Marr KA, Hadley S, Kontoyiannis DP, Walsh TJ, Fridkin SK, Pappas PG, Warnock DW. Incidence of invasive aspergillosis following hematopoietic stem cell and solid organ transplantation: interim results of a prospective multicenter surveillance program. Med. Mycol. 2005;43(Suppl 1):S49–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16110792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hohl TM, Rivera A, Lipuma L, Gallegos A, Shi C, Mack M, Pamer EG. Inflammatory monocytes facilitate adaptive CD4 T cell responses during respiratory fungal infection. Cell Host Microbe. 2009;6:470–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2785497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19917501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gantner BN, Simmons RM, Underhill DM. Dectin-1 mediates macrophage recognition of Candida albicans yeast but not filaments. EMBO J. 2005;24:1277–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC556398</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15729357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo HJ, Kohler JR, DiDomenico B, Loebenberg D, Cacciapuoti A, Fink GR. Nonfilamentous C. albicans mutants are avirulent. Cell. 1997;90:939–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9298905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubin-Bejerano I, Abeijon C, Magnelli P, Grisafi P, Fink GR. Phagocytosis by human neutrophils is stimulated by a unique fungal cell wall component. Cell Host Microbe. 2007;2:55–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2083279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18005717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamasaki S, Matsumoto M, Takeuchi O, Matsuzawa T, Ishikawa E, Sakuma M, Tateno H, Uno J, Hirabayashi J, Mikami Y, Takeda K, Akira S, Saito T. C-type lectin Mincle is an activating receptor for pathogenic fungus, Malassezia. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2009;106:1897–902.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2644135</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19171887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jouault T, El Abed-El Behi M, Martinez-Esparza M, Breuilh L, Trinel PA, Chamaillard M, Trottein F, Poulain D. Specific recognition of Candida albicans by macrophages requires galectin-3 to discriminate Saccharomyces cerevisiae and needs association with TLR2 for signaling. J. Immunol. 2006;177:4679–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16982907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Netea MG, Brown GD, Kullberg BJ, Gow NA. An integrated model of the recognition of Candida albicans by the innate immune system. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2008;6:67–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18079743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato K, Yang XL, Yudate T, Chung JS, Wu J, Luby-Phelps K, Kimberly RP, Underhill D, Cruz PD, Jr., Ariizumi K. Dectin-2 is a pattern recognition receptor for fungi that couples with the Fc receptor gamma chain to induce innate immune responses. J. Biol. Chem. 2006;281:38854–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17050534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson MJ, Osorio F, Rosas M, Freitas RP, Schweighoffer E, Gross O, Verbeek JS, Ruland J, Tybulewicz V, Brown GD, Moita LF, Taylor PR, Reis ESC. Dectin-2 is a Syk-coupled pattern recognition receptor crucial for Th17 responses to fungal infection. J. Exp. Med. 2009;206:2037–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2737172</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19703985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saijo S, Ikeda S, Yamabe K, Kakuta S, Ishigame H, Akitsu A, Fujikado N, Kusaka T, Kubo S, Chung SH, Komatsu R, Miura N, Adachi Y, Ohno N, Shibuya K, Yamamoto N, Kawakami K, Yamasaki S, Saito T, Akira S, Iwakura Y. Dectin-2 recognition of alpha-mannans and induction of Th17 cell differentiation is essential for host defense against Candida albicans. Immunity. 2010;32:681–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20493731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaragoza O, Rodrigues ML, De Jesus M, Frases S, Dadachova E, Casadevall A. The capsule of the fungal pathogen Cryptococcus neoformans. Adv. Appl. Microbiol. 2009;68:133–216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2739887</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19426855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rappleye CA, Eissenberg LG, Goldman WE. Histoplasma capsulatum alpha-(1,3)-glucan blocks innate immune recognition by the beta-glucan receptor. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2007;104:1366–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1783108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17227865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aimanianda V, Bayry J, Bozza S, Kniemeyer O, Perruccio K, Elluru SR, Clavaud C, Paris S, Brakhage AA, Kaveri SV, Romani L, Latge JP. Surface hydrophobin prevents immune recognition of airborne fungal spores. Nature. 2009;460:1117–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19713928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheeler RT, Kombe D, Agarwala SD, Fink GR. Dynamic, morphotype-specific Candida albicans beta-glucan exposure during infection and drug treatment. PLoS Pathog. 2008;4:e1000227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2587227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hohl TM. Stage-specific innate immune recognition of Aspergillus fumigatus and modulation by echinocandin drugs. Med. Mycol. 2008:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3808522</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18608931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Speth C, Rambach G, Wurzner R, Lass-Florl C. Complement and fungal pathogens: an update. Mycoses. 2008;51:477–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18705662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rambach G, Dum D, Mohsenipour I, Hagleitner M, Wurzner R, Lass-Florl C, Speth C. Secretion of a fungal protease represents a complement evasion mechanism in cerebral aspergillosis. Mol. Immunol. 47:1438–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20303595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brandhorst TT, Wuthrich M, Finkel-Jimenez B, Warner T, Klein BS. Exploiting type 3 complement receptor for TNF-alpha suppression, immune evasion, and progressive pulmonary fungal infection. J. Immunol. 2004;173:7444–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15585870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filler SG, Sheppard DC. Fungal invasion of normally non-phagocytic host cells. PLoS Pathog. 2006;2:e129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1757199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17196036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>d’Ostiani CF, Del Sero G, Bacci A, Montagnoli C, Spreca A, Mencacci A, Ricciardi-Castagnoli P, Romani L. Dendritic cells discriminate between yeasts and hyphae of the fungus Candida albicans. Implications for initiation of T helper cell immunity in vitro and in vivo. J. Exp. Med. 2000;191:1661–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193147</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10811860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bozza S, Gaziano R, Spreca A, Bacci A, Montagnoli C, di Francesco P, Romani L. Dendritic cells transport conidia and hyphae of Aspergillus fumigatus from the airways to the draining lymph nodes and initiate disparate Th responses to the fungus. J. Immunol. 2002;168:1362–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11801677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luther K, Rohde M, Sturm K, Kotz A, Heesemann J, Ebel F. Characterisation of the phagocytic uptake of Aspergillus fumigatus conidia by macrophages. Microbes Infect. 2008;10:175–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18248765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neumann AK, Jacobson K. A novel pseudopodial component of the dendritic cell anti-fungal response: the fungipod. PLoS Pathog. 2010;6:e1000760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820528</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20169183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behnsen J, Narang P, Hasenberg M, Gunzer F, Bilitewski U, Klippel N, Rohde M, Brock M, Brakhage AA, Gunzer M. Environmental dimensionality controls the interaction of phagocytes with the pathogenic fungi Aspergillus fumigatus and Candida albicans. PLoS Pathog. 2007;3:e13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1790725</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17274685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Cabec V, Emorine LJ, Toesca I, Cougoule C, Maridonneau-Parini I. The human macrophage mannose receptor is not a professional phagocytic receptor. J. Leukoc. Biol. 2005;77:934–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerrigan AM, Brown GD. C-type lectins and phagocytosis. Immunobiology. 2009;214:562–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2702671</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19261355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herre J, Marshall AJ, Caron E, Edwards AD, Williams DL, Schweighoffer E, Tybulewicz VL, Reis e Sousa C, Gordon S, Brown GD. Dectin-1 utilizes novel mechanisms for yeast phagocytosis in macrophages. Blood. 2004;104:4038–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15304394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers NC, Slack EC, Edwards AD, Nolte MA, Schulz O, Schweighoffer E, Williams DL, Gordon S, Tybulewicz VL, Brown GD, Reis e Sousa C. Syk-dependent cytokine induction by dectin-1 reveals a novel pattern recognition pathway for C-type lectins. Immunity. 2005;22:507–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15845454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luther K, Torosantucci A, Brakhage AA, Heesemann J, Ebel F. Phagocytosis of Aspergillus fumigatus conidia by murine macrophages involves recognition by the dectin-1 beta-glucan receptor and Toll-like receptor 2. Cell. Microbiol. 2007;9:368–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16953804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellocchio S, Montagnoli C, Bozza S, Gaziano R, Rossi G, Mambula SS, Vecchi A, Mantovani A, Levitz SM, Romani L. The contribution of the toll-like/IL-1 receptor superfamily to innate and adaptive immunity to fungal pathogens in vivo. J. Immunol. 2004;172:3059–69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14978111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marr KA, Balajee SA, Hawn TR, Ozinsky A, Pham U, Akira S, Aderem A, Liles WC. Differential role of MyD88 in macrophage-mediated responses to opportunistic fungal pathogens. Infect. Immun. 2003;71:5280–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC187297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12933875</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaposzta R, Marodi L, Hollinshead M, Gordon S, da Silva RP. Rapid recruitment of late endosomes and lysosomes in mouse macrophages ingesting Candida albicans. J. Cell Sci. 1999;112:3237–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10504329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blander JM, Medzhitov R. Regulation of phagosome maturation by signals from toll-like receptors. Science. 2004;304:1014–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15143282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yates RM, Russell DG. Phagosome maturation proceeds independently of stimulation of toll-like receptors 2 and 4. Immunity. 2005;23:409–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16226506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanjuan MA, Dillon CP, Tait SW, Moshiach S, Dorsey F, Connell S, Komatsu M, Tanaka K, Cleveland JL, Withoff S, Green DR. Toll-like receptor signalling in macrophages links the autophagy pathway to phagocytosis. Nature. 2007;450:1253–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18097414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balestrieri B, Maekawa A, Xing W, Gelb MH, Katz HR, Arm JP. Group V secretory phospholipase A2 modulates phagosome maturation and regulates the innate immune response against Candida albicans. J. Immunol. 2009;182:4891–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19342668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinsbroek SE, Taylor PR, Martinez FO, Martinez-Pomares L, Brown GD, Gordon S. Stage-specific sampling by pattern recognition receptors during Candida albicans phagocytosis. PLoS Pathog. 2008;4:e1000218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2583056</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19043561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinsbroek SE, Kamen LA, Taylor PR, Brown GD, Swanson J, Gordon S. Actin and phosphoinositide recruitment to fully formed Candida albicans phagosomes in mouse macrophages. J Innate Immun. 2009;1:244–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20375582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Philippe B, Ibrahim-Granet O, Prevost MC, Gougerot-Pocidalo MA, Perez M Sanchez, Van der Meeren A, Latge JP. Killing of Aspergillus fumigatus by alveolar macrophages is mediated by reactive oxidant intermediates. Infect. Immun. 2003;71:3034–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12761080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods JP. Knocking on the right door and making a comfortable home: Histoplasma capsulatum intracellular pathogenesis. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2003;6:327–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12941399</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez-Arenas E, Bleck CK, Nombela C, Gil C, Griffiths G, Diez-Orejas R. Candida albicans actively modulates intracellular membrane trafficking in mouse macrophage phagosomes. Cell. Microbiol. 2009;11:560–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19134116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonnett CR, Cornish EJ, Harmsen AG, Burritt JB. Early neutrophil recruitment and aggregation in the murine lung inhibit germination of Aspergillus fumigatus Conidia. Infect. Immun. 2006;74:6528–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1698102</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hornbach A, Heyken A, Schild L, Hube B, Loffler J, Kurzai O. The glycosylphosphatidylinositol-anchored protease Sap9 modulates the interaction of Candida albicans with human neutrophils. Infect. Immun. 2009;77:5216–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786460</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voelz K, May RC. Cryptococcal Interactions with the Host Immune System. Eukaryot. Cell. 2010;9:835–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901644</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levitz SM, Harrison TS, Tabuni A, Liu X. Chloroquine induces human mononuclear phagocytes to inhibit and kill Cryptococcus neoformans by a mechanism independent of iron deprivation. J. Clin. Invest. 1997;100:1640–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC508346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9294133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tucker SC, Casadevall A. Replication of Cryptococcus neoformans in macrophages is accompanied by phagosomal permeabilization and accumulation of vesicles containing polysaccharide in the cytoplasm. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2002;99:3165–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122490</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vonk AG, Netea MG, van der Meer JW, Kullberg BJ. Host defence against disseminated Candida albicans infection and implications for antifungal immunotherapy. Expert Opin. Biol. Ther. 2006;6:891–903.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16918256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nosanchuk JD, Gacser A. Histoplasma capsulatum at the host-pathogen interface. Microbes Infect. 2008;10:973–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2586805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18672088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mednick AJ, Feldmesser M, Rivera J, Casadevall A. Neutropenia alters lung cytokine production in mice and reduces their susceptibility to pulmonary cryptococcosis. Eur. J. Immunol. 2003;33:1744–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12778493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vazquez-Torres A, Balish E. Macrophages in resistance to candidiasis. Microbiol. Mol. Biol. Rev. 1997;61:170–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC232606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9184009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levitz SM, Diamond RD. Killing of Aspergillus fumigatus spores and Candida albicans yeast phase by the iron-hydrogen peroxide-iodide cytotoxic system: comparison with the myeloperoxidase-hydrogen peroxide-halide system. Infect. Immun. 1984;43:1100–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC264303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6321349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lefkowitz SS, Gelderman MP, Lefkowitz DL, Moguilevsky N, Bollen A. Phagocytosis and intracellular killing of Candida albicans by macrophages exposed to myeloperoxidase. J. Infect. Dis. 1996;173:1202–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8627073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antachopoulos C, Walsh TJ, Roilides E. Fungal infections in primary immunodeficiencies. Eur. J. Pediatr. 2007;166:1099–117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17551753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aratani Y, Kura F, Watanabe H, Akagawa H, Takano Y, Suzuki K, Dinauer MC, Maeda N, Koyama H. Relative contributions of myeloperoxidase and NADPH-oxidase to the early host defense against pulmonary infections with Candida albicans and Aspergillus fumigatus. Med. Mycol. 2002;40:557–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12521119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aratani Y, Kura F, Watanabe H, Akagawa H, Takano Y, Ishida-Okawara A, Suzuki K, Maeda N, Koyama H. Contribution of the myeloperoxidase-dependent oxidative system to host defence against Cryptococcus neoformans. J. Med. Microbiol. 2006;55:1291–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16914663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reeves EP, Lu H, Jacobs HL, Messina CG, Bolsover S, Gabella G, Potma EO, Warley A, Roes J, Segal AW. Killing activity of neutrophils is mediated through activation of proteases by K+ flux. Nature. 2002;416:291–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11907569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romani L, Fallarino F, De Luca A, Montagnoli C, D’Angelo C, Zelante T, Vacca C, Bistoni F, Fioretti MC, Grohmann U, Segal BH, Puccetti P. Defective tryptophan catabolism underlies inflammation in mouse chronic granulomatous disease. Nature. 2008;451:211–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18185592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlsson A, Follin P, Leffler H, Dahlgren C. Galectin-3 activates the NADPH-oxidase in exudated but not peripheral blood neutrophils. Blood. 1998;91:3430–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9558402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Underhill DM, Rossnagle E, Lowell CA, Simmons RM. Dectin-1 activates Syk tyrosine kinase in a dynamic subset of macrophages for reactive oxygen production. Blood. 2005;106:2543–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1895265</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15956283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miletic AV, Graham DB, Montgrain V, Fujikawa K, Kloeppel T, Brim K, Weaver B, Schreiber R, Xavier R, Swat W. Vav proteins control MyD88-dependent oxidative burst. Blood. 2007;109:3360–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17158234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gantner BN, Simmons RM, Canavera SJ, Akira S, Underhill DM. Collaborative Induction of Inflammatory Responses by Dectin-1 and Toll-like Receptor 2. J. Exp. Med. 2003;197:1107–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2193968</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12719479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguirre KM, Gibson GW. Differing requirement for inducible nitric oxide synthase activity in clearance of primary and secondary Cryptococcus neoformans infection. Med. Mycol. 2000;38:343–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11092381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farah CS, Saunus JM, Hu Y, Kazoullis A, Ashman RB. Gene targeting demonstrates that inducible nitric oxide synthase is not essential for resistance to oral candidiasis in mice, or for killing of Candida albicans by macrophages in vitro. Oral Microbiol. Immunol. 2009;24:83–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19121076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balish E, Warner TF, Nicholas PJ, Paulling EE, Westwater C, Schofield DA. Susceptibility of germfree phagocyte oxidase- and nitric oxide synthase 2-deficient mice, defective in the production of reactive metabolites of both oxygen and nitrogen, to mucosal and systemic candidiasis of endogenous origin. Infect. Immun. 2005;73:1313–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1064974</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15731028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman SL, Gootee L, Gabay JE, Selsted ME. Identification of constituents of human neutrophil azurophil granules that mediate fungistasis against Histoplasma capsulatum. Infect. Immun. 2000;68:5668–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10992469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohatsu L, Hsu DK, Jegalian AG, Liu FT, Baum LG. Galectin-3 induces death of Candida species expressing specific beta-1,2-linked mannans. J. Immunol. 2006;177:4718–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16982911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishore U, Greenhough TJ, Waters P, Shrive AK, Ghai R, Kamran MF, Bernal AL, Reid KB, Madan T, Chakraborty T. Surfactant proteins SP-A and SP-D: structure, function and receptors. Mol. Immunol. 2006;43:1293–315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16213021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vylkova S, Sun JN, Edgerton M. The role of released ATP in killing Candida albicans and other extracellular microbial pathogens by cationic peptides. Purinergic Signal. 2007;3:91–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2096768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18404422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murakami M, Lopez-Garcia B, Braff M, Dorschner RA, Gallo RL. Postsecretory processing generates multiple cathelicidins for enhanced topical antimicrobial defense. J. Immunol. 2004;172:3070–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14978112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>den Hertog AL, van Marle J, Veerman EC, Valentijn-Benz M, Nazmi K, Kalay H, Grun CH, Van’t Hof W, Bolscher JG, Nieuw Amerongen AV. The human cathelicidin peptide LL-37 and truncated variants induce segregation of lipids and proteins in the plasma membrane of Candida albicans. Biol. Chem. 2006;387:1495–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17081124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benincasa M, Scocchi M, Pacor S, Tossi A, Nobili D, Basaglia G, Busetti M, Gennaro R. Fungicidal activity of five cathelicidin peptides against clinically isolated yeasts. J. Antimicrob. Chemother. 2006;58:950–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Garcia B, Lee PH, Yamasaki K, Gallo RL. Anti-fungal activity of cathelicidins and their potential role in Candida albicans skin infection. J. Invest. Dermatol. 2005;125:108–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15982310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopera D, Aristizabal BH, Restrepo A, Cano LE, Gonzalez A. Lysozyme plays a dual role against the dimorphic fungus Paracoccidioides brasiliensis. Rev. Inst. Med. Trop. Sao Paulo. 2008;50:169–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18604417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marquis G, Montplaisir S, Garzon S, Strykowski H, Auger P. Fungitoxicity of muramidase. Ultrastructural damage to Candida albicans. Lab. Invest. 1982;46:627–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7045520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pham CT. Neutrophil serine proteases: specific regulators of inflammation. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2006;6:541–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16799473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tkalcevic J, Novelli M, Phylactides M, Iredale JP, Segal AW, Roes J. Impaired immunity and enhanced resistance to endotoxin in the absence of neutrophil elastase and cathepsin G. Immunity. 2000;12:201–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10714686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal AW. How neutrophils kill microbes. Annu. Rev. Immunol. 2005;23:197–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2092448</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15771570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCabe D, Cukierman T, Gabay JE. Basic residues in azurocidin/HBP contribute to both heparin binding and antimicrobial activity. J. Biol. Chem. 2002;277:27477–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenssen H, Hancock RE. Antimicrobial properties of lactoferrin. Biochimie. 2009;91:19–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18573312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puliti M, Radzioch D, Mazzolla R, Barluzzi R, Bistoni F, Blasi E. Influence of the Bcg locus on macrophage response to the dimorphic fungus Candida albicans. Infect. Immun. 1995;63:4170–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173587</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7558336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sroussi HY, Kohler GA, Agabian N, Villines D, Palefsky JM. Substitution of methionine 63 or 83 in S100A9 and cysteine 42 in S100A8 abrogate the antifungal activities of S100A8/A9: potential role for oxidative regulation. FEMS Immunol. Med. Microbiol. 2009;55:55–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2730662</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voganatsi A, Panyutich A, Miyasaki KT, Murthy RK. Mechanism of extracellular release of human neutrophil calprotectin complex. J. Leukoc. Biol. 2001;70:130–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11435495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urban CF, Ermert D, Schmid M, Abu-Abed U, Goosmann C, Nacken W, Brinkmann V, Jungblut PR, Zychlinsky A. Neutrophil extracellular traps contain calprotectin, a cytosolic protein complex involved in host defense against Candida albicans. PLoS Pathog. 2009;5:e1000639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763347</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19876394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaillon S, Peri G, Delneste Y, Fremaux I, Doni A, Moalli F, Garlanda C, Romani L, Gascan H, Bellocchio S, Bozza S, Cassatella MA, Jeannin P, Mantovani A. The humoral pattern recognition receptor PTX3 is stored in neutrophil granules and localizes in extracellular traps. J. Exp. Med. 2007;204:793–804.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2118544</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17389238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bianchi M, Hakkim A, Brinkmann V, Siler U, Seger RA, Zychlinsky A, Reichenbach J. Restoration of NET formation by gene therapy in CGD controls aspergillosis. Blood. 2009;114:2619–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19541821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wellington M, Dolan K, Krysan DJ. Live Candida albicans suppresses production of reactive oxygen species in phagocytes. Infect. Immun. 2009;77:405–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18981256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao G, Miyazato A, Inden K, Nakamura K, Shiratori K, Nakagawa K, Miyazawa T, Suzuki K, Kaku M, Kawakami K. Cryptococcus neoformans inhibits nitric oxide synthesis caused by CpG-oligodeoxynucleotide-stimulated macrophages in a fashion independent of capsular polysaccharides. Microbiol. Immunol. 2008;52:171–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18402599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown AJ, Haynes K, Quinn J. Nitrosative and oxidative stress responses in fungal pathogenicity. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2009;12:384–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Missall TA, Lodge JK, McEwen JE. Mechanisms of resistance to oxidative and nitrosative stress: implications for fungal survival in mammalian hosts. Eukaryot. Cell. 2004;3:835–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC500878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15302816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kornitzer D. Fungal mechanisms for host iron acquisition. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2009;12:377–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19540796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brock M. Fungal metabolism in host niches. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2009;12:371–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poeck H, Ruland J. ITAM Receptor Signaling and the NLRP3 Inflammasome in Antifungal Immunity. J. Clin. Immunol. 2010 In Press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20401526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calich VL, Pina A, Felonato M, Bernardino S, Costa TA, Loures FV. Toll-like receptors and fungal infections: the role of TLR2, TLR4 and MyD88 in paracoccidioidomycosis. FEMS Immunol. Med. Microbiol. 2008;53:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18384366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villamon E, Gozalbo D, Roig P, O’Connor JE, Fradelizi D, Gil ML. Toll-like receptor-2 is essential in murine defenses against Candida albicans infections. Microbes Infect. 2004;6:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14738887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Netea MG, Sutmuller R, Hermann C, Van der Graaf CA, Van der Meer JW, van Krieken JH, Hartung T, Adema G, Kullberg BJ. Toll-like receptor 2 suppresses immunity against Candida albicans through induction of IL-10 and regulatory T cells. J. Immunol. 2004;172:3712–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15004175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Netea MG, Gow NA, Joosten LA, Verschueren I, van der Meer JW, Kullberg BJ. Variable recognition of Candida albicans strains by TLR4 and lectin recognition receptors. Med. Mycol. 2010 In press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20166865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho A, Cunha C, Pasqualotto AC, Pitzurra L, Denning DW, Romani L. Genetic variability of innate immunity impacts human susceptibility to fungal diseases. Int. J. Infect. Dis. 2010;14:e460–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Bernuth H, Picard C, Jin Z, Pankla R, Xiao H, Ku CL, Chrabieh M, Mustapha IB, Ghandil P, Camcioglu Y, Vasconcelos J, Sirvent N, Guedes M, Vitor AB, Herrero-Mata MJ, Arostegui JI, Rodrigo C, Alsina L, Ruiz-Ortiz E, Juan M, Fortuny C, Yague J, Anton J, Pascal M, Chang HH, Janniere L, Rose Y, Garty BZ, Chapel H, Issekutz A, Marodi L, Rodriguez-Gallego C, Banchereau J, Abel L, Li X, Chaussabel D, Puel A, Casanova JL. Pyogenic bacterial infections in humans with MyD88 deficiency. Science. 2008;321:691–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2688396</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18669862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reid DM, Gow NA, Brown GD. Pattern recognition: recent insights from Dectin-1. Curr. Opin. Immunol. 2009;21:30–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2684021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19223162</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giles SS, Dagenais TR, Botts MR, Keller NP, Hull CM. Elucidating the pathogenesis of spores from the human fungal pathogen Cryptococcus neoformans. Infect. Immun. 2009;77:3491–500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2715683</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu S, Huo J, Lee KG, Kurosaki T, Lam KP. Phospholipase Cgamma2 is critical for Dectin-1-mediated Ca2+ flux and cytokine production in dendritic cells. J. Biol. Chem. 2009;284:7038–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2652331</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19136564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenblatt MB, Aliprantis A, Hu B, Glimcher LH. Calcineurin regulates innate antifungal immunity in neutrophils. J. Exp. Med. 2010;207:923–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867274</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20421389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodridge HS, Shimada T, Wolf AJ, Hsu YM, Becker CA, Lin X, Underhill DM. Differential use of CARD9 by Dectin-1 in macrophages and dendritic cells. J. Immunol. 2009;182:1146–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosas M, Liddiard K, Kimberg M, Faro-Trindade I, McDonald JU, Williams DL, Brown GD, Taylor PR. The induction of inflammation by dectin-1 in vivo is dependent on myeloid cell programming and the progression of phagocytosis. J. Immunol. 2008;181:3549–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18714028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Said-Sadier N, Padilla E, Langsley G, Ojcius DM. Aspergillus fumigatus stimulates the NLRP3 inflammasome through a pathway requiring ROS production and the Syk tyrosine kinase. PLoS ONE. 2010;5:e10008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2848854</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20368800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor PR, Tsoni SV, Willment JA, Dennehy KM, Rosas M, Findon H, Haynes K, Steele C, Botto M, Gordon S, Brown GD. Dectin-1 is required for beta-glucan recognition and control of fungal infection. Nat. Immunol. 2007;8:31–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1888731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17159984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Werner JL, Metz AE, Horn D, Schoeb TR, Hewitt MM, Schwiebert LM, Faro-Trindade I, Brown GD, Steele C. Requisite role for the dectin-1 beta-glucan receptor in pulmonary defense against Aspergillus fumigatus. J. Immunol. 2009;182:4938–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3434356</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19342673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saijo S, Fujikado N, Furuta T, Chung SH, Kotaki H, Seki K, Sudo K, Akira S, Adachi Y, Ohno N, Kinjo T, Nakamura K, Kawakami K, Iwakura Y. Dectin-1 is required for host defense against Pneumocystis carinii but not against Candida albicans. Nat. Immunol. 2007;8:39–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17159982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferwerda B, Ferwerda G, Plantinga TS, Willment JA, van Spriel AB, Venselaar H, Elbers CC, Johnson MD, Cambi A, Huysamen C, Jacobs L, Jansen T, Verheijen K, Masthoff L, Morre SA, Vriend G, Williams DL, Perfect JR, Joosten LA, Wijmenga C, van der Meer JW, Adema GJ, Kullberg BJ, Brown GD, Netea MG. Human dectin-1 deficiency and mucocutaneous fungal infections. N. Engl. J. Med. 2009;361:1760–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2773015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glocker EO, Hennigs A, Nabavi M, Schaffer AA, Woellner C, Salzer U, Pfeifer D, Veelken H, Warnatz K, Tahami F, Jamal S, Manguiat A, Rezaei N, Amirzargar AA, Plebani A, Hannesschlager N, Gross O, Ruland J, Grimbacher B. A homozygous CARD9 mutation in a family with susceptibility to fungal infections. N. Engl. J. Med. 2009;361:1727–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2793117</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19864672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gross O, Gewies A, Finger K, Schafer M, Sparwasser T, Peschel C, Forster I, Ruland J. Card9 controls a non-TLR signalling pathway for innate anti-fungal immunity. Nature. 2006;442:651–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862125</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willment JA, Brown GD. C-type lectin receptors in antifungal immunity. Trends Microbiol. 2008;16:27–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18160296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SJ, Zheng NY, Clavijo M, Nussenzweig MC. Normal Host Defense during Systemic Candidiasis in Mannose Receptor-Deficient Mice. Infect. Immun. 2003;71:437–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC143203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12496194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swain SD, Lee SJ, Nussenzweig MC, Harmsen AG. Absence of the macrophage mannose receptor in mice does not increase susceptibility to Pneumocystis carinii infection in vivo. Infect. Immun. 2003;71:6213–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC219593</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14573639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dan JM, Kelly RM, Lee CK, Levitz SM. Role of the mannose receptor in a murine model of Cryptococcus neoformans infection. Infect. Immun. 2008;76:2362–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2423054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18391001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrett NA, Maekawa A, Rahman OM, Austen KF, Kanaoka Y. Dectin-2 recognition of house dust mite triggers cysteinyl leukotriene generation by dendritic cells. J. Immunol. 2009;182:1119–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3682801</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19124755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells CA, Salvage-Jones JA, Li X, Hitchens K, Butcher S, Murray RZ, Beckhouse AG, Lo YL, Manzanero S, Cobbold C, Schroder K, Ma B, Orr S, Stewart L, Lebus D, Sobieszczuk P, Hume DA, Stow J, Blanchard H, Ashman RB. The Macrophage-Inducible C-Type Lectin, Mincle, Is an Essential Component of the Innate Immune Response to Candida albicans. J. Immunol. 2008;180:7404–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18490740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mansour MK, Latz E, Levitz SM. Cryptococcus neoformans glycoantigens are captured by multiple lectin receptors and presented by dendritic cells. J. Immunol. 2006;176:3053–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16493064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serrano-Gomez D, Dominguez-Soto A, Ancochea J, Jimenez-Heffernan JA, Leal JA, Corbi AL. Dendritic cell-specific intercellular adhesion molecule 3-grabbing nonintegrin mediates binding and internalization of Aspergillus fumigatus conidia by dendritic cells and macrophages. J. Immunol. 2004;173:5635–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15494514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cambi A, Netea MG, Mora-Montes HM, Gow NA, Hato SV, Lowman DW, Kullberg BJ, Torensma R, Williams DL, Figdor CG. Dendritic cell interaction with Candida albicans critically depends on N-linked mannan. J. Biol. Chem. 2008;283:20590–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2459306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18482990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahara K, Yashima Y, Omatsu Y, Yoshida H, Kimura Y, Kang YS, Steinman RM, Park CG, Inaba K. Functional comparison of the mouse DC-SIGN, SIGNR1, SIGNR3 and Langerin, C-type lectins. Int. Immunol. 2004;16:819–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15096474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gringhuis SI, den Dunnen J, Litjens M, van Het Hof B, van Kooyk Y, Geijtenbeek TB. C-Type Lectin DC-SIGN Modulates Toll-like Receptor Signaling via Raf-1 Kinase-Dependent Acetylation of Transcription Factor NF-kappaB. Immunity. 2007;26:605–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17462920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Means TK, Mylonakis E, Tampakakis E, Colvin RA, Seung E, Puckett L, Tai MF, Stewart CR, Pukkila-Worley R, Hickman SE, Moore KJ, Calderwood SB, Hacohen N, Luster AD, El Khoury J. Evolutionarily conserved recognition and innate immunity to fungal pathogens by the scavenger receptors SCARF1 and CD36. J. Exp. Med. 2009;206:637–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19237602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gringhuis SI, den Dunnen J, Litjens M, van der Vlist M, Geijtenbeek TB. Carbohydrate-specific signaling through the DC-SIGN signalosome tailors immunity to Mycobacterium tuberculosis, HIV-1 and Helicobacter pylori. Nat. Immunol. 2009;10:1081–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19718030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Netea MG, Gow NA, Munro CA, Bates S, Collins C, Ferwerda G, Hobson RP, Bertram G, Hughes HB, Jansen T, Jacobs L, Buurman ET, Gijzen K, Williams DL, Torensma R, McKinnon A, MacCallum DM, Odds FC, Van der Meer JW, Brown AJ, Kullberg BJ. Immune sensing of Candida albicans requires cooperative recognition of mannans and glucans by lectin and Toll-like receptors. J. Clin. Invest. 2006;116:1642–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1462942</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16710478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pop SM, Kolls JK, Steele C. Pneumocystis: immune recognition and evasion. Int. J. Biochem. Cell Biol. 2006;38:17–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16182595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romani L, Montagnoli C, Bozza S, Perruccio K, Spreca A, Allavena P, Verbeek S, Calderone RA, Bistoni F, Puccetti P. The exploitation of distinct recognition receptors in dendritic cells determines the full range of host immune relationships with Candida albicans. Int. Immunol. 2004;16:149–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14688070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huffnagle GB, Chen GH, Curtis JL, McDonald RA, Strieter RM, Toews GB. Down-regulation of the afferent phase of T cell-mediated pulmonary inflammation and immunity by a high melanin-producing strain of Cryptococcus neoformans. J. Immunol. 1995;155:3507–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7561046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romani L. Immunity to fungal infections. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2004;4:1–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14661066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szymczak WA, Deepe GS., Jr The CCL7-CCL2-CCR2 axis regulates IL-4 production in lungs and fungal immunity. J. Immunol. 2009;183:1964–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2743878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19587014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osterholzer JJ, Curtis JL, Polak T, Ames T, Chen GH, McDonald R, Huffnagle GB, Toews GB. CCR2 mediates conventional dendritic cell recruitment and the formation of bronchovascular mononuclear cell infiltrates in the lungs of mice infected with Cryptococcus neoformans. J. Immunol. 2008;181:610–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2735104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18566428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montagnoli C, Bacci A, Bozza S, Gaziano R, Mosci P, Sharpe AH, Romani L. B7/CD28-dependent CD4+CD25+ regulatory T cells are essential components of the memory-protective immunity to Candida albicans. J. Immunol. 2002;169:6298–308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12444136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mencacci A, Del Sero G, Cenci E, d’Ostiani CF, Bacci A, Montagnoli C, Kopf M, Romani L. Endogenous interleukin 4 is required for development of protective CD4+ T helper type 1 cell responses to Candida albicans. J. Exp. Med. 1998;187:307–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212115</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9449711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chai LY, van de Veerdonk F, Marijnissen RJ, Cheng SC, Khoo AL, Hectors M, Lagrou K, Vonk AG, Maertens J, Joosten LA, Kullberg BJ, Netea MG. Anti-Aspergillus human host defence relies on type 1 T helper (Th1), rather than type 17 T helper (Th17), cellular immunity. Immunology. 2010;130:46–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2855792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20002791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti HR, Gaffen SL. Host responses to Candida albicans: Th17 cells and mucosal candidiasis. Microbes Infect. 2010;12:518–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang W, Na L, Fidel PL, Schwarzenberger P. Requirement of interleukin-17A for systemic anti-Candida albicans host defense in mice. J. Infect. Dis. 2004;190:624–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15243941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zelante T, De Luca A, Bonifazi P, Montagnoli C, Bozza S, Moretti S, Belladonna ML, Vacca C, Conte C, Mosci P, Bistoni F, Puccetti P, Kastelein RA, Kopf M, Romani L. IL-23 and the Th17 pathway promote inflammation and impair antifungal immune resistance. Eur. J. Immunol. 2007;37:2695–706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17899546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Netea MG, Van der Graaf C, Van der Meer JW, Kullberg BJ. Recognition of fungal pathogens by Toll-like receptors. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 2004;23:672–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15322932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van de Veerdonk FL, Marijnissen RJ, Kullberg BJ, Koenen HJ, Cheng SC, Joosten I, van den Berg WB, Williams DL, van der Meer JW, Joosten LA, Netea MG. The macrophage mannose receptor induces IL-17 in response to Candida albicans. Cell Host Microbe. 2009;5:329–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19380112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leibundgut-Landmann S, Gross O, Robinson MJ, Osorio F, Slack EC, Tsoni SV, Schweighoffer E, Tybulewicz V, Brown GD, Ruland J, Reis ESC. Syk- and CARD9-dependent coupling of innate immunity to the induction of T helper cells that produce interleukin 17. Nat. Immunol. 2007;8:630–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17450144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
