<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">21540820</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2011</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-087X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Issue>50</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2011</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of visualized experiments : JoVE</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Vis Exp</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Physiological, morphological and neurochemical characterization of neurons modulated by movement.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2650</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3791/2650</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The role of individual neurons and their function in neuronal circuits is fundamental to understanding the neuronal mechanisms of sensory and motor functions. Most investigations of sensorimotor mechanisms rely on either examination of neurons while an animal is static or record extracellular neuronal activity during a movement. While these studies have provided the fundamental background for sensorimotor function, they either do not evaluate functional information which occurs during a movement or are limited in their ability to fully characterize the anatomy, physiology and neurochemical phenotype of the neuron. A technique is shown here which allows extensive characterization of individual neurons during an in vivo movement. This technique can be used not only to study primary afferent neurons but also to characterize motoneurons and sensorimotor interneurons. Initially the response of a single neuron is recorded using electrophysiological methods during various movements of the mandible followed by determination of the receptive field for the neuron. A neuronal tracer is then intracellularly injected into the neuron and the brain is processed so that the neuron can be visualized with light, electron or confocal microscopy (Fig. 1). The detailed morphology of the characterized neuron is then reconstructed so that neuronal morphology can be correlated with the physiological response of the neuron (Figs. 2,3). In this communication important key details and tips for successful implementation of this technique are provided. Valuable additional information can be determined for the neuron under study by combining this method with other techniques. Retrograde neuronal labeling can be used to determine neurons with which the labeled neuron synapses; thus allowing detailed determination of neuronal circuitry. Immunocytochemistry can be combined with this method to examine neurotransmitters within the labeled neuron and to determine the chemical phenotypes of neurons with which the labeled neuron synapses. The labeled neuron can also be processed for electron microscopy to determine the ultrastructural features and microcircuitry of the labeled neuron. Overall this technique is a powerful method to thoroughly characterize neurons during in vivo movement thus allowing substantial insight into the role of the neuron in sensorimotor function.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dessem</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dean</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neural and Pain Sciences, University of Maryland, USA. ddessem@umaryland.edu</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 DE010132</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DE</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>DE15386</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DE</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 DE015386</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DE</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>DE10132</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DE</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>RR017971</GrantID>
            <Acronym>RR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D059040">Video-Audio Media</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Vis Exp</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101313252</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1940-087X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009068" MajorTopicYN="N">Movement</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009448" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurochemistry</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013569" MajorTopicYN="N">Synapses</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540820</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169281</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/2650</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">2650</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuellar CA, Tapia JA, Juarez V, Quevedo J, Linares P, Marinez L, Manjarrez E. Propagation of sinusoidal electrical waves along the spinal cord during a fictive motor task. J. Neurosci. 2010;29:798–810.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6665157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19158305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frigon A, Gossard J. Evidence for specialized rhythm-generating mechanisms in the adult mammalian spinal cord. J. Neurosci. 2010;30:7061–7071.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6632641</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20484648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W, Chan SS, Heldman DA, Moran DW. Motor cortical representation of hand translation and rotation during reaching. J. Neurosci. 2010;30:958–962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6633081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma C, He J. A method for investigating cortical control of stand and squat in conscious behavioral monkeys. J. Neurosci. Meth. 2010;192:1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20600310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dessem D, Donga R, Luo P. Primary- and secondary-like jaw-muscle spindle afferents have characteristic topographic distributions. J. Neurophysiol. 1997;77:2925–2944.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9212247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dessem D, Moritaini A, Ambalavanar R. Nociceptive craniofacial muscle primary afferent neurons synapse in both the rostral and caudal brain stem. J. Neurophysiol. 2007;98:214–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17493918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo P, Dessem D. Inputs from identified jaw-muscle spindle afferents to trigeminothalamic neurons in the rat: a double-labeling study using retrograde HRP and intracellular. J. Comp. Neurol. 1995;353:50–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7714249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dessem D, Luo P. Jaw-muscle spindle afferent feedback to the cervical spinal cord in the rat. J. Comp. Neurol. 1999;128:451–459.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10541739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo P, Wong R, Dessem D. Projection of jaw-muscle spindle afferents to the caudal brainstem in rats demonstrated using intracellular biotinamide. J. Comp. Neurol. 1995;358:63–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7560277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo P, Dessem D. Ultrastructural anatomy of physiologically identified jaw-muscle spindle afferent terminations onto retrogradely labeled jaw-elevator motoneurons in the rat. J. Comp. Neurol. 1999;406:384–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10102503</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hassani OK, Henny P, Lee MG, Jones BE. GABAergic neurons intermingled with orexin and MCH neurons in the lateral hypothalamus discharge maximally during sleep. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2010;32:448–457.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2921479</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20597977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inokawa H, Yamada H, Matsumoto N, Muranishi M, Kimura M. Juxtacellular labeling of tonically active neurons and phasically active neurons in the rat striatum. Neuroscience. 2010;168:395–404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20371269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
