<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">21733197</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1752-8526</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2010</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2010</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>24</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMJ clinical evidence</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMJ Clin Evid</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Intimate partner violence towards women.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1013</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Between 10% and 70% of women may have been physically or sexually assaulted by a partner at some stage, with assault rates against men reported at about one quarter of the rate against women. In at least half of people studied, the problem lasts for 5 years or more. Women reporting intimate partner violence (IPV) are more likely than other women to complain of poor physical or mental health, and of disability.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS AND OUTCOMES" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a systematic review and aimed to answer the following clinical question: What are the effects of interventions initiated by healthcare professionals aimed at female victims of intimate partner violence? We searched: Medline, Embase, The Cochrane Library, and other relevant databases up to September 2009 (Clinical Evidence reviews are updated periodically, please check our website for the most up-to-date version of this review).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We found 26 systematic reviews, RCTs, or observational studies that met our inclusion criteria. We performed a GRADE evaluation of the quality of evidence for interventions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this systematic review we present information relating to the effectiveness and safety of the following interventions: advocacy; career counselling plus critical consciousness awareness; cognitive behavioural counselling; cognitive trauma therapy; counselling; nurse support and guidance; peer support groups; safety planning; and shelters.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sadowski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laura</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Collaborative Research Unit, Cook County Hospital/Department of Internal Medicine, Rush Medical College, Chicago, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Casteel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carri</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMJ Clin Evid</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101294314</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1462-3846</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003376" MajorTopicYN="N">Counseling</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019317" MajorTopicYN="N">Evidence-Based Medicine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000066511" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intimate Partner Violence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012449" MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012747" MajorTopicYN="N">Sexual Partners</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013179" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spouse Abuse</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014754" MajorTopicYN="N">Violence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2010</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21733197</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2907621</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">1013</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Center for Injury Prevention and Control. Injury fact book 2001–2002. Atlanta, GA: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krug EG, Dahlberg LL, Mercy JA, et al. World report on violence and health. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12596453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tjaden P, Thoennes N. Full report of the prevalence, incidence, and consequences of violence against women. Washington, DC: National Institute of Justice, 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gazmarian JA, Lazorick S, Spitz AM, et al. Prevalence of violence against pregnant women. JAMA 1996;275:1915–1920.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8648873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savona-Ventura C, Savona-Ventura M, Dregsted-Nielsen S, et al. Domestic abuse in a central Mediterranean pregnant population. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 2001;98:3–8.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11516791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Purwar MB, Jeyaseelan L, Varhadpande U, et al. Survey of physical abuse during pregnancy GMCH, Nagpur, India. J Obstet Gynaecol Res 1999;25:165–171.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10467788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lueng WC, Lueng TW, Lam YY, et al. The prevalence of domestic violence against pregnant women in a Chinese community. Int J Gynaecol Obstet 1999;66:23–30.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10458546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedin LW, Grimstad H, Moller A, et al. Prevalence of physical and sexual abuse before and during pregnancy among Swedish couples. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand 1999;78:310–315.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10203298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauer H, Rodriguez MA, Perez-Stable EJ. Prevalence and determinants of intimate partner abuse among public hospital primary care patients. J Gen Intern Med 2000;15:811–817.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11119174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richardson J, Coid J, Petruckevitch A, et al. Identifying domestic violence: cross-sectional study in primary care. BMJ 2002;324:271–277.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC65060</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11823360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCauley J, Kern DE, Kolodner K, et al. The "battering syndrome": prevalence and clinical characteristics of domestic violence in primary care internal medicine practices. Ann Intern Med 1995;123:737–746.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7574191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gin NE, Ruker L, Frayne S, et al. Prevalence of domestic violence among patients in three ambulatory care internal medicine clinics. J Gen Intern Med 1991;6:317–322.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1890502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher JA, Felbau-Kohn S, Smith-Slep AM, et al. Risk factors for male to female physical abuse. Aggress Violent Behav 2001;6:281–352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stith S, Tritt D, Smith B, et al. Intimate partner physical abuse perpetration and victimization risk factors: a meta-analytic review. Aggress Violent Behav 2004;10:65–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher JA, Smith-Slep AM, Heyman RE. Risk factors for male-to-female psychological abuse. Aggress Violent Behav 2001;6:255–268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caetano R, Schafer J, Fals-Stewart W. Stability and change in intimate partner violence and drinking among white, black, and Hispanic couples over a 5-year interval. Alcohol Clin Exp Res 2003;27:292–300.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12605079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell J, Jones AS, Dienemann J, et al. Intimate partner violence and physical health consequences. Arch Intern Med 2002;162:1157–1163.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12020187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coker AL, Smith PH, Bethea L, et al. Physical health consequences of physical and psychological intimate partner violence. Arch Fam Med 2000;9:451–457.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10810951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson HD, Nygren P, McInerney Y, et al. Screening women and elderly adults for family and intimate partner violence: a review of the evidence for the U. S. Preventive Services Task Force. Ann Intern Med 2004;140:387–396.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14996681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anglin D, Sachs C. Preventive care in the emergency department: screening for domestic violence in the emergency department. Acad Emerg Med 2003;10:1118–1127.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14525748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramsay J, Carter Y, Davidson L, et al. Advocacy interventions to reduce or eliminate violence and promote the physical and psychosocial well-being of women who experience intimate partner abuse. In: The Cochrane Library, Issue 3, 2009. Chichester, UK: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19588364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wathen C, MacMillan H. Interventions for violence against women: scientific review. JAMA 2003;289:589–600. Search date 2002.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12578492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan CM, Bybee DI. Reducing violence using community based advocacy for women with abusive partners. J Consult Clin Psychol 1999;67:43–53.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10028208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bell ME, Goodman LA. Supporting battered women involved with the court system: an evaluation of a law school-based advocacy intervention. Violence Women 2001;7:1377–1404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarlane J, Soeken K, Wiist W. An evaluation of interventions to decrease intimate partner violence to pregnant women. Public Health Nurs 2000;17:443–451.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11115142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centre for Clinical Effectiveness. Is therapy/counseling/group work more effective than no treatment for women who are victims of domestic violence? Melbourne: Southern Health/Monash Institute of Public Health, 2001. Search date 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubany ES, Hill EE, Owens JA, et al. Cognitive trauma therapy for battered women with PTSD (CTT-BW). J Consult Clin Psychol 2004;72:3–18.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14756610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilbert L, El-Bassel N, Manuel J, et al. An integrated relapse prevention and relationship safety intervention for women on methadone: testing short-term effects on intimate partner violence and substance use. Violence Vict 2006;21:657–672.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17022356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laverde DI. Effects of cognitive-behavioural therapy in controlling wife abuse. Rev Anal Comp 1987;3:193–200. [In Spanish]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chalk R, King PA (eds). Violence in families. Assessing prevention and treatment programs. Washington, DC: National Academy Press, 1998. Search date 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramsay J, Richardson J, Carter Y, et al. Should health professionals screen women for domestic violence? Systematic review. BMJ 2002;325:314–327. Search date 2001.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC117773</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12169509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergman B, Brismar B. A 5-year follow-up of 117 battered women. Am J Public Health 1991;81:1486–1489.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1405671</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1951810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim S, Kim J. The effects of group intervention for battered women in Korea. Arch Psychiatr Nurs 2001;15:257–264.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weir BW, O'Brien K, Bard RS, et al. Reducing hiv and partner violence risk among women with criminal justice system involvement: a randomized controlled trial of two motivational interviewing-based interventions. AIDS Behav 2009;13:509–522.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2855899</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18636325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mancoske RJ, Standifer D, Cauley C. The effectiveness of brief counseling services for battered women. Res Soc Work Pract 1994;4:53–63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stith SM, Rosen KH, McCollum EE, et al. Treating intimate partner violence within intact couple relationships: outcomes of multi-couple versus individual couple therapy. J Marital Fam Ther 2004;30:305–318.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15293649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brannen SJ, Rubin A. Comparing the effectiveness of gender-specific and couples groups in court-mandated spouse abuse treatment program. Res Soc Work Pract 1996;6:405–424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Leary KD, Heyman RE, Neidig PH. Treatment of wife abuse: a comparison of gender-specific and conjoint approaches. Behav Ther 1999;30:475–505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chronister KM, McWhirter EH. An experimental examination of two career interventions for battered women. J Counseling Psychol 2006;53:151–164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Constantino R, Kim Y, Crane PA. Effects of a social support intervention on health outcomes in residents of a domestic violence shelter: a pilot study. Issues Ment Health Nurs 2005;26:575–590.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16020071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarlane JM, Groff JY, O'Brien JA, et al. Secondary prevention of intimate partner violence: a randomized controlled trial. Nurs Res 2006;55:52–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16439929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curry MA, Durham L, Bullock L, et al. Nurse case management for pregnant women experiencing or at risk for abuse. J Obstet Gynecol Neonat Nurs 2006;3:35:181–192.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16620243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiwari A, Leung WC, Leung TW, et al. A randomized controlled trial of empowerment training for Chinese abused pregnant women in Hong King. BJOG 2005;112:1249–1256.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16101604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarlane J, Malecha A, Gist J, et al. An intervention to increase safety behaviours of abused women: results of a randomised clinical trial. Nurs Res 2002;51:347–354.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12464754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarlane J, Malecha A, Gist J, et al. Increasing the safety-promoting behaviours of abused women. Am J Nurs 2004;104:40–50.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15108570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parker B, McFarlane J, Soeken K, et al. Testing an intervention to prevent further abuse to pregnant women. Res Nurs Health 1999;22:59–66.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9928964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berk RD, Newton PJ, Berk SF. What a difference a day makes: an empirical study of the impact of shelters for battered women. J Marriage Fam 1986;48:481–490.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
