<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">22144846</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2012</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1998-393X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2011</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of oral and maxillofacial pathology : JOMFP</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Oral Maxillofac Pathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Papillon-Lefévre syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>352</StartPage>
          <EndPage>357</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>352-7</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/0973-029X.86724</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The goal of periodontal therapy has always been regeneration of the lost tissues. However, conventional periodontal therapy has not always been successful in achieving regeneration, especially when it is part of a syndrome. This case report involves a 13-year old male patient with the chief complaint of mobile teeth for over 3 months. His dental history revealed early loss of primary dentition, around 3-4 years of age and that he noticed mobility of permanent incisors and molars at 9-10 years. Keratotic skin lesions on the palms and soles were present since the age of 3 years. Full mouth intra-oral periapical radiographs showed extensive bone loss upto apical thirds of the teeth and an orthopantamograph showed "floating in air" appearance. Further, a lateral cephalogram was taken to rule out any calcifications of the duramater. The case was provisionally diagnosed to be Papillon Lefévre syndrome. A conventional polymerase chain reaction assay was also done to assess the virulence genes in aggressive periodontitis. Though the management of PLS involves the regular phases of periodontal therapy, namely, etiotropic, surgical, restorative and maintenance phases, the complete esthetic and functional rehabilitation also involves other specialities especially prosthodontic and dermatologic and later an implantologist. After appropriate periodontal and prosthodontic management, the patient has been followed up for over a year and is maintaining in a stable condition.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Veerabahu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bagavad Gita</ForeName>
            <Initials>BG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Periodontology, Sree Balaji Dental College and Hospital, Chennai, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chandrasekaran</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sc</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammed Nazish</ForeName>
            <Initials>MN</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Krishnan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mahalakshmi</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Oral Maxillofac Pathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101227995</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0973-029X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Generalized aggressive periodontitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Palmoplantar hyperkeratosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Papillon-Lefévre syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neutrophil function tests</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymerase chain reaction</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest:</b> None declared.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22144846</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3227270</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0973-029X.86724</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">JOMFP-15-352</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papillon MM, Lefévre P. 2 cases of symmetrically, familiarly palmar and plantar hyperkeratosis (Meleda disease) within brother and sister combined with severe dental alterations in both cases. Soc Franc Dermat Syph. 1924;31:82–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angel TA, Hsu S, Kornbleuth SI, Kornbleuth J, Kramer EM. Papillon. Lefevre syndrome: A case report of four affected siblings. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2002;46(2 Suppl):S8–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11807457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slots J, Ashimoto A, Flynn MJ, Li G, Chen C. Detection of putative pathogens in subgingival specimens by 16S ribosomal DNA amplification with the polymerase chain reaction. Clin Infect Dis. 1995;20(Suppl 2):S304–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7548580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe K, Frommel TO. Porphyromonas gingivalis, Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans and Treponema denticola detection in oral plaque samples using the polymerase chain reaction. J Clin Periodontol. 1996;23:212–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8707980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishihara K, Honma K, Miura T, Kato T, Okuda K. Cloning and sequence analysis of the fimbriae associated protein (fap) gene from Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans. Microb Pathog. 1997;23:63–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9245617</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashimoto A, Chen C, Bakker I, Slots J. Polymerase chain reaction detection of 8 putative periodontal pathogens in subgingival plaque of gingivitis and advanced periodontitis lesions. Oral Microbiol Immunol. 1996;11:266–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9002880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorlin RJ, Sedano H, Anderson VE. The syndrome of Palmoplantar hyperkeratosis and premature destruction of the teeth. A clinical and genetic analysis of the Papillon Lefévre syndrome. J Pediatr. 1964;65:895–908.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14244097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart TC, Hart PS, Michalec MD, Zhang Y, Marazita ML, et al.  Localization of a gene for prepubertal periodontitis to chromosome 11q14 and identification of a cathepsin C gene mutation. J Med Genet. 2000;37:95–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734516</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10662808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VanDyke TE, Taubman MA, Ebersole JL, Haffajee AD, Socransky SS, Smith DJ, et al.  The Papillon-Lefévre syndrome: Neutrophil dysfunction with severe periodontal disease. Clin Immunol Immunopathol. 1984;31:419–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6232030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyberg T. Immunological and metabolical studies in two siblings with Papillon-Lefévre syndrome. J Periodontal Res. 1982;17:563–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6219203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellado JR, Freedman Al, Salkin LM, Stein MD, Schneider DB, Cutler RH. The clinical relevance of microbiological testing: A comparative analysis of microbiologic samples secured from the same sites and cultured in two independent laboratories. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2001;21:232–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11490400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salkin LM, Freedman Al, Mellado JR, Stein MD, Schneider DB, Butler L. The clinical relevance of microbiological testing. Part 2. A comparative analysis of microbiologic samples secured simultaneously from the same sites and cultured in the same laboratory. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 2003;23:121–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12710815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gelmetti C, Nazzaro V, Cerri D, Fracasso L. Long-term preservation of permanent teeth in a patient with Papillon-Lefévre syndrome treated with etretinate. Pediatr Dermatol. 1989;6:222–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2529483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morishima T, Higaki M, Maeda T. A case of an infant with Papillon Lefévre syndrome successfully with oral administration of etretinate. J Pediatr Dermatol. 1983;2:2355–60. not able to get page nos. it's a Japanese article which we got translated.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almuneef M, Al Khenaizan S, Al Ajaji S, Al-Anazi A. Pyogenic liver abscess and Papillon-Lefévre syndrome: Not a rare association. Pediatrics. 2003;111:e85–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12509601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bullon P, Pascual A, Fernandez-Novoa MC, Borobio MV, Muniain MA, Camacho F. Late onset Papillon Lefévre syndrome? A chromosomic neutrophil function and microbiological study. J Clin Periodontol. 1993;20:662–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8227454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toygar HU, Kircelli C, Firat E, Guzeldemir E. Combined therapy in a patient with Papillon-Lefévre syndrome: A 13 year follow–up. J Periodontol. 2007;78:1819–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17760554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
