<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">22185868</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2012</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-547X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>379</Volume>
            <Issue>9817</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2012</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Lancet (London, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lancet</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Myocarditis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>738</StartPage>
          <EndPage>747</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>738-47</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60648-X</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Myocarditis is an underdiagnosed cause of acute heart failure, sudden death, and chronic dilated cardiomyopathy. In developed countries, viral infections commonly cause myocarditis; however, in the developing world, rheumatic carditis, Trypanosoma cruzi, and bacterial infections such as diphtheria still contribute to the global burden of the disease. The short-term prognosis of acute myocarditis is usually good, but varies widely by cause. Those patients who initially recover might develop recurrent dilated cardiomyopathy and heart failure, sometimes years later. Because myocarditis presents with non-specific symptoms including chest pain, dyspnoea, and palpitations, it often mimics more common disorders such as coronary artery disease. In some patients, cardiac MRI and endomyocardial biopsy can help identify myocarditis, predict risk of cardiovascular events, and guide treatment. Finding effective therapies has been challenging because the pathogenesis of chronic dilated cardiomyopathy after viral myocarditis is complex and determined by host and viral genetics as well as environmental factors. Findings from recent clinical trials suggest that some patients with chronic inflammatory cardiomyopathy have a progressive clinical course despite standard medical care and might improve with a short course of immunosuppression.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright Â© 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sagar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sandeep</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Diseases, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Peter P</ForeName>
            <Initials>PP</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cooper</LastName>
            <ForeName>Leslie T</ForeName>
            <Initials>LT</Initials>
            <Suffix>Jr</Suffix>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 HL056267</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R56 HL056267</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Lancet</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>2985213R</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0140-6736</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000208" MajorTopicYN="N">Acute Disease</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001424" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009205" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocarditis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014777" MajorTopicYN="N">Virus Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of interest</b>. PPL ans SS declare that they have no conflicts of interest. LTC has received consultancy fees from Sanofi Pasteur.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2012</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22185868</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS940696</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5814111</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60648-X</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0140-6736(11)60648-X</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heidecker B, Kittleson MM, Kasper EK, et al.  Transcriptomic biomarkers for the accurate diagnosis of myocarditis. Circulation. 2011;123:1174–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3408077</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhl U, Pauschinger M, Seeberg B, et al.  Viral persistence in the myocardium is associated with progressive cardiac dysfunction. Circulation. 2005;112:1965–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16172268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper LT, Baughman KL, Feldman AM, et al.  The role of endomyocardial biopsy in the management of cardiovascular disease: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association, the American College of Cardiology, and the European Society of Cardiology. Circulation. 2007;116:2216–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17959655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaji M, Kuno H, Turu T, Sato Y, Oizumi K. Elevated serum myosin light chain I in influenza patients. Intern Med. 2001;40:594–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11506298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engler RJM, Collins LC, Gibbs BT, et al.  Myocarditis after smallpox/vaccinia immunization: passive vaccine safety surveillance compared to prospective studies. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2009;123:S264.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan J, Roper MH, Sperling L, et al.  Myocarditis, pericarditis, and dilated cardiomyopathy after smallpox vaccination among civilians in the United States, January-October 2003. Clin Infect Dis. 2008;46(suppl 3):S242–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18284365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kasper E, Agema W, Hutchins G, Deckers J, Hare J, Baughman K. The causes of dilated cardiomyopathy: a clinicopathologic review of 673 consecutive patients. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1994;23:586–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8113538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarthy RE, 3rd, Boehmer JP, Hruban RH, et al.  Long-term outcome of fulminant myocarditis as compared with acute (nonfulminant) myocarditis. N Engl J Med. 2000;342:690–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10706898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamara DM, Starling RC, Cooper LT, et al. for the IMAC Investigators  Clinical and demographic predictors of outcomes in recent onset dilated cardiomyopathy. Results of the IMAC (intervention in myocarditis and acute cardiomyopathy)-2 study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;58:1112–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6467576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21884947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvarez JA, Orav EJ, Wilkinson JD, et al. for the Pediatric Cardiomyopathy Registry Investigators  Competing risks for death and cardiac transplantation in children with dilated cardiomyopathy: results from the pediatric cardiomyopathy registry. Circulation. 2011;124:814–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3199969</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21788591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper LT, Berry GJ, Shabetai R. Giant cell myocarditis: natural history and treatment. N Engl J Med. 1997;336:1860–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9197214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assomull RG, Prasad SK, Lyne J, et al.  Cardiovascular magnetic resonance, fibrosis, and prognosis in dilated cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;48:1977–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17112987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dec GW, Jr, Waldman H, Southern J, Fallon JT, Hutter AM, Jr, Palacios I. Viral myocarditis mimicking acute myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1992;20:85–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1607543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz A, Mahrholdt H, Athanasiadis A, et al.  Coronary vasospasm as the underlying cause for chest pain in patients with PVB19 myocarditis. Heart. 2008;94:1456–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18230640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarda L, Colin P, Boccara F, et al.  Myocarditis in patients with clinical presentation of myocardial infarction and normal coronary angiograms. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2001;37:786–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11693753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhl U, Pauschinger M, Bock T, et al.  Parvovirus B19 infection mimicking acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2003;108:945–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12925460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magnani JW, Danik HJ, Dec GW, Jr, DiSalvo TG. Survival in biopsy-proven myocarditis: a long-term retrospective analysis of the histopathologic, clinical, and hemodynamic predictors. Am Heart J. 2006;151:463–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16442915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imazio M, Brucato A, Mayosi BM, et al.  Medical therapy of pericardial diseases: part I: idiopathic and infectious pericarditis. J Cardiovasc Med (Hagerstown) 2010;11:712–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20736783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uemura A, Morimoto S, Hiramitsu S, Hishida H. Endomyocardial biopsy findings in 50 patients with idiopathic atrioventricular block: presence of myocarditis. Jpn Heart J. 2001;42:691–700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11933919</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel RA, DiMarco JP, Akar JG, Voros S, Kramer CM. Chagas myocarditis and syncope. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2005;7:685–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16136859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costello JM, Alexander ME, Greco KM, Perez-Atayde AR, Laussen PC. Lyme carditis in children: presentation, predictive factors, and clinical course. Pediatrics. 2009;123:e835–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kandolin R, Lehtonen J, Kupari M. Cardiac sarcoidosis and giant cell myocarditis as causes of atrioventricular block in young and middle-aged adults. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2011;4:303–09.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21427276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okura Y, Dec GW, Hare JM, et al.  A clincal and histopathologic comparison of cardiac sarcoidosis and idiopathic giant cell myocarditis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2003;42:322–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12535829</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pieroni M, Dello Russo A, Marzo F, et al.  High prevalence of myocarditis mimicking arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy differential diagnosis by electroanatomic mapping-guided endomyocardial biopsy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:681–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19232901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wojnicz R, Nowalany-Kozielska E, Wojciechowska C, et al.  Randomized, placebo-controlled study for immunosuppressive treatment of inflammatory dilated cardiomyopathy: two-year follow-up results. Circulation. 2001;104:39–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11435335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kindermann I, Kindermann M, Kandolf R, et al.  Predictors of outcome in patients with suspected myocarditis. Circulation. 2008;118:639–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18645053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frustaci A, Chimenti C, Calabrese F, Pieroni M, Thiene G, Maseri A. Immunosuppressive therapy for active lymphocytic myocarditis: virological and immunologic profile of responders versus nonresponders. Circulation. 2003;107:857–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12591756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frustaci A. Randomized study of the efficacy of immunosuppressive therapy in patients with virus-negative inflammatory cardiomyopathy: the TIMIC study. Eur Heart J. 2009;30:1995–2002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19556262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Leeuw N, Melchers WJ, Balk AH, de Jonge N, Galama JM. Study on microbial persistence in end-stage idiopathic dilated. Clin Infect Dis. 1999;29:522–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10530439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mavrouli MD, Spanakis N, Levidiotou S, et al.  Serologic prevalence of coxsackievirus group B in Greece. Viral Immunol. 2007;20:11–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17425417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumori A, Matoba Y, Sasayama S. Dilated cardiomyopathy associated with hepatitis C virus infection. Circulation. 1995;92:2519–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7586353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhl U, Pauschinger M, Noutsias M, et al.  High prevalence of viral genomes and multiple viral infections in the myocardium of adults with “idiopathic” left ventricular dysfunction. Circulation. 2005;111:887–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhl U, Pauschinger M, Schwimmbeck PL, et al.  Interferon-beta treatment eliminates cardiotropic viruses and improves left ventricular function in patients with myocardial persistence of viral genomes and left ventricular dysfunction. Circulation. 2003;107:2793–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhl U, Lassner D, Pauschinger M, et al.  Prevalence of erythrovirus genotypes in the myocardium of patients with dilated cardiomyopathy. J Med Virol. 2008;80:1243–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18461615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Punukollu G, Gowda RM, Khan IA, Navarro VS, Vasavada BC. Clinical aspects of the Chagas’ heart disease. Int J Cardiol. 2007;115:279–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16769134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galazka A. The changing epidemiology of diphtheria in the vaccine era. J Infect Dis. 2000;181(suppl 1):S2–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10657184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alarcón de Noya B, Díaz-Bello Z, Colmenares C, et al.  Large urban outbreak of orally acquired acute Chagas disease at a school in Caracas, Venezuela. J Infect Dis. 2010;201:1308–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20307205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grupi CJ, Moffa PJ, Barbosa SA, et al.  Holter monitoring in Chagas’ heart disease. Sao Paulo Med J. 1995;113:835–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8650484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marques DS, Canesin MF, Barutta F, Júnior, Fuganti CJ, Barretto AC. Evaluation of asymptomatic patients with chronic Chagas disease through ambulatory electrocardiogram, echocardiogram and B-Type natriuretic peptide analyses. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2006;87:336–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17057935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marin-Neto JA, Cunha-Neto E, Maciel BC, Simoes MV. Pathogenesis of chronic Chagas heart disease. Circulation. 2007;115:1109–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ntsekhe M, Mayosi BM. Cardiac manifestations of HIV infection: an African perspective. Nat Clin Pract Cardiovasc Med. 2009;6:120–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19104517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sendagire H, Easterbrook PJ, Nankya I, Arts E, Thomas D, Reynolds SJ. The challenge of HIV-1 antiretroviral resistance in Africa in the era of HAART. AIDS Rev. 2009;11:59–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19529746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu QN, Reddy S, Sayre JW, Pop V, Graves MC, Fiala M. Essential role of HIV type 1-infected and cyclooxygenase 2-activated macrophages and T cells in HIV type 1 myocarditis. AIDS Res Hum Retroviruses. 2001;17:1423–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11679155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pugliese A, Isnardi D, Saini A, Scarabelli T, Raddino R, Torre D. Impact of highly active antiretroviral therapy in HIV-positive patients with cardiac involvement. J Infect. 2000;40:282–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10908024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobb S, Anderson F, Bauer W. Length of life and cause of death in rheumatoid arthritis. N Engl J Med. 1953;249:553–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13087647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prior P, Symmons DP, Scott DL, Brown R, Hawkins CF. Cause of death in rheumatoid arthritis. Br J Rheumatol. 1984;23:92–99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6722416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levin MD, Zoet-Nugteren SK, Markusse HM. Myocarditis and primary Sjogren’s syndrome. Lancet. 1999;354:128–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10408493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peltomaa R, Paimela L, Kautiainen H, Leirisalo-Repo M. Mortality in patients with rheumatoid arthritis treated actively from the time of diagnosis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2002;61:889–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753911</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12228159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enko K, Tada T, Ohgo KO, et al.  Fulminant eosinophilic myocarditis associated with visceral larva migrans caused by Toxocara canis infection. Circ J. 2009;73:1344–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19122304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu L, Cooper LT, Kephart G, Gleich GJ.  The eosinophil in cardiac disease. In: Cooper L, editor. Myocarditis: from bench to bedside. Totowa, NJ: Humana Press; 2002. pp. 437–53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniels P, Berry G, Tazelaar H, Cooper L. Hypersensitivity myocarditis presenting histologically with fulminant giant cell myocarditis. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2000;9:287–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11064276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben m’rad M, Leclerc-Mercier S, Blanche P, et al.  Drug-induced hypersensitivity syndrome: clinical and biologic disease patterns in 24 patients. Medicine. 2009;88:131–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19440116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barton M, Finkelstein Y, Opavsky MA, et al.  Eosinophilic myocarditis temporally associated with conjugate meningococcal C and hepatitis B vaccines in children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2008;27:831–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18664932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper LT. Giant cell and granulomatous myocarditis. Heart Failure Clinics. 2005;1:431–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17386865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper LT, Jr, Hare JM, Tazelaar HD, et al.  Usefulness of immunosuppression for giant cell myocarditis. Am J Cardiol. 2008;102:1535–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2613862</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maekawa Y, Ouzounian M, Opavsky MA, Liu PP. Connecting the missing link between dilated cardiomyopathy and viral myocarditis: virus, cytoskeleton, and innate immunity. Circulation. 2007;115:5–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17200452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper LT., Jr Myocarditis. N Engl J Med. 2009;360:1526–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5814110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19357408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu PP, Opavsky MA. Viral myocarditis: receptors that bridge the cardiovascular. Circulation Res. 2000;86:253–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10679474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noutsias M, Fechner H, de Jonge H, et al.  Human coxsackie-adenovirus receptor is colocalized with integrins alpha(v) beta(3) and alpha(v)beta(5) on the cardiomyocyte sarcolemma and upregulated in dilated cardiomyopathy: implications for cardiotropic viral infections. Circulation. 2001;104:275–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coyne CB, Bergelson JM. Virus-induced Abl and Fyn kinase signals permit coxsackievirus entry through epithelial tight junctions. Cell. 2006;124:119–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16413486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiong D, Yajima T, Lim BK, et al.  Inducible cardiac-restricted expression of enteroviral protease 2A is sufficient to induce dilated cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 2007;115:94–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17190866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuse K, Chan G, Liu Y, et al.  Myeloid differentiation factor-88 plays a crucial role in the pathogenesis of Coxsackievirus B3-induced myocarditis and influences type I interferon production. Circulation. 2005;112:2276–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16216974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Y, Fukuoka M, Li G, et al.  Regulatory T cells protect mice against coxsackievirus-induced myocarditis through the transforming growth factor beta-coxsackie-adenovirus receptor pathway. Circulation. 2010;121:2624–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20530002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JK, Zaidi SH, Liu P, et al.  A serine elastase inhibitor reduces inflammation and fibrosis and preserves. Nat Med. 1998;4:1383–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9846575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindenfeld J, Albert NM, Boehmer JP, et al.  Executive summary: HFSA 2010 comprehensive heart failure practice guideline. J Card Fail. 2010;16:475–539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Task Force for Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute and Chronic Heart Failure of European Society of Cardiology. Dickstein K, Cohen-Solal A, Filippatos G, et al.  ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure 2008: the Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute and Chronic Heart Failure 2008 of the European Society of Cardiology. Developed in collaboration with the Heart Failure Association of the ESC (HFA) and endorsed by the European Society of Intensive Care Medicine (ESICM) Eur Heart J. 2008;29:2388–442.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hunt SA, Abraham WT, Chin MH, et al.  2009 Focused update incorporated into the ACC/AHA 2005 Guidelines for the Diagnosis and Management of Heart Failure in Adults. A Report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines developed in collaboration with the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:e1–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19358937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith SC, Ladenson JH, Mason JW, Jaffe AS. Elevations of cardiac troponin I associated with myocarditis. Experimental and clinical correlates. Circulation. 1997;95:163–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8994432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park JP, Song J-M, Kim S-H, et al.  In-hospital prognostic factors in patients with acute myocarditis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:A144–97. (abstr 1042–178)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuse K, Kodama M, Okura Y, et al.  Predictors of disease course in patients with acute myocarditis. Circulation. 2000;102:2829–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11104740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishii M, Inomata T, Takehana H, et al.  Serum levels of interleukin-10 on admission as a prognostic predictor of human fulminant myocarditis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;44:1292–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15364334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caforio AL, Tona F, Bottaro S, et al.  Clinical implications of anti-heart autoantibodies in myocarditis and dilated cardiomyopathy. Autoimmunity. 2008;41:35–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18176863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakashima H, Katayama T, Ishizaki M, Takeno M, Honda Y, Yano K. Q wave and non-Q wave myocarditis with special reference to clinical significance. Jpn Heart J. 1998;39:763–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10089938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ukena C, Mahfoud F, Kindermann I, Kandolf R, Kindermann M, Böhm M. Prognostic electrocardiographic parameters in patients with suspected myocarditis. Eur J Heart Fail. 2011;13:398–405.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21239404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skouri HN, Dec GW, Friedrich MG, Cooper LT. Noninvasive imaging in myocarditis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;48:2085–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17112998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendes LA, Dec GW, Picard MH, Palacios IF, Newell J, Davidoff R. Right ventricular dysfunction: an independent predictor of adverse outcome. Am Heart J. 1994;128:301–07.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8037097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American College of Cardiology Foundation Task Force on Expert Consensus Documents. Hundley WG, Bluemke DA, Finn JP, et al.  ACCF/ACR/AHA/NASCI/SCMR 2010 Expert Consensus Document on Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation Task Force on Expert Consensus Documents. Circulation. 2010;121:2462–508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3034132</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479157</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baccouche H, Mahrholdt H, Meinhardt G, et al.  Diagnostic synergy of non-invasive cardiovascular magnetic resonance and invasive endomyocardial biopsy in troponin-positive patients without coronary artery disease. Eur Heart J. 2009;30:2869–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedrich MG, Sechtem U, Schulz-Menger J, et al.  Cardiovascular magnetic resonance in myocarditis: a JACC White Paper. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:1475–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2743893</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19389557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahrholdt H, Wagner A, Deluigi CC, et al.  Presentation, patterns of myocardial damage, and clinical course of viral myocarditis. Circulation. 2006;114:1581–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17015795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holzmann M, Nicko A, Kuhl U, et al.  Complication rate of right ventricular endomyocardial biopsy via the femoral approach: a retrospective and prospective study analyzing 3048 diagnostic procedures over an 11-year period. Circulation. 2008;118:1722–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18838566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill KD, Atkinson JB, Doyle TP, Dodd D. Routine performance of endomyocardial biopsy decreases the incidence of orthotopic heart transplant for myocarditis. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2009;28:1261–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz A, Kindermann I, Kindermann M, et al.  Comparative evaluation of left and right ventricular endomyocardial biopsy: differences in complication rate and diagnostic performance. Circulation. 2010;122:900–09.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20713901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rezkalla SH, Raikar S, Kloner RA. Treatment of viral myocarditis with focus on captopril. Am J Cardiol. 1996;77:634–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8610616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saegusa S, Fei Y, Takahashi T, et al.  Oral administration of candesartan improves the survival of mice with viral myocarditis through modification of cardiac adiponectin expression. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2007;21:155–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17484035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maron BJ, Ackerman MJ, Nishimura RA, Pyeritz RE, Towbin JA, Udelson JE. Task Force 4: HCM and other cardiomyopathies, mitral valve prolapse, myocarditis, and Marfan syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005;45:1340–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15837284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason JW, O’Connell JB, Herskowitz A, et al.  A clinical trial of immunosuppressive therapy for myocarditis. The Myocarditis Treatment Trial Investigators. N Engl J Med. 1995;333:269–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7596370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishimoto C, Takada H, Hiraoka Y. Intravenous IgG: supertherapy for myocarditis and acute dilated cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 1999;99:975.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10027823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drucker NA, Colan SD, Lewis AB, Beiser AS, Wessel DL, Takahashi M. Gamma-globulin treatment of acute myocarditis in the pediatric population. Circulation. 1994;89:252–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8281654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tedeschi A, Airaghi L, Giannini S, Ciceri L, Massari FM. High-dose intravenous immunoglobulin in the treatment of acute myocarditis. A case report and review of the literature. J Intern Med. 2002;251:169–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11905592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamara DM, Holubkov R, Starling RC, et al.  Controlled trial of intravenous immune globulin in recent-onset dilated cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 2001;103:2254–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11342473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hia CP, Yip WC, Tai BC, Quek SC. Immunosuppressive therapy in acute myocarditis: an 18 year systematic review. Arch Dis Child. 2004;89:580–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1719952</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155409</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pages O, Aubert S, Combes A, et al.  Paracorporeal pulsatile biventricular assist device versus extracorporal membrane oxygenation-extracorporal life support in adult fulminant myocarditis. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2009;137:194–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19154925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duncan B, Bohn D, Atz A, French J, Laussen P, Wessel D. Mechanical circulatory support for the treatment of children with acute fulminant myocarditis. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2001;122:440–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11547292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reinhartz O, Hill J, Al-Khaldi A, Pelletier M, Robbins R, Farrar D. Thoratec ventricular assist devices in pediatric patients: update on clinical results. ASAIO J. 2005;51:501–03.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16322705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Topkara V, Dang NC, Barili F, et al.  Ventricular assist device use for the treatment of acute viral myocarditis. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2006;131:1190–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16678619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moloney ED, Egan JJ, Kelly P, Wood AE, Cooper LT., Jr Transplantation for myocarditis: a controversy revisited. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2005;24:1103–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16102447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvarez JA, Orav EJ, Wilkinson JD, et al. for the Pediatric Cardiomyopathy Registry Investigators  Competing risks for death and cardiac transplantation in children with dilated cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 2011;124:814–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3199969</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21788591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costanzo-Nordin MR, Reap EA, O’Connell JB, Robinson JA, Scanlon PJ. A nonsteroid anti-inflammatory drug exacerbates Coxsackie B3 murine myocarditis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1985;6:1078–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2995470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zipes D, Camm A, Borggrefe M, et al.  ACC/AHA/ESC 2006 Guideline for management of patients with ventricular arrhythmias and the prevention of sudden cardiac death. Circulation. 2006;114:e385–484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16935995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
