<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">22876388</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK98937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>Transworld Research Network</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Trivandrum (India)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="pctm">Pancreatic Cancer and Tumor Microenvironment</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2012</Year></PubDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grippo</LastName><ForeName>Paul J.</ForeName><Initials>PJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Robert H. Lurie Comprehensive Cancer Center of Northwestern University Chicago, IL 60611, USA</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munshi</LastName><ForeName>Hidayatullah G.</ForeName><Initials>HG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Robert H. Lurie Comprehensive Cancer Center of Northwestern University Chicago, IL 60611, USA</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Isbn>9788178955483</Isbn></Book><LocationLabel Type="chapter">Chapter 3</LocationLabel><ArticleTitle book="pctm" part="ch3">Pancreatic stellate cells and fibrosis</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Phillips</LastName><ForeName>Phoebe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pancreatic Cancer Translational Research Group, School of Medical Sciences University of New South Wales, Sydney, Australia</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Pancreatic cancer is characterised by a prominent desmoplastic/stromal reaction. It is now known that pancreatic stellate cells (PSCs) are the principal source of fibrosis in the stroma and interact closely with cancer cells to create a tumor facilitatory environment that stimulates local tumor growth and distant metastasis. Pancreatic fibrosis is initiated when PSCs become activated and undergo morphological and, more importantly, functional changes so that the rate of extracellular matrix (ECM) deposition exceeds the rate of ECM degradation in the gland. It is now well established that pancreatic cancer cells activate PSCs leading to increased fibrosis. This chapter summarises recent advances in our understanding of the role of fibrosis in pancreatic cancer, with particular reference to the central role played by pancreatic stellate cells. An improved knowledge of PSC biology has the potential to provide an insight into pathways that may be therapeutically targeted to inhibit PSC activation, thereby inhibiting the development of fibrosis in pancreatic cancer and interrupting stellate cell - cancer cell interactions so as to retard cancer progression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2012, Transworld Research Network.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Introduction">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.The_microenvironment_of_pancreatic_c">The microenvironment of pancreatic cancer</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.The_biology_of_pancreatic_stellate_c">The biology of pancreatic stellate cells</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Role_of_pancreatic_stellate_cells_in">Role of pancreatic stellate cells in pancreatic fibrosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.The_role_of_cancer_stellate_cell_int">The role of cancer-stellate cell interactions in tumor progression</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.The_hypoxia_fibrosis_cycle">The hypoxia fibrosis cycle</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Role_of_pancreatic_stellate_cells_an">Role of pancreatic stellate cells and fibrosis in epithelial- mesenchymal transition</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Targeting_pancreatic_stellate_cell_m">Targeting pancreatic stellate cell mediated fibrosis: A potential therapy</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Summary_Points">Summary Points</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Conclusion">Conclusion</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.Acknowledgements">Acknowledgements</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="pctm" part="ch3" sec="ch3.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo M. Pancreatic cancer. N Engl J Med. 2010;362:1605–1617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20427809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jemal A, Siegel R, Ward E, Hao Y, Xu J, Murray T, Thun MJ. Cancer statistics, 2008. CA Cancer J Clin. 2008;58:71–96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18287387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson R, Aho U, Nilsson BI, Peters GJ, Pastor-Anglada M, Rasch W, Sandvold ML. Gemcitabine chemoresistance in pancreatic cancer: molecular mechanisms and potential solutions. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2009;44:782–786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19214867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Li Y, Ahmad A, Banerjee S, Azmi AS, Kong D, Sarkar FH. Pancreatic cancer: understanding and overcoming chemoresistance. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2011;8:27–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21102532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zalatnai A, Molnar J. Review. Molecular background of chemoresistance in pancreatic cancer. In Vivo. 2007;21:339–347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17436586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trouilloud I, Dubreuil O, Boussaha T, Lepere C, Landi B, Zaanan A, Bachet JB, Taieb J. Medical treatment of pancreatic cancer: New hopes after 10 years of gemcitabine. Clin Res Hepatol Gastroenterol. 2011;35:367–374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21435966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apte M, Pirola R, Wilson J. New insights into alcoholic pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;24 Suppl 3:S51–S56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19799699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duner S, Lopatko Lindman J, Ansari D, Gundewar C, Andersson R. Pancreatic cancer: the role of pancreatic stellate cells in tumor progression. Pancreatology. 2010;10:673–681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21242706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrow B, Albo D, Berger DH. The role of the tumor microenvironment in the progression of pancreatic cancer. J Surg Res. 2008;149:319–328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18639248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habisch H, Zhou S, Siech M, Bachem MG. Interaction of Stellate Cells with Pancreatic Carcinoma Cells. Cancers. 2010;2:1661–1682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24281180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadevan D, Von Hoff DD. Tumor-stroma interactions in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Mol Cancer Ther. 2007;6:1186–1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17406031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neesse A, Michl P, Frese KK, Feig C, Cook N, Jacobetz MA, Lolkema MP, Buchholz M, Olive KP, Gress TM, Tuveson DA. Stromal biology and therapy in pancreatic cancer. Gut. 2010;60:861–880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apte MV, Park S, Phillips PA, Santucci N, Goldstein D, Kumar RK, Ramm GA, Buchler M, Friess H, McCarroll JA, Keogh G, Merrett N, Pirola R, Wilson JS. Desmoplastic reaction in pancreatic cancer: role of pancreatic stellate cells. Pancreas. 2004;29:179–187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15367883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachem MG, Schünemann M, Ramadani M, Siech M, Beger H, Buck A, Zhou S, Schmid-Kotsas A, Adler G. Pancreatic carcinoma cells induce fibrosis by stimulating proliferation and matrix synthesis of stellate cells. Gastroenterology. 2005;128:907–921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15825074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan M, Reiser-Erkan C, Michalski CW, Deucker S, Sauliunaite D, Streit S, Esposito I, Friess H, Kleeff J. Cancer-stellate cell interactions perpetuate the hypoxia-fibrosis cycle in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Neoplasia. 2009;11:497–508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2671860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19412434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang RF, Moore T, Arumugam T, Ramachandran V, Amos KD, Rivera A, Ji B, Evans DB, Logsdon CD. Cancer-associated stromal fibroblasts promote pancreatic tumor progression. Cancer Res. 2008;68:918–926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2519173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18245495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonlaufen A, Joshi S, Qu C, Phillips PA, Xu Z, Parker NR, Toi CS, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Goldstein D, Apte MV. Pancreatic stellate cells: partners in crime with pancreatic cancer cells. Cancer Res. 2008;68:2085–2093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Z, Vonlaufen A, Phillips PA, Fiala-Beer E, Zhang X, Yang L, Biankin AV, Goldstein D, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Role of pancreatic stellate cells in pancreatic cancer metastasis. Am J Pathol. 2010;177:2585–2596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2966814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20934972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan M, Reiser-Erkan C, Michalski CW, Kleeff J. Tumor microenvironment and progression of pancreatic cancer. Exp Oncol. 2010;32:128–131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21403605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J, Wientjes MG, Au JL. Pancreatic cancer: pathobiology, treatment options, and drug delivery. AAPS J. 2010;12:223–232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2844509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20198462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller MM, Fusenig NE. Friends or foes - bipolar effects of the tumour stroma in cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2004;4:839–849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15516957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apte MV, Phillips PA, Fahmy RG, Darby SJ, Rodgers SC, McCaughan GW, Korsten MA, Pirola RC, Naidoo D, Wilson JS. Does alcohol directly stimulate pancreatic fibrogenesis? Studies with rat pancreatic stellate cells. Gastroenterology. 2000;118:780–794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10734030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apte MV, Pirola RC, Wilson JS. Battle-scarred pancreas: role of alcohol and pancreatic stellate cells in pancreatic fibrosis. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2006;21 Suppl 3:S97–S101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16958684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haber PS, Keogh GW, Apte MV, Moran CS, Stewart NL, Crawford DH, Pirola RC, McCaughan GW, Ramm GA, Wilson JS. Activation of pancreatic stellate cells in human and experimental pancreatic fibrosis. Am J Pathol. 1999;155:1087–1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1867025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10514391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motoo Y, Shimasaki T, Ishigaki Y, Nakajima H, Kawakami K, Minamoto T. Metabolic Disorder, Inflammation, and Deregulated Molecular Pathways Converging in Pancreatic Cancer Development: Implications for New Therapeutic Strategies. Cancers. 2011;3:446–460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3756371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24212624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan M, Michalski CW, Rieder S, Reiser-Erkan C, Abiatari I, Kolb A, Giese NA, Esposito I, Friess H, Kleeff J. The activated stroma index is a novel and independent prognostic marker in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2008;6:1155–1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18639493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couvelard A, O'Toole D, Leek R, Turley H, Sauvanet A, Degott C, Ruszniewski P, Belghiti J, Harris AL, Gatter K, Pezzella F. Expression of hypoxia- inducible factors is correlated with the presence of a fibrotic focus and angiogenesis in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinomas. Histopathology. 2005;46:668–676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15910598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan M, Kleeff J, Gorbachevski A, Reiser C, Mitkus T, Esposito I, Giese T, Buchler MW, Giese NA, Friess H. Periostin creates a tumor-supportive microenvironment in the pancreas by sustaining fibrogenic stellate cell activity. Gastroenterology. 2007;132:1447–1464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17408641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koong AC, Mehta VK, Le QT, Fisher GA, Terris DJ, Brown JM, Bastidas AJ, Vierra M. Pancreatic tumors show high levels of hypoxia. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2000;48:919–922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11072146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olive KP, Jacobetz MA, Davidson CJ, Gopinathan A, McIntyre D, Honess D, Madhu B, Goldgraben MA, Caldwell ME, Allard D, Frese KK, Denicola G, Feig C, Combs C, Winter SP, Ireland-Zecchini H, Reichelt S, Howat WJ, Chang A, Dhara M, Wang L, Ruckert F, Grutzmann R, Pilarsky C, Izeradjene K, Hingorani SR, Huang P, Davies SE, Plunkett W, Egorin M, Hruban RH, Whitebread N, McGovern K, Adams J, Iacobuzio-Donahue C, Griffiths J, Tuveson DA. Inhibition of Hedgehog signaling enhances delivery of chemotherapy in a mouse model of pancreatic cancer. Science. 2009;324:1457–1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2998180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19460966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apte MV, Haber PS, Applegate TL, Norton ID, McCaughan GW, Korsten MA, Pirola RC, Wilson JS. Periacinar Stellate Shaped Cells in Rat Pancreas - Identification, Isolation, and Culture. Gut. 1998;43:128–133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1727174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9771417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachem MG, Schneider E, Gross H, Weidenbach H, Schmid RM, Menke A, Siech M, Beger H, Grunert A, Adler G. Identification, Culture, and Characterization of Pancreatic Stellate Cells in Rats and Humans. Gastroenterology. 1998;115:421–432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9679048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Omary MB, Lugea A, Lowe AW, Pandol SJ. The pancreatic stellate cell: a star on the rise in pancreatic diseases. J Clin Invest. 2007;117:50–59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1716214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17200706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erkan M, Weis N, Pan Z, Schwager C, Samkharadze T, Jiang X, Wirkner U, Giese NA, Ansorge W, Debus J, Huber PE, Friess H, Abdollahi A, Kleeff J. Organ-, inflammation- and cancer specific transcriptional fingerprints of pancreatic and hepatic stellate cells. Mol Cancer. 2010;9:88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20416094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchholz M, Kestler HA, Holzmann K, Ellenrieder V, Schneiderhan W, Siech M, Adler G, Bachem MG, Gress TM. Transcriptome analysis of human hepatic and pancreatic stellate cells: organ-specific variations of a common transcriptional phenotype. J Mol Med. 2005;83:795–805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15976918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips PA, McCarroll JA, Park S, Wu MJ, Pirola R, Korsten M, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Rat pancreatic stellate cells secrete matrix metalloproteinases: implications for extracellular matrix turnover. Gut. 2003;52:275–282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1774949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12524413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips PA, Yang L, Shulkes A, Vonlaufen A, Poljak A, Bustamante S, Warren A, Xu Z, Guilhaus M, Pirola R, Apte MV, Wilson JS. Pancreatic stellate cells produce acetylcholine and may play a role in pancreatic exocrine secretion. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107:17397–17402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2951425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masamune A, Satoh A, Watanabe T, Kikuta K, Satoh M, Suzuki N, Satoh K, Shimosegawa T. Effects of ethanol and its metabolites on human pancreatic stellate cells. Dig Dis Sci. 2010;55:204–211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apte MV, Haber PS, Darby SJ, Rodgers SC, McCaughan GW, Korsten MA, Pirola RC, Wilson JS. Pancreatic stellate cells are activated by proinflammatory cytokines : implications for pancreatic fibrogenesis. Gut. 1999;44:534–541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1727467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10075961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao R, Brigstock DR. Connective tissue growth factor (CCN2) in rat pancreatic stellate cell function: integrin alpha5beta1 as a novel CCN2 receptor. Gastroenterology. 2005;129:1019–1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16143139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordes C, Brookmann S, Haussinger D, Klonowski-Stumpe H. Differential and synergistic effects of platelet-derived growth factor-BB and transforming growth factor-beta1 on activated pancreatic stellate cells. Pancreas. 2005;31:156–167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16025003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mews P, Phillips P, Fahmy R, Korsten M, Pirola R, Wilson J, Apte M. Pancreatic stellate cells respond to inflammatory cytokines: potential role in chronic pancreatitis. Gut. 2002;50:535–541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1773172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11889076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonlaufen A, Phillips PA, Yang L, Xu Z, Fiala-Beer E, Zhang X, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Isolation of quiescent human pancreatic stellate cells: a promising in vitro tool for studies of human pancreatic stellate cell biology. Pancreatology. 2010;10:434–443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20733342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips PA, Wu MJ, Kumar RK, Doherty E, McCarroll JA, Park S, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Cell migration: a novel aspect of pancreatic stellate cell biology. Gut. 2003;52:677–682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1773645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12692052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider E, Schmid-Kotsas A, Zhao J, Weidenbach H, Schmid RM, Menke A, Adler G, Waltenberger J, Grunert A, Bachem MG. Identification of mediators stimulating proliferation and matrix synthesis of rat pancreatic stellate cells. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2001;281:C532–C543.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11443052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoki H, Ohnishi H, Hama K, Ishijima T, Satoh Y, Hanatsuka K, Ohashi A, Wada S, Miyata T, Kita H, Yamamoto H, Osawa H, Sato K, Tamada K, Yasuda H, Mashima H, Sugano K. Autocrine loop between TGF-beta1 and IL-1beta through Smad3- and ERK-dependent pathways in rat pancreatic stellate cells. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2006;290:C1100–C1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16371439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoki H, Ohnishi H, Hama K, Shinozaki S, Kita H, Yamamoto H, Osawa H, Sato K, Tamada K, Sugano K. Existence of autocrine loop between interleukin-6 and transforming growth factor-beta1 in activated rat pancreatic stellate cells. J Cell Biochem. 2006;99:221–228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16598747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang X, Abiatari I, Kong B, Erkan M, De Oliveira T, Giese NA, Michalski CW, Friess H, Kleeff J. Pancreatic islet and stellate cells are the main sources of endocrine gland-derived vascular endothelial growth factor/ prokineticin-1 in pancreatic cancer. Pancreatology. 2009;9:165–172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohnishi N, Miyata T, Ohnishi H, Yasuda H, Tamada K, Ueda N, Mashima H, Sugano K. Activin A is an autocrine activator of rat pancreatic stellate cells: potential therapeutic role of follistatin for pancreatic fibrosis. Gut. 2003;52:1487–1493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1773818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shek FW, Benyon RC, Walker FM, McCrudden PR, Pender SL, Williams EJ, Johnson PA, Johnson CD, Bateman AC, Fine DR, Iredale JP. Expression of Transforming Growth Factor-b1 by Pancreatic Stellate Cells and Its Implications for Matrix Secretion and Turnover in Chronic Pancreatitis. Am J Pathol. 2002;160:1787–1798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1850856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12000730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masamune A, Shimosegawa T. Signal transduction in pancreatic stellate cells. J Gastroenterol. 2009;44:249–260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19271115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masamune A, Satoh M, Kikuta K, Suzuki N, Shimosegawa T. Activation of JAK-STAT pathway is required for platelet-derived growth factor-induced proliferation of pancreatic stellate cells. World J Gastroenterol. 2005;11:3385–3391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15948243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarroll JA, Phillips PA, Kumar RK, Park S, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Pancreatic stellate cell migration: role of the phosphatidylinositol 3- kinase(PI3-kinase) pathway. Biochem Pharmacol. 2004;67:1215–1225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15006556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klonowski-Stumpe H, Reinehr R, Fischer R, Warskulat U, Luthen R, Haussinger D. Production and effects of endothelin-1 in rat pancreatic stellate cells. Pancreas. 2003;27:67–74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12826908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yen TW, Aardal NP, Bronner MP, Thorning DR, Savard CE, Lee SP, Bell RH., Jr Myofibroblasts are responsible for the desmoplastic reaction surrounding human pancreatic carcinomas. Surgery. 2002;131:129–134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11854689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vonlaufen A, Phillips PA, Xu Z, Goldstein D, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Pancreatic stellate cells and pancreatic cancer cells: an unholy alliance. Cancer Res. 2008;68:7707–7710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18829522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneiderhan W, Diaz F, Fundel M, Zhou S, Siech M, Hasel C, Moller P, Gschwend JE, Seufferlein T, Gress T, Adler G, Bachem MG. Pancreatic stellate cells are an important source of MMP-2 in human pancreatic cancer and accelerate tumor progression in a murine xenograft model and CAM assay. J Cell Sci. 2007;120:512–519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17227797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neesse A, Wagner M, Ellenrieder V, Bachem M, Gress TM, Buchholz M. Pancreatic stellate cells potentiate proinvasive effects of SERPINE2 expression in pancreatic cancer xenograft tumors. Pancreatology. 2007;7:380–385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17703087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe I, Hasebe T, Sasaki S, Konishi M, Inoue K, Nakagohri T, Oda T, Mukai K, Kinoshita T. Advanced pancreatic ductal cancer: fibrotic focus and beta-catenin expression correlate with outcome. Pancreas. 2003;26:326–333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12717263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita H, Ohuchida K, Mizumoto K, Egami T, Miyoshi K, Moriyama T, Cui L, Yu J, Zhao M, Manabe T, Tanaka M. Tumor-stromal interactions with direct cell contacts enhance proliferation of human pancreatic carcinoma cells. Cancer Sci. 2009;100:2309–2317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19735487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans SM, Koch CJ. Prognostic significance of tumor oxygenation in humans. Cancer Lett. 2003;195:1–16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12767506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain RK. Normalization of tumor vasculature: an emerging concept in antiangiogenic therapy. Science. 2005;307:58–62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15637262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tredan O, Galmarini CM, Patel K, Tannock IF. Drug resistance and the solid tumor microenvironment. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2007;99:1441–1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17895480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masamune A, Kikuta K, Watanabe T, Satoh K, Hirota M, Shimosegawa T. Hypoxia stimulates pancreatic stellate cells to induce fibrosis and angiogenesis in pancreatic cancer. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2008;295:G709–G717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18669622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey JM, Swanson BJ, Hamada T, Eggers JP, Singh PK, Caffery T, Ouellette MM, Hollingsworth MA. Sonic hedgehog promotes desmoplasia in pancreatic cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2008;14:5995–6004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2782957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18829478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komar G, Kauhanen S, Liukko K, Seppanen M, Kajander S, Ovaska J, Nuutila P, Minn H. Decreased blood flow with increased metabolic activity: a novel sign of pancreatic tumor aggressiveness. Clin Cancer Res. 2009;15:5511–5517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19706808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akakura N, Kobayashi M, Horiuchi I, Suzuki A, Wang J, Chen J, Niizeki H, Kawamura K, Hosokawa M, Asaka M. Constitutive expression of hypoxia-inducible factor-1alpha renders pancreatic cancer cells resistant to apoptosis induced by hypoxia and nutrient deprivation. Cancer Res. 2001;61:6548–6554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11522653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arumugam T, Ramachandran V, Fournier KF, Wang H, Marquis L, Abbruzzese JL, Gallick GE, Logsdon CD, McConkey DJ, Choi W. Epithelial to mesenchymal transition contributes to drug resistance in pancreatic cancer. Cancer Res. 2009;69:5820–5828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4378690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19584296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz DL, Bankson JA, Lemos R, Jr, Lai SY, Thittai AK, He Y, Hostetter G, Demeure MJ, Von Hoff DD, Powis G. Radiosensitization and stromal imaging response correlates for the HIF-1 inhibitor PX-478 given with or without chemotherapy in pancreatic cancer. Mol Cancer Ther. 2010;9:2057–2067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2935253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20587661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah AN, Summy JM, Zhang J, Park SI, Parikh NU, Gallick GE. Development and characterization of gemcitabine-resistant pancreatic tumor cells. Ann Surg Oncol. 2007;14:3629–3637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muerkoster S, Wegehenkel K, Arlt A, Witt M, Sipos B, Kruse ML, Sebens T, Kloppel G, Kalthoff H, Folsch UR, Schafer H. Tumor stroma interactions induce chemoresistance in pancreatic ductal carcinoma cells involving increased secretion and paracrine effects of nitric oxide and interleukin-1beta. Cancer Res. 2004;64:1331–1337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14973050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto H, Murakami T, Tsuchida K, Sugino H, Miyake H, Tashiro S. Tumor-stroma interaction of human pancreatic cancer: acquired resistance to anticancer drugs and proliferation regulation is dependent on extracellular matrix proteins. Pancreas. 2004;28:38–44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14707728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kikuta K, Masamune A, Watanabe T, Ariga H, Itoh H, Hamada S, Satoh K, Egawa S, Unno M, Shimosegawa T. Pancreatic stellate cells promote epithelial-mesenchymal transition in pancreatic cancer cells. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2010;403:380–384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21081113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thayer SP, di Magliano MP, Heiser PW, Nielsen CM, Roberts DJ, Lauwers GY, Qi YP, Gysin S, Fernandez-del Castillo C, Yajnik V, Antoniu B, McMahon M, Warshaw AL, Hebrok M. Hedgehog is an early and late mediator of pancreatic cancer tumorigenesis. Nature. 2003;425:851–856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3688051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14520413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bailey JM, Mohr AM, Hollingsworth MA. Sonic hedgehog paracrine signaling regulates metastasis and lymphangiogenesis in pancreatic cancer. Oncogene. 2009;28:3513–3525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2910592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19633682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter K, Omura N, Hong SM, Griffith M, Vincent A, Borges M, Goggins M. Overexpression of smoothened activates the sonic hedgehog signaling pathway in pancreatic cancer-associated fibroblasts. Clin Cancer Res. 2010;16:1781–1789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2846609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20215540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruck R, Genina O, Aeed H, Alexiev R, Nagler A, Avni Y, Pines M. Halofuginone to prevent and treat thioacetamide-induced liver fibrosis in rats. Hepatology. 2001;33:379–386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11172339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zion O, Genin O, Kawada N, Yoshizato K, Roffe S, Nagler A, Iovanna JL, Halevy O, Pines M. Inhibition of transforming growth factor beta signaling by halofuginone as a modality for pancreas fibrosis prevention. Pancreas. 2009;38:427–435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spector I, Honig H, Kawada N, Nagler A, Genin O, Pines M. Inhibition of pancreatic stellate cell activation by halofuginone prevents pancreatic xenograft tumor development. Pancreas. 2010;39:1008–1015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20442678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzner B, Brock P, Holzhuter SA, Nizze H, Sparmann G, Emmrich J, Liebe S, Jaster R. Synergistic growth inhibitory effects of the dual endothelin-1 receptor antagonist bosentan on pancreatic stellate and cancer cells. Dig Dis Sci. 2009;54:309–320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18612819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunnumakkara AB, Sung B, Ravindran J, Diagaradjane P, Deorukhkar A, Dey S, Koca C, Yadav VR, Tong Z, Gelovani JG, Guha S, Krishnan S, Aggarwal BB. {Gamma}-tocotrienol inhibits pancreatic tumors and sensitizes them to gemcitabine treatment by modulating the inflammatory microenvironment. Cancer Res. 2010;70:8695–8705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2970705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickmann M, Vaquero EC, Malagelada JR, Molero X. Tocotrienols induce apoptosis and autophagy in rat pancreatic stellate cells through the mitochondrial death pathway. Gastroenterology. 2007;132:2518–2532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17570223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarroll JA, Phillips PA, Santucci N, Pirola RC, Wilson JS, Apte MV. Vitamin A inhibits pancreatic stellate cell activation: implications for treatment of pancreatic fibrosis. Gut. 2006;55:79–89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1856372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16043492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo J, Xiao B, Lou Y, Yan C, Zhan L, Wang D, Zhao W. Antitumor effects of all-trans-retinoic acid on cultured human pancreatic cancer cells. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2006;21:443–448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16509872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brembeck FH, Schoppmeyer K, Leupold U, Gornistu C, Keim V, Mossner J, Riecken EO, Rosewicz S. A phase II pilot trial of 13-cis retinoic acid and interferon-alpha in patients with advanced pancreatic carcinoma. Cancer. 1998;83:2317–2323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9840531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael A, Hill M, Maraveyas A, Dalgleish A, Lofts F. 13-cis- Retinoic acid in combination with gemcitabine in the treatment of locally advanced and metastatic pancreatic cancer--report of a pilot phase II study. Clin Oncol (R Coll Radiol) 2007;19:150–153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17355112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore DF, Jr, Pazdur R, Sugarman S, Jones D, 3rd, Lippman SM, Bready B, Abbruzzese JL. Pilot phase II trial of 13-cis-retinoic acid and interferon-alpha combination therapy for advanced pancreatic adenocarcinoma. Am J Clin Oncol. 1995;18:525–527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8526197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dang CT, Shapiro CL, Hudis CA. Potential role of selective COX-2 inhibitors in cancer management. Oncology. 2002;16:30–36. [Williston Park].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12102578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chavez E, Segovia J, Shibayama M, Tsutsumi V, Vergara P, Castro-Sanchez L, Salazar EP, Moreno MG, Muriel P. Antifibrotic and fibrolytic properties of celecoxib in liver damage induced by carbon tetrachloride in the rat. Liver Int. 2010;30:969–978.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20524983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aoki H, Ohnishi H, Hama K, Shinozaki S, Kita H, Osawa H, Yamamoto H, Sato K, Tamada K, Sugano K. Cyclooxygenase-2 is required for activated pancreatic stellate cells to respond to proinflammatory cytokines. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2007;292:C259–C268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16837651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida S, Ujiki M, Ding XZ, Pelham C, Talamonti MS, Bell RH, Jr, Denham W, Adrian TE. Pancreatic stellate cells (PSCs) express cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) and pancreatic cancer stimulates COX-2 in PSCs. Mol Cancer. 2005;4:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1201567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16083499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding XZ, Tong WG, Adrian TE. Blockade of cyclooxygenase-2 inhibits proliferation and induces apoptosis in human pancreatic cancer cells. Anticancer Res. 2000;20:2625–2631.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10953335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato N, Maehara N, Goggins M. Gene expression profiling of tumor- stromal interactions between pancreatic cancer cells and stromal fibroblasts. Cancer Res. 2004;64:6950–6956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15466186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipton A, Campbell-Baird C, Witters L, Harvey H, Ali S. Phase II trial of gemcitabine, irinotecan, and celecoxib in patients with advanced pancreatic cancer. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2010;44:286–288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20216081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henderson NC, Mackinnon AC, Farnworth SL, Poirier F, Russo FP, Iredale JP, Haslett C, Simpson KJ, Sethi T. Galectin-3 regulates myofibroblast activation and hepatic fibrosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:5060–5065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1458794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16549783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang HB, Xu M, Wang XP. Pancreatic stellate cells promote proliferation and invasiveness of human pancreatic cancer cells via galectin-3. World J Gastroenterol. 2008;14:2023–2028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaster R, Sparmann G, Emmrich J, Liebe S. Extracellular signal regulated kinases are key mediators of mitogenic signals in rat pancreatic stellate cells. Gut. 2002;51:579–584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1773393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masamune A, Suzuki N, Kikuta K, Satoh M, Satoh K, Shimosegawa T. Curcumin blocks activation of pancreatic stellate cells. J Cell Biochem. 2006;97:1080–1093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16294327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masamune A, Kikuta K, Satoh M, Suzuki N, Shimosegawa T. Green tea polyphenol epigallocatechin-3-gallate blocks PDGF-induced proliferation and migration of rat pancreatic stellate cells. World J Gastroenterol. 2005;11:3368–3374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15948241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SW, Chen YX, Zhang XR, Qian H, Chen WZ, Xie WF. Targeted inhibition of platelet-derived growth factor receptor-beta subunit in hepatic stellate cells ameliorates hepatic fibrosis in rats. Gene Ther. 2008;15:1424–1435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18509379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagashio Y, Ueno H, Imamura M, Asaumi H, Watanabe S, Yamaguchi T, Taguchi M, Tashiro M, Otsuki M. Inhibition of transforming growth factor beta decreases pancreatic fibrosis and protects the pancreas against chronic injury in mice. Lab Invest. 2004;84:1610–1618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15502860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoo BM, Yeo M, Oh TY, Choi JH, Kim WW, Kim JH, Cho SW, Kim SJ, Hahm KB. Amelioration of pancreatic fibrosis in mice with defective TGF- beta signaling. Pancreas. 2005;30:e71–e79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15782092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura T, Takio K, Eto Y, Shibai H, Titani K, Sugino H. Activin- binding protein from rat ovary is follistatin. Science. 1990;247:836–838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2106159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim N, Yoo W, Lee J, Kim H, Lee H, Kim YS, Kim DU, Oh J. Formation of vitamin A lipid droplets in pancreatic stellate cells requires albumin. Gut. 2009;58:1382–1390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19293176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber K. Improved Paclitaxel formulation hints at new chemotherapy approach. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2004;96:90–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14734692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber K. Stromal Depletion Goes on Trial in Pancreatic Cancer. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2010;102:448–450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20339135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22876388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
