<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">22972724</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2013</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1715-5258</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>58</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2012</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Canadian family physician Medecin de famille canadien</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Can Fam Physician</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>957</StartPage>
          <EndPage>959</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>957-9</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="QUESTION" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">I have heard about children who have tic disorders that seem to be exacerbated by group A β-hemolytic streptococcal infection. Should children presenting with this phenomenon receive treatment with antibiotics, receive prophylactic treatment, or use immunomodulators to treat the symptoms?</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="ANSWER" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections (PANDAS) constitute a condition that includes neuropsychiatric symptoms, mainly obsessive-compulsive disorder or tic disorders, temporally associated with an immune-mediated response to streptococcal infections. The actual existence of PANDAS as a unique clinical entity is still up for debate, as a temporal association between group A β-hemolytic streptococcal infections and symptom exacerbations has been difficult to prove thus far. Based on only a few studies, positive results have been found using antibiotic prophylaxis and immunomodulatory therapy in children with PANDAS. At this time, however, evidence does not support a recommendation for long-term antibiotic prophylaxis or immunomodulatory therapy.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jason</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>BC Children's Hospital, Department of Pediatrics, Room K4-226, Ambulatory Care Bldg, 4480 Oak St, Vancouver, BC V6H 3V4.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Smith</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christine H</ForeName>
            <Initials>CH</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Goldman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ran D</ForeName>
            <Initials>RD</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Can Fam Physician</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0120300</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0008-350X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016756">Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007155">Immunologic Factors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C537163">Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated with Streptococcal infections</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016756" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007155" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunologic Factors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009771" MajorTopicYN="N">Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010951" MajorTopicYN="N">Plasma Exchange</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013290" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcal Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013297" MajorTopicYN="Y">Streptococcus pyogenes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">
        <AbstractText><b><i>Question</i></b> J’ai entendu parler d’enfants ayant des tics qui semblent exacerbés par une infection à streptocoques β-hémolytiques du groupe A. Les enfants qui présentent un tel phénomène devraient-ils recevoir un traitement aux antibiotiques, un traitement prophylactique ou utiliser des immunomodulateurs pour traiter les symptômes? <b><i>Réponse</i></b> Les affections neuropsychiatriques autoimmunes pédiatriques associées aux infections à streptocoques (PANDAS) sont un problème qui comporte des symptômes neuropsychiatriques, principalement un trouble obsessif-compulsif ou des tics, temporellement reliés à une réaction à médiation immunitaire à des infections à streptocoques. L’existence réelle des PANDAS en tant qu’entité clinique particulière est encore sujette à controverse, car il a été difficile à prouver jusqu’à présent une association temporelle entre les infections à streptocoques β-hémolytiques du groupe A et les exacerbations des symptômes. En se fondant sur quelques études seulement, on peut dire que des résultats positifs ont été observés à la suite d’une prophylaxie aux antibiotiques et d’une thérapie avec des immunomodulateurs chez les enfants présentant une PANDAS. À l’heure actuelle, cependant, les données scientifiques n’appuient pas la recommandation d’une prophylaxie aux antibiotiques ou d’une thérapie aux immunomodulateurs à long terme.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2012</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2012</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22972724</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3440267</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">58/9/957</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Garvey M, Mittleman B, Allen AJ, Perlmutter S, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry. 1998;155(4):264–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabbay V, Coffey BJ, Babb JS, Meyer L, Wachtel C, Anam S, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus: comparison of diagnosis and treatment in the community and at a specialty clinic. Pediatrics. 2008;122(2):273–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R, Johnson D, Kaplan EL. Streptococcal infection and exacerbations of childhood tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective blinded cohort study. Pediatrics. 2008;121(6):1188–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF, King RA, Gilbert DL, Coffey BJ, Singer HS, Dure LS, 4th, et al.  Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and exacerbations of tic and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective longitudinal study. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2011;50(2):108–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R, Kaplan EL. The pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection (PANDAS) etiology for tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: hypothesis or entity? Practical considerations for the clinician. Pediatrics. 2004;113(4):883–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15060240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS. PANDAS and immunomodulatory therapy. Lancet. 1999;354(9185):1137–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mell LK, Davis RL, Owens D. Association between streptococcal infection and obsessive-compulsive disorder, Tourette’s syndrome, and tic disorder. Pediatrics. 2005;116(1):56–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan EL. PANDAS? Or PAND? Or both? Or neither? Contemp Pediatr. 2000;17(8):81–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Gause C, Morris C, Lopez P, Tourette Syndrome Study Group  Serial immune markers do not correlate with clinical exacerbations in pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2008;121(6):1198–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Loiselle CR, Lee O, Minzer K, Swedo S, Grus FH. Anti-basal ganglia antibodies in PANDAS. Mov Disord. 2004;19(4):406–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Rapoport JL. The pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection (PANDAS) subgroup: separating fact from fiction. Pediatrics. 2004;113(4):907–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15060242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy ML, Pichichero ME. Prospective identification and treatment of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with group A streptococcal infection (PANDAS) Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2002;156(4):356–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey MA, Perlmutter SJ, Allen AJ, Hamburger S, Lougee L, Leonard HL, et al.  A pilot study of penicillin prophylaxis for neuropsychiatric exacerbations triggered by streptococcal infections. Biol Psychiatry. 1999;45(12):1564–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10376116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA, Lougee L, Slattery M, Grant P, Swedo SE. Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;57(7):788–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perlmutter SJ, Leitman SF, Garvey MA, Hamburger S, Feldman E, Leonard HL, et al.  Therapeutic plasma exchange and intravenous immunoglobulin for obsessive-compulsive disorder and tic disorders in childhood. Lancet. 1999;354(9185):1153–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shulman ST. Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococci (PANDAS): update. Pediatrics. 2009;18(3):127–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19242249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
