<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">23236641</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK114807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="hcp">Hereditary Coproporphyria</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Bruce</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco San Francisco, California</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bissell</LastName><ForeName>D Montgomery</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco San Francisco, California</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Hereditary coproporphyria (HCP) is an acute (hepatic) porphyria in which the acute symptoms are neurovisceral and occur in discrete episodes. Attacks typically start in the abdomen with low-grade pain that slowly increases over a period of days (not hours) with nausea progressing to vomiting. In some individuals, the pain is predominantly in the back or extremities. When an acute attack is untreated, a motor neuropathy may develop over a period of days or a few weeks. The neuropathy first appears as weakness proximally in the arms and legs, then progresses distally to involve the hands and feet. Some individuals experience respiratory insufficiency due to loss of innervation of the diaphragm and muscles of respiration. Acute attacks are associated commonly with use of certain medications, caloric deprivation, and changes in female reproductive hormones. About 20% of those with an acute attack also experience photosensitivity associated with bullae and skin fragility.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The most sensitive and specific biochemical screening test for any one of the acute porphyrias (including HCP) during an acute attack is a striking increase in urinary porphobilinogen. Quantitative analysis of porphyrins in both urine and feces is essential to distinguish between the different acute porphyrias and establish the diagnosis of HCP. Identification of a heterozygous pathogenic variant in <i>CPOX</i> (encoding the enzyme coproporphyrinogen-III oxidase) confirms the diagnosis and enables family studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Acute attacks are treated by discontinuation of any medications thought to induce attacks, management of dehydration and/or hyponatremia, administration of carbohydrate, and infusion of hematin (Panhematin<sup>®</sup>, Recordati Group). Individuals with more than four attacks per year have historically been at highest risk for developing chronic neurologic manifestations. Givosiran, an siRNA that works directly against ALAS1 and is effective in preventing acute attacks in such individuals, was approved in the US in November 2019; however, its effectiveness remains to be determined with long-term study. Treatment of symptoms and complications, such as seizures, should be with medications known to be safe in acute porphyria (see www.drugs-porphyria.org). A minority of affected individuals experience repeat acute attacks, in which case management strategies include suppression of ovulation in females, prophylactic use of hematin, and liver transplantation when attacks and neurologic complications persist despite multiple courses of hematin. Treatment of chronic (cutaneous) manifestations is through avoidance of sun/light, including wearing protective clothing and using protective tinted glass for cars and windows to prevent exposure to blue light. <i>Prevention of primary manifestations:</i> Agents or circumstances that may trigger an acute attack (including use of oral contraception and progestins in women) are avoided. Suppression of menses using a GnRH agonist (leuprolide, nafarelin, and others) may help <i>CPOX</i> heterozygotes who experience monthly exacerbations. Menopausal symptoms may occur as a side effect of GnRH agonists and can be treated with a low dose of estrogen. In <i>CPOX</i> heterozygotes undergoing surgery, minimize preoperative fasting and provide intravenous glucose in the perioperative period. Anesthesia induction using non-barbiturate agents is recommended. <i>Surveillance</i>: Annual liver and kidney function in those with chronically elevated ALA levels and/or those older than age 60 years; assessment for liver fibrosis (transient elastography [FibroScan<sup>®</sup>] or a blood-based test [FibroTest<sup>®</sup> or FibroSure<sup>®</sup>]); annual screening for hepatocellular carcinoma with abdominal imaging and serum alpha-fetoprotein in those older than age 60. <i>Agents/circumstances to avoid:</i> Fasting, use of oral contraception and progestins in females, and certain drugs including barbiturates and phenytoin. <i>Evaluation of relatives at risk:</i> If the family-specific <i>CPOX</i> pathogenic variant is known, clarification of the genetic status of relatives at risk allows early diagnosis of heterozygotes and education regarding how to avoid risk factors known to be associated with acute attacks.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">HCP is inherited in an autosomal dominant manner with low penetrance. Most individuals with HCP have an affected parent; the proportion with a <i>de novo</i> pathogenic variant is unknown. Each child of an individual with HCP has a 50% chance of inheriting the <i>CPOX</i> pathogenic variant. Because of reduced penetrance, many individuals with a <i>CPOX</i> pathogenic variant have no signs or symptoms of HCP. Prenatal testing for pregnancies at increased risk is possible if the pathogenic variant in an affected family member is known.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorder">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="hcp" sec="hcp.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen-dependent coproporphyrinogen-III oxidase, mitochondrial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CPOX</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hereditary Coproporphyria</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2012</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal N, Bagga R, Sawhney H, Suri V, Vasishta K. Pregnancy with acute intermittent porphyria: a case report and review of literature. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2002;28:160–2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12214832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akagi R, Inoue R, Muranaka S, Tahara T, Taketani S, Anderson KE, Phillips JD, Sassa S. Dual gene defects involving delta-aminolaevulinate dehydratase and coproporphyrinogen oxidase in a porphyria patient. Br J Haematol. 2006;132:237–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16398658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KE, Bloomer JR, Bonkovsky HL, Kushner JP, Pierach CA, Pimstone NR, Desnick RJ. Recommendations for the diagnosis and treatment of the acute porphyrias. Ann Intern Med. 2005;142:439–50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KE, Bonkovsky HL, Bloomer JR, Shedlofsky SI. Reconstitution of hematin for intravenous infusion. Ann Intern Med. 2006;144:537–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16585674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson C, Innala E, Bäckström T. Acute intermittent porphyria in women: clinical expression, use and experience of exogenous sex hormones. A population-based study in northern Sweden. J Intern Med. 2003;254:176–83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12859699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badminton MN, Deybach JC. Treatment of an acute attack of porphyria during pregnancy. Eur J Neurol. 2006;13:668–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16796597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balwani M, Sardh E, Ventura P, Peiró PA, Rees DC, Stölzel U, Bissell DM, Bonkovsky HL, Windyga J, Anderson KE, Parker C, Silver SM, Keel SB, Wang JD, Stein PE, Harper P, Vassiliou D, Wang B, Phillips J, Ivanova A, Langendonk JG, Kauppinen R, Minder E, Horie Y, Penz C, Chen J, Liu S, Ko JJ, Sweetser MT, Garg P, Vaishnaw A, Kim JB, Simon AR, Gouya L, et al.  Phase 3 trial of RNAi therapeutic givosiran for acute intermittent porphyria. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:2289–301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32521132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balwani M, Wang B, Anderson KE, Bloomer JR, Bissell DM, Bonkovsky HL, Phillips JD, Desnick RJ, et al.  Acute hepatic porphyrias: recommendations for evaluation and long-term management. Hepatology. 2017;66:1314–22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28605040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbaro M, Kotajärvi M, Harper P, Floderus Y. Identification of an AluY-mediated deletion of exon 5 in the CPOX gene by MLPA analysis in patients with hereditary coproporphyria. Clin Genet. 2012;81:249–56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21231929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billing BH. Twenty-five years of progress in bilirubin metabolism (1952-77). Gut. 1978;19:481–91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1412033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">98394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissell DM, Lai JC, Meister RK, Blanc PD. Role of delta-aminolevulinic acid in the symptoms of acute porphyria. Am J Med. 2015;128:313–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4339446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25446301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake D, McManus J, Cronin V, Ratnaike S. Fecal coproporphyrin isomers in hereditary coproporphyria. Clin Chem. 1992;38:96–100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1733615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonkovsky HL, Siao P, Roig Z, Hedley-Whyte ET, Flotte TJ. Case records of the Massachusetts General Hospital. Case 20-2008. A 57-year-old woman with abdominal pain and weakness after gastric bypass surgery. N Engl J Med. 2008;358:2813–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodie MJ, Thompson GG, Moore MR, Beattie AD, Goldberg A. Hereditary coproporphyria. Demonstration of the abnormalities in haem biosynthesis in peripheral blood. Q J Med. 1977;46:229–41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">866576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan A, Liebow A, Yasuda M, Gan L, Racie T, Maier M, Kuchimanchi S, Foster D, Milstein S, Charisse K, Sehgal A, Manoharan M, Meyers R, Fitzgerald K, Simon A, Desnick RJ, Querbes W. Preclinical development of a subcutaneous ALAS1 RNAi therapeutic for treatment of hepatic porphyrias using circulating RNA quantification. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids. 2015;4:e263. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4877445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26528940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowman JK, Gunson BK, Bramhall S, Badminton MN, Newsome PN. Liver transplantation from donors with acute intermittent porphyria. Ann Intern Med. 2011;154:571–2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farfaras A, Zagouri F, Zografos G, Kostopoulou A, Sergentanis TN, Antoniou S. Acute intermittent porphyria in pregnancy: a common misdiagnosis. Clin Exp Obstet Gynecol. 2010;37:256–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21355451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson PR, Grant J, Cronin V, Blake D, Ratnaike S. Effect of hepatobiliary disease, chronic hepatitis C and hepatitis B virus infections and interferon-alpha on porphyrin profiles in plasma, urine and faeces. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2000;15:192–201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10735544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetsch CA, Bissell DM. Instability of hematin used in the treatment of acute hepatic porphyria. N Engl J Med. 1986;315:235–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3724815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimes R, Gilleece Y, Appleby T, Stockwell S, Pinto-Sander N, Sahabandu T, Stein P, Bradshaw D. A case of hereditary coproporphyria precipitated by efavirenz. AIDS. 2016;30:2142–3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haimowitz S, Hsieh J, Shcherba M, Averbukh Y. Liver failure after Hydroxycut™ use in a patient with undiagnosed hereditary coproporphyria. J Gen Intern Med. 2015;30:856–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25666208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasanoglu A, Balwani M, Kasapkara CS, Ezgü FS, Okur I, Tümer L, Cakmak A, Nazarenko I, Yu C, Clavero S, Bishop DF, Desnick RJ. Harderoporphyria due to homozygosity for coproporphyrinogen oxidase missense mutation H327R. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2011;34:225–31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3091031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21103937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa K, Tanaka H, Yamashita M, Higuchi Y, Miyai T, Yoshimoto J, Okada A, Suzuki N, Iwatsuki K, Tsukahara H. Neonatal-onset hereditary coproporphyria: a new variant of hereditary coproporphyria. JIMD Rep. 2017;37:99–106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5740044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28349448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isenschmid M, König C, Fässli C, Haenel A, Hänggi W, Schneider H. Acute intermittent porphyria in pregnancy: glucose or hematin therapy? Schweiz Med Wochenschr. 1992;122:1741–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1448679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jara-Prado A, Yescas P, Sánchez FJ, Ríos C, Garnica R, Alonso E. Prevalence of acute intermittent porphyria in a Mexican psychiatric population. Arch Med Res. 2000;31:404–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11068084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kühnel A, Gross U, Doss MO. Hereditary coproporphyria in Germany: clinical-biochemical studies in 53 patients. Clin Biochem. 2000;33:465–73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11074238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambie D, Florkowski C, Sies C, Raizis A, Siu WK, Towns C. A case of hereditary coproporphyria with posterior reversible encephalopathy and novel coproporphyrinogen oxidase gene mutation c.863T&gt;G (p.Leu288Trp). Ann Clin Biochem. 2018;55:616–19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29660996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamoril J, Puy H, Whatley SD, Martin C, Woolf JR, Da Silva V, Deybach JC, Elder GH. Characterization of mutations in the CPO gene in British patients demonstrates absence of genotype-phenotype correlation and identifies relationship between hereditary coproporphyria and harderoporphyria. Am J Hum Genet. 2001;68:1130–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1226094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11309681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee DS, Flachsová E, Bodnárová M, Demeler B, Martásek P, Raman CS. Structural basis of hereditary coproporphyria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102:14232–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1224704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16176984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma E, Mar V, Varigos G, Nicoll A, Ross G. Haem arginate as effective maintenance therapy for hereditary coproporphyria. Australas J Dermatol. 2011;52:135–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21605099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosipal R, Lamoril J, Puy H, Da Silva V, Gouya L, De Rooij FW, Te Velde K, Nordmann Y, Martàsek P, Deybach JC. Systematic analysis of coproporphyrinogen oxidase gene defects in hereditary coproporphyria and mutation update. Hum Mutat. 1999;13:44–53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9888388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh M, Blatt I, Martonovits G, Karni A, Goldhammer Y. Treatment of porphyric convulsions with magnesium sulfate. Epilepsia. 1991;32:712–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1915181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sardh E, Wahlin S, Björnstedt M, Harper P, Andersson DE. High risk of primary liver cancer in a cohort of 179 patients with acute hepatic porphyria. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2013;36:1063–71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23344888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt C, Gouya L, Malonova E, Lamoril J, Camadro JM, Flamme M, Rose C, Lyoumi S, Da Silva V, Boileau C, Grandchamp B, Beaumont C, Deybach JC, Puy H. Mutations in human CPO gene predict clinical expression of either hepatic hereditary coproporphyria or erythropoietic harderoporphyria. Hum Mol Genet. 2005;14:3089–98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16159891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenhav S, Gemer O, Sassoon E, Segal S. Acute intermittent porphyria precipitated by hyperemesis and metoclopramide treatment in pregnancy. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 1997;76:484–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9197454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soonawalla ZF, Orug T, Badminton MN, Elder GH, Rhodes JM, Bramhall SR, Elias E. Liver transplantation as a cure for acute intermittent porphyria. Lancet. 2004;363:705–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15001330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TP, Leduc K, Savard M, Dupré N, Rivest D, Nguyen DK. Acute porphyria presenting as epilepsia partialis continua. Case Rep Neurol. 2013;5:116–24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3724138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23898283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Steeg E, Stránecký V, Hartmannová H, Nosková L, Hřebíček M, Wagenaar E, van Esch A, de Waart DR, Oude Elferink RP, Kenworthy KE, Sticová E, al-Edreesi M, Knisely AS, Kmoch S, Jirsa M, Schinkel AH. Complete OATP1B1 and OATP1B3 deficiency causes human Rotor syndrome by interrupting conjugated bilirubin reuptake into the liver. J Clin Invest. 2012;122:519–28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3266790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22232210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Tuyll van Serooskerken AM, de Rooij FW, Edixhoven A, Bladergroen RS, Baron JM, Joussen S, Merk HF, Steijlen PM, Poblete-Gutiérrez P, te Velde K, Wilson JH, Koole RH, van Geel M, Frank J. Digenic inheritance of mutations in the coproporphyrinogen oxidase and protoporphyrinogen oxidase genes in a unique type of porphyria. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:2249–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21734717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vercesi AE, Castilho RF, Meinicke AR, Valle VG, Hermes-Lima M, Bechara EJ. Oxidative damage of mitochondria induced by 5-aminolevulinic acid: role of Ca2+ and membrane protein thiols. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1994;1188:86–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7947907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whatley SD, Mason NG, Woolf JR, Newcombe RG, Elder GH, Badminton MN. Diagnostic strategies for autosomal dominant acute porphyrias: retrospective analysis of 467 unrelated patients referred for mutational analysis of the HMBS, CPOX, or PPOX gene. Clin Chem. 2009;55:1406–14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19460837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23236641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
