<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">23363620</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2013</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1347-4405</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2013</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Microbes and environments</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Microbes Environ</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Interspecies interaction between Pseudomonas aeruginosa and other microorganisms.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>13</StartPage>
          <EndPage>24</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>13-24</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Microbes interact with each other in multicellular communities and this interaction enables certain microorganisms to survive in various environments. Pseudomonas aeruginosa is a highly adaptable bacterium that ubiquitously inhabits diverse environments including soil, marine habitats, plants and animals. Behind this adaptivity, P. aeruginosa has abilities not only to outcompete others but also to communicate with each other to develop a multispecies community. In this review, we focus on how P. aeruginosa interacts with other microorganisms. P. aeruginosa secretes antimicrobial chemicals to compete and signal molecules to cooperate with other organisms. In other cases, it directly conveys antimicrobial enzymes to other bacteria using the Type VI secretion system (T6SS) or membrane vesicles (MVs). Quorum sensing is a central regulatory system used to exert their ability including antimicrobial effects and cooperation with other microbes. At least three quorum sensing systems are found in P. aeruginosa, Las, Rhl and Pseudomonas quinolone signal (PQS) systems. These quorum-sensing systems control the synthesis of extracellular antimicrobial chemicals as well as interaction with other organisms via T6SS or MVs. In addition, we explain the potential of microbial interaction analysis using several micro devices, which would bring fresh sensitivity to the study of interspecies interaction between P. aeruginosa and other organisms.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tashiro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yosuke</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Environmental Engineering, Hokkaido University, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yawata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yutaka</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Toyofuku</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masanori</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Uchiyama</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroo</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nomura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nobuhiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Microbes Environ</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9710937</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1342-6311</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000890">Anti-Infective Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000890" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Infective Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015964" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation, Bacterial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056265" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microbial Interactions</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011550" MajorTopicYN="N">Pseudomonas aeruginosa</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053038" MajorTopicYN="N">Quorum Sensing</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013045" MajorTopicYN="N">Species Specificity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D022161" MajorTopicYN="N">Transport Vesicles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23363620</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4070684</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1264/jsme2.me12167</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">DN/JST.JSTAGE/jsme2/ME12167</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-Mawgoud A, Lépine F, Déziel E. Rhamnolipids: diversity of structures, microbial origins and roles. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2010;86:1323–1336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2854365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20336292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allan ND, Beveridge TJ. Gentamicin delivery to Burkholderia cepacia group IIIa strains via membrane vesicles from Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2003;47:2962–2965.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anjaiah V, Koedam N, Nowak-Thompson B, Loper JE, Höfte M, Tambong JT, Cornelis P. Involvement of phenazines and anthranilate in the antagonism of Pseudomonas aeruginosa PNA1 and Tn5 derivatives toward Fusarium spp. and Pythium spp. Mol Plant Microbe Interact. 1998;11:847–854.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkinson S, Chang C-Y, Sockett RE, Cámara M, Williams P. Quorum sensing in Yersinia enterocolitica controls swimming and swarming motility. J Bacteriol. 2006;188:1451–1461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1367215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16452428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandara H, Yau J, Watt R, Jin L, Samaranayake L. Pseudomonas aeruginosa inhibits in-vitro Candida biofilm development. BMC Microbiol. 2010;10:125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2874548</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20416106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beveridge T. Structures of Gram-negative cell walls and their derived membrane vesicles. J Bacteriol. 1999;181:4725–4733.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10438737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boles BR, Thoendel M, Singh PK. Rhamnolipids mediate detachment of Pseudomonas aeruginosa from biofilms. Mol Microbiol. 2005;57:1210–1223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16101996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bottomley MJ, Muraglia E, Bazzo R, Carfi A. Molecular insights into quorum sensing in the human pathogen Pseudomonas aeruginosa from the structure of the virulence regulator LasR bound to its autoinducer. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:13592–13600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17363368</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bredenbruch F, Geffers R, Nimtz M, Buer J, Häussler S. The Pseudomonas aeruginosa quinolone signal (PQS) has an iron-chelating activity. Environ Microbiol. 2006;8:1318–1329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16872396</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caiazza NC, Merritt JH, Brothers KM, O’Toole GA. Inverse regulation of biofilm formation and swarming motility by Pseudomonas aeruginosa PA14. J Bacteriol. 2007;189:3603–3612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1855903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17337585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caiazza NC, Shanks RMQ, O’Toole GA. Rhamnolipids modulate swarming motility patterns of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. J Bacteriol. 2005;187:7351–7361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1273001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16237018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell J, Lin Q, Geske GD, Blackwell HE. New and unexpected insights into the modulation of LuxR-type quorum sensing by cyclic dipeptides. ACS Chem Biol. 2009;4:1051–1059.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2801563</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19928886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnes EC, Lopez DM, Donegan NP, Cheung A, Gresham H, Timmins GS, Brinker CJ. Confinement-induced quorum sensing of individual Staphylococcus aureus bacteria. Nature Chem Biol. 2010;6:41–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201857</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19935660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiura HX. Broad host range xenotrophic gene transfer by virus-like particles from a hot spring. Microbes Environ. 2002;17:53–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiura HX. Novel broad-host range gene transfer particles in nature. Microbes Environ. 2004;19:249–264.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiura HX, Uchiyama N, Kogure K. Broad-host range gene transporter particles produced by Aliivibrio fischeri. Microbes Environ. 2009;24:322–329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21566392</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiura HX, Umitsu M. Isolation and characterisation of broad-host range gene transporter particles from geo-thermal vent of the Toyoha Mine. Microbes Environ. 2004;19:20–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiura HX, Yamamoto H, Koketsu D, Naito H, Kato K. Virus-like particle derived from a bacterium belonging to the oldest lineage of the domain bacteria. Microbes Environ. 2002;17:48–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu W, Zere TR, Weber MM, Wood TK, Whiteley M, Hidalgo-Romano B, Valenzuela E, Jr, McLean RJ. Indole production promotes Escherichia coli mixed-culture growth with Pseudomonas aeruginosa by inhibiting quorum signaling. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2012;78:411–419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255741</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101045</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chugani SA, Whiteley M, Lee KM, D’Argenio D, Manoil C, Greenberg EP. QscR, a modulator of quorum-sensing signal synthesis and virulence in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2001;98:2752–2757.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC30211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11226312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung K, Okabe S. Continuous power generation and microbial community structure of the anode biofilms in a three-stage microbial fuel cell system. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2009;83:965–977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19404637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cugini C, Calfee MW, Farrow JM, 3rd, Morales DK, Pesci EC, Hogan DA. Farnesol, a common sesquiterpene, inhibits PQS production in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Mol Microbiol. 2007;65:896–906.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17640272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davey ME, Caiazza NC, O’Toole GA. Rhamnolipid surfactant production affects biofilm architecture in Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1. J Bacteriol. 2003;185:1027–1036.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC142794</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12533479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies DG, Marques CNH. A fatty acid messenger is responsible for inducing dispersion in microbial biofilms. J Bacteriol. 2009;191:1393–1403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2648214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19074399</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Kievit TR, Parkins MD, Gillis RJ, Srikumar R, Ceri H, Poole K, Iglewski BH, Storey DG. Multidrug efflux pumps: expression patterns and contribution to antibiotic resistance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilms. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2001;45:1761–1770.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC90543</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11353623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Degrassi G, Aguilar C, Bosco M, Zahariev S, Pongor S, Venturi V. Plant growth-promoting Pseudomonas putida produces and secretes four cyclic dipeptides: cross-talk with quorum sensing bacterial sensors. Curr Microbiol. 2002;45:250–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12192521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Déziel E, Lépine F, Milot S, He J, Mindrinos MN, Tompkins RG, Rahme LG. Analysis of Pseudomonas aeruginosa 4-hydroxy-2-alkylquinolines (HAQs) reveals a role for 4-hydroxy-2-heptylquinoline in cell-to-cell communication. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2004;101:1339–1344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC337054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14739337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dietrich L, Price-Whelan A, Petersen A, Whiteley M, Newman D. The phenazine pyocyanin is a terminal signalling factor in the quorum sensing network of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Mol Microbiol. 2006;61:1308–1321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16879411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dietrich L, Teal TK, Price-Whelan A, Newman D. Redox-active antibiotics control gene expression and community behavior in divergent bacteria. Science. 2008;321:1203–1206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2745639</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18755976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diggle SP, Lumjiaktase P, Dipilato F, Winzer K, Kunakorn M, Barrett DA, Chhabra SR, Cámara M, Williams P. Functional genetic analysis reveals a 2-alkyl-4-quinolone signaling system in the human pathogen Burkholderia pseudomallei and related bacteria. Chem Biol. 2006;13:701–710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16873018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diggle SP, Matthijs S, Wright VJ, et al.  The Pseudomonas aeruginosa 4-quinolone signal molecules HHQ and PQS play multifunctional roles in quorum sensing and iron entrapment. Chem Biol. 2007;14:87–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17254955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eberl L, Winson MK, Sternberg C, et al.  Involvement of N-acyl-l-homoserine lactone autoinducers in controlling the multicellular behaviour of Serratia liquefaciens. Mol Microbiol. 1996;20:127–136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8861211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ensley BD, Ratzkin BJ, Osslund TD, Simon MJ, Wackett LP, Gibson DT. Expression of naphthalene oxidation genes in Escherichia coli results in the biosynthesis of indigo. Science. 1983;222:167–169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6353574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernández-Piñar R, Cámara M, Dubern J-F, Ramos JL, Espinosa-Urgel M. The Pseudomonas aeruginosa quinolone quorum sensing signal alters the multicellular behaviour of Pseudomonas putida KT2440. Res Microbiol. 2011;162:773–781.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21742029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flickinger ST, Copeland MF, Downes EM, Braasch AT, Tuson HH, Eun YJ, Weibel DB. Quorum sensing between Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilms accelerates cell growth. J Am Chem Soc. 2011;133:5966–5975.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3076519</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21434644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher LA, McKnight SL, Kuznetsova MS, Pesci EC, Manoil C. Functions required for extracellular quinolone signaling by Pseudomonas aeruginosa. J Bacteriol. 2002;184:6472–6480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC135424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12426334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gans J, Wolinsky M, Dunbar J. Computational improvements reveal great bacterial diversity and high metal toxicity in soil. Science. 2005;309:1387–1390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16123304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson J, Sood A, Hogan DA. Pseudomonas aeruginosa-Candida albicans interactions: localization and fungal toxicity of a phenazine derivative. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2009;75:504–513.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2620721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haba E, Pinazo A, Jauregui O, Espuny MJ, Infante MR, Manresa A. Physicochemical characterization and antimicrobial properties of rhamnolipids produced by Pseudomonas aeruginosa 47T2 NCBIM 40044. Biotechnol Bioeng. 2003;81:316–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12474254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haruta S, Kato S, Yamamoto K, Igarashi Y. Intertwined interspecies relationships: approaches to untangle the microbial network. Environ Microbiol. 2009;11:2963–2969.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19508345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häussler S, Becker T. The pseudomonas quinolone signal (PQS) balances life and death in Pseudomonas aeruginosa populations. PLoS Pathog. 2008;4:e1000166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2533401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18818733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez ME, Kappler A, Newman DK. Phenazines and other redox-active antibiotics promote microbial mineral reduction. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2004;70:921–928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC348881</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14766572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirakawa H, Inazumi Y, Masaki T, Hirata T, Yamaguchi A. Indole induces the expression of multidrug exporter genes in Escherichia coli. Mol Microbiol. 2005;55:1113–1126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15686558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman LR, Déziel E, D’Argenio DA, Lépine F, Emerson J, McNamara S, Gibson RL, Ramsey BW, Miller SI. Selection for Staphylococcus aureus small-colony variants due to growth in the presence of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2006;103:19890–19895.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1750898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17172450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holden MTG, Ram Chhabra S, De Nys R, et al.  Quorum-sensing cross talk: isolation and chemical characterization of cyclic dipeptides from Pseudomonas aeruginosa and other Gram-negative bacteria. Mol Microbiol. 1999;33:1254–1266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10510239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong SH, Hegde M, Kim J, Wang X, Jayaraman A, Wood TK. Synthetic quorum-sensing circuit to control consortial biofilm formation and dispersal in a microfluidic device. Nature Comm. 2012;3:613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3272573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22215088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hood RD, Singh P, Hsu F, et al.  A type VI secretion system of Pseudomonas aeruginosa targets a toxin to bacteria. Cell Host Microbe. 2010;7:25–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2831478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20114026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosono Honda N, Kimura S, Tateda K, Horikawa M, Ueda C, Ishii Y, Ishiguro M, Miyairi S, Yamaguchi K. Roles of Pseudomonas aeruginosa autoinducers and their degradation products, tetramic acids, in bacterial survival and behavior in ecological niches. Microbes Environ. 2011;26:160–164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iino R, Nishino K, Noji H, Yamaguchi A, Matsumoto Y. A microfluidic device for simple and rapid evaluation of multidrug efflux pump inhibitors. Front Microbiol. 2012;3:40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274760</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irie Y, O’Toole GA, Yuk MH. Pseudomonas aeruginosa rhamnolipids disperse Bordetella bronchiseptica biofilms. FEMS Microbiol Lett. 2005;250:237–243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishii S, Ikeda S, Minamisawa K, Senoo K. Nitrogen cycling in rice paddy environments: past achievements and future challenges. Microbes Environ. 2011;26:282–292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeong HH, Lee SH, Kim JM, Kim HE, Kim YG, Yoo JY, Chang WS, Lee CS. Microfluidic monitoring of Pseudomonas aeruginosa chemotaxis under the continuous chemical gradient. Biosens Bioelectron. 2010;26:351–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20810268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato S, Haruta S, Cui Z, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Network relationships of bacteria in a stable mixed culture. Microb Ecol. 2008;56:403–411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18196313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato S, Haruta S, Cui ZJ, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Effective cellulose degradation by a mixed-culture system composed of a cellulolytic Clostridium and aerobic non-cellulolytic bacteria. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2004;51:133–142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16329862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato S, Haruta S, Cui ZJ, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Stable coexistence of five bacterial strains as a cellulose-degrading community. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2005;71:7099–7106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287685</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato S, Watanabe K. Ecological and evolutionary interactions in syntrophic methanogenic consortia. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:145–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufmann GF, Sartorio R, Lee S-H, et al.  Revisiting quorum sensing: discovery of additional chemical and biological functions for 3-oxo-N-acylhomoserine lactones. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2005;102:309–314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC544315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15623555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan NH, Ahsan M, Taylor WD, Kogure K. Culturability and survival of marine, freshwater and clinical Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:266–274.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J, Park HD, Chung S. Microfluidic approaches to bacterial biofilm formation. Molecules. 2012;17:9818–9834.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6268732</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimata N, Nishino T, Suzuki S, Kogure K. Pseudomonas aeruginosa isolated from marine environments in Tokyo Bay. Microb Ecol. 2004;47:41–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15259268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura S, Tateda K, Ishii Y, Horikawa M, Miyairi S, Gotoh N, Ishiguro M, Yamaguchi K. Pseudomonas aeruginosa Las quorum sensing autoinducer suppresses growth and biofilm production in Legionella species. Microbiology. 2009;155:1934–1939.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19383702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolling GL, Matthews KR. Export of virulence genes and Shiga toxin by membrane vesicles of Escherichia coli O157:H7. Appl Environ Microbiol. 1999;65:1843–1848.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC91264</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10223967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledgham F, Ventre I, Soscia C, Foglino M, Sturgis JN, Lazdunski A. Interactions of the quorum sensing regulator QscR: interaction with itself and the other regulators of Pseudomonas aeruginosa LasR and RhlR. Mol Microbiol. 2003;48:199–210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12657055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J, Attila C, Cirillo SL, Cirillo JD, Wood TK. Indole and 7-hydroxyindole diminish Pseudomonas aeruginosa virulence. Microb Biotechnol. 2009;2:75–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3815423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21261883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J-H, Lequette Y, Greenberg EP. Activity of purified QscR, a Pseudomonas aeruginosa orphan quorum-sensing transcription factor. Mol Microbiol. 2006;59:602–609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16390453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lesic B, Starkey M, He J, Hazan R, Rahme LG. Quorum sensing differentially regulates Pseudomonas aeruginosa type VI secretion locus I and homologous loci II and III, which are required for pathogenesis. Microbiology. 2009;155:2845–2855.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888175</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19497948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leung KY, Siame BA, Snowball H, Mok Y-K. Type VI secretion regulation: crosstalk and intracellular communication. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2011;14:9–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20971679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z, Clarke AJ, Beveridge TJ. Gram-negative bacteria produce membrane vesicles which are capable of killing other bacteria. J Bacteriol. 1998;180:5478–5483.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC107602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9765585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z, Clarke AJ, Beveridge TJ. A major autolysin of Pseudomonas aeruginosa: subcellular distribution, potential role in cell growth and division and secretion in surface membrane vesicles. J Bacteriol. 1996;178:2479–2488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC177969</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8626312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lowery CA, Park J, Gloeckner C, et al.  Defining the mode of action of tetramic acid antibacterials derived from Pseudomonas aeruginosa quorum sensing signals. J Am Chem Soc. 2009;131:14473–14479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19807189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald KL, Beveridge TJ. Bactericidal effect of gentamicin-induced membrane vesicles derived from Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1 on gram-positive bacteria. Can J Microbiol. 2002;48:810–820.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12455613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashburn LM, Jett AM, Akins DR, Whiteley M. Staphylococcus aureus serves as an iron source for Pseudomonas aeruginosa during in vivo coculture. J Bacteriol. 2005;187:554–566.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC543556</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15629927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashburn LM, Whiteley M. Membrane vesicles traffic signals and facilitate group activities in a prokaryote. Nature. 2005;437:422–425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16163359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashburn-Warren L, Howe J, Garidel P, Richter W, Steiniger F, Roessle M, Brandenburg K, Whiteley M. Interaction of quorum signals with outer membrane lipids: insights into prokaryotic membrane vesicle formation. Mol Microbiol. 2008;69:491–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18630345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashburn-Warren LM, Whiteley M. Special delivery: vesicle trafficking in prokaryotes. Mol Microbiol. 2006;61:839–846.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16879642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto Y, Hayama K, Sakakihara S, Nishino K, Noji H, Iino R, Yamaguchi A. Evaluation of multidrug efflux pump inhibitors by a new method using microfluidic channels. PLoS One. 2011;6:e18547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075257</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21533264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuzaka E, Nomura N, Maseda H, Otagaki H, Nakajima-Kambe T, Nakaharai T, Uchiyama H. Participation of nitrite reductase in conversion of NO2−to NO3−in a heterotrophic nitrifier, Burkholderia cepacia NH-17, with denitrification activity. Microbes Environ. 2003;18:203–209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazzola M, Cook RJ, Thomashow LS, Weller DM, Pierson LS. Contribution of phenazine antibiotic biosynthesis to the ecological competence of fluorescent pseudomonads in soil habitats. Appl Environ Microbiol. 1992;58:2616–2624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC195829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1514808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDaniel LD, Young E, Delaney J, Ruhnau F, Ritchie KB, Paul JH. High frequency of horizontal gene transfer in the oceans. Science. 2010;330:50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller MB, Bassler BL. Quorum sensing in bacteria. Annu Rev Microbiol. 2001;55:165–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11544353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milton DL, Chalker VJ, Kirke D, Hardman A, Cámara M, Williams P. The LuxM homologue VanM from Vibrio anguillarum directs the synthesis of N-(3-hydroxyhexanoyl) homoserine lactone and N-hexanoylhomoserine lactone. J Bacteriol. 2001;183:3537–3547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95229</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11371516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minagawa S, Inami H, Kato T, Sawada S, Yasuki T, Miyairi S, Horikawa M, Okuda J, Gotoh N. RND type efflux pump system MexAB-OprM of Pseudomonas aeruginosa selects bacterial languages, 3-oxo-acyl-homoserine lactones, for cell-to-cell communication. BMC Microbiol. 2012;12:70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460771</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22574700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mireles JR, Toguchi A, Harshey RM. Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium swarming mutants with altered biofilm-forming abilities: surfactin inhibits biofilm formation. J Bacteriol. 2001;183:5848–5854.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC99661</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11566982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moffitt JR, Lee JB, Cluzel P. The single-cell chemostat: an agarose-based, microfluidic device for high-throughput, single-cell studies of bacteria and bacterial communities. Lab Chip. 2012;12:1487–1494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3646658</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22395180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morimoto S, Hayatsu M, Takada Hoshino Y, Nagaoka K, Yamazaki M, Karasawa T, Takenaka M, Akiyama H. Quantitative analyses of ammonia-oxidizing archaea (AOA) and ammonia-oxidizing bacteria (AOB) in fields with different soil types. Microbes Environ. 2011;26:248–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morohoshi T, Ebata A, Nakazawa S, Kato N, Ikeda T. N-acyl homoserine lactone-producing or -degrading bacteria isolated from the intestinal microbial flora of Ayu Fish (Plecoglossus altivelis) Microbes Environ. 2005;20:264–268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mougous JD, Cuff ME, Raunser S, et al.  A virulence locus of Pseudomonas aeruginosa encodes a protein secretion apparatus. Science. 2006;312:1526–1530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800167</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16763151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narisawa N, Haruta S, Arai H, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Coexistence of antibiotic-producing and antibiotic-sensitive bacteria in biofilms is mediated by resistant bacteria. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2008;74:3887–3894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2446560</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18441106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okabe S, Oshiki M, Kamagata Y, et al.  A great leap forward in microbial ecology. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:230–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okada N, Nomura N, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchiyama H. Characterization of the aerobic denitrification in Mesorhizo-bium sp. strain NH-14 in comparison with that in related rhizobia. Microbes Environ. 2005;20:208–215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park S, Wolanin PM, Yuzbashyan EA, Silberzan P, Stock JB, Austin RH. Motion to form a quorum. Science. 2003;301:188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12855801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parsek MR, Greenberg EP. Acyl-homoserine lactone quorum sensing in Gram-negative bacteria: a signaling mechanism involved in associations with higher organisms. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2000;97:8789–8793.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC34013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10922036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pesci EC, Milbank JB, Pearson JP, McKnight S, Kende AS, Greenberg EP, Iglewski BH. Quinolone signaling in the cell-to-cell communication system of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1999;96:11229–11234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC18016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10500159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price-Whelan A, Dietrich LEP, Newman DK. Rethinking ‘secondary’ metabolism: physiological roles for phenazine antibiotics. Nature Chem Biol. 2006;2:71–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16421586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pukatzki S, McAuley SB, Miyata ST. The type VI secretion system: translocation of effectors and effector-domains. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2009;12:11–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19162533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin Z, Yang L, Qu D, Molin S, Tolker-Nielsen T. Pseudomonas aeruginosa extracellular products inhibit staphylococcal growth, and disrupt established biofilms produced by Staphylococcus epidermidis. Microbiology. 2009;155:2148–2156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19389780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabaey K, Boon N, Höfte M, Verstraete W. Microbial phenazine production enhances electron transfer in biofuel cells. Environ Sci Technol. 2005;39:3401–3408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15926596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabaey K, Boon N, Siciliano SD, Verhaege M, Verstraete W. Biofuel cells select for microbial consortia that self-mediate electron transfer. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2004;70:5373–5382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC520914</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15345423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rashid R, Morohoshi T, Someya N, Ikeda T. Degradation of N-acylhomoserine lactone quorum sensing signaling molecules by potato root surface-associated Chryseobacterium strains. Microbes Environ. 2011;26:144–148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reen FJ, Mooij MJ, Holcombe LJ, McSweeney CM, McGlacken GP, Morrissey JP, O’Gara F. The Pseudomonas quinolone signal (PQS), and its precursor HHQ, modulate inter-species and interkingdom behaviour. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2011;77:413–428.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21539583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renelli M, Matias V, Lo RY, Beveridge TJ. DNA-containing membrane vesicles of Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1 and their genetic transformation potential. Microbiology. 2004;150:2161–2169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15256559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riedel K, Hentzer M, Geisenberger O, et al.  N-acylhomoserine-lactone-mediated communication between Pseudo-monas aeruginosa and Burkholderia cepacia in mixed biofilms. Microbiology. 2001;147:3249–3262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11739757</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rui L, Reardon KF, Wood TK. Protein engineering of toluene ortho-monooxygenase of Burkholderia cepacia G4 for regiospecific hydroxylation of indole to form various indigoid compounds. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2005;66:422–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15290130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell AB, Hood RD, Bui NK, LeRoux M, Vollmer W, Mougous JD. Type VI secretion delivers bacteriolytic effectors to target cells. Nature. 2011;475:343–347.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3146020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21776080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan RP, Fouhy Y, Garcia BF, Watt SA, Niehaus K, Yang L, Tolker-Nielsen T, Dow JM. Interspecies signalling via the Stenotrophomonas maltophilia diffusible signal factor influences biofilm formation and polymyxin tolerance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Mol Microbiol. 2008;68:75–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18312265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryder C, Byrd M, Wozniak D. Role of polysaccharides in Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilm development. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2007;10:644–648.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2176169</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17981495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schertzer JW, Brown SA, Whiteley M. Oxygen levels rapidly modulate Pseudomonas aeruginosa social behaviours via substrate limitation of PqsH. Mol Microbiol. 2010;77:1527–1538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3098721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20662781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schertzer JW, Whiteley M. A bilayer-couple model of bacterial outer membrane vesicle biogenesis. mBio. 2012;3:e00297–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3312216</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22415005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuster M, Lostroh CP, Ogi T, Greenberg EP. Identification, timing, and signal specificity of Pseudomonas aeruginosa quorum-controlled genes: a transcriptome analysis. J Bacteriol. 2003;185:2066–2079.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC151497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12644476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaw PD, Ping G, Daly SL, Cha C, Cronan JE, Rinehart KL, Farrand SK. Detecting and characterizing N-acyl-homoserine lactone signal molecules by thin-layer chromatography. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1997;94:6036–6041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC20996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9177164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimomura Y, Morimoto S, Takada Hoshino Y, Uchida Y, Akiyama H, Hayatsu M. Comparison among amoA primers suited for quantification and diversity analyses of ammonia-oxidizing bacteria in soil. Microbes Environ. 2012;27:94–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22075625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimoyama T, Yamazawa A, Ueno Y, Watanabe K. Phylogenetic analyses of bacterial communities developed in a cassette-electrode microbial fuel cell. Microbes Environ. 2009;24:188–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21566373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Someya N, Morohoshi T, Ikeda T, Tsuchiya K, Ikeda S. Genetic diversity and ecological evaluation of fluorescent Pseudomonads isolated from the leaves and roots of potato plants. Microbes Environ. 2012;27:122–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22791043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sotirova A, Spasova D, Galabova D, Karpenko E, Shulga A. Rhamnolipid–biosurfactant permeabilizing effects on Gram-positive and Gram-negative bacterial strains. Curr Microbiol. 2008;56:639–644.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18330632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stover CK, Pham XQ, Erwin AL, et al.  Complete genome sequence of Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1, an opportunistic pathogen. Nature. 2000;406:959–964.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10984043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swift S, Karlyshev AV, Fish L, Durant EL, Winson MK, Chhabra SR, Williams P, Macintyre S, Stewart GS. Quorum sensing in Aeromonas hydrophila and Aeromonas salmonicida: identification of the LuxRI homologs AhyRI and AsaRI and their cognate N-acylhomoserine lactone signal molecules. J Bacteriol. 1997;179:5271–5281.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC179392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9286976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka Y, Tamaki H, Matsuzawa H, Nigaya M, Mori K, Kamagata Y. Microbial community analysis in the roots of aquatic plants and isolation of novel microbes including an organism of the candidate phylum OP10. Microbes Environ. 2012;27:149–157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22791047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Ichikawa S, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchimura H, Nomura N. Pseudomonas quinolone signal affects membrane vesicle production in not only Gram-negative but also Gram-positive bacteria. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:120–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Ichikawa S, Shimizu M, Toyofuku M, Takaya N, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Variation of physiochemical properties and cell association activity of membrane vesicles with growth phase in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2010;76:3732–3739.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Inagaki A, Shimizu M, Ichikawa S, Takaya N, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Characterization of phospholipids in membrane vesicles derived from Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2011;75:605–607.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Nomura N, Nakao R, et al.  Opr86 is essential for viability and is a potential candidate for a protective antigen against biofilm formation by Pseudomonas aeruginosa. J Bacteriol. 2008;190:3969–3978.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2395022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18390657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Sakai R, Toyofuku M, Sawada I, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Outer membrane machinery and alginate synthesis regulators control membrane vesicle production in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. J Bacteriol. 2009;191:7509–7519.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786613</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19837799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Toyofuku M, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Bicyclic compounds repress membrane vesicle production and Pseudomonas quinolone signal synthesis in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. FEMS Microbiol Lett. 2010;304:123–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20146747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Multifunctional membrane vesicles in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Environ Micro-biol. 2012;14:1349–1362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22103313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomson NR, Crow MA, McGowan SJ, Cox A, Salmond GPC. Biosynthesis of carbapenem antibiotic and prodigiosin pigment in Serratia is under quorum sensing control. Mol Microbiol. 2000;36:539–556.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10844645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tommonaro G, Abbamondi G, Iodice C, Tait K, De Rosa S. Diketopiperazines produced by the halophilic archaeon, Haloterrigena hispanica, activate AHL bioreporters. Microb Ecol. 2012;63:490–495.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22109096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyofuku M, Nakajima-Kambe T, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. The effect of a cell-to-cell communication molecule, Pseudomonas quinolone signal (PQS), produced by P. aeruginosa on other bacterial species. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyofuku M, Nomura N, Fujii T, Takaya N, Maseda H, Sawada I, Nakajima T, Uchiyama H. Quorum sensing regulates denitrification in Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1. J Bacteriol. 2007;189:4969–4972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1913425</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17449629</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyofuku M, Nomura N, Kuno E, Tashiro Y, Nakajima T, Uchiyama H. Influence of the Pseudomonas quinolone signal on denitrification in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. J Bacteriol. 2008;190:7947–7956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2593205</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyofuku M, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Social behaviours under anaerobic conditions in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Int J Microbiol. 2012;2012:ID405191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsuchiya Y, Hiraki A, Kiriyama C, Arakawa T, Kusakabe R, Morisaki H. Seasonal change of bacterial community structure in a biofilm formed on the surface of the aquatic macro-phyte Phragmites australis. Microbes Environ. 2011;26:113–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Twomey KB, O’Connell OJ, McCarthy Y, Dow JM, O’Toole GA, Plant BJ, Ryan RP. Bacterial cis-2-unsaturated fatty acids found in the cystic fibrosis airway modulate virulence and persistence of Pseudomonas aeruginosa. ISME J. 2012;6:939–950.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3329111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22134647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valiente E, Bruhn JB, Nielsen KF, Larsen JL, Roig FJ, Gram L, Amaro C. Vibrio vulnificus produces quorum sensing signals of the AHL-class. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2009;69:16–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19453744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vial L, Lépine F, Milot S, Groleau MC, Dekimpe V, Woods DE, Déziel E. Burkholderia pseudomallei, B. thailandensis, and B. ambifaria produce 4-hydroxy-2-alkylquinoline analogues with a methyl group at the 3 position that is required for quorum-sensing regulation. J Bacteriol. 2008;190:5339–5352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493281</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18539738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J-H, Quan C-S, Qi X-H, Li X, Fan S-D. Determination of diketopiperazines of Burkholderia cepacia CF-66 by gas chromatography–mass spectrometry. Anal Bioanal Chem. 2010;396:1773–1779.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20062980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L-H, He Y, Gao Y, et al.  A bacterial cell–cell communication signal with cross-kingdom structural analogues. Mol Microbiol. 2004;51:903–912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14731288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang P, Robert L, Pelletier J, Dang WL, Taddei F, Wright AS. Robust growth of Escherichia coli. Curr Biol. 2010 Jun.20:1099–1103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2902570</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20537537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang WZ, Morohoshi T, Someya N, Ikeda T. Diversity and distribution of N-acylhomoserine lactone (AHL)-degrading activity and AHL-lactonase (AiiM) in genus Microbacterium. Microbes Environ. 2012;27:330–333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22446311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Kern SE, Newman DK. Endogenous phenazine antibiotics promote anaerobic survival of Pseudomonas aeruginosa via extracellular electron transfer. J Bacteriol. 2010;192:365–369.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798253</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19880596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe K, Manefield M, Lee M, Kouzuma A. Electron shuttles in biotechnology. Curr Opin Biotechnol. 2009;20:633–641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833503</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao G, Déziel E, He J, et al.  MvfR, a key Pseudomonas aeruginosa pathogenicity LTTR-class regulatory protein, has dual ligands. Mol Microbiol. 2006;62:1689–1699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17083468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto K, Arai H, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Involvement of flagella-driven motility and pili in Pseudomonas aeruginosa colonization at the air-liquid interface. Microbes Environ. 2012;27:320–323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036044</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22353768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto K, Arai H, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Trade-off between oxygen and iron acquisition in bacterial cells at the air–liquid interface. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2011;77:83–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21395624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto K, Haruta S, Kato S, Ishii M, Igarashi Y. Determinative factors of competitive advantage between aerobic bacteria for niches at the air-liquid interface. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:317–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yawata Y, Maseda H, Okabe S, Ito A, Sawada I, Kurashima H, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. The response of Pseudomonas aeruginosa PAO1 efflux pump-defective mutants to N-octanoyl-l-homoserine lactone. Microbes Environ. 2009;24:338–342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21566394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yawata Y, Toda K, Setoyama E, Fukuda J, Suzuki H, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Bacterial growth monitoring in a microfluidic device by confocal reflection microscopy. J Biosci Bioeng. 2010;110:130–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yawata Y, Toda K, Setoyama E, Fukuda J, Suzuki H, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Monitoring biofilm development in a microfluidic device using modified confocal reflection microscopy. J Biosci Bioeng. 2010;110:377–380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20547370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yawata Y, Uchiyama H, Nomura N. Visualizing the effects of biofilm structures on the influx of fluorescent material using combined confocal reflection and fluorescent microscopy. Microbes Environ. 2010;25:49–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin B, Gu JD, Wan NS. Degradation of indole by enrichment culture and Pseudomonas aeruginosa Gs isolated from mangrove sediment. Int Biodeter Biodegr. 2005;56:243–248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoon SS, Hennigan RF, Hilliard GM, et al.  Pseudomonas aeruginosa anaerobic respiration in biofilms: relationships to cystic fibrosis pathogenesis. Dev Cell. 2002;3:593–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12408810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu J, Chai Y, Zhong Z, Li S, Winans SC. Agrobacterium bioassay strain for ultrasensitive detection of N-acylhomoserine lactone-type quorum-sensing molecules: detection of autoinducers in Mesorhizobium huakuii. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2003;69:6949–6953.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC262303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14602662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
