<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">23563869</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2013</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-5520</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>56</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2013</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical obstetrics and gynecology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Obstet Gynecol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Indications, contraindications, and complications of mesh in surgical treatment of pelvic organ prolapse.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>276</StartPage>
          <EndPage>288</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>276-88</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/GRF.0b013e318282f2e8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Women are seeking care for pelvic organ prolapse in increasing numbers and a significant proportion of them will undergo a second repair for recurrence. This has initiated interest by both surgeons and industry to utilize and design prosthetic mesh materials to help augment longevity of prolapse repairs. Unfortunately, the introduction of transvaginal synthetic mesh kits for use in women was done without the benefit of level 1 data to determine its utility compared with native tissue repair. This report summarizes the potential benefit/risks of transvaginal synthetic mesh use for pelvic organ prolapse and recommendations regarding its continued use.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ellington</LastName>
            <ForeName>David R</ForeName>
            <Initials>DR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Division of Urogynecology and Pelvic Reconstructive Surgery, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Richter</LastName>
            <ForeName>Holly E</ForeName>
            <Initials>HE</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>K24 DK068389</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Obstet Gynecol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0070014</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0009-9201</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000075202" MajorTopicYN="N">Contraindications</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056887" MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic Organ Prolapse</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="Y">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011183" MajorTopicYN="Y">Postoperative Complications</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013526" MajorTopicYN="Y">Surgical Mesh</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23563869</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS435486</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3644007</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/GRF.0b013e318282f2e8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nygaard I, et al.  NHANES. Prevalence of Symptomatic Pelvic Floor Disorders in US Women. JAMA. 2008 Sep 17;300(11):1311–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918416</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tegerstedt G, Maehle-Schmidt M, Nyrén O, Hammarström M. Prevalence of symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse in a Swedish population. Int Urogynecol J Pelvic Floor Dysfunct. 2005;16:497.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15986100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rortveit G, Brown JS, Thom DH, et al.  Symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse: prevalence and risk factors in a population-based, racially diverse cohort. Obstet Gynecol. 2007;109:1396.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17540813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones KA, Shepherd JP, Oliphant SS, et al.  Trends in inpatient prolapse procedures in the United States, 1979-2006. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2010;202:501.e1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20223444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olsen AL, Smith VJ, Bergstrom JO, et al.  Epidemiology of surgically managed pelvic organ prolapse and urinary incontinence. Obstet Gynecol. 1997;89:501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9083302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJ, Holman CD, Moorin RE, Tsokos N. Lifetime risk of undergoing surgery for pelvic organ prolapse. Obstet Gynecol. 2010;116:1096.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blandon RE, Bharuch AE, Melton LJ, et al.  Incidence of pelvic floor repair after hysterectomy: A population-based cohort study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2007;197:664.e.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2562278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18060973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whiteside JL, Weber AM, Meyn LA, Walters MD. Risk factors for prolapse recurrence after vaginal repair. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004;191:1533–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15547521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sung VW, Rogers RG, Schaffer JI, Balk EM, Uhlig K, Lau J, et al.  Graft use in transvaginal pelvic organ prolapse repair: a systematic review. Society of Gynecologic Surgeons Systematic Review Group. Obstet Gynecol. 2008;112:1131–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Food and Drug Administration  . FDA safety communication: UPDATE on serious complications associated with transvaginal placement of surgical mesh for pelvic organ prolapse. Silver Spring (MD); FDA: 2011.  Available at:  http://www.fda.gov/MedicalDevices/Safety/AlertsandNotices/ucm.262435.htm. Retrieved July 27, 2011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22086260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Response of The American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists to the FDA’s 2011 Patient Safety Communication: Update on serious complications associated with transvaginal placement of surgical mesh for pelvic organ prolapse. Jul 13, 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Society of Gynecologic Surgeons Executive Committee Statement Regarding the FDA Communication: Surgical placement of mesh to repair pelvic organ prolapse imposes risks. Jul 25, 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Urogynecologic Society Response: FDA Safety Communication: Update on serious complications associated with transvaginal placement of surgical mesh for pelvic organ prolapse. Jul, 2011. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22086260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Society for Female Urology and Urodynamics Response: FDA Safety Communication: Update on serious complications associated with transvaginal placement of surgical mesh for pelvic organ prolapse. Jul, 2011. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22086260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelovsek JE, Barber MD. Women seeking treatment for advanced pelvic organ prolapse have decreased body image and quality of life. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2006;194:1455–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16647928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davila GW, Baessler K, Cosson M, Cardozo L. Selection of patients in whom vaginal graft use may be appropriate. Consensus of the 2nd IUGA Grafts Roundtable: Optimizing safety and appropriateness of graft use in transvaginal pelvic reconstructive surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2012;23:S7–S14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22395288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arya LA, Novi JM, Shaunik A, et al.  Pelvic organ prolapse, constipation and dietary intake in women; a case-control study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005;193:1687–1691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15902178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araco F, Gravante G, Sorge R, Overton J, DeVita D, et al.  the influence of BMI, smoking and age on vaginal erosions after synthetic mesh repair for pelvic organ prolapses. A multicenter study. Acta Obstet Gynecol. 2009;88:772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19452293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen CC, Collins SA, Rodgers AK, Paraiso MF, Walters MD, Barber MD. Perioperative complications in obese women vs. normal weight women who undergo vaginal surgery. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2007;197:98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17618776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collinet P, Belot F, Debodinance P, HaDuc E, Lucot JP, Cosson M. Transvaginal mesh technique for pelvic organ prolapse repair: mesh exposure management and risk factors. Int Urogynecol J. 2006;17:315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16228121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lowman JK, Woodman PJ, Nosti PA, Bump RC, Terry CL, Hale DS. Tobacco use is a risk factor for mesh erosion after abdominal sacral colpoperineorrhaphy. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2008;198:561e1–561e4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18377864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caquant F, Collinet P, Debodinance P, et al.  Safety of transvaginal mesh procedure: retrospective study of 684 patients. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2008;34(4):449–456.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18937698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore RD, Miklos JR. Vaginal mesh kits for pelvic organ prolapse, friend or foe: a comprehensive review. The Scientific World Journal. 2009;9:163–189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5823225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19252757</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang AC, Lee L, Lin CT, Chen JR. A histologic and immunohistochemical analysis of defective vaginal healing after continence taping procedures: a prospective case-controlled pilot study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004;191:1868–1874.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15592267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brill AI. The hoopla over mesh: what it means for practice. Obstetrics and Gynecology News. Jan. 2012:14–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haylen BT, Freeman RM, Swift SE, et al.  An International Urogynecological Association (IUGA)/International Continence Society (ICS) joint terminology and classification of the complications related directly to the insertion of prostheses (meshes, implants, tapes) and grafts in female pelvic floor surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2011;22:3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21140130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abed H, Rahn DD, Lowenstein L, Balk EM, Clemons JL, Rogers RG, Society of Gynecologic Surgeons Systematic Review Group  Incidence and management of graft erosion, wound granulation, and dyspareunia following vaginal prolapse repair with graft materials: a systematic review. Int Urogynecol J. 2011 Jul;22(7):789–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424785</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rardin CR, Washington BB. New considerations in the use of vaginal mesh for prolapse repair. J Minim Invasive Gynecol. 2009;16:360–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19423069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brubaker L, Glazener C, Jacquentin B, Maher C, Melgrem A, Norton P, et al.   4th International Consultation on Incontinence. Recommendations of the International Scientific Committee: evaluation and treatment of urinary incontinence, pelvic organ prolapse and faecal incontinence. Paris, France; Jul 5-9, 2008. Surgery for pelvic organ prolapse; pp. 1273–320. Available at:  http://www.icsoffice.org/Publications/ICI_4/files-book/comite-15.pdf. Retrieved June 2nd, 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen J, Jakus-Waldman S, Walter A, White T, Menefee S. Perioperative complications and reoperations after incontinence and prolapse surgeries using prosthetic implants. Obstet Gynecol. 2012;119:539–546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22353951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feiner B, Maher C. Vaginal mesh contraction: definition, clinical presentation, and management. Obstet Gynecol. 2010;115:325–330.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20093906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber AM, Walter MD, Piedmonte MR. Sexual function and vaginal anatomy in women before and after surgery for pelvic organ prolapse and urinary incontinence. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2000;182:1610–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10871485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milani R, Salvatore S, Soligo M, et al.  Functional and anatomical outcome of anterior and posterior vaginal prolapse repair with prolene mesh. BJOG. 2005;112:107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieminen K, Hitunen R, Heiskanen E, Takala T. Symptom resolution and sexual function after anterior vaginal wall repair with or without polypropylene mesh. Int Urogynecol J Pelvic Floor Dysunct. 2008;19:1611–1616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18716704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sentilhes L, Berthier A, Sergent F, et al.  Sexual function in women before and after transvaginal mesh repair for pelvic organ prolapse. Int Urogynecol J Pelvic Floor Dysfunct. 2008;19:763–772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18071618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firoozi F, Ingber M, Moore C, Vasavada S, Rackley R, Goldman H. Purely transvaginal/perineal management of complications from commercial prolapse kits using a new prostheses/grafts complication classification system. J Urology. 2012;187:1674–1679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22425114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA Executive Summary  Surgical mesh for the treatment of women with pelvic organ prolapse and stress urinary incontinence; Obstetrics and Gynecology Devices Advisory Committee Meeting; 2011.Sep 8-9, </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ignjatovic I, Stosic D. Retrovesical haematoma after Prolift procedure for cystocele correction. Int Urogynecol J. 2007;18:1495–1497.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17599235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada BS, Govier FE, Stefanovic KB, Kobashi KC. Vesicovaginal fistula and mesh erosion after Perigee (transobturator polypropylene mesh anterior repair) Urology. 2006;68(5):1121–e5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17095064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flood CG, Drutz HP, Waja L. Anterior colporrhaphy reinforced with Marlex mesh for the treatment of cystoceles. Int Urogynecol J Pelvic Floor Dysfunct. 9:200–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9795824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy M. Clinical practice guidelines on vaginal graft use from the society of gynecologic surgeons. Society of Gynecologic Surgeons Systematic Review Group. Obstet Gynecol. 2008;112:1123–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiltunen R, Nieminen K, Takala T, Heiskanen E, Merikari M, Niemi K, et al.  Low-weight polypropylene mesh for anterior vaginal wall prolapse: a randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2007;110:455–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17666627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maher C, Feiner B, Baessler K, Glazener CM. Surgical management of pelvic organ prolapse in women. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2010 Issue 4 Art.No.:CD004014.DOI:10.1002/14651858.CD004014.pub4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20393938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jia X, Glazener C, Mowatt G, Jenkinson D, Fraser C, Bain C, Burr J. Systematic review of the efficacy and safety of using mesh in surgery for uterine or vaginal vault prolapse. Int Urogynecol J. 2010;21:1413–1431.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20552168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menefee SA, Dyer KY, Lukacz ES, Simsiman AJ, Luber KM, Nguyen JN. Colporrhaphy compared with mesh or graft-reinforced vaginal paravaginal repair for anterior vaginal wall prolapse: a randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2011;118:1337–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22067717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altman D, Vayrynen T, Engh ME, Axelsen S, Falconer C, Nordic Transvaginal Mesh Group  Anterior colporrhaphy versus transvaginal mesh for pelvic organ prolapse. N Engl J Med. 2011;364:1826–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21561348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Culligan PJ, Blackwell L, Goldsmith LJ, et al.  A randomized controlled trial comparing fascia lata and synthetic mesh for sacral colpopexy. Obstet Gynecol. 2005;106:29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15994614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feiner B, Jelovsek JE, Maher C. Efficacy and safety of transvaginal mesh kits in the treatment of prolapse of the vaginal apex: a systematic review. BJOG. 2009;116:15–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nygaard IE, McCreery R, Brubaker L, et al.  Abdominal sacrocolpopexy: a comprehensive review. Obstet Gynecol. 2004;104:805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15458906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diwadkar GB, Barber MD, Feiner B, Maher C, Jelovsek JE. Complication and reoperation rates after apical vaginal prolapse surgical repair. Obstet Gynecol. 2009;113:367–373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19155908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercer-lnameJones MA, Sprowson A, Varma JS. Outcome after transperineal mesh repair of rectocele: a case-series. Dis Colon Rectum. 2004;47:864.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15085441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iglesia CB, et al.  Vaginal mesh for prolapse: a randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2010;116:293–303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20664388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Withagen MI, et al.  Trocar-guided mesh compared with conventional vaginal repair in recurrent prolapse: a randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2011;117:242–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21252735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmid C, et al.  Laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy for recurrent pelvic organ prolapse after failed transvaginal polypropylene mesh surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2012 DOI 10.1007/s00192-012-1926-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22976531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iglesia C, Hale D, Lucente V. Laparoscopic sacrocolpopexy vesus transvaginal mesh for recurrent pelvic organ prolapse. Int Urogynecol J. 2012 DOI 10.1007/s00192-012-1918-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maher CF, Feiner B, DeCuyper EM, Nichols CJ, Hickey KV, O’Rouke P. Laparoscopic sacral colpopexy versus total vaginal mesh for vaginal vault prolapse: a randomized trial. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011;204(4):360.e1–360.e7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDermott CD, Hale DS. Abdominal, laparoscopic, and robotic surgery for pelvic organ prolapse. Obstet Gynecol Clin North Am. 2009;36(3):585–614.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19932417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists Committee Opinion: Vaginal Placement of Synthetic Mesh for Pelvic Organ Prolapse. Dec, 2011.  Number 513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
