<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">23584863</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2015</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1930-0573</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>31</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2008</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Alcohol research &amp; health : the journal of the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Alcohol Res Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Communication networks in the brain: neurons, receptors, neurotransmitters, and alcohol.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>196</StartPage>
          <EndPage>214</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>196-214</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Nerve cells (i.e., neurons) communicate via a combination of electrical and chemical signals. Within the neuron, electrical signals driven by charged particles allow rapid conduction from one end of the cell to the other. Communication between neurons occurs at tiny gaps called synapses, where specialized parts of the two cells (i.e., the presynaptic and postsynaptic neurons) come within nanometers of one another to allow for chemical transmission. The presynaptic neuron releases a chemical (i.e., a neurotransmitter) that is received by the postsynaptic neuron's specialized proteins called neurotransmitter receptors. The neurotransmitter molecules bind to the receptor proteins and alter postsynaptic neuronal function. Two types of neurotransmitter receptors exist-ligand-gated ion channels, which permit rapid ion flow directly across the outer cell membrane, and G-protein-coupled receptors, which set into motion chemical signaling events within the cell. Hundreds of molecules are known to act as neurotransmitters in the brain. Neuronal development and function also are affected by peptides known as neurotrophins and by steroid hormones. This article reviews the chemical nature, neuronal actions, receptor subtypes, and therapeutic roles of several transmitters, neurotrophins, and hormones. It focuses on neurotransmitters with important roles in acute and chronic alcohol effects on the brain, such as those that contribute to intoxication, tolerance, dependence, and neurotoxicity, as well as maintained alcohol drinking and addiction.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lovinger</LastName>
            <ForeName>David M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory for Integrative Neuroscience at the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, Bethesda, Maryland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Alcohol Res Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100900708</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1535-7414</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018377">Neurotransmitter Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D043562">Receptors, G-Protein-Coupled</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017981">Receptors, Neurotransmitter</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn">
          <RefSource>Alcohol Res Health. 31(3):279.</RefSource>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000437" MajorTopicYN="N">Alcoholism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018377" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurotransmitter Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D043562" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, G-Protein-Coupled</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017981" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Neurotransmitter</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013569" MajorTopicYN="N">Synapses</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2008</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23584863</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3860493</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adinoff B, Iranmanesh A, Veldhuis J, Fisher L. Disturbances of the stress response: The role of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis during alcohol withdrawal and abstinence. Alcohol Research &amp; Health. 1998;22(1):67–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6761816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15706736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ait-Daoud N, Malcolm RJ, Jr, Johnson BA. An overview of medications for the treatment of alcohol withdrawal and alcohol dependence with an emphasis on the use of older and newer anticonvulsants. Addictive Behaviors. 2006;31(9):1628–1649.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16472931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alger BE. Retrograde signaling in the regulation of synaptic transmission: Focus on endocannabinoids. Progress in Neurobiology. 2002;68:247–286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12498988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altshuler HL, Phillips PA, Feinhandler DE. Alteration of ethanol self-administration by naltrexone. Life Sciences. 1980;26:679–688.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6767889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altar CA, DiStefano PS. Neurotrophin trafficking by anterograde transport. Trends in Neuroscience. 1998;21(10):433–437.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9786341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amara SG, Sonders MS. Neurotransmitter transporters as molecular targets for addictive drugs. Drug and Alcohol Dependence. 1998;51(1–2):87–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9716932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnsten AF. Stimulants: Therapeutic actions in ADHD. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2006;31(11):2376–2383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ariwodola OJ, Weiner JL. Ethanol potentiation of GABAergic synaptic transmission may be self-limiting: Role of presynaptic GABA(B) receptors. Journal of Neuroscience. 2004;24(47):10679–10686.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15564584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baek JK, Heaton MB, Walker DW. Up-regulation of high-affinity neurotrophin receptor, trk B-like protein on western blots of rat cortex after chronic ethanol treatment. Brain Research: Molecular Brain Research. 1996;40:161–164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8840027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbacid M. Neurotrophic factors and their receptors. Current Opinion in Cell Biology. 1995;7:148–155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7612265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barde YA, Edgar D, Thoenen H. Purification of a new neurotrophic factor from mammalian brain. The EMBO Journal. 1982;1:549–553.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC553086</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7188352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barde YA. Neurotrophins: A family of proteins supporting the survival of neurons. Progress in Clinical and Biological Research. 1994;390:45–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7724649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrett JE, Vanover KE. 5-HT receptors as targets for the development of novel anxiolytic drugs: Models, mechanisms and future directions. Psychopharmacology (Berlin) 1993;112(1):1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7870996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basavarajappa BS, Hungund BL. Chronic ethanol increases the cannabinoid receptor agonist anandamide and its precursor N-arachidonoylphosphatidylethanolamine in SK-N-SH cells. Journal of Neurochemistry. 1999;72(2):522–528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9930723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basavarajappa BS, Cooper TB, Hungund BL. Chronic ethanol administration down-regulates cannabinoid receptors in mouse brain synaptic plasma membrane. Brain Research. 1998;793(1–2):212–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9630633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basavarajappa BS, Saito M, Cooper TB, Hungund BL. Stimulation of cannabinoid receptor agonist 2-arachidonylglycerol by chronic ethanol and its modulation by specific neuromodulators in cerebellar granule neurons. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta. 2000;1535(1):78–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11113634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basavarajappa BS, Saito M, Cooper TB, Hungund BL. Chronic ethanol inhibits the anandamide transport and increases extracellular anandamide levels in cerebellar granule neurons. European Journal of Pharmacology. 2003;466(1–2):73–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12679143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggio G, Concas A, Follesa P, et al.  Stress, ethanol, and neuroactive steroids. Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2007;116(1):140–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3000046</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17555824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowers BJ, Radcliffe RA, Smith AM, et al.  Microarray analysis identifies cerebellar genes sensitive to chronic ethanol treatment in PKCγ mice. Alcohol. 2006;40:19–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1931504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17157717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowery NG. GABAB receptor: A site of therapeutic benefit. Current Opinion in Pharmacology. 2006;6(1):37–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16361115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowery N, Bitteger H, Olpe H-R, editors. GABAB Receptors in Mammalian Function. New York: Wiley and Sons; 1990. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MS, Pesold C, Appel SB. Ethanol directly excites dopaminergic ventral tegmental area reward neurons. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research. 1999;23(11):1848–1852.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10591603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruns MB, Miller MW. Neurotrophin ligand-receptor systems in somatosensory cortex of adult rat are affected by repeated episodes of ethanol. Experimental Neurology. 2007;204:680–692.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1995597</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17320080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunton L, Lazo J, Parker K.  Goodman &amp; Gilman’s The Pharmacological Basis of Therapeutics. New York: McGraw-Hill; 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charness ME. Ethanol and opioid receptor signalling. Experientia. 1989;45:418–428.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2542082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chao MV, Hempstead BL. p75 and Trk: A two-receptor system. Trends in Neuroscience. 1995;18:321–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7571013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chevaleyre V, Takahashi KA, Castillo PE. Endocannabinoid-mediated synaptic plasticity in the CNS. Annual Review of Neuroscience. 2006;29:37–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16776579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi DS, Cascini MG, Mailliard W, et al.  The type 1 equilibrative nucleoside transporter regulates ethanol intoxication and preference. Nature Neuroscience. 2004;7(8):855–861.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15258586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colombo G, Orru A, Lai P, et al.  The cannabinoid CB1 receptor antagonist, rimonabant, as a promising pharmacotherapy for alcohol dependence: Preclinical evidence. Molecular Neurobiology. 2007;36(1):102–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17952655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Compton WM, Volkow ND. Major increases in opioid analgesic abuse in the United States: Concerns and strategies. Drug and Alcohol Dependence. 2006;81(2):103–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16023304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connor M, Christie MD. Opioid receptor signalling mechanisms. Clinical and Experimental Pharmacology &amp; Physiology. 1999;26(7):493–499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coutinho V, Knöpfel T. Metabotropic glutamate receptors: Electrical and chemical signaling properties. Neuroscientist. 2002;8(6):551–561.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12467377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis MI. Ethanol-BDNF interactions: Still more questions than answers. Pharmacology and Therapeutics. 2008;118(1):36–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2553254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18394710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis MI, Szarowski D, Turner JN, et al.  In vivo activation and in situ BDNF- stimulated nuclear translocation of mitogen-activated/extracellular signal-regulated protein kinase is inhibited by ethanol in the developing rat hippocampus. Neuroscience Letters. 1999;272:95–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10507550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daws LC, Montañez S, Munn JL, et al.  Ethanol inhibits clearance of brain serotonin by a serotonin transporter-independent mechanism. Journal of Neuroscience. 2006;26(24):6431–6438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6674049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16775130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diamond I, Nagy L, Mochly-Rosen D, Gordon A. The role of adenosine and adenosine transport in ethanol-induced cellular tolerance and dependence: Possible biologic and genetic markers of alcoholism. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences. 1991;625:473–487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2058901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Marzo V, Goparaju SK, Wang L, et al.  Leptin-regulated endocannabinoids are involved in maintaining food intake. Nature. 2001;410(6830):822–825.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11298451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunwiddie TV, Masino SA. The role and regulation of adenosine in the central nervous system. Annual Review of Neuroscience. 2001;24:31–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11283304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ericson M, Lof E, Stomberg R, et al.  Nicotinic acetylcholine receptors in the anterior, but not posterior, VTA mediate ethanol induced elevation of accumbal dopamine levels. Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics. 2008 (Epub ahead of print)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18369179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fadda F, Rossetti ZL. Chronic ethanol consumption: From neuroadaptation to neurodegeneration. Progress in Neurobiology. 1998;56:385–431.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9775400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fantegrossi WE, Murnane KS, Reissig CJ. The behavioral pharmacology of hallucinogens. Biochemical Pharmacology. 2008;75(1):17–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2247373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17977517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Wilens TE. Effect of stimulant medications for attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder on later substance use and the potential for stimulant misuse, abuse, and diversion. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry. 2007;68(Suppl. 11):15–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18307377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fattori V, Abe SI, Kobayashi K, et al.  Effects of postnatal ethanol exposure on neurotrophic factors and signal transduction pathways in rat brain. Journal of Applied Toxicology. 2008;28:370–376.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17685400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fredholm BB, Chen JF, Cunha RA, et al.  Adenosine and brain function. International Review of Neurobiology. 2005;63:191–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15797469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fredholm BB, Chern Y, Franco R, Sitkovsky M. Aspects of the general biology of adenosine A2A signaling. Progress in Neurobiology. 2007;83(5):263–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17804147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerfen CR. The neostriatal mosaic: Multiple levels of compartmental organization in the basal ganglia. Annual Review of Neuroscience. 1992;15:285–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1575444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gessa GL, Muntoni F, Collu M, et al.  Low doses of ethanol activate dopaminergic neurons in the ventral tegmental area. Brain Research. 1985;348(1):201–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2998561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gianoulakis C. The effect of ethanol on the biosynthesis and regulation of opioid peptides. Experientia. 1989;45:428–435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2656284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gianoulakis C. Alcohol-seeking behavior: The roles of the hypothalamic–pituitary–adrenal axis and the endogenous opioid system. Alcohol Health &amp; Research World. 1998;22(3):202–210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6761903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15706797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginty DD, Segal RA. Retrograde neurotrophin signaling: Trk-ing along the axon. Current Opinion in Neurobiology. 2002;12:268–274.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12049932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzales RA, Weiss F. Suppression of ethanol-reinforced behavior by naltrexone is associated with attenuation of the ethanol-induced increase in dialysate dopamine levels in the nucleus accumbens. Journal of Neuroscience. 1998;18:10663–10671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9852601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzales RA, Job MO, Doyon WM. The role of mesolimbic dopamine in the development and maintenance of ethanol reinforcement. Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2004;103(2):121–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15369680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grady SR, Salminen O, Laverty DC, et al.  The subtypes of nicotinic acetylcholine receptors on dopaminergic terminals of mouse striatum. Biochemical Pharmacology. 2007;74(8):1235–1246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2735219</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17825262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haas H, Panula P. The role of histamine and the tuberomamillary nucleus in the nervous system. Nature Reviews Neuroscience. 2003;4(2):121–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12563283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayashi R, Wada H, Ito K, Adcock IM. Effects of glucocorticoids on gene transcription. European Journal of Pharmacology. 2004;500(1–3):51–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15464020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heilig M, Koob GF. A key role for corticotropin-releasing factor in alcohol dependence. Trends in Neuroscience. 2007;30(8):399–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2747092</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17629579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemmings HC, Jr, Akabas MH, Goldstein PA, et al.  Emerging molecular mechanisms of general anesthetic action. Trends in Pharmacological Sciences. 2005;26(10):503–510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16126282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hohmann AG, Suplita RL, Bolton NM, et al.  An endocannabinoid mechanism for stress-induced analgesia. Nature. 2005;435(7045):1108–1112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15973410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howlett AC. Pharmacology of cannabinoid receptors. Annual Review of Pharmacology and Toxicology. 1995;35:607–634.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7598509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ip NY, Li Y, Yancopoulos GD, Lindsay RM. Cultured hippocampal neurons show responses to BDNF, NT-3, and NT-4, but not NGF. Journal of Neuroscience. 1993a;13:3394–3405.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6576536</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7688038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ip NY, Stitt TN, Tapley P, et al.  Similarities and differences in the way neurotrophins interact with the Trk receptors in neuronal and nonneuronal cells. Neuron. 1993b;10:137–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7679912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarvis MF, Williams M. Direct autoradiographic localization of adenosine A2 receptors in the rat brain using the A2-selective agonist, [3H]CGS 21680. European Journal of Pharmacology. 1989;168:243–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2558026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson SW, North RA. Opioids excite dopamine neurons by hyperpolarization of local interneurons. Journal of Neuroscience. 1992;12:483–488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6575608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1346804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kandel ER, Schwartz JH, Jessell TM.  Principles of Neural Science. New York: McGraw-Hill; 2000. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan DR, Martin-Zanca D, Parada LF. Tyrosine phosphorylation and tyrosine kinase activity of the trk proto-oncogene product induced by NGF. Nature. 1991;350(6314):158–160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1706478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapur S, Agid O, Mizrahi R, Li M. How antipsychotics work: From receptors to reality. NeuroRx. 2006;3(1):10–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitson SL. 5-hydroxytryptamine (5-HT) receptor ligands. Current Pharmaceutical Design. 2007;13(25):2621–2637.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17897004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koob GF. A role for GABA mechanisms in the motivational effects of alcohol. Biochemical Pharmacology. 2004;68(8):1515–1525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15451394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishnan-Sarin S, Wand GS, Li XW, et al.  Effect of mu opioid receptor blockade on alcohol intake in rats bred for high alcohol drinking. Pharmacology, Biochemistry, and Behavior. 1998;59(3):627–635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9512064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krystal JH, Petrakis IL, Mason G, et al.  N-methyl-D-aspartate glutamate receptors and alcoholism: Reward, dependence, treatment, and vulnerability. Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2003;99(1):79–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12804700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krystal JH, Staley J, Mason G, et al.  Gamma-aminobutyric acid type A receptors and alcoholism: Intoxication, dependence, vulnerability, and treatment. Archives of General Psychiatry. 2006;63(9):957–968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16952998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Fleming RL, Morrow AL. Ethanol regulation of gamma-aminobutyric acid A receptors: Genomic and nongenomic mechanisms. Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2004;101(3):211–226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15031000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lachowicz JD, Sibley DR. Molecular characteristics of mammalian dopamine receptors. Pharmacology &amp; Toxicology. 1997;81(3):105–113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9335067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SP, So CH, Rashid AJ, et al.  Dopamine D1 and D2 receptor co-activation generates a novel phospholipase C-mediated calcium signal. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2004;279:35671–35678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15159403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LeMarquand D, Pihl RO, Benkelfat C. Serotonin and alcohol intake, abuse, and dependence: Findings of animal studies. Biological Psychiatry. 1994;36(6):395–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7803601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levi-Montalcini R. The nerve growth factor 35 years later. Science. 1987;237(4819):1154–1162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3306916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levi-Montalcini R, Cohen S. Effects of the extract of the mouse submaxillary salivary glands on the sympathetic system of mammals. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences. 1960;85:324–341.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14416187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z, Ding M, Thiele CJ, Luo J. Ethanol inhibits brain-derived neurotrophic factor-mediated intracellular signaling and activator protein-1 activation in cerebellar granule neurons. Neuroscience. 2004;126:149–162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15145081</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovinger DM. Serotonin’s role in alcohol’s effects on the brain. Alcohol Health &amp; Research World. 1997;21(2):114–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6826824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15704346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovinger DM. 5-HT3 receptors and the neural actions of alcohols: An increasingly exciting topic. Neurochemistry International. 1999;35(2):125–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovinger DM. Presynaptic modulation by endocannabinoids. Handbook of Experimental Pharmacology. 2008;(184):435–477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18064422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovinger DM, Homanics GE. Tonic for what ails us? High-affinity GABAA receptors and alcohol. Alcohol. 2007;41(3):139–143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2043151</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17521844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacLennan AJ, Lee N, Walker DW. Chronic ethanol administration decreases brain-derived neurotrophic factor gene expression in the rat hippocampus. Neuroscience Letters. 1995;197:105–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8552271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maldonado R, Valverde O, Berrendero F. Involvement of the endocannabinoid system in drug addiction. Trends in Neuroscience. 2006;29(4):225–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16483675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGough NN, He DY, Logrip ML, et al.  RACK1 and brain-derived neurotrophic factor: A homeostatic pathway that regulates alcohol addiction. Journal of Neuroscience. 2004;24:10542–10552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730316</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15548669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKenna DJ, Peroutka SJ. Neurochemistry and neurotoxicity of 3,4-methylenedioxymethamphetamine (MDMA, “ecstasy”) Journal of Neurochemistry. 1990;54:14–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1967141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller MW. Repeated episodic exposure to ethanol affects neurotrophin content in the forebrain of the mature rat. Experimental Neurology. 2004;189:173–181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15296847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller MW, Mooney SM. Chronic exposure to ethanol alters neurotrophin content in the basal forebrain cortex system in the mature rat: Effects on autocrine-paracrine mechanisms. Journal of Neurobiology. 2004;60:490–498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15307153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mller R, King MA, Heaton MB, Walker DW. The effects of chronic ethanol consumption on neurotrophins and their receptors in the rat hippocampus and basal forebrain. Brain Research. 2002;950:137–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12231238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell EA, Herd MB, Gunn BG, et al.  Neurosteroid modulation of GABAA receptors: Molecular determinants and significance in health and disease. Neurochemistry International. 2008;52(4–5):588–595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18055067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyakawa T, Yagi T, Kitazawa H, et al.  Fynkinase as a determinant of ethanol sensitivity: Relation to NMDA-receptor function. Science. 1997;278(5338):698–701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9381182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohler H. Benzodiazepine receptors: Mode of interaction of agonists and antagonists. Advances in Biochemical Psychopharmacology. 1983;37:247–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6314762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohler H. GABAA receptors in central nervous system disease: Anxiety, epilepsy, and insomnia. Journal of Receptor and Signal Transduction Research. 2006;26(5–6):731–740.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17118808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrow AL, VanDoren MJ, Penland SN, Matthews DB. The role of GABAergic neuroactive steroids in ethanol action, tolerance and dependence. Brain Research Brain Research Reviews. 2001;37(1–3):98–109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11744078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagy LE, Diamond I, Casso DJ, et al.  Ethanol increases extracellular adenosine by inhibiting adenosine uptake via the nucleoside transporter. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 1990;265(4):1946–1951.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2298733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naranjo CA, Kadlec KE. An evaluation of the clinical effects of serotonin uptake inhibitors in alcoholics. Biological Psychiatry. 1991;29:510S.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naassila M, Ledent C, Daoust M. Low ethanol sensitivity and increased ethanol consumption in mice lacking adenosine A2A receptors. Journal of Neuroscience. 2002;22(23):10487–10493.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6758745</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12451148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nie Z, Schweitzer P, Roberts AJ, et al.  Ethanol augments GABAergic transmission in the central amygdala via CRF1 receptors. Science. 2004;303(5663):1512–1514.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15001778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Brien CP. Anticraving medications for relapse prevention: A possible new class of psychoactive medications. American Journal of Psychiatry. 2005;162(8):1423–1431.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16055763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Malley SS, Froehlich JC. Advances in the use of naltrexone: An integration of preclinical and clinical findings. Recent Developments in Alcoholism. 2003;16:217–245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12638640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohrtman JD, Stancik EK, Lovinger DM, Davis MI. Ethanol inhibits brain-derived neurotrophic factor stimulation of extracellular signal-regulated/mitogen-activated protein kinase in cerebellar granule cells. Alcohol. 2006;39:29–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16938627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okamoto T, Harnett MT, Morikawa H. Hyperpolarization-activated cation current (Ih) is an ethanol target in midbrain dopamine neurons of mice. Journal of Neurophysiology. 2006;95(2):619–626.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1454360</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16148268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pandey SC, Zhang D, Mittal N, Nayyar D. Potential role of the gene transcription factor cyclic AMP- responsive element binding protein in ethanol withdrawal-related anxiety. Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics. 1999;288:866–878.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9918601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patil S, Zhang L, Martenyi F, et al.  Activation of mGlu2/3 receptors as a new approach to treat schizophrenia: A randomized phase 2 clinical trial. Nature Medicine. 2007;13:1102–1107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17767166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pertwee RG. The therapeutic potential of drugs that target cannabinoid receptors or modulate the tissue levels or actions of endocannabinoids. AAPS Journal. 2005;7(3):E625–E654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751266</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16353941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pettinati HM. Use of serotonin selective pharmacotherapy in the treatment of alcohol dependence. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research. 1996;20(7 Suppl):23A–29A.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pidoplichko VI, DeBiasi M, Williams JT, Dani JA. Nicotine activates and desensitizes midbrain dopamine neurons. Nature. 1997;390(6658):401–404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9389479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piomelli D, Giuffrida A, Calignano A, Rodriguez de Fonseca F. The endocannabinoid system as a target for therapeutic drugs. Trends in Pharmacological Sciences. 2000;21(6):218–224.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10838609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravinet Trillou C, Arnone M, Delgorge C, et al.  Anti-obesity effect of SR141716, a CB1 receptor antagonist, in diet-induced obese mice. American Journal of Physiology, Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology. 2003;284(2):R345–R353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12399252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddymasu SC, Soykan I, McCallum RW. Domperidone: Review of pharmacology and clinical applications in gastroenterology. American Journal of Gastroenterology. 2007;102(9):2036–2045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17488253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reichardt LF. Neurotrophin-regulated signalling pathways. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B, Biological Sciences. 2006;361:1545–1564.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1664664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16939974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reul JM, Holsboer F. Corticotropin-releasing factor receptors 1 and 2 in anxiety and depression. Current Opinion in Pharmacology. 2002;2(1):23–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11786305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivier C. Alcohol stimulates ACTH secretion in the rat: Mechanisms of action and interactions with other stimuli. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research. 1996;20(2):240–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8730214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robbins TW, Murphy ER. Behavioural pharmacology: 40+ years of progress, with a focus on glutamate receptors and cognition. Trends in Pharmacological Sciences. 2006;27(3):141–148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1867319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16490260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roth BL, Baner K, Westkaemper R, et al.  Salvinorin: A potent naturally occurring nonnitroge-nous kappa opioid selective agonist. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2002;99(18):11934–11939.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC129372</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12192085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanger DJ. The pharmacology and mechanisms of action of new generation, non-benzodiazepine hypnotic agents. CNS Drugs. 2004;18(Suppl. 1):9–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15291009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz JC, Malfroy B, De La Baume S. Biological inactivation of enkephalins and the role of enkephalin-dipeptidyl-carboxypeptidase (“enkephalinase”) as neuropeptidase. Life Sciences. 1981;29(17):1715–1740.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6272046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sieghart W, Sperk G. Subunit composition, distribution and function of GABA(A) receptor subtypes. Current Topics in Medicinal Chemistry. 2002;2(8):795–816.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12171572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigel E. Mapping of the benzodiazepine recognition site on GABAA receptors. Current Topics in Medicinal Chemistry. 2002;2(8):833–839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12171574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siggins GR, Roberto M, Nie Z. The tipsy terminal: Presynaptic effects of ethanol. Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2005;107(1):80–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15963352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinner B, Graf BM. Ketamine. Handbook of Experimental Pharmacology. 2008;(182):313–333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18175098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stacy M, Galbreath A. Optimizing long-term therapy for Parkinson disease: Levodopa, dopamine agonists, and treatment-associated dyskinesia. Clinical Neuropharmacology. 2008;31(1):51–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18303491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stell BM, Brickley SG, Tang CY, et al.  Neuroactive steroids reduce neuronal excitability by selectively enhancing tonic inhibition mediated by delta subunit-containing GABAA receptors. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2003;100:14439–14444.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC283610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14623958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Surmeier DJ, Kitai ST. D1 and D2 dopamine receptor modulation of sodium and potassium currents in rat neostriatal neurons. Progress in Brain Research. 1993;99:309–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7906427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapia-Arancibia L, Rage F, Givalois L, et al.  Effects of alcohol on brain-derived neurotrophic factor mRNA expression in discrete regions of the rat hippocampus and hypothalamus. Journal of Neuroscience Research. 2001;63:200–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11169630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson AJ, Lummis SC. The 5-HT3 receptor as a therapeutic target. Expert Opinion on Therapeutic Targets. 2007;11(4):527–540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1994432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17373882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorsell A. Neuropeptide Y (NPY) in alcohol intake and dependence. Peptides. 2007;28(2):480–483.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17239487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unsicker K. GDNF: A cytokine at the interface of TGF-betas and neurotrophins. Cell Tissue Research. 1996;286(2):175–158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8854886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VanDoren MJ, Matthews DB, Janis GC, et al.  Neuroactive steroid 3alpha-hydroxy-5alpha-pregnan-20-one modulates electrophysiological and behavioral actions of ethanol. Journal of Neuroscience. 2000;20(5):1982–1989.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6772919</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10684899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vengeliene V, Bilbao A, Molander A, Spanagel R. Neuropharmacology of alcohol addiction. British Journal of Pharmacology. 2008;154(2):299–315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2442440</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18311194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volkow ND, Wang GJ, Telang F, et al.  Profound decreases in dopamine release in striatum in detoxified alcoholics: Possible orbitofrontal involvement. Journal of Neuroscience. 2007;27(46):12700–12706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6673312</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18003850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wade DT, Robson P, House H, et al.  A preliminary controlled study to determine whether whole-plant cannabis extracts can improve intractable neurogenic symptoms. Clinical Rehabilitation. 2003;17:21–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12617376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L, Liu J, Harvey-White J, et al.  Endocannabinoid signaling via cannabinoid receptor 1 is involved in ethanol preference and its age-dependent decline in mice. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2003;100(3):1393–1398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC298783</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12538878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Carnicella S, Phamluong K, et al.  Ethanol induces long-term facilitation of NR2B-NMDA receptor activity in the dorsal striatum: Implications for alcohol drinking behavior. Journal of Neuroscience. 2007;27(13):3593–3602.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17392475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiner JL, Valenzuela CF. Ethanol modulation of GABAergic transmission: The view from the slice. Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2006;111(3):533–554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16427127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams JT, Christie MJ, Manzoni O. Cellular and synaptic adaptations mediating opioid dependence. Physiological Reviews. 2001;81(1):299–343.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11152760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winkelman JW, Allen RP, Tenzer P, Hening W. Restless legs syndrome: Nonpharmacologic and pharmacologic treatments. Geriatrics. 2007;62(10):13–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17922563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong DF, Maini A, Rousset OG, Brasic JR. Positron emission tomography: A tool for identifying the effects of alcohol dependence on the brain. Alcohol Research &amp; Health. 2003;27(2):161–173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6668888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15303627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodward JJ. Ethanol and NMDA receptor signaling. Critical Reviews in Neurobiology. 2000;14(1):69–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11253956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wurst FM, Rasmussen DD, Hillemacher T, et al.  Alcoholism, craving, and hormones: The role of leptin, ghrelin, prolactin, and the pro-opiomelanocortin system in modulating ethanol intake. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research. 2007;31(12):1963–1967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18034691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Dhillon HS, Barron S, et al.  Effects of chronic ethanol administration on expression of BDNF and trkB mRNAs in rat hippocampus after experimental brain injury. Brain Research Molecular Brain Research. 2000;79:174–179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10925157</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
