<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">24106651</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2013</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2160-8288</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>3</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2013</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Tremor and other hyperkinetic movements (New York, N.Y.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Tremor Other Hyperkinet Mov (N Y)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated with Streptococcal Infections (PANDAS): An Evolving Concept.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">tre-03-167-4158-7</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7916/D8ZC81M1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus infections (PANDAS) originated from the observational work of Swedo and collaborators, who formalized their definition in 1998 in a set of operational criteria. The application of these criteria, which focuses on tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms as core symptoms, has encountered difficulties, eventually leading to a high rate of misdiagnosis. In particular, the core feature represented by the association between newly diagnosed infections and neuropsychiatric symptom relapses in youths with this diagnosis could not be demonstrated by longitudinal studies. Exploratory studies aiming to identify clinical or cognitive features that could discriminate PANDAS from other pediatric obsessive-compulsive and tic disorders present methodological limitations, and therefore are not conclusive. Other behavioral features, in addition to obsessive-compulsive symptoms and tics, have been included in pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndromes (PANS) and childhood acute neuropsychiatric syndromes (CANS), two new concepts recently proposed in order to define a much broader clinical spectrum encompassing etiologically diverse entities. Given the uncertainties on the clinical definition of PANDAS, it is not surprising that evidence in support of a post-infectious, immune-mediated pathophysiology is also insufficient. Anti-dopamine receptor antibodies might be relevant to both Sydenham's chorea (SC)-the prototypical post-streptococcal neuropsychiatric disorder-and some rare forms of encephalitis targeting the basal ganglia specifically, but studies exploring their association with children fulfilling Swedo's criteria for PANDAS have been inconclusive. Moreover, we lack evidence in favor of the efficacy of antibiotic prophylaxis or tonsillectomy in patients fulfilling Swedo's criteria for PANDAS, whereas a response to immune-mediated treatments like intravenous immunoglobulins has been documented by one study, but needs replication in larger trials. Overall, the available evidence does not convincingly support the concept that PANDAS are a well-defined, isolated clinical entity subdued by definite pathophysiological mechanisms; larger, prospective studies are necessary to reshape the nosography and disease mechanisms of post-streptococcal acute neuropsychiatric disorders other than SC. Research is also under way to shed further light on a possible relationship between streptococcal infections, other biological and psychosocial stressors, and the complex pathobiology of chronic tic disorders.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Macerollo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Antonella</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sobell Department of Motor Neuroscience and Movement Disorders, National Hospital of Neurology and Neurosurgery, Institute of Neurology, University College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martino</LastName>
            <ForeName>Davide</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Tremor Other Hyperkinet Mov (N Y)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101569493</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2160-8288</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CANS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Group-A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PANDAS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PANS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tourette syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmunity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obsessive-compulsive symptoms</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interests:</b> The authors report no conflict of interest. <b>Financial disclosures:</b> D. Martino received honoraria for speaking engagements from Chiesi Farmaceutici, UCB pharma and the Movement Disorders Society, and served on the editorial advisory board of Frontiers in Movement Disorders.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24106651</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3783973</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7916/D8ZC81M1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">tre-03-167-4158-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giovannoni G. PANDAS: overview of the hypothesis. Adv Neurol. 2006;99:159–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16536362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE. Sydenham’s chorea (SC): a model for childhood autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders. J Am Med Assoc. 1994;272:1788–1791. doi: 10.1001/jama.1994.03520220082035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.1994.03520220082035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7661914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey MA, Giedd JN, Swedo SE. PANDAS: the search for environmental triggers of pediatric neuropsychiatric disorders. Lessons from rheumatic fever. J Child Neurol. 1998;13:413–423. doi: 10.1177/088307389801300901.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/088307389801300901</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9733286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman AH, Pilkey L, Gibbons MJ. A psychosomatic study of eight children with Sydenham’s chorea. Pediatrics. 1958;21:582–595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13542101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman JM, Aron AM, Collard JE, Mackay MC. The emotional correlates of Sydenham’s chorea. Pediatrics. 1965;35:42–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14223224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondo K, Kabasawa T. Improvement in Gilles de la Tourette syndrome after corticosteroid therapy. Ann Neurol. 1978;4:387. doi: 10.1002/ana.410040423.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410040423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">281893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiessling LS. Tic disorders associated with evidence of invasive group A beta-hemolytic streptococcal disease. Dev Med Child Neurol Suppl. 1989;59:48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Rapoport JL, Cheslow DL, et al.  High prevalence of obsessive-compulsive symptoms in patients with Sydenham’s chorea. Am J Psychiatry. 1989a;146:246–249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2912267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Rapoport JL, Leonard H, Lenane M, Cheslow D. Obsessive-compulsive disorder in children and adolescents. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1989b;46:335–341. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.1989.01810040041007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.1989.01810040041007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2930330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Schapiro MB, et al.  Sydenham’s chorea: physical and psychological symptoms of St Vitus dance. Pediatrics. 1993;91:706–713.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8464654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen AJ, Leonard HL, Swedo SE. Case study: a new infection-triggered, autoimmune subtype of pediatric OCD and Tourette’s syndrome. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1995;34:307–311. doi: 10.1097/00004583-199503000-00015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004583-199503000-00015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7896671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Garvey M, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry. 1998;155:264–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson DR, Kurlan R, Leckman J, Kaplan EL. The human immune response to streptococcal extracellular antigens: clinical, diagnostic, and potential pathogenetic implications. Clin Infect Dis. 2010;50:481–490. doi: 10.1086/650167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/650167</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20067422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabbay V, Coffey BJ, Babb JS, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus: comparison of diagnosis and treatment in the community and at a specialty clinic. Pediatrics. 2008;122:273–278. doi: 10.1542/peds.2007-1307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2007-1307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R, Johnson D, Kaplan EL; Tourette Syndrome Study Group  Streptococcal infection and exacerbations of childhood tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective blinded cohort study. Pediatrics. 2008;121:1188–1197. doi: 10.1542/peds.2007-2657.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2007-2657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF, King RA, Gilbert DL, et al.  Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and exacerbations of tic and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective longitudinal study. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2011;50:108–118. doi: 10.1016/j.jaac.2010.10.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2010.10.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK.  Infections and tic disorders. In: Martino D, Leckman JF, . In. New York: Oxford University Press; 2013. pp. p. 168–201. editors). Tourette syndrome.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernstein GA, Victor AM, Pipal AJ, Williams KA. Comparison of clinical characteristics of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections and childhood obsessive-compulsive disorder. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2010;20:333–340. doi: 10.1089/cap.2010.0034.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2010.0034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3678581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Storch EA, Lewin AB, Edge PJ, Goodman WK. Clinical factors associated with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections. J Pediatr. 2012;160:314–319. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.07.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.07.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3227761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21868033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirschtritt ME, Hammond CJ, Luckenbaugh D, et al.  Executive and attention functioning among children in the PANDAS subgroup. Child Neuropsychol. 2009;15:179–194. doi: 10.1080/09297040802186899.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09297040802186899</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2693234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18622810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewin AB, Storch EA, Mutch PJ, Murphy TK. Neurocognitive functioning in youth with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2011;23:391–398. doi: 10.1176/appi.neuropsych.23.4.391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.neuropsych.23.4.391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22231309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold MH, Tyndall A. Poststreptococcal reactive arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 1989;48:686–688. doi: 10.1136/ard.48.8.686.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.48.8.686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1003848</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2675783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA, Sachdev V, MaCkaronis JE, St Peter M, Swedo SE. Echocardiographic findings in the PANDAS subgroup. Pediatrics. 2004;114:e748–e751. doi: 10.1542/peds.2004-0308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2004-0308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15545618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segarra AR, Murphy TK. Cardiac involvement in children with PANDAS. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2008;47:603–604. doi: 10.1097/CHI.0b013e3181676b82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CHI.0b013e3181676b82</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Gilbert DL, Wolf DS, Mink JW, Kurlan R. Moving from PANDAS to CANS. J Pediatr. 2012;160:725–731. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.11.040.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.11.040</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22197466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leckman JF, Rose NR. From research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome) Pediatr Therapeut. 2012;2:2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Fazio MP, Morales J, Davis R. Acute myoclonus secondary to group A beta-hemolytic streptococcus infection: a PANDAS variant. J Child Neurol. 1998;13:516–518. doi: 10.1177/088307389801301010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/088307389801301010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9796759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Church AJ, Benton S, et al.  Post-streptococcal autoimmune dystonia with isolated bilateral striatal necrosis. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2002;44:485–489. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-8749.2002.tb00310.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.2002.tb00310.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12162386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Church AJ, Surtees RA, Thompson EJ, Giovannoni G, Neville BG. Post-streptococcal autoimmune neuropsychiatric disease presenting as paroxysmal dystonic choreoathetosis. Mov Disord. 2002;17:817–820. doi: 10.1002/mds.10169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.10169</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12210883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo M, Tsuchiya K, Hamasaki Y, Singer HS. Restless legs syndrome: association with streptococcal or mycoplasms infection. Pediatr Neurol. 2004;31:119–121. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2003.12.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2003.12.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15301831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squintani G, Tinazzi M, Gambarin M, et al.  Post-streptococcal ‘complex’ movement disorders: unusual concurrence of psychogenic and organic symptoms. J Neurol Sci. 2010;288:68–71. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2009.10.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2009.10.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19896680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Heyman I, Surtees RAH, et al.  Dyskinesias and associated psychiatric disorders following streptococcal infections. Arch Dis Child. 2004;89:604–610. doi: 10.1136/adc.2003.031856.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.2003.031856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1719997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15210487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sokol MS. Infection-triggered anorexia nervosa in children: clinical description of four cases. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2000;10:133–145. doi: 10.1089/cap.2000.10.133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2000.10.133</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10933123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Church AJ, Cardoso F, et al.  Poststreptococcal acute disseminated encephalomyelitis with basal ganglia involvement and auto-reactive antibasal ganglia antibodies. Ann Neurol. 2001;50:588–595. doi: 10.1002/ana.1250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.1250</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Merheb V, Pillai S, et al.  Antibodies to surface dopamine-2 receptor in autoimmune movement and psychiatric disorders. Brain. 2012;135:3453–3468. doi: 10.1093/brain/aws256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aws256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23065479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aran A, Lin L, Nevsimalova S, et al.  Elevated anti-streptococcal antibodies in patients with recent narcolepsy onset. Sleep. 2009;32:979–983.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2717204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19725248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das A, Radhakrishnan A. A case of PANDAS with Kleine-Levin type periodic hypersomnia. Sleep Med. 2012;13:319–320. doi: 10.1016/j.sleep.2011.11.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sleep.2011.11.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22261244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oosterveer DM, Overweg-Plandsoen WC, Roos RA. Sydenham’s chorea: a practical overview of the current literature. Pediatr Neurol. 2010;43:1–6. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2009.11.015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2009.11.015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso F. Sydenham’s chorea. Handb Clin Neurol. 2011;100:221–229. doi: 10.1016/B978-0-444-52014-2.00014-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-444-52014-2.00014-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21496581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baizabal-Carvallo JF, Jankovic J. Movement disorders in autoimmune diseases. Mov Disord. 2012;27:935–946. doi: 10.1002/mds.25011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22555904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham MW. Pathogenesis of group A streptococcal infections and their sequelae. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2008;609:29–42. doi: 10.1007/978-0-387-73960-1_3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-0-387-73960-1_3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18193655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giedd JN, Rapoport JL, Garvey MA, Perlmutter S, Swedo SE. MRI assessment of children with obsessive-compulsive disorder or tics associated with streptococcal infection. Am J Psychiatry. 2000;157:281–283. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.157.2.281.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.157.2.281</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10671403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Hong JJ, Yoon DY, Williams PN. Serum autoantibodies do not differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. Neurology. 2005;65:1701–1707. doi: 10.1212/01.wnl.0000183223.69946.f1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000183223.69946.f1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16207842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Gause C, Morris C, Lopez P; Tourette Syndrome Study Group  Serial immune markers do not correlate with clinical exacerbations in pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2008;121:1198–1205. doi: 10.1542/peds.2007-2658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2007-2658</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Dale RC, Gilbert DL, Giovannoni G, Leckman JF. Immunopathogenic mechanisms in Tourette syndrome: a critical review. Mov Disord. 2009;24:1267–1279. doi: 10.1002/mds.22504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.22504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3972005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19353683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brimberg L, Benhar I, Mascaro-Blanco A, et al.  Behavioral, pharmacological, and immunological abnormalities after streptococcal exposure: a novel rat model of Sydenham chorea and related neuropsychiatric disorders. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2012;37:2076–2087. doi: 10.1038/npp.2012.56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2012.56</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3398718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22534626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirvan CA, Swedo SE, Snider LA, Cunningham MW. Antibody-mediated neuronal cell signalling in behavior and movement disorders. J Neuroimmunol. 2006;179:173–179. doi: 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2006.06.017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2006.06.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16875742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brilot F, Merheb V, Ding A, Murphy T, Dale RC. Antibody binding to neuronal surface in Sydenham chorea, but not in PANDAS or Tourette syndrome. Neurology. 2011;76:1508–1513. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182181090.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182181090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3087465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21411742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor JR, Morshed SA, Parveen S, et al.  An animal model of Tourette’s syndrome. Am J Psychiatry. 2002;159:657–660. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.159.4.657.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.159.4.657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11925307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loiselle CR, Lee O, Moran TH, Singer HS. Striatal microinfusion of Tourette syndrome and PANDAS sera: failure to induce behavioral changes. Mov Disord. 2004;19:390–396. doi: 10.1002/mds.10522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.10522</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman KL, Hornig M, Yaddanapudi K, Jabado O, Lipkin WI. A murine model for neuropsychiatric disorders associated with group A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection. J Neurosci. 2004;24:1780–1791. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0887-03.2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0887-03.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14973249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaddanapudi K, Hornig M, Serge R, et al.  Passive transfer of streptococcus-induced antibodies reproduces behavioral disturbances in a mouse model of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection. Mol Psychiatry. 2010;15:712–726. doi: 10.1038/mp.2009.77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2009.77</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19668249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen SK, Tvrdik P, Peden E, et al.  Hematopoietic origin of pathological grooming in Hoxb8 mutant mice. Cell. 2010;141:775–785. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2010.03.055.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2010.03.055</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2894573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20510925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy ML, Pichichero ME. Prospective identification and treatment of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with group A streptococcal infection (PANDAS) Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2002;156:356–361. doi: 10.1001/archpedi.156.4.356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpedi.156.4.356</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey MA, Perlmutter SJ, Allen AJ, et al.  A pilot study of penicillin prophylaxis for neuropsychiatric exacerbations triggered by streptococcal infections. Biol Psychiatry. 1999;45:1564–1571. doi: 10.1016/S0006-3223(99)00020-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-3223(99)00020-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10376116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA, Lougee L, Slattery M, Grant P, Swedo SE. Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;57:788–792. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orvidas LJ, Slattery MJ. Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders and streptococcal infections: role of otolaryngologist. Laryngoscope. 2001;111:1515–1519. doi: 10.1097/00005537-200109000-00005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005537-200109000-00005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11568599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heubi C, Shott SR. PANDAS: pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections—an uncommon, but important indication for tonsillectomy. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2003;67:837–840. doi: 10.1016/S0165-5876(03)00158-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0165-5876(03)00158-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12880661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batuecas Calerio A, Sanchez Gonzalez F, Santa Cruz Ruiz S, Santos Gorjon P, Blanco Perez P. PANDAS Syndrome: a new tonsillectomy indication? Acta Otorrinolaringol Esp. 2008;59:362–363. doi: 10.1016/S0001-6519(08)75557-2.. in Spanish.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0001-6519(08)75557-2.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18817720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arostegui S, Aguero JA, Escar C. PANDAS following amygdalectomy. An Sist Sanit Navar. 2003;26:287–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12951624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Lewin AB, Parker-Athill EC, Storch EA, Mutch PJ. Tonsillectomies and adenoidectomies do not prevent the onset of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with group A streptococcus. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2013;32:834–838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3740796</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23518825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perlmutter SJ, Leitman SF, Garvey MA, et al.  Therapeutic plasma exchange and intravenous immunoglobulin for obsessive-compulsive disorder and tic disorders in childhood. Lancet. 1999;354:1153–1158. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(98)12297-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(98)12297-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Kurlan R, Leckman J. The immunobiology of Tourette’s disorder, pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with Streptococcus, and related disorders: a way forward. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2010;20:317–331. doi: 10.1089/cap.2010.0043.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2010.0043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4003464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storch EA, Murphy TK, Geffken GR, et al.  Cognitive-behavioral therapy for PANDAS-related obsessive-compulsive disorder: findings from a preliminary waitlist controlled open trial. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2006;45:1171–1178. doi: 10.1097/01.chi.0000231973.43966.a0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.chi.0000231973.43966.a0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ, Manson WL, Steenhuis MP, Kallenberg CG, Minderaa RB. Association of common cold with exacerbations in pediatric but not adult patients with tic disorder: a prospective longitudinal study. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2005;15:285–292. doi: 10.1089/cap.2005.15.285.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2005.15.285</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15910212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller N, Riedel M, Blendinger C, Oberle K, Jacobs E, Abele-Horn M. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection and Tourette’s syndrome. Psychiatry Res. 2004;129:119–125. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2004.04.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2004.04.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15590039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riedel M, Straube A, Schwarz MJ, Wilske B, Muller N. Lyme disease presenting as Tourette’s syndrome. Lancet. 1998;351:418–419. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(05)78357-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)78357-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9482302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turley JM. Tourette-like disorder after herpes encephalitis. Am J Psychiatry. 1988;145:1604–1605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3195682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Chiarotti F, Buttiglione M, et al.  The relationship between group A streptococcal infections and Tourette syndrome: a study on a large service-based cohort. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2011;53:951–957. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-8749.2011.04018.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.2011.04018.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21679362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bombaci M, Grifantini R, Mora M, et al.  Protein array profiling of tic patient sera reveals a broad range and enhanced immune response against Group A Streptococcus antigens. PLoS One. 2009;4:e6332. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0006332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0006332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2709431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19623252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mell LK, Davis RL, Owens D. Association between streptococcal infection and obsessive-compulsive disorder, Tourette’s syndrome, and tic disorder. Pediatrics. 2005;116:56–60. doi: 10.1542/peds.2004-2058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2004-2058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leslie DL, Kozma L, Martin A, et al.  Neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection: a case-control study among privately insured children. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2008;47:1166–1172. doi: 10.1097/CHI.0b013e3181825a3d.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CHI.0b013e3181825a3d</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2783578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18724258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag A, Gilbert R, Giovannoni G, Robertson MM, Metcalfe C, Ben-Shlomo Y. Streptococcal infection, Tourette syndrome, and OCD: is there a connection? Neurology. 2009;73:1256–1263. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bd10fd.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bd10fd</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2889814</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19794128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Sajid M, Soto O, et al.  Detecting pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus in children with obsessive-compulsive disorder and tics. Biol Psychiatry. 2004;55:61–68. doi: 10.1016/S0006-3223(03)00704-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-3223(03)00704-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14706426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H, Williams KA, Katsovich L, et al.  Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and psychosocial stress predict future tic and obsessive-compulsive symptom severity in children and adolescents with Tourette syndrome and obsessive-compulsive disorder. Biol Psychiatry. 2010;67:684–691. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.08.020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.08.020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2843763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lit L, Gilbert DL, Walker W, Sharp FR. A subgroup of Tourette’s patients overexpress specific natural killer cell genes in blood: a preliminary report. Am J Med Genet B. 2007;144B:958–963. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.b.30550.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.b.30550</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17503477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lit L, Enstrom A, Sharp FR, Gilbert DL. Age-related gene expression in Tourette syndrome. J Psychiatr Res. 2009;43:319–330. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychires.2008.03.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2008.03.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662336</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18485367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matz J, Krause DL, Dehning S, et al.  Altered monocyte activation markers in Tourette’s syndrome: a case-control study. BMC Psychiatry. 2012;12:29. doi: 10.1186/1471-244X-12-29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-12-29</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3356225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22471395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krause D, Matz J, Weidinger E, et al.  Association between intracellular infectious agents and Tourette’s syndrome. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2010;260:359–363. doi: 10.1007/s00406-009-0084-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-009-0084-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo F, Leckman JF, Katsovich L, et al.  Prospective longitudinal study of children with tic disorders and/or obsessive-compulsive disorder: relationship of symptom exacerbations to newly acquired streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2004;113:e578–585. doi: 10.1542/peds.113.6.e578.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.113.6.e578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ, Anderson GM, Troost PW, et al.  Plasma kynurenine and related measures in tic disorder patients. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2007;16(Suppl. 1):71–77. doi: 10.1007/s00787-007-1009-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00787-007-1009-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF, Katsovich L, Kawikova I, et al.  Increased serum levels of interleukin-12 and tumor necrosis factor-alpha in Tourette’s syndrome. Biol Psychiatry. 2005;57:667–673. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15780855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ, Bijzet J, Limburg PC, et al.  Elevated binding of D8/17-specific monoclonal antibody to B lymphocytes in tic disorder patients. Am J Psychiatry. 2004;161:1501–1502. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.161.8.1501-a.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.161.8.1501-a</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15285987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moller JC, Tackenberg B, Heinzel-Gutenbrunner M, et al.  Immunophenotyping in Tourette syndrome—a pilot study. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15:749–753. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02159.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02159.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18484991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawikova I, Leckman JF, Kronig H, et al.  Decreased numbers of regulatory T cells suggest impaired immune tolerance in children with tourette syndrome: a preliminary study. Biol Psychiatry. 2007;61:273–278. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2006.06.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2006.06.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bos-Veneman NG, Olieman R, Tobiasova Z, et al.  Altered immunoglobulin profiles in children with Tourette syndrome. Brain Behav Immun. 2011;25:532–538. doi: 10.1016/j.bbi.2010.12.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2010.12.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21156204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawikova I, Grady BP, Tobiasova Z, et al.  Children with Tourette’s syndrome may suffer immunoglobulin A dysgammaglobulinemia: preliminary report. Biol Psychiatry. 2010;67:679–683. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.09.034.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.09.034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3974615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20006327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Storch EA, Turner A, Reid JM, Tan J, Lewin AB. Maternal history of autoimmune disease in children presenting with tics and/or obsessive-compulsive disorder. J Neuroimmunol. 2010;229:243–247. doi: 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2010.08.017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2010.08.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2991439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang YT, Li YF, Muo CH, et al.  Correlation of Tourette syndrome and allergic disease: nationwide population-based case-control study. J Dev Behav Pediatr. 2011;32:98–102. doi: 10.1097/DBP.0b013e318208f561.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DBP.0b013e318208f561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21217404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wenzel C, Wurster U, Muller-Vahl KR. Oligoclonal bands in cerebrospinal fluid in patients with Tourette’s syndrome. Mov Disord. 2011;26:343–346. doi: 10.1002/mds.23403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20960488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
