<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">24117026</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2014</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2249</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>175</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2014</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical and experimental immunology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Immunol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Myasthenia gravis: an update for the clinician.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>408</StartPage>
          <EndPage>418</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>408-18</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cei.12217</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This paper provides a thorough overview of the current advances in diagnosis and therapy of myasthenia gravis (MG). Nowadays the term 'myasthenia gravis' includes heterogeneous autoimmune diseases, with a postsynaptic defect of neuromuscular transmission as the common feature. Myasthenia gravis should be classified according to the antibody specificity [acetylcholine, muscle-specific receptor tyrosine kinase (MuSK), low-density lipoprotein receptor-related protein 4 (LRP4), seronegative], thymus histology (thymitis, thymoma, atrophy), age at onset (in children; aged less than or more than 50 years) and type of course (ocular or generalized). With optimal treatment, the prognosis is good in terms of daily functions, quality of life and survival. Symptomatic treatment with acetylcholine esterase inhibition is usually combined with immunosuppression. Azathioprine still remains the first choice for long-term immunosuppressive therapy. Alternative immunosuppressive options to azathioprine include cyclosporin, cyclophosphamide, methotrexate, mycophenolate mofetil and tacrolimus. Rituximab is a promising new drug for severe generalized MG. Emerging therapy options include belimumab, eculizumab and the granulocyte- macrophage colony-stimulating factor. One pilot study on etanercept has given disappointing results. For decades, thymectomy has been performed in younger adults to improve non-paraneoplastic MG. However, controlled prospective studies on the suspected benefit of this surgical procedure are still lacking. In acute exacerbations, including myasthenic crisis, intravenous immunoglobulin, plasmapheresis and immunoadsorption are similarly effective.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2013 British Society for Immunology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sieb</LastName>
            <ForeName>J P</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, HELIOS Hanseklinikum Stralsund, University Hospital Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Exp Immunol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0057202</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0009-9104</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009157" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myasthenia Gravis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myasthenia gravis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroimmunology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">therapy/immunotherapy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24117026</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3927901</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cei.12217</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pakzad Z, Aziz T, Oger J. Increasing incidence of myasthenia gravis among elderly in British Columbia, Canada. Neurology. 2011;76:1526–1528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21519005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pallaver F, Riviera AP, Piffer S, et al.  Change in myasthenia gravis epidemiology in Trento, Italy, after twenty years. Neuroepidemiology. 2011;36:282–287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21757957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuda M, Dohi-Iijima N, Nakamura A, et al.  Increase in incidence of elderly-onset patients with myasthenia gravis in Nagano Prefecture, Japan. Intern Med. 2005;44:572–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16020882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zivkovic SA, Clemens PR, Lacomis D. Characteristics of late-onset myasthenia gravis. J Neurol. 2012;259:2167–2171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22476514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leite MI, Jacob S, Viegas S, et al.  IgG1 antibodies to acetylcholine receptors in ‘seronegative’ myasthenia gravis. Brain. 2008;131:1940–1952.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2442426</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18515870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu H, Xiong WC, Mei L. To build a synapse: signaling pathways in neuromuscular junction assembly. Development. 2010;137:1017–1033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2835321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20215342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoch W, McConville J, Helms S, Newsom-Davis J, Melms A, Vincent A. Auto-antibodies to the receptor tyrosine kinase MuSK in patients with myasthenia gravis without acetylcholine receptor antibodies. Nat Med. 2001;7:365–368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11231638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pevzner A, Schoser B, Peters K, et al.  Anti-LRP4 autoantibodies in AChR-and MuSK-antibody-negative myasthenia gravis. J Neurol. 2012;259:427–435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21814823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang B, Tzartos JS, Belimezi M, et al.  Autoantibodies to lipoprotein-related protein 4 in patients with double-seronegative myasthenia gravis. Arch Neurol. 2012;69:445–451.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farrugia ME, Robson MD, Clover L, et al.  MRI and clinical studies of facial and bulbar muscle involvement in MuSK antibody-associated myasthenia gravis. Brain. 2006;129:1481–1492.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16672291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baggi F, Andreetta F, Maggi L, et al.  Complete stable remission and autoantibody specificity in myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2013;80:188–195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23255823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behin A, Mayer M, Kassis-Makhoul B, et al.  Severe neonatal myasthenia due to maternal anti-MuSK antibodies. Neuromuscul Disord. 2008;18:443–446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18434154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poulas K, Koutsouraki E, Kordas G, Kokla A, Tzartos SJ. Anti-MuSK-and anti-AChR-positive myasthenia gravis induced by d-penicillamine. J Neuroimmunol. 2012;250:94–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22683336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez AM, Van Den Broeck J, Vrolix K, et al.  Antibody effector mechanisms in myasthenia gravis-pathogenesis at the neuromuscular junction. Autoimmunity. 2010;43:353–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20380584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cole RN, Reddel SW, Gervasio OL, Phillips WD. Anti-MuSK patient antibodies disrupt the mouse neuromuscular junction. Ann Neurol. 2008;63:782–789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18384168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawakami Y, Ito M, Hirayama M, et al.  Anti-MuSK autoantibodies block binding of collagen Q to MuSK. Neurology. 2011;77:1819–1826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233209</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill JT, Sanders DB, Evoli A. Anti-MuSK antibody myasthenia gravis: clinical findings and response to treatment in two large cohorts. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:36–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21674519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pasnoor M, Wolfe GI, Nations S, et al.  Clinical findings in MuSK-antibody positive myasthenia gravis: a U.S. experience. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:370–374.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19882635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niks EH, vanLeeuwen Y, Leite MI, et al.  Clinical fluctuations in MuSK myasthenia gravis are related to antigen-specific IgG4 instead of IgG1. J Neuroimmunol. 2008;195:151–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18384886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauriola L, Ranelletti F, Maggiano N, et al.  Thymus changes in anti-MuSK-positive and-negative myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2005;64:536–538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leite MI, Strobel P, Jones M, et al.  Fewer thymic changes in MuSK antibody-positive than in MuSK antibody-negative MG. Ann Neurol. 2005;57:444–448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15732104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz-Manera J, Martinez-Hernandez E, Querol L, et al.  Long-lasting treatment effect of rituximab in MuSK myasthenia. Neurology. 2012;78:189–193.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22218276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi H, Kawaguchi N, Nemoto Y, Hattori T. High-dose intravenous immunoglobulin for the treatment of MuSK antibody-positive seronegative myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Sci. 2006;247:239–241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16876198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voltz RD, Albrich WC, Nagele A, et al.  Paraneoplastic myasthenia gravis: detection of anti-MGT30 (titin) antibodies predicts thymic epithelial tumor. Neurology. 1997;49:1454–1457.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spaggiari L, Casiraghi M, Guarize J. Multidisciplinary treatment of malignant thymoma. Curr Opin Oncol. 2012;24:117–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22143371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venuta F, Rendina EA, Anile M, deGiacomo T, Vitolo D, Coloni GF. Thymoma and thymic carcinoma. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2012;60:1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22237733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leite MI, Coutinho E, Lana-Peixoto M, et al.  Myasthenia gravis and neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a multicenter study of 16 patients. Neurology. 2012;78:1601–1607.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3348852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22551731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Paul F, Franciotta D, et al.  Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders in patients with myasthenia gravis: ten new aquaporin-4 antibody positive cases and a review of the literature. Mult Scler. 2012;18:1135–1143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22183934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kister I, Gulati S, Boz C, et al.  Neuromyelitis optica in patients with myasthenia gravis who underwent thymectomy. Arch Neurol. 2006;63:851–856.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16769866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aarli JA. Herzmyasthenie: myasthenia of the heart. Arch Neurol. 2009;66:1322–1323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19901161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki S, Utsugisawa K, Yoshikawa H, et al.  Autoimmune targets of heart and skeletal muscles in myasthenia gravis. Arch Neurol. 2009;66:1334–1338.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19752287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romi F, Suzuki S, Suzuki N, Petzold A, Plant GT, Gilhus NE. Anti-voltage-gated potassium channel Kv1.4 antibodies in myasthenia gravis. J Neurol. 2012;259:1312–1316.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22167224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Lapiscina EH, Aguirre ME, Blanco TA, Pascual IJ. Myasthenia gravis: sleep quality, quality of life, and disease severity. Muscle Nerve. 2012;46:174–180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22806365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deymeer F, Gungor-Tuncer O, Yilmaz V, et al.  Clinical comparison of anti-MuSK-vs anti-AChR-positive and seronegative myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2007;68:609–611.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17310034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonett JR, Jaretzki A., III Thymectomy for nonthymomatous myasthenia gravis: a critical analysis. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2008;1132:315–328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18567883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youssef SJ, Louie BE, Farivar AS, Blitz M, Aye RW, Vallieres E. Comparison of open and minimally invasive thymectomies at a single institution. Am J Surg. 2010;199:589–593.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20466100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin MW, Chang YL, Huang PM, Lee YC. Thymectomy for non-thymomatous myasthenia gravis: a comparison of surgical methods and analysis of prognostic factors. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2010;37:7–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19615918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newsom-Davis J, Cutter G, Wolfe GI, et al.  Status of the thymectomy trial for nonthymomatous myasthenia gravis patients receiving prednisone. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2008;1132:344–347.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18567886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maggi L, Mantegazza R. Treatment of myasthenia gravis: focus on pyridostigmine. Clin Drug Invest. 2011;31:691–701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21815707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sieb JP, Köhler W. Benefits from sustained-release pyridostigmine bromide in myasthenia gravis: results of a prospective multicenter open-label trial. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2010;112:781–784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sussman JD, Argov Z, McKee D, Hazum E, Brawer S, Soreq H. Antisense treatment for myasthenia gravis: experience with monarsen. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2008;1132:283–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18567879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sussman J, Argov Z, Wirguin Y, Apolski S, Milic-Rasic V, Soreq H. Further developments with antisense treatment for myasthenia gravis. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2012;1275:13–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner S, Janzen RW, Mohs C, Pohlmann S, Klingel R, Grützmacher PW. Long-term treatment of refractory myasthenia gravis with immunoadsorption. Dtsch Med Wochenschr. 2008;133:2377–2382. [in German]</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18988129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jani-Acsadi A, Lisak RP. Myasthenic crisis: guidelines for prevention and treatment. J Neurol Sci. 2007;261:127–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17544450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill JT, Oakley D, Kuchibhatla M, et al.  A Retrospective study of complications of therapeutic plasma exchange in myasthenia. Muscle Nerve. 2013;47:170–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23168720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Köhler W, Bucka C, Klingel R. A randomized and controlled study comparing immunoadsorption and plasma exchange in myasthenic crisis. J Clin Apher. 2011;26:347–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22095647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barth D, Nabavi NM, Ng E, Nwe P, Bril V. Comparison of IVIg and PLEX in patients with myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2011;76:2017–2023.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3109880</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21562253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mandawat A, Kaminski HJ, Cutter G, Katirji B, Alshekhlee A. Comparative analysis of therapeutic options used for myasthenia gravis. Ann Neurol. 2010;68:797–805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21061395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palace J, Newsom-Davis J, Lecky B Myasthenia Gravis Study Group. A randomized double-blind trial of prednisolone alone or with azathioprine in myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 1998;50:1778–1783.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9633727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drachman DB, Jones RJ, Brodsky RA. Treatment of refractory myasthenia: ‘rebooting’ with high-dose cyclophosphamide. Ann Neurol. 2003;53:29–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12509845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heckmann JM, Rawoot A, Bateman K, Renison R, Badri M. A single-blinded trial of methotrexate versus azathioprine as steroid-sparing agents in generalized myasthenia gravis. BMC Neurol. 2011;11:97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3170595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21819556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanders DB, Hart IK, Mantegazza R, et al.  An international, phase III, randomized trial of mycophenolate mofetil in myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2008;71:400–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18434638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muscle Study Group. A trial of mycophenolate mofetil with prednisone as initial immunotherapy in myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2008;71:394–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18434639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hehir MK, Burns TM, Alpers J, Conaway MR, Sawa M, Sanders DB. Mycophenolate mofetil in AChR-antibody-positive myasthenia gravis: outcomes in 102 patients. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:593–598.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20405499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schalke B, Kappos L, Rohrbach E, et al.  Cyclosporin A versus azathioprine in the treatment of myasthenia gravis: final results of a randomized, controlled double-blind clinical trial. Neurology. 1988;38(Suppl. 1):135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tindall RS, Phillips JT, Rollins JA, Wells L, Hall K. A clinical therapeutic trial of cyclosporine in myasthenia gravis. Ann NY Acad Sci. 1993;681:539–551.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8357194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonifati DM, Angelini C. Long-term cyclosporine treatment in a group of severe myasthenia gravis patients. J Neurol. 1997;244:542–547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9352450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagane Y, Suzuki S, Suzuki N, Utsugisawa K. Two-year treatment with cyclosporine microemulsion for responder myasthenia gravis patients. Eur Neurol. 2010;64:186–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20720424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshikawa H, Iwasa K, Satoh K, Takamori M. FK506 prevents induction of rat experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis. J Autoimmun. 1997;10:11–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9080295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ponseti JM, Gamez J, Azem J, et al.  Post-thymectomy combined treatment of prednisone and tacrolimus versus prednisone alone for consolidation of complete stable remission in patients with myasthenia gravis: a non-randomized, non-controlled study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2007;23:1269–1278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17559724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evoli A, Di SC, Marsili F, Punzi C. Successful treatment of myasthenia gravis with tacrolimus. Muscle Nerve. 2002;25:111–114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11754194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ponseti JM, Fort JM, Espin E, Armengol M. Tacrolimus (FK506) in the treatment of prednisone-resistant myasthenia gravis. Preliminary results of 20 cases. Med Clin (Barc) 2002;118:117. [In Spanish]</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11825555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minami N, Fujiki N, Doi S, et al.  Five-year follow-up with low-dose tacrolimus in patients with myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Sci. 2011;300:59–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21035148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshikawa H, Kiuchi T, Saida T, Takamori M. Randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of tacrolimus in myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:970–977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784757</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imai T, Tsuda E, Hozuki T, et al.  Early effect of tacrolimus in improving excitation–contraction coupling in myasthenia gravis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2012;123:1886–1890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22386321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onrust SV, Lamb HM, Balfour JA. Rituximab. Drugs. 1999;58:79–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10439931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheson BD. Rituximab: clinical development and future directions. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2002;2:97–110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rommer PS, Zettl UK, Kieseier B. Requirement for safety monitoring for approved multiple sclerosis therapies: an overview. Clin Exp Immunol. 2014;175:397–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3927900</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24102425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rommer PS, Dudesek A, Stüve O, Zettl UK. Monoclonal antibodies in treatment of multiple sclerosis. Clin Exp Immunol. 2014;175:373–384.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3927898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24001305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collongues N, Casez O, Lacour A, et al.  Rituximab in refractory and non-refractory myasthenia: a retrospective multicenter study. Muscle Nerve. 2012;46:687–691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stieglbauer K, Topakian R, Schäffer V, Aichner FT. Rituximab for myasthenia gravis: three case reports and review of the literature. J Neurol Sci. 2009;280:120–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19272616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stein B, Bird SJ. Rituximab in the treatment of MuSK antibody-positive myasthenia gravis. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2011;12:163–164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson RP, Jr, Pascuzzi RM, Kessler K, et al.  Rituximab for the treatment of thymoma-associated and de novo myasthenia gravis: 3 cases and review. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2009;10:170–177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19494727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maddison P, McConville J, Farrugia ME, et al.  The use of rituximab in myasthenia gravis and Lambert–Eaton myasthenic syndrome. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82:671–673.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zebardast N, Patwa HS, Novella SP, Goldstein JM. Rituximab in the management of refractory myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2010;41:375–378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19852027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindberg C, Bokarewa M. Rituximab for severe myasthenia gravis – experience from five patients. Acta Neurol Scand. 2010;122:225–228.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20199513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evoli A, Bianchi MR, Riso R, et al.  Response to therapy in myasthenia gravis with anti-MuSK antibodies. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2008;1132:76–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18567856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerkeni S, Marotte H, Miossec P. Improvement with rituximab in a patient with both rheumatoid arthritis and myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2008;38:1343–1345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18816604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molloy ES. PML and rheumatology: the contribution of disease and drugs. Cleve Clin J Med. 2011;78(Suppl. 2):S28–S32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22123931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bharat A, Xie F, Baddley JW, et al.  Incidence and risk factors for progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy among patients with selected rheumatic diseases. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2012;64:612–615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3310319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22162369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palazzo E, Yahia SA. Progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy in autoimmune diseases. Joint Bone Spine. 2012;79:351–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22281228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molloy ES, Calabrese LH. Progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy associated with immunosuppressive therapy in rheumatic diseases: evolving role of biologic therapies. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64:3043–3051.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez AM, Willcox N, Molenaar PC, et al.  Targeting plasma cells with proteasome inhibitors: possible roles in treating myasthenia gravis? Ann NY Acad Sci. 2012;1274:48–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragheb S, Lisak RP. B-cell-activating factor and autoimmune myasthenia gravis. Autoimmune Dis. 2011;2011:939520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3251912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22235365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lisak RP, Ragheb S. The role of B cell-activating factor in autoimmune myasthenia gravis. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2012;1274:60–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragheb S, Lisak R, Lewis R, Van SG, Gonzales F, Simon K. A potential role for B-cell activating factor in the pathogenesis of autoimmune myasthenia gravis. Arch Neurol. 2008;65:1358–1362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18852352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, Jr, Barohn RJ, Cutter GR, et al.  A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Phase II study of eculizumab in patients with refractory generalized myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2013;48:76–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23512355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christadoss P, Goluszko E. Treatment of experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis with recombinant human tumor necrosis factor receptor Fc protein. J Neuroimmunol. 2002;122:186–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11777558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowin J, Meriggioli MN, Tuzun E, Leurgans S, Christadoss P. Etanercept treatment in corticosteroid-dependent myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2004;63:2390–2392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15623708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fee DB, Kasarskis EJ. Myasthenia gravis associated with etanercept therapy. Muscle Nerve. 2009;39:866–870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19373885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiruppathi M, Rowin J, Li JQ, Sheng JR, Prabhakar BS, Meriggioli MN. Functional defect in regulatory T cells in myasthenia gravis. Ann NY Acad Sci. 2012;1274:68–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3531815</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowin J, Thiruppathi M, Arhebamen E, Sheng J, Prabhakar BS, Meriggioli MN. Granulocyte macrophage colony-stimulating factor treatment of a patient in myasthenic crisis: effects on regulatory T cells. Muscle Nerve. 2012;46:449–453.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3428740</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22907239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
