<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">24470531</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2014</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1549-490X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2014</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The oncologist</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Oncologist</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>193</StartPage>
          <EndPage>201</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>193-201</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0328</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNST) are uncommon, biologically aggressive soft tissue sarcomas of neural origin that pose tremendous challenges to effective therapy. In 50% of cases, they occur in the context of neurofibromatosis type I, characterized by loss of function mutations to the tumor suppressor neurofibromin; the remainder arise sporadically or following radiation therapy. Prognosis is generally poor, with high rates of relapse following multimodality therapy in early disease, low response rates to cytotoxic chemotherapy in advanced disease, and propensity for rapid disease progression and high mortality. The last few years have seen an explosion in data surrounding the potential molecular drivers and targets for therapy above and beyond neurofibromin loss. These data span multiple nodes at various levels of cellular control, including major signal transduction pathways, angiogenesis, apoptosis, mitosis, and epigenetics. These include classical cancer-driving genetic aberrations such as TP53 and phosphatase and tensin homolog (PTEN) loss of function, and upregulation of mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) and (mechanistic) target of rapamycin (TOR) pathways, as well as less ubiquitous molecular abnormalities involving inhibitors of apoptosis proteins, aurora kinases, and the Wingless/int (Wnt) signaling pathway. We review the current understanding of MPNST biology, current best practices of management, and recent research developments in this disease, with a view to informing future advancements in patient care.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Farid</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohamad</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Tisch Cancer Institute, Mount Sinai School of Medicine, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Demicco</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elizabeth G</ForeName>
            <Initials>EG</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Garcia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberto</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ahn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Linda</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Merola</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pamela R</ForeName>
            <Initials>PR</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cioffi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Angela</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert G</ForeName>
            <Initials>RG</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Oncologist</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9607837</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1083-7159</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018317" MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve Sheath Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trials</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular targeted therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurofibromatosis type 1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sarcoma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Disclosures of potential conflicts of interest may be found at the end of this article.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24470531</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926794</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0328</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">theoncologist.2013-0328</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fletcher CDM, Bridge JA, Hogendoorn PCW. et al.   WHO Classification of Tumours of Soft Tissue and Bone. Lyon, France: IARC; 2013. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng VY, Scharschmidt TJ, Mayerson JL, et al.  Incidence and survival in sarcoma in the United States: A focus on musculoskeletal lesions. Anticancer Res. 2013;33:2597–2604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23749914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widemann BC. Current status of sporadic and neurofibromatosis type 1-associated malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Curr Oncol Rep. 2009;11:322–328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6689400</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19508838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cichowski K, Shih TS, Schmitt E, et al.  Mouse models of tumor development in neurofibromatosis type 1. Science. 1999;286:2172–2176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10591652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Y, Ghosh P, Charnay P, et al.  Neurofibromas in NF1: Schwann cell origin and role of tumor environment. Science. 2002;296:920–922.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11988578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staser K, Yang FC, Clapp DW. Pathogenesis of plexiform neurofibroma: Tumor-stromal/hematopoietic interactions in tumor progression. Annu Rev Pathol. 2012;7:469–495.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3694738</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22077553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou C, Smith KD, Liu J, et al.  Clinical, pathological, and molecular variables predictive of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor outcome. Ann Surg. 2009;249:1014–1022.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19474676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou CY, Smith KD, Zhu QS, et al.  Dual targeting of AKT and mammalian target of rapamycin: A potential therapeutic approach for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor. Mol Cancer Ther. 2009;8:1157–1168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19417153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregorian C, Nakashima J, Dry SM, et al.  PTEN dosage is essential for neurofibroma development and malignant transformation. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2009;106:19479–19484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2765459</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradtmöller M, Hartmann C, Zietsch J, et al.  Impaired Pten expression in human malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours. PLoS One. 2012;7:e47595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23139750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu J, Patmore DM, Jousma E et al. EGFR-STAT3 signaling promotes formation of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Oncogene 2013 [E-pub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres KE, Zhu QS, Bill K, et al.  Activated MET is a molecular prognosticator and potential therapeutic target for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Clin Cancer Res. 2011;17:3943–3955.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3117912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21540237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson AL, Rahrmann EP, Moriarity BS, et al.  Canonical Wnt/β-catenin signaling drives human schwann cell transformation, progression, and tumor maintenance. Cancer Discov. 2013;3:674–689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3679355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berghmans S, Murphey RD, Wienholds E, et al.  tp53 mutant zebrafish develop malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2005;102:407–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC544293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15630097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subramanian S, Thayanithy V, West RB, et al.  Genome-wide transcriptome analyses reveal p53 inactivation mediated loss of miR-34a expression in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours. J Pathol. 2010;220:58–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4058327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verdijk RM, den Bakker MA, Dubbink HJ, et al.  TP53 mutation analysis of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2010;69:16–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feber A, Wilson GA, Zhang L, et al.  Comparative methylome analysis of benign and malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Genome Res. 2011;21:515–524.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065699</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21324880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Presneau N, Eskandarpour M, Shemais T, et al.  MicroRNA profiling of peripheral nerve sheath tumours identifies miR-29c as a tumour suppressor gene involved in tumour progression. Br J Cancer. 2013;108:964–972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590650</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23175151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brekke HR, Ribeiro FR, Kolberg M, et al.  Genomic changes in chromosomes 10, 16, and X in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors identify a high-risk patient group. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28:1573–1582.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20159821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas L, Mautner VF, Cooper DN, et al.  Molecular heterogeneity in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors associated with neurofibromatosis type 1. Hum Genomics. 2012;6:18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3500234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23244685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bottillo I, Ahlquist T, Brekke H, et al.  Germline and somatic NF1 mutations in sporadic and NF1-associated malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours. J Pathol. 2009;217:693–701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19142971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun D, Haddad R, Kraniak JM, et al.  RAS/MEK-independent gene expression reveals BMP2-related malignant phenotypes in the Nf1-deficient MPNST. Mol Cancer Res. 2013;11:616–627.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23423222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz D, Lazar A, Lev D. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumour (MPNST): The clinical implications of cellular signalling pathways. Expert Rev Mol Med. 2009;11:e30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19835664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gladdy RA, Qin LX, Moraco N, et al.  Do radiation-associated soft tissue sarcomas have the same prognosis as sporadic soft tissue sarcomas? J Clin Oncol. 2010;28:2064–2069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651600</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LaFemina J, Qin LX, Moraco NH, et al.  Oncologic outcomes of sporadic, neurofibromatosis-associated, and radiation-induced malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Ann Surg Oncol. 2013;20:66–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3567771</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22878618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans DG, Baser ME, McGaughran J, et al.  Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours in neurofibromatosis 1. J Med Genet. 2002;39:311–314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735122</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12011145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferner RE, Golding JF, Smith M, et al.  [18F]2-fluoro-2-deoxy-D-glucose positron emission tomography (FDG PET) as a diagnostic tool for neurofibromatosis 1 (NF1) associated malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours (MPNSTs): A long-term clinical study. Ann Oncol. 2008;19:390–394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17932395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beert E, Brems H, Daniëls B, et al.  Atypical neurofibromas in neurofibromatosis type 1 are premalignant tumors. Genes Chromosomes Cancer. 2011;50:1021–1032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21987445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stucky CC, Johnson KN, Gray RJ, et al.  Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNST): The Mayo Clinic experience. Ann Surg Oncol. 2012;19:878–885.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Endo M, Yamamoto H, Setsu N, et al.  Prognostic significance of AKT/mTOR and MAPK pathways and antitumor effect of mTOR inhibitor in NF1-related and sporadic malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Clin Cancer Res. 2013;19:450–461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23209032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porter DE, Prasad V, Foster L, et al.  Survival in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours: A comparison between sporadic and neurofibromatosis type 1-associated tumours. Sarcoma. 2009;2009:756395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2666272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19360115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrari A, Miceli R, Rey A, et al.  Non-metastatic unresected paediatric non-rhabdomyosarcoma soft tissue sarcomas: Results of a pooled analysis from United States and European groups. Eur J Cancer. 2011;47:724–731.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3539303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carli M, Ferrari A, Mattke A, et al.  Pediatric malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor: The Italian and German soft tissue sarcoma cooperative group. J Clin Oncol. 2005;23:8422–8430.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16293873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolberg M, Høland M, Agesen TH, et al.  Survival meta-analyses for &gt;1800 malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor patients with and without neurofibromatosis type 1. Neuro-oncol. 2013;15:135–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3548581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23161774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn GP, Spiliopoulos K, Plotkin SR, et al.  Role of resection of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1. J Neurosurg. 2013;118:142–148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23101443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pervaiz N, Colterjohn N, Farrokhyar F, et al.  A systematic meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials of adjuvant chemotherapy for localized resectable soft-tissue sarcoma. Cancer. 2008;113:573–581.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18521899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widemann BC, Reinke D, Helman L, et al.  SARC006: Phase II trial of chemotherapy in sporadic and neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1)-associated high-grade malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNSTs) J Clin Oncol.  31, 2013 (suppl; abstr 10522)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroep JR, Ouali M, Gelderblom H, et al.  First-line chemotherapy for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor (MPNST) versus other histological soft tissue sarcoma subtypes and as a prognostic factor for MPNST: An EORTC soft tissue and bone sarcoma group study. Ann Oncol. 2011;22:207–214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3003614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skotheim RI, Kallioniemi A, Bjerkhagen B, et al.  Topoisomerase-II alpha is upregulated in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors and associated with clinical outcome. J Clin Oncol. 2003;21:4586–4591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14673046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steins MB, Serve H, Zühlsdorf M, et al.  Carboplatin/etoposide induces remission of metastasised malignant peripheral nerve tumours (malignant schwannoma) refractory to first-line therapy. Oncol Rep. 2002;9:627–630.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11956640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widemann BC, Salzer WL, Arceci RJ, et al.  Phase I trial and pharmacokinetic study of the farnesyltransferase inhibitor tipifarnib in children with refractory solid tumors or neurofibromatosis type I and plexiform neurofibromas. J Clin Oncol. 2006;24:507–516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16421428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattingly RR, Kraniak JM, Dilworth JT, et al.  The mitogen-activated protein kinase/extracellular signal-regulated kinase kinase inhibitor PD184352 (CI-1040) selectively induces apoptosis in malignant schwannoma cell lines. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2006;316:456–465.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16239399</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maki RG, D’Adamo DR, Keohan ML, et al.  Phase II study of sorafenib in patients with metastatic or recurrent sarcomas. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27:3133–3140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2716936</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19451436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim A, Dombi E, Tepas K, et al.  Phase I trial and pharmacokinetic study of sorafenib in children with neurofibromatosis type I and plexiform neurofibromas. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2013;60:396–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6309697</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22961690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johannessen CM, Reczek EE, James MF, et al.  The NF1 tumor suppressor critically regulates TSC2 and mTOR. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2005;102:8573–8578.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1142482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15937108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson G, Mahller YY, Collins MH, et al.  Effective in vivo targeting of the mammalian target of rapamycin pathway in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Mol Cancer Ther. 2008;7:1237–1245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2855168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18483311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghadimi MP, Lopez G, Torres KE, et al.  Targeting the PI3K/mTOR axis, alone and in combination with autophagy blockade, for the treatment of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Mol Cancer Ther. 2012;11:1758–1769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3416967</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22848094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Raedt T, Walton Z, Yecies JL, et al.  Exploiting cancer cell vulnerabilities to develop a combination therapy for ras-driven tumors. Cancer Cell. 2011;20:400–413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233475</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21907929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albritton KH, Rankin C, Coffin CM et al. Phase II study of erlotinib in metastatic or unresectable malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNST). J Clin Oncol (Meeting Abstracts) June 2006;24 no. 18_suppl 9518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D’Adamo DR, Anderson SE, Albritton K, et al.  Phase II study of doxorubicin and bevacizumab for patients with metastatic soft-tissue sarcomas. J Clin Oncol. 2005;23:7135–7142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16192597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Graaf WT, Blay JY, Chawla SP, et al. EORTC Soft Tissue and Bone Sarcoma Group. PALETTE Study Group  Pazopanib for metastatic soft-tissue sarcoma (PALETTE): A randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2012;379:1879–1886.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22595799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robertson KA, Nalepa G, Yang FC, et al.  Imatinib mesylate for plexiform neurofibromas in patients with neurofibromatosis type 1: A phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2012;13:1218–1224.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23099009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klampfer L, Huang J, Shirasawa S, et al.  Histone deacetylase inhibitors induce cell death selectively in cells that harbor activated kRasV12: The role of signal transducers and activators of transcription 1 and p21. Cancer Res. 2007;67:8477–8485.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17875686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez G, Torres K, Liu J, et al.  Autophagic survival in resistance to histone deacetylase inhibitors: Novel strategies to treat malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Cancer Res. 2011;71:185–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064267</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21084276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storlazzi CT, Brekke HR, Mandahl N, et al.  Identification of a novel amplicon at distal 17q containing the BIRC5/SURVIVIN gene in malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours. J Pathol. 2006;209:492–500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16721726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghadimi MP, Young ED, Belousov R, et al.  Survivin is a viable target for the treatment of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Clin Cancer Res. 2012;18:2545–2557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3932367</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22407831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howell VM. Sleeping beauty—a mouse model for all cancers? Cancer Lett. 2012;317:1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22079740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahrmann EP, Watson AL, Keng VW, et al.  Forward genetic screen for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor formation identifies new genes and pathways driving tumorigenesis. Nat Genet. 2013;45:756–766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3695033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23685747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel AV, Eaves D, Jessen WJ, et al.  Ras-driven transcriptome analysis identifies aurora kinase A as a potential malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor therapeutic target. Clin Cancer Res. 2012;18:5020–5030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3902639</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22811580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
