<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">24672362</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2015</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-744X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2014</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2014</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>TheScientificWorldJournal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>ScientificWorldJournal</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Cutaneous and mucosal lichen planus: a comprehensive review of clinical subtypes, risk factors, diagnosis, and prognosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>742826</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>742826</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">742826</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2014/742826</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Lichen planus (LP) is a chronic inflammatory disorder that most often affects middle-aged adults. LP can involve the skin or mucous membranes including the oral, vulvovaginal, esophageal, laryngeal, and conjunctival mucosa. It has different variants based on the morphology of the lesions and the site of involvement. The literature suggests that certain presentations of the disease such as esophageal or ophthalmological involvement are underdiagnosed. The burden of the disease is higher in some variants including hypertrophic LP and erosive oral LP, which may have a more chronic pattern. LP can significantly affect the quality of life of patients as well. Drugs or contact allergens can cause lichenoid reactions as the main differential diagnosis of LP. LP is a T-cell mediated immunologic disease but the responsible antigen remains unidentified. In this paper, we review the history, epidemiology, and clinical subtypes of LP. We also review the histopathologic aspects of the disease, differential diagnoses, immunopathogenesis, and the clinical and genetic correlations.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gorouhi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Farzam</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1197-7242</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Davis, 3301 C Street, Sacramento, CA 95816, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Davari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Parastoo</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2285-5603</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Davis, 3301 C Street, Sacramento, CA 95816, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fazel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nasim</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3905-8715</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Davis, 3301 C Street, Sacramento, CA 95816, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>ScientificWorldJournal</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101131163</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1537-744X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008010" MajorTopicYN="N">Lichen Planus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2013</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24672362</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3929580</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/742826</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar V, Abbas A, Aster J.  Robbins &amp; Cotran Pathologic Basis of Disease. 8th ed edition. Philadelphia, Pa, USA: Saunders; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daoud M, Pittelkow M.  Lichen Planusin. In: Goldsmith L, Katz SI, Gilchrest BA, Paller AS, Leffell DJ, Wolff K, editors. Fitzpatrick's Dermatology in General Medicine. New York, NY, USA: McGraw-Hill; 2012. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson E. On leichen planus. Journal of Cutaneous Medicine and Surgery. 1869;3(10):117–132.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pindborg JJ, Reichart PA, Smith CI.  WHO international histological classification of tumours. In: Pindborg JJ, Reichart PA, Smith CI, editors. Histological Typing of Cancer and Precancer of the Oral Mucosa. Berlin, Germany: Springer; 1997. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stelwagon HW.  Treatise on Diseases of the Skin for the Use of Advanced Students and Practitioners. 7th edition. Philadelphia, Pa, USA: W. B. Sauders; 1914. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weyl A. Bemerkungen zum Lichen Planus. Deutsche Medizinische Wochenschrift. 1885;11:624–626.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickham LF. Sur un signe pathognomonique du lichen de Wilson (lichen plan) Stries et ponctuations grisatres. Annales de Dermatologie et de Syphiligraphie. 1895;6:517–520.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darier J.  Precis de Dermatologie. Paris, France: Masson; 1909. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gougerot H, Burnier R. Lichen plan du col uterin, accompagnant un lichen plan jugal et un lichen plan stomacal: lichen plurimuqueux sans lichen cutane. Bulletin de la Société Française de Dermatologie et de Syphiligraphie. 1937;44:637–640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelisse M, Leibowitch M, Sedel D, Hewitt J. A new vulvo-vagino-gingival syndrome. Mucosal erosive Lichen Planus. Annales de Dermatologie et de Venereologie. 1982;109(9):797–798.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7158935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shiohara T, Kano Y.  Lichen Planus and lichenoid dermatoses. In: Bolognia JL, Jorizzo J, Rapini RP, editors. Dermatology. New York, NY, USA: Mosby Elsevier; 2008. pp. 159–180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller CS, Epstein JB, Hall EH, Sirois D. Changing oral care needs in the United States: the continuing need for oral medicine. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontics. 2001;91(1):34–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11174569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouquot JE, Gorlin RJ. Leukoplakia, Lichen Planus, and other oral keratoses in 23,616 white Americans over the age of 35 years. Oral Surgery Oral Medicine and Oral Pathology. 1986;61(4):373–381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3458148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axéll T, Rundquist L. Oral Lichen Planus—a demographic study. Community Dentistry and Oral Epidemiology. 1987;15(1):52–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3467894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alabi GO, Akinsanya JB. Lichen Planus in tropical Africa. Tropical and Geographical Medicine. 1981;33(2):143–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7281214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlosser BJ. Lichen Planus and lichenoid reactions of the oral mucosa. Dermatologic Therapy. 2010;23(3):251–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20597944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCartan BE, Healy CM. The reported prevalence of oral Lichen Planus: a review and critique. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 2008;37(8):447–453.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18624932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrozzo M. How common is oral Lichen Planus? Evidence-Based Dentistry. 2008;9(4):112–113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19151683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pannell RS, Fleming DM, Cross KW. The incidence of molluscum contagiosum, scabies and Lichen Planus. Epidemiology and Infection. 2005;133(6):985–991.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16274495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisen D. The clinical features, malignant potential, and systemic associations of oral Lichen Planus: a study of 723 patients. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2002;46(2):207–214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11807431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma R, Maheshwari V. Childhood Lichen Planus: a report of fifty cases. Pediatric Dermatology. 1999;16(5):345–348.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10571830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanwar AJ, De D. Lichen Planus in childhood: report of 100 cases. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2010;35(3):257–262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19874373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walton KE, Bowers EV, Drolet BA, Holland KE. Childhood Lichen Planus: demographics of a U.S. population. Pediatric Dermatology. 2010;27(1):34–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20199407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanwar AJ, Dogra S, Handa S, Parsad D, Radotra BD. A study of 124 Indian patients with Lichen Planus pigmentosus. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2003;28(5):481–485.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12950331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salman SM, Kibbi A-G, Zaynoun S. Actinic Lichen Planus. A clinicopathologic study of 16 patients. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1989;20(2, part 1):226–231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2915056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan E, Martinka M, Ball N, Shapiro J. Primary cicatricial alopecias: clinicopathology of 112 cases. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2004;50(1):25–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14699361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorouhi F, Firooz A, Khatami A, et al.  Interventions for cutaneous Lichen Planus. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2009;(4)CD008038</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsh JP, Skvarka CB, Allen HB. A novel visual clue for the diagnosis of hypertrophic Lichen Planus. Archives of Dermatology. 2006;142(7):p. 954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16847230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willsteed E, Bhogal BS, Das AK, Wojnarowska F, Black MM, McKee PH. Lichen Planus pemphigoides: a clinicopathological study of nine cases. Histopathology. 1991;19(2):147–154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1757068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos-Juanes J, Mas-Vidal A, Coto-Segura P, Sánchez Del Río J, Galache Osuna C. Pigmented actinic Lichen Planus successfully treated with intense pulsed light. British Journal of Dermatology. 2010;163(3):662–663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20491768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dekio I, Matsuki S, Furumura M, Morita E, Morita A. Actinic Lichen Planus in a Japanese man: first case in the East Asian population. Photodermatology Photoimmunology and Photomedicine. 2010;26(6):333–335.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21140994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reich HL, Nguyen JT, James WD. Annular Lichen Planus: a case series of 20 patients. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2004;50(4):595–599.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badri T, Kenani N, Benmously R, Debbiche A, Mokhtar I, Fenniche S. Isolated genital annular, Lichen Planus. Acta Dermatovenerologica Alpina, Pannonica et Adriatica. 2011;20(1):31–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21879203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morales-Callaghan A, Jr., Martínez G, Aragoneses H, Miranda-Romero A. Annular atrophic Lichen Planus. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2005;52(5):906–908.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15858488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batra P, Wang N, Kamino H, Possick P. Linear Lichen Planus. Dermatology Online Journal. 2008;14(10):p. 16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19061615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perry D, Fazel N. Zosteriform Lichen Planus. Dermatology Online Journal. 2006;12(5):p. 3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16962018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Happle R. Linear Lichen Planus of the face and neck versus amalgam-induced “isotopic” cutaneous Lichen Planus. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2005;52(2):p. 375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15692500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh SK, Bandyopadhyay D, Chatterjee G, Saha D. Wolf’s isotopic response: large annular polycyclic Lichen Planus occurring on healed lesions of dermatophytosis. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2009;23(3):355–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18624876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohshima N, Shirai A, Saito I, Asahina A. Lichen Planus pigmentosus-inversus occurring extensively in multiple intertriginous areas. Journal of Dermatology. 2012;39(4):412–414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22035127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaertner E, Elstein W. Lichen Planus pigmentosus-inversus: case report and review of an unusual entity. Dermatology Online Journal. 2012;18(2):p. 11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22398232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang H, Alzolibani AA, Otberg N, Shapiro J. Lichen planopilaris. Dermatologic Therapy. 2008;21(4):249–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18715294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assouly P, Reygagne P. Lichen planopilaris: update on diagnosis and treatment. Seminars in Cutaneous Medicine and Surgery. 2009;28(1):3–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19341936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehregan DA, Van Hale HM, Muller SA. Lichen planopilaris: clinical and pathologic study of forty-five patients. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1992;27(6, part 1):935–942.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1479098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gunduz K, Sacar T, Inanir I, Demireli P. Flexural follicular Lichen Planus. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2009;34(7):e297–e298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19456791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang YZ, Tosti A, Chaudhry IH, et al.  Lichen planopilaris following hair transplantation and face-lift surgery. British Journal of Dermatology. 2012;166(3):666–670.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21985326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crisóstomo MR, Crisóstomo MGR, Crisóstomo MR, Crisóstomo MCC, Gondim VJT, Benevides AN. Hair loss due to lichen planopilaris after hair transplantation: a report of two cases and a literature review. Anais Brasileiros de Dermatologia. 2011;86(2):359–362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zinkernagel MS, Trüeb RM. Fibrosing alopecia in a pattern distribution: patterned lichen planopilaris or androgenetic alopecia with a lichenoid tissue reaction pattern? Archives of Dermatology. 2000;136(2):205–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10677097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kossard S, Lee M-S, Wilkinson B. Postmenopausal frontal fibrosing alopecia: a frontal variant of lichen planopilaris. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1997;36(1):59–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8996262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pai VV, Kikkeri N, Sori T, Dinesh US. Graham-little piccardi lassueur syndrome: an unusual variant of follicular Lichen Planus. International Journal of Trichology. 2011;3(1):28–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3129120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21769233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davari P, Gorouhi F, Fazel N.  Treatment of lichen planus. In: Maibach H, Gorouhi F, editors. Evidence Based Dermatology. 2nd edition. Shelton, Conn, USA: PMPH-USA; 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sánchez-Pérez J, Buceta LR, Fraga J, García-Díez A. Lichen Planus with lesions on the palms and/or soles: prevalence and clinicopathological study of 36 patients. British Journal of Dermatology. 2000;142(2):310–314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10730766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim MJ, Choi M, Na SY, Lee JH, Cho S. Two cases of palmoplantar Lichen Planus with various clinical features. Journal of Dermatology. 2010;37(11):985–989.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21039788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM, Cambiaghi S, Jorizzo M. Nail Lichen Planus in children: clinical features, response to treatment, and long-term follow-up. Archives of Dermatology. 2001;137(8):1027–1032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11493095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM, Cambiaghi S, Jorizzo M.  Color Atlas of Nails. Berlin, Germany: Springer; 2010. Nail Lichen Planusin; pp. 83–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokozeki H, Niiyama S, Nishioka K. Twenty-nail dystrophy (trachyonychia) caused by Lichen Planus in a patient with gold allergy. The British Journal of Dermatology. 2005;152(5):1087–1089.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15888190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taniguchi S, Kutsuna H, Tani Y, Kawahira K, Hamada T. Twenty-nail dystrophy (trachyonychia) caused by Lichen Planus in a patient with alopecia universalis and ichthyosis vulgaris. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1995;33(5, part 2):903–905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7593807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nnoruka EN. Lichen Planus in African children: a study of 13 patients. Pediatric Dermatology. 2007;24(5):495–498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17958794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richert B, Iorizzo M, Tosti A, André J. Nail bed Lichen Planus associated with onychopapilloma. British Journal of Dermatology. 2007;156(5):1071–1072.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17355232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juhlin L, Baran R. On longitudinal melanonychia after healing of Lichen Planus. Acta Dermato-Venereologica. 1990;70(2):p. 183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1969214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisen D. The evaluation of cutaneous, genital, scalp, nail, esophageal, and ocular involvement in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontics. 1999;88(4):431–436.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10519750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Sousa FA, Rosa LEB. Oral Lichen Planus: clinical and histopathological considerations. Brazilian Journal of Otorhinolaryngology. 2008;74(2):284–292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18568210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorn JJ, Holmstrup P, Rindum J, Pindborg JJ. Course of various clinical forms of oral Lichen Planus. A prospective follow-up study of 611 patients. Journal of Oral Pathology. 1988;17(5):213–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3144584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bricker SL. Oral Lichen Planus: a review. Seminars in Dermatology. 1994;13(2):87–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8060831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mollaoglu N. Oral Lichen Planus: a review. British Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery. 2000;38(4):370–377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10922170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zegarelli DJ. The treatment of oral Lichen Planus. Annals of Dentistry. 1993;52(2):3–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8267377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourenço SV, Resende ACB, Bologna SB, Nico MMS. Lichen Planus sialadenitis: a mucosal analog of lichen planopilaris and lichen planoporitis. Journal of Cutaneous Pathology. 2010;37(3):396–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McPherson T, Cooper S. Vulval lichen sclerosus and Lichen Planus. Dermatologic Therapy. 2010;23(5):523–532.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20868406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schorge J, Schaffer J, Halvorson L.  Williams Gynecology. 1st edition. Philadelphia, Pa, USA: McGraw-Hill; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis FM. Vulval Lichen Planus. British Journal of Dermatology. 1998;138(4):569–575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9640359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper SM, Wojnarowska F. Influence of treatment of erosive Lichen Planus of the vulva on its prognosis. Archives of Dermatology. 2006;142(3):289–294.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16549703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldstein AT, Metz A. Vulvar Lichen Planus. Clinical Obstetrics and Gynecology. 2005;48(4):818–823.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16286828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helgesen ALO, Gjersvik P, Jebsen P, Kirschner R, Tanbo T. Vaginal involvement in genital erosive Lichen Planus. Acta Obstetricia et Gynecologica Scandinavica. 2010;89(7):966–970.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20583940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson RC, Littlewood SM, Cooper SM, et al.  Real-life experience of managing vulval erosive Lichen Planus: a case-based review and U.K. multicentre case note audit. British Journal of Dermatology. 2012;167(1):85–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22384934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belfiore P, Di Fede O, Cabibi D, et al.  Prevalence of vulval Lichen Planus in a cohort of women with oral Lichen Planus: an interdisciplinary study. British Journal of Dermatology. 2006;155(5):994–998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17034531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramer MA, Altchek A, Deligdisch L, Phelps R, Montazem A, Buonocore PM. Lichen Planus and the vulvovaginal-gingival syndrome. Journal of Periodontology. 2003;74(9):1385–1393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14584875</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox LP, Lightdale CJ, Grossman ME. Lichen Planus of the esophagus: what dermatologists need to know. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2011;65(1):175–183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21536343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Izol B, Karabulut AA, Biyikoglu I, Gonultas M, Eksioglu M. Investigation of upper gastrointestinal tract involvement and H. pylori presence in Lichen Planus: a case controlled study with endoscopic and histopathological findings. International Journal of Dermatology. 2010;49(10):1121–1126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20597994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katzka DA, Smyrk TC, Bruce AJ, Romero Y, Alexander JA, Murray JA. Variations in presentations of esophageal involvement in Lichen Planus. Clinical Gastroenterology and Hepatology. 2010;8(9):777–782.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20471494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Şanli B, Çetin EN, Bir F, Taşli L, Yaldizkaya F, Yaylali V. Conjunctival impression cytology, ocular surface and tear-film changes in patients with Lichen Planus. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rhee MK, Mootha VV. Bilateral Keratoconjunctivitis Associated with Lichen Planus. Cornea. 2004;23(1):100–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14701968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webber NK, Setterfield JF, Lewis FM, Neill SM. Lacrimal canalicular duct scarring in patients with Lichen Planus. Archives of Dermatology. 2012;148(2):224–227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22351823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma R, Singhal N. Lichen Planus of the eyelids. A report of 5 cases. Dermatology Online Journal. 2001;7(1):p. 5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11328626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verma SB. Lichen Planus affecting eyelid alone: a rare entity. Indian Journal of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprology. 2006;72(5):p. 398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17050949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crosby MB, Crosby CV, Wojno TH, Grossniklaus HE. Conjunctival Lichen Planus in a patient with herpes simplex virus keratitis. Cornea. 2009;28(8):936–937.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2993155</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos-Esteban JC, Schoenfield L, Singh AD. Conjunctival Lichen Planus simulating ocular surface squamous neoplasia. Cornea. 2009;28(10):1181–1183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19770715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz ER, Martínez-Escala ME, Juanpere N, Armentia J, Pujol RM, Herrero-González JE. Isolated conjunctival Lichen Planus: a diagnostic challenge. Archives of Dermatology. 2011;147(4):465–467.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21482896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pakravan M, Klesert TR, Akpek EK. Isolated Lichen Planus of the conjunctiva. British Journal of Ophthalmology. 2006;90(10):1325–1326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1857434</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16980648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehta M, Siddique SS, Gonzalez-Gonzalez LA, Foster CS. Immunohistochemical differences between normal and chronically inflamed conjunctiva: diagnostic features. American Journal of Dermatopathology. 2011;33(8):786–789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21785328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorne JE, Jabs DA, Nikolskaia OV, Mimouni D, Anhalt GJ, Nousari HC. Lichen Planus and cicatrizing conjunctivitis: characterization of five cases. American Journal of Ophthalmology. 2003;136(2):239–243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12888044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewer JD, Ekdawi NS, Torgerson RR, et al.  Lichen Planus and cicatricial conjunctivitis: disease course and response to therapy of 11 patients. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2011;25(1):100–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20477930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rennie CE, Dwivedi RC, Khan AS, Agrawal N, Ziyada W. Lichen Planus of the larynx. Journal of Laryngology and Otology. 2011;125(4):432–435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21272411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaikh ZI, Arfan-ul-Bari A, Mashhood AA, Qayyum A, Latif-ur-Rahman L. Mucosal Lichen Planus simultaneously involving oral mucosa, conjunctiva and larynx. Journal of the College of Physicians and Surgeons Pakistan. 2010;20(7):478–479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20642951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kunelskaya Ya. V, Arievich AM. Affection of the laryngeal mucosa in lichen ruber planus striatus. Vestnik Oto-Rino-Laringologii. 1978;40(5):32–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">706073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busm KJ.  Dermatopathology: A Volume in the Foundations in Diagnostic Pathology Series, Expert Consult-Online and Print. 1st edition. New York, NY, USA: Saunders; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laskaris G, Sklavounou A, Angelopoulos A. Direct immunofluorescence in oral Lichen Planus. Oral Surgery Oral Medicine and Oral Pathology. 1982;53(5):483–487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7048185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elder DE, Elenitsas R, Johnson BL, Murphy GF, Xu X.  Lever's Histopathology of the Skin. 10th edition. Philadelphia, Pa, USA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gougerot H, Civatte A. Clinical and histologic criteria of cutaneous and mucosal Lichen Planus; delimitation. Annales de Dermatologie et de Syphiligraphie. 1953;80(1):5–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13051009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis FA. Histopathology of Lichen Planus based on analysis of one hundred biopsy specimens. Journal of Investigative Dermatology. 1967;48(2):143–148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6020677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragaz A, Ackerman AB. Evolution, maturation, and regression of lesions of Lichen Planus. New observations and correlations of clinical and histologic findings. American Journal of Dermatopathology. 1981;3(1):5–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7235199</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moscarella E, González S, Agozzino M, et al.  Pilot study on reflectance confocal microscopy imaging of Lichen Planus: a real-time, non-invasive aid for clinical diagnosis. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2012;26(10):1258–1265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21958425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mobini N, Tam S, Kamino H. Possible role of the bulge region in the pathogenesis of inflammatory scarring alopecia: Lichen planopilaris as the prototype. Journal of Cutaneous Pathology. 2005;32(10):675–679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16293179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shklar G. Erosive and bullous oral lesions of Lichen Planus: histologic studies. Archives of Dermatology. 1968;97(4):411–416.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5643235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lage D, Juliano PB, Metze K, Souza EMD, Cintra ML. Lichen Planus and lichenoid drug-induced eruption: a histological and immunohistochemical study. International Journal of Dermatology. 2012;51(10):1199–1205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22416968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halevy S, Shai A. Lichenoid drug eruptions. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1993;29(2, part 1):249–255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8335745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yiannias JA, El-Azhary RA, Hand JH, Pakzad SY, Rogers RS., III Relevant contact sensitivities in patients with the diagnosis of oral Lichen Planus. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2000;42(2, part 1):177–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10642670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Athavale PN, Shum KW, Yeoman CM, Gawkrodger DJ. Oral lichenoid lesions and contact allergy to dental mercury and gold. Contact Dermatitis. 2003;49(5):264–265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14996055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lartitegui-Sebastian MJ, Martínez-Revilla B, Saiz-Garcia C, Eguizabal-Saracho S, Aguirre-Urizar JM. Oral lichenoid lesions associated with amalgam restorations: a prospective pilot study addressing the adult population of the Basque Country. Medicina Oral, Patologia Oral, Cirugia Bucal. 2012;17(4):e545–e549.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3476013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22322507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers RS, III, Bruce AJ. Lichenoid contact stomatitis: is inorganic mercury the culprit? Archives of Dermatology. 2004;140(12):1524–1525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen CM, Blozis GG. Oral mucosal reactions to cinnamon-flavored chewing gum. The Journal of the American Dental Association. 1988;116(6):664–667.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3164031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gunatheesan S, Tam MM, Tate B, Tversky J, Nixon R. Retrospective study of oral Lichen Planus and allergy to spearmint oil. Australasian Journal of Dermatology. 2012;53(3):224–228.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22686635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guitart J, Peduto M, Caro WA, Roenigk HH. Lichenoid changes in mycosis fungoides. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1997;36(3, part 1):417–422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9091473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vega ME, Waxtein L, Arenas R, Hojyo MT, Dominguez-Soto L. Ashy dermatosis and Lichen Planus pigmentosus: a clinicopathologic study of 31 cases. International Journal of Dermatology. 1992;31(2):90–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1559749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White GM, Cox NH.  Diseases of the Skin. A Color Atlas and Text. 2nd edition. New York, NY, USA: Mosby; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waldorf DS. Lichen planopilaris. Histopathologic study of disease. Progression to scarring alopedia. Archives of Dermatology. 1966;93(6):684–691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5932155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grant-Kels JM.  Color Atlas of Dermatopathology (Dermatology: Clinical &amp; Basic Science) 1st edition. San Francisco, NC, USA: Informa Healthcare; 2007. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estrada BD, Tamler C, Sodré CT, Barcaui CB, Pereira FBC. Dermoscopy patterns of cicatricial alopecia resulting from discoid lupus erythematosus and lichen planopilaris. Anais Brasileiros de Dermatologia. 2010;85(2):179–183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20520933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gawkrodger DJ, Stavropoulos PG, McLaren KM, Buxton PK. Bullous Lichen Planus and Lichen Planus pemphigoides—clinico-pathological comparisons. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 1989;14(2):150–153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2598489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bope ET, Kellerman RD, Bope RRE.  Conn'S Current Therapy 2011. Philadelphia, Pa, USA: Elsevier Saunders; 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ichimura M, Hiratsuka K, Ogura N, et al.  Expression profile of chemokines and chemokine receptors in epithelial cell layers of oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 2006;35(3):167–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16454813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iijima W, Ohtani H, Nakayama T, et al.  Infiltrating CD8+ T cells in oral Lichen Planus predominantly express CCR5 and CXCR3 and carry respective chemokine ligands RANTES/CCL5 and IP-10/CXCL10 in their cytolytic granules: a potential self-recruiting mechanism. American Journal of Pathology. 2003;163(1):261–268.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1868180</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12819030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spandau U, Toksoy A, Goebeler M, Bröcker E, Gillitzer R. MIG is a dominant lymphocyte-attractant chemokine in Lichen Planus lesions. Journal of Investigative Dermatology. 1998;111(6):1003–1009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9856808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janardhanam SB, Prakasam S, Swaminathan VT, Kodumudi KN, Zunt SL, Srinivasan M. Differential expression of TLR-2 and TLR-4 in the epithelial cells in oral Lichen Planus. Archives of Oral Biology. 2012;57(5):495–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22119043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siponen M, Kauppila JH, Soini Y, Salo T. TLR4 and TLR9 are induced in oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology &amp; Medicine. 2012;41(10):741–747.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22672741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carbone T, Nasorri F, Pennino D, et al.  CD56highCD16- NK cell involvement in cutaneous Lichen Planus. European Journal of Dermatology. 2010;20(6):724–730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20959273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lei L, Tan WX, Zhou XL, Zheng PE. Expression of Fas and Fas ligand in infiltrating lymphocytes in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Zhonghua Kou Qiang Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2010;45(4):219–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20654197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadzi-Mihailovic M, Raybaud H, Monteil R, Jankovic L. Expression of Fas/FasL in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of B.U.ON. 2009;14(3):487–493.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19810143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santoro A, Majorana A, Bardellini E, et al.  Cytotoxic molecule expression and epithelial cell apoptosis in oral and cutaneous Lichen Planus. American Journal of Clinical Pathology. 2004;121(5):758–764.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15151217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brant JMC, Vasconcelos AC, Rodrigues LV. Role of apoptosis in erosive and reticular oral Lichen Planus exhibiting variable epithelial thickness. Brazilian Dental Journal. 2008;19(3):179–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18949287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pandey A, Setty S, Rao R, Radhakrishnan R. Assessment of Langerhans cells in oral Lichen Planus by ATPase histochemistry: a clinicopathologic correlation. Quintessence International. 2011;42(3):225–234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21465009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermejo-Fenoll A, López-Jornet P. Familial oral Lichen Planus: presentation of six families. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontology. 2006;102(2):e12–e15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16876038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singal A. Familial mucosal Lichen Planus in three successive generations. International Journal of Dermatology. 2005;44(1):81–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girardi C, Luz C, Cherubini K, Figueiredo MAZD, Nunes MLT, Salum FG. Salivary cortisol and dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA) levels, psychological factors in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Archives of Oral Biology. 2011;56(9):864–868.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manolache L, Seceleanu-Petrescu D, Benea V. Lichen Planus patients and stressful events. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2008;22(4):437–441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18363912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohamadi Hasel K, Besharat MA, Abdolhoseini A, Alaei Nasab S, Niknam S. Relationships of personality factors to perceived stress, depression, and oral Lichen Planus severity. International Journal of Behavioral Medicine. 2012:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22311191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Pola Vallejo MJ, Huerta G, Cerero R, Seoane JM. Anxiety and depression as risk factors for oral Lichen Planus. Dermatology. 2001;203(4):303–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11752817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S, Yao S, Wei W, Tian W, Zhang H, Wang B. Hepatitis C virus and Lichen Planus: a reciprocal association determined by a meta-analysis. Archives of Dermatology. 2009;145(9):1040–1047.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19770446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lodi G, Giuliani M, Majorana A, et al.  Lichen Planus and hepatitis C virus: a multicentre study of patients with oral lesions and a systematic review. British Journal of Dermatology. 2004;151(6):1172–1181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15606512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lodi G, Pellicano R, Carrozzo M. Hepatitis C virus infection and Lichen Planus: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Oral Diseases. 2010;16(7):601–612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20412447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin L, Lu S, Lu S. Seroprevalence of anti-HCV among patients with oral Lichen Planus in Southern Taiwan. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontology. 2010;109(3):408–414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20097108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Y, Jiang L, Liu J, Zeng X, Chen Q. The prevalence of hepatitis C virus infection in oral Lichen Planus in an ethnic Chinese cohort of 232 patients. International Journal of Oral Science. 2010;2(2):90–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20737935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halawani M, Balbisi A, Alotaibi H, Alsaif F, Bakir TM. The prevalence of HCV antibodies in skin disease patients in Saudi Arabia. Saudi Pharmaceutical Journal. 2010;18(1):35–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3730984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23960718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubsam K, Schroll A, Weisenseel P, Multhaup S, Ruzicka T, Prinz JC. Lichen Planus and hepatitis virus infections: causal association? Journal der Deutschen Dermatologischen Gesellschaft. 2011;9(6):464–468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birkenfeld S, Dreiher J, Weitzman D, Cohen AD. A study on the association with hepatitis B and hepatitis C in 1557 patients with Lichen Planus. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2011;25(4):436–440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666875</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syrjänen S, Lodi G, von Bültzingslöwen I, et al.  Human papillomaviruses in oral carcinoma and oral potentially malignant disorders: a systematic review. Oral Diseases. 2011;17(supplement 1):58–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorsky M, Epstein JB. Oral Lichen Planus: malignant transformation and human papilloma virus: a review of potential clinical implications. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontology. 2011;111(4):461–464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21330164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigurgeirsson B, Lindelof B. Lichen Planus and malignancy: an epidemiologic study of 2071 patients and a review of the literature. Archives of Dermatology. 1991;127(11):1684–1688.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1952973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai J, Lin M, Zeng X, et al.  Association of polymorphisms in the human IFN-γ and IL-4 gene with oral Lichen Planus: a study in an ethnic Chinese cohort. Journal of Interferon and Cytokine Research. 2008;28(6):351–358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18593330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimkong I, Nakkuntod J, Sodsai P, Hirankarn N, Kitkumthorn N. Association of interferon-gamma gene polymorphisms with susceptibility to oral Lichen Planus in the Thai population. Archives of Oral Biology. 2012;57(5):491–494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22041017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimkong I, Hirankarn N, Nakkuntod J, Kitkumthorn N. Tumour necrosis factor-alpha gene polymorphisms and susceptibility to oral Lichen Planus. Oral Diseases. 2011;17(2):206–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20796230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xavier GM, Sá ARD, Guimarães ALS, Silva TAD, Gomez RS. Investigation of functional gene polymorphisms interleukin-1β, interleukin-6, interleukin-10 and tumor necrosis factor in individuals with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 2007;36(8):476–481.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17686006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujita H, Kobayashi T, Tai H, et al.  Assessment of 14 functional gene polymorphisms in Japanese patients with oral Lichen Planus: a pilot case-control study. International Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery. 2009;38(9):978–983.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19497711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai J, Jiang L, Lin M, Zeng X, Wang Z, Chen Q. Association of polymorphisms in the tumor necrosis factor-α and interleukin-10 genes with oral Lichen Planus: a study in a Chinese cohort with Han ethnicity. Journal of Interferon and Cytokine Research. 2009;29(7):381–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19450147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai J, Zhang Y, Lin M, et al.  Interleukin-18 gene polymorphisms and haplotypes in patients with oral Lichen Planus: a study in an ethnic Chinese cohort. Tissue Antigens. 2007;70(5):390–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17854431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanatatsaneeji P, Kitkumthorn N, Dhammawipark C, Rabalert J, Patel V, Mutirangura A. Codon72 polymorphism in the p53 tumor suppressor gene in oral Lichen Planus lesions in a Thai population. Asian Pacific Journal of Cancer Prevention. 2010;11(4):1137–1141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21133638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schifter M, Jones AM, Walker DM. Epithelial p53 gene expression and mutational analysis, combined with growth fraction assessment, in oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 1998;27(7):318–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9725569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veien NK, Risum G, Jorgensen HP, Svejgaard A. HLA antigens in patients with Lichen Planus. Acta Dermato-Venereologica. 1979;59(3):205–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">87076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lowe NJ, Cudworth AG, Woodrow JC. HL A antigens in Lichen Planus. British Journal of Dermatology. 1976;95(2):169–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">952753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Copeman PWM, Tan RSH, Timlin D, Samman PD. Familial Lichen Planus. Another disease or a distinct people? British Journal of Dermatology. 1978;98(5):573–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">656330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potts EDA, Rowell NR. Lichen Planus: a distinct entity from lupus erythematosus. Acta Dermato-Venereologica. 1981;61(5):413–416.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6172929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ognjenovic M, Karelović D, Mikelić M, Tadin I, Vrebalov-Cindro V. Oral Lichen Planus and HLA B. Coll Antropol. 1998;22:93–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9951147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porter K, Klouda P, Scully C, Bidwell J, Porter SR. Class I and II HLA antigens in British patients with oral Lichen Planus. Oral Surgery Oral Medicine and Oral Pathology. 1993;75(2):176–180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8426716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe T, Ohishi M, Tanaka K, Sato H. Analysis of HLA antigens in Japanese with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology. 1986;15(10):529–533.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3104559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powell FC, Rogers RS, Dickson ER, Breanndan Moore S. An association between HLA DR1 and Lichen Planus. British Journal of Dermatology. 1986;114(4):473–478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3485991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valsecchi R, Bontempelli M, Bellavita PM, et al.  HLA-DR1 and lichen ruber planus. Giornale Italiano di Dermatologia e Venereologia. 1987;122(6):277–280.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3497868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carcassi C, Cottoni F, Floris L, et al.  The HLA-DRB1(∗)0101 allele is responsible for HLA susceptibility to lichen ruber planus. European Journal of Immunogenetics. 1994;21(6):425–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9098452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White AG, Rostom AI. HLA antigens in Arabs with Lichen Planus. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 1994;19(3):236–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8033385</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>La Nasa G, Cottoni F, Mulargia M, et al.  HLA antigen distribution in different clinical subgroups demonstrates genetic heterogeneity in Lichen Planus. British Journal of Dermatology. 1995;132(6):897–900.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7662567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valsecchi R, Bontempelli M, Rossi A, et al.  HLA-DR and DQ antigens in Lichen Planus. Acta Dermato-Venereologica. 1988;68(1):77–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2449017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luis-Montoya P, Yamamoto-Furusho JK, Vega-Memije E, et al.  HLA-DRB1∗0101 is associated with the genetic susceptibility to develop Lichen Planus in the Mexican Mestizo population. Archives of Dermatological Research. 2007;299(8):405–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17665209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roitberg-Tambur A, Friedmann A, Korn S, et al.  Serologic and molecular analysis of the HLA system in Israeli Jewish patients with oral erosive Lichen Planus. Tissue Antigens. 1994;43(4):219–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8085257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jontell M, Ståhlblad PA, Rosdahl I, Lindblom B. HLA-DR3 antigens in erosive oral Lichen Planus, cutaneous Lichen Planus, and lichenoid reactions. Acta Odontologica Scandinavica. 1987;45(5):309–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3499742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin S-C, Sun A. HLA-DR and DQ antigens in Chinese patients with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 1990;19(7):298–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1700115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setterfield JF, Neill S, Shirlaw PJ, et al.  The vulvovaginal gingival syndrome: a severe subgroup of Lichen Planus with characteristic clinical features and a novel association with the class II HLA DQB1∗0201 allele. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2006;55(1):98–113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16781300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun A, Wu YC, Wang JT, Liu BY, Chiang CP. Association of HLA-te22 antigen with anti-nuclear antibodies in Chinese patients with erosive oral Lichen Planus. Proceedings of the National Science Council, Republic of China B. 2000;24(2):63–69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10809082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Z, Yao H, Cui B, Ning G, Tang GY. Genetic linkage analysis of oral Lichen Planus in a Chinese family. Genetics and Molecular Research. 2011;10(3):1427–1433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21823092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sezer E, Ozugurlu F, Ozyurt H, Sahin S, Etikan I. Lipid peroxidation and antioxidant status in Lichen Planus. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2007;32(4):430–434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17459065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scrobotǎ I, Mocan T, Cǎtoi C, Bolfǎ P, Mureşan A, Bǎciuţ G. Histopathological aspects and local implications of oxidative stress in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Romanian Journal of Morphology and Embryology. 2011;52(4):1305–1309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22203938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sapuntsova SG, Lebed’ko OA, Shchetkina MV, Fleyshman MY, Kozulin EA, Timoshin SS. Status of free-radical oxidation and proliferation processes in patients with atopic dermatitis and Lichen Planus. Bulletin of Experimental Biology and Medicine. 2011;150(6):690–692.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22235418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Upadhyay RB, Carnelio S, Shenoy RP, Gyawali P, Mukherjee M. Oxidative stress and antioxidant defense in oral Lichen Planus and oral lichenoid reaction. Scandinavian Journal of Clinical and Laboratory Investigation. 2010;70(4):225–228.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20233035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel Hay RM, Fawzy MM, Metwally D, et al.  DNA polymorphisms and tissue cyclooxygenase-2 expression in oral Lichen Planus: a case-control study. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2012;26(9):1122–1126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21923838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Compilato D, Paderni C, Di Fede O, Gulotta G, Campisi G. Association of oral Lichen Planus with thyroid disease in a Finnish population: a retrospective case-control study:, ‘A different finding from a Mediterranean area’. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontology. 2011;111(1):12–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21176818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang JY, Chiang C, Hsiao CK, Sun A. Significantly higher frequencies of presence of serum autoantibodies in Chinese patients with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 2009;38(1):48–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18764857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H, Wang Y, Chia J, Sun A. Modulation of serum anti-thyroglobulin and anti-thyroid microsomal autoantibody levels by levamisole in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of the Formosan Medical Association. 2011;110(3):169–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21497280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wankiewicz A, Iwan-Ziȩtek I, Rość D. Chosen blood coagulation parameters in patients with Lichen Planus. Polski Merkuriusz Lekarski. 2004;16(97):55–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15559612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fonseca-Silva T, De Oliveira MVM, Fraga CADC, et al.  DNMT3B (C46359T) polymorphisms and immunoexpression of DNMT3b and DNMT1 proteins in oral Lichen Planus. Pathobiology. 2012;79(1):18–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22236544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arão TC, Guimarães ALS, de Paula AMB, Gomes CC, Gomez RS. Increased miRNA-146a and miRNA-155 expressions in oral Lichen Planus. Archives of Dermatological Research. 2011:1–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22139425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terlou A, Santegoets LAM, Van Der Meijden WI, et al.  An autoimmune phenotype in vulvar lichen sclerosus and Lichen Planus: a Th1 response and high levels of microRNA-155. Journal of Investigative Dermatology. 2012;132(3):658–666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22113482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou G, Xia K, Du G, et al.  Activation of nuclear factor-kappa B correlates with tumor necrosis factor-alpha in oral Lichen Planus: a clinicopathologic study in atrophic-erosive and reticular form. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 2009;38(7):559–564.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19453840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Inigo E, Arrieta JJ, Casqueiro M, et al.  TT virus detection in oral Lichen Planus lesions. Journal of Medical Virology. 2001;64(2):183–189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11360251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fehér E, Gáll T, Murvai M, et al.  Investigation of the occurrence of torque tenovirus in malignant and potentially malignant disorders associated with human papillomavirus. Journal of Medical Virology. 2009;81(11):1975–1981.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19774682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bez C, Hallett R, Carrozzo M, et al.  Lack of association between hepatotropic transfusion transmitted virus infection and oral Lichen Planus in British and Italian populations. British Journal of Dermatology. 2001;145(6):990–993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11899155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishizawa T, Okamoto H, Konishi K, Yoshizawa H, Miyakawa Y, Mayumi M. A novel DNA virus (TTV) associated with elevated transaminase levels in posttransfusion hepatitis of unknown etiology. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications. 1997;241(1):92–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9405239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fehér E, Kardos G, Gáll T, Kis A, Gergely L, Szarka K. Comparison of diversity of torque teno virus 1 in different mucosal tissues and disorders. Acta Microbiologica et Immunologica Hungarica. 2011;58(4):319–337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22207290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghodratnama F, Riggio MP, Wray D. Search for human herpesvirus 6, human cytomegalovirus and varicella zoster virus DNA in recurrent aphthous stomatitis tissue. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 1997;26(4):192–197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9176795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghodratnama F, Wray D, Bagg J. Detection of serum antibodies against cytomegalovirus, varicella zoster virus and human herpesvirus 6 in patients with recurrent aphthous stomatitis. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 1999;28(1):12–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9890451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun RP, Barua D, Masouye I. Zosteriform Lichen Planus after herpes zoster. Dermatology. 1998;197(1):87–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9711434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arias-Santiago S, Buenda-Eisman A, Aneiros-Fernndez J, et al.  Cardiovascular risk factors in patients with Lichen Planus. American Journal of Medicine. 2011;124(6):543–548.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21605731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Touraine R, Revuz J, Dreyfus B, Rochant H, Mannoni P. Graft versus host reaction and Lichen Planus. British Journal of Dermatology. 1975;92(5):p. 589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">240375</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saurat JH, Didier-Jean L, Gluckman E, Bussel A. Graft versus host reaction and Lichen Planus-like eruption in man. British Journal of Dermatology. 1975;92(5):591–592.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">240376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saurat JH. Lichen Planus and graft versus host disease. Giornale Italiano di Dermatologia e Venereologia. 1982;117(6):369–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7187427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Study of Lichen Planus conducted by the IGESD: results, implications for clinical practice, prospects. Italian Group of Epidemiological Studies in Dermatology (IGESD) Giornale Italiano di Dermatologia e Venereologia. 1990;125(12):563–567.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2091979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cainelli T. Epidemiological evidence of the association between Lichen Planus and two immune-related diseases. Alopecia areata and ulcerative colitis. Archives of Dermatology. 1991;127(5):688–691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2024987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee CW, Hur H, Youn JI. Pemphigus vulgaris coexisting with generalized Lichen Planus. Journal of Dermatology. 1987;14(4):388–391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3320133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens SR, Griffiths CEM, Anhalt GJ, Cooper KD. Paraneoplastic pemphigus presenting as a Lichen Planus pemphigoides-like eruption. Archives of Dermatology. 1993;129(7):866–869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8323308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pratt AG. Dermatitis herpetiformis followed by lesions resembling Lichen Planus. Archives of Dermatology and Syphilology. 1946;53:p. 664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20987165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bologa EI, Vaida F. Lichen ruber planus in regression with following Duhring’s dermatitis herpetiformis. Dermatologische Monatsschrift. 1971;157(6):447–452.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5110694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stingl G, Holubar K. Coexistence of Lichen Planus and bullous pemphigoid. An immunopathological study. British Journal of Dermatology. 1975;93(3):313–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1103935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rekant SI. Lichen Planus and bullous pemphigoid. Archives of Dermatology. 1976;112(11):p. 1613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">791154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins NJ, Dowling JP. Lichen Planus and bullous pemphigoid. Australasian Journal of Dermatology. 1982;23(1):9–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6751311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohshima N, Shirai A, Asahina A. Coexistence of linear Lichen Planus and psoriasis in a single patient. Journal of Dermatology. 2011;38(12):1182–1184.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21453315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gül U, Soylu S, Demiriz M. Colocalization of Lichen Planus and vitiligo associated with selective IgA deficiency. Skinmed. 2007;6(4):202–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17618176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ujiie H, Sawamura D, Shimizu H. Development of Lichen Planus and psoriasis on lesions of vitiligo vulgaris. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2006;31(3):375–377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16681580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sardana K, Sharma RC, Koranne RV, Mahajan S. An interesting case of colocalization of segmental Lichen Planus and vitiligo in a 14-year-old boy. International Journal of Dermatology. 2002;41(8):508–509.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12207769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melato M, Gorji N, Rizzardi C, Maglione M. Associated localization of morphea and Lichen Planus of the lip in a patient with vitiligo. Minerva Stomatologica. 2000;49(11-12):549–554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11345685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawamura D, Yaguchi T, Hashimoto I, Nomura K, Konta R, Umeki K. Coexistence of generalized morphea with histological changes in lichen sclerosus et atrophicus and Lichen Planus. Journal of Dermatology. 1998;25(6):409–411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9675351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connelly MG, Winkelmann r. K. Coexistence of lichen sclerosus, morphea, and Lichen Planus: report of four cases and review of the literature. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1985;12(5, part 1):844–851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4008688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner W, Diem E, Gschnait F. Coincidence of vitiligo, alopecia areata, onychodystrophy, localized scleroderma and Lichen Planus. Dermatologica. 1979;159(4):356–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">478074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Najjar A, Reilly GD, Harrington CI. Dermatomyositis and Lichen Planus—an association or manifestation? Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 1985;10(2):174–178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3978866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmes SC, Burden AD. Lichen sclerosus and Lichen Planus: a spectrum of disease? Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 1998;23(3):129–131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9861744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bazex A, Salvador R, Dupre A, Parant M, Christol B. Lichen sclerosus et atrophicus and Lichen Planus sclerosus. Bulletin de la Société française de dermatologie et de syphiligraphie. 1963;70:450–451.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14079091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham-Brown RAC, Sarkany I. Lichen sclerosus et atrophicus: with primary biliary cirrhosis and Lichen Planus. International Journal of Dermatology. 1986;25(5):p. 317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3721668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lichen Planus and liver diseases: a multicentre case-control study. Gruppo Italiano Studi Epidemiologici in Dermatologia (GISED) British Medical Journal. 1990;300(6719):227–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1662065</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2106930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham-Brown RAC, Sarkany I, Sherlock S. Lichen Planus and primary biliary cirrhosis. British Journal of Dermatology. 1982;106(6):699–703.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7082575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powell FC, Rogers RS, III, Dickson ER. Primary biliary cirrhosis and Lichen Planus. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 1983;9(4):540–545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6355216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu C-Y, Yang C-Y, Huang S-F, Lu S-C, Wang L-F. Lichen Planus with xanthomatous change in a patient with primary biliary cirrhosis. British Journal of Dermatology. 2000;142(2):377–378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10730783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong DC, Ferguson MM. Concurrent oral Lichen Planus and primary sclerosing cholangitis. British Journal of Dermatology. 2002;147(2):356–358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12174112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rebora A. Hcv and Lichen Planus. Hepatitis Monthly. 2011;11(2):134–135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3206664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22087134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sand LP, Jalouli J, Larsson P, Hirsch J. Prevalence of Epstein-Barr virus in oral squamous cell carcinoma, oral Lichen Planus, and normal oral mucosa. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontics. 2002;93(5):586–592.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12075209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen A. Abnormal EBV immune status in oral Lichen Planus. Oral Diseases. 1996;2(2):125–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8957924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ÓFlatharta C, Flint SR, Toner M, Butler D, Mabruk MJEMF. Investigation into a possible association between oral Lichen Planus, the human herpesviruses, and the human papillomaviruses. Molecular Diagnosis. 2003;7(2):73–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14580227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Razavi SM, Ghalayani P, Salehi MR, Attarzadeh H, Shahmoradi M. Human papilloma virus as a possible factor in the pathogenesis of oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Dental Research. 2009;6(2):82–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075460</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21528036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khovidhunkit SP, Buajeeb W, Sanguansin S, Poomsawat S, Weerapradist W. Detection of human papillomavirus in oral squamous cell carcinoma, leukoplakia and Lichen Planus in Thai patients. Asian Pacific Journal of Cancer Prevention. 2008;9(4):771–775.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19256774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vries HJC, Teunissen MBM, Zorgdrager F, Picavet D, Cornelissen M. Lichen Planus remission is associated with a decrease of human herpes virus type 7 protein expression in plasmacytoid dendritic cells. Archives of Dermatological Research. 2007;299(4):213–219.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1914293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17404748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vries HJC, Van Marle J, Teunissen MBM, et al.  Lichen Planus is associated with human herpesvirus type 7 replication and infiltration of plasmacytoid dendritic cells. British Journal of Dermatology. 2006;154(2):361–364.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16433811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vainio E, Huovinen S, Liutu M, Uksila J, Leino R. Peptic ulcer and Helicobacter pylori in patients with Lichen Planus. Acta Dermato-Venereologica. 2000;80(6):427–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11243636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dauden E, Vázquez-Carrasco MA, Peñas PF, Pajares JM, García-Díez A. Association of Helicobacter pylori infection with psoriasis and Lichen Planus: prevalence and effect of eradication therapy. Archives of Dermatology. 2000;136(10):1275–1276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11030788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attia EAS, Abdel Fattah NSA, Abdella HM. Upper gastrointestinal findings and detection of Helicobacter pylori in patients with oral Lichen Planus: clinical dermatology • Original article. Clinical and Experimental Dermatology. 2010;35(4):355–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19663844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreiher J, Shapiro J, Cohen AD. Lichen Planus and dyslipidaemia: a case-control study. British Journal of Dermatology. 2009;161(3):626–629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19438850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arias-Santiago S, Buendía-Eisman A, Aneiros-Fernández J. Lipid levels in patients with Lichen Planus: a case-control study. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2011;25(12):1398–1401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21348899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camisa C, Allen CM, Bowen B, Olsen RG. Indirect immunofluorescence of oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology. 1986;15(4):218–220.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3088237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaudhary S. Psychosocial stressors in oral Lichen Planus. Australian Dental Journal. 2004;49(4):192–195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15762340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colella G, Gritti P, De Luca F, de Vito M. The psychopathological aspects of oral Lichen Planus (OLP) Minerva Stomatologica. 1993;42(6):265–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8232133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koray M, Dülger O, Ak G, et al.  The evaluation of anxiety and salivary cortisol levels in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Oral Diseases. 2003;9(6):298–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14629330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundqvist EN, Wahlin YB, Bergdahl M, Bergdahl J. Psychological health in patients with genital and oral erosive Lichen Planus. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2006;20(6):661–666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16836492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCartan BE. Psychological factors associated with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of oral Pathology &amp; Medicine. 1995;24(6):273–275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7562664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pokupec JSG, Gruden V, Gruden V., Jr. Lichen ruber planus as a psychiatric problem. Psychiatria Danubina. 2009;21(4):514–516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19935485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojo-Moreno JL, Bagán JV, Rojo-Moreno J, Donat JS, Milián MA, Jiménez Y. Psychologic factors and oral Lichen Planus: a psychometric evaluation of 100 cases. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontics. 1998;86(6):687–691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9868726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah B, Ashok L, Sujatha GP. Evaluation of salivary cortisol and psychological factors in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Indian Journal of Dental Research. 2009;20(3):288–292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19884710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soto Araya M, Rojas Alcayaga G, Esguep A. Association between psychological disorders and the presence of Oral Lichen Planus, Burning mouth syndrome and Recurrent aphthous Stomatitis. Medicina Oral. 2004;9(1):1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14704611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu XH, He XD, Wu SH, Xia H. Study of association between oral Lichen Planus and depression in female patients. Shanghai Kou Qiang Yi Xue. 2011;20(5):548–552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22109378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macleod RI. Psychological factors in oral Lichen Planus. British Dental Journal. 1992;173(3):p. 88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1503848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akay A, Pekcanlar A, Bozdag KE, Altintas L, Karaman A. Assessment of depression in subjects with psoriasis vulgaris and Lichen Planus. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2002;16(4):347–352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12224690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiappelli F, Kung MA, Nguyen P, Villanueva P, Arash Farhadian E, Eversole LR. Cellular immune correlates of clinical severity in oral Lichen Planus: preliminary association with mood states. Oral Diseases. 1997;3(2):64–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9467344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ivanovski K, Nakova M, Warburton G, et al.  Psychological profile in oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Clinical Periodontology. 2005;32(10):1034–1040.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16174265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puchalski Z. Psychosomatic aspects in patients with alopecia areata, rosacea and lichen ruber planus. Zeitschrift fur Hautkrankheiten. 1983;58(22):1648–1654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6229098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De D, Kanwar A. Eruptive Lichen Planus in a child with celiac disease. Indian Journal of Dermatology, Venereology and Leprology. 2008;74(2):164–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fortune F, Buchanan JAG. Oral Lichen Planus and coeliac disease. The Lancet. 1993;341(8853):1154–1155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8097838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scully C, Porter SR, Eveson JW. Oral Lichen Planus and coeliac disease. The Lancet. 1993;341(8861):p. 1660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8100018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Compilato D, Carroccio A, Campisi G. Hidden coeliac disease in patients suffering from oral Lichen Planus. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2012;26(3):390–391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22129230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeda J, Kohriyama T, Maruyama H, Tanaka T, Nakamura S. A patient of myasthenia gravis complicated by Lichen Planus 9 years after thymectomy. Clinical Neurology. 1999;39(6):625–628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10502986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mineo TC, Biancari F, D’Andrea V. Myasthenia gravis, psychiatric disturbances, idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura, and Lichen Planus associated with cervical thymoma. Journal of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery. 1996;111(2):486–487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8583825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghigliotti G, Nigro A, Gambini C, Burroni A, De Marchi R. Lichen Planus and thymoma. A case report. Annales de Dermatologie et de Venereologie. 1995;122(10):692–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8687056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aronson IK, Soltani K, Paik KI, Rubenstein D, Lorincz AL. Triad of Lichen Planus, myasthenia gravis, and thymoma. Archives of Dermatology. 1978;114(2):255–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">629553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller TN. Myasthenia gravis, ulcerative colitis and Lichen Planus. Proceedings of the Royal Society of Medicine. 1971;64(8):807–808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1811999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4328085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiao J, Zhou G, Ding Y, Zhu D, Fang H. Multiple paraneoplastic syndromes: myasthenia gravis, vitiligo, alopecia areata, and oral Lichen Planus associated with thymoma. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 2011;308(1-2):177–179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21689830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanchard M, Méneret A, Moguelet P, et al.  Oral erosive Lichen Planus associated with Good syndrome. Revue de Medecine Interne. 2010;31(7):498–501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20494493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inalöz HS, Chowdhury MMU, Motley RJ. Lupus erythematosus/Lichen Planus overlap syndrome with scarring alopecia. Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. 2001;15(2):171–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11495530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim H, Pomeranz MK. Lupus erythematosus and Lichen Planus overlap syndrome. Journal of Drugs in Dermatology. 2004;3(3):311–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15176168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagao K, Chen K. A case of lupus erythematosus/Lichen Planus overlap syndrome. Journal of Dermatology. 2006;33(3):187–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16620224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi T, Hatamochi A, Kamada N, Matsue H, Shinkai H. Systemic lupus erythematosus with Lichen Planus-like eruptions associated with pericarditis. Journal of Dermatology. 2008;35(5):306–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18477234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermejo Fenoll A, López Jornet MP. Oral Lichen Planus and Sjogren’s syndrome. 2 cases of association. Avances en Odontoestomatologia. 1991;7(1):29–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2018610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsuboi H, Katsuoka K. Ulcerative Lichen Planus associated with Sjögren’s syndrome. Journal of Dermatology. 2007;34(2):131–134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17239152</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sepčić J, Ristić R, Perković O, et al.  A case of lichen ruber planus in a patient with familial multiple sclerosis. Journal of International Medical Research. 2010;38(5):1856–1860.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21309502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siponen M, Huuskonen L, Läärä E, Salo T. Association of oral Lichen Planus with thyroid disease in a Finnish population: a retrospective case-control study. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontology. 2010;110(3):319–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fite C, Plantier F, Dupin N, Avril M, Moyal-Barracco M. Vulvar verruciform xanthoma: ten cases associated with lichen sclerosus, Lichen Planus, or other conditions. Archives of Dermatology. 2011;147(9):1087–1092.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21576553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basra MKA, Fenech R, Gatt RM, Salek MS, Finlay AY. The dermatology life quality index 1994–2007: a comprehensive review of validation data and clinical results. British Journal of Dermatology. 2008;159(5):997–1035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18795920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balci DD, Inandi T. Dermatology life quality index scores in Lichen Planus: comparison of psoriasis and healthy controls. Turkderm Deri Hastaliklari ve Frengi Arsivi. 2008;42(4):127–130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slade GD, Spencer AJ. Development and evaluation of the oral health impact profile. Community Dental Health. 1994;11(1):3–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8193981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Jornet P, Camacho-Alonso F. Quality of life in patients with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice. 2010;16(1):111–113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20367822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Jornet P, Camacho-Alonso F, Lucero Berdugo M. Measuring the impact of oral mucosa disease on quality of life. European Journal of Dermatology. 2009;19(6):603–606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19592326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegarty AM, McGrath C, Hodgson TA, Porter SR. Patient-centred outcome measures in oral medicine: are they valid and reliable? International Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery. 2002;31(6):670–674.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12521327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Accurso BT, Warner BM, Knobloch TJ, et al.  Allelic imbalance in oral Lichen Planus and assessment of its classification as a premalignant condition. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontology. 2011;112(3):359–366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3324304</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21764610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vered M, Fürth E, Shalev Y, Dayan D. Inflammatory cells of immunosuppressive phenotypes in oral Lichen Planus have a proinflammatory pattern of expression and are associated with clinical parameters. Clinical Oral Investigations. 2013;17(5):1365–1373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22893035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi P, Liu W, Zhou Z, He Q, Jiang W. Podoplanin and ABCG2: malignant transformation risk markers for oral Lichen Planus. Cancer Epidemiology Biomarkers and Prevention. 2010;19(3):844–849.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20200437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman S, Jr., Gorsky M, Lozada-Nur F. A prospective follow-up study of 570 patients with oral Lichen Planus: persistence, remission, and malignant association. Oral Surgery Oral Medicine and Oral Pathology. 1985;60(1):30–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3862010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honma M, Minami-Hori M, Takahashi H, Iizuka H. Podoplanin expression in wound and hyperproliferative psoriatic epidermis: regulation by TGF-β and STAT-3 activating cytokines, IFN-γ, IL-6, and IL-22. Journal of Dermatological Science. 2012;65(2):134–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22189341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gandarillas A, Scholl FG, Benito N, Gamallo C, Quintanilla M. Induction of PA2. 26, a cell-surface antigen expressed by active fibroblasts, in mouse epidermal keratinocytes during carcinogenesis. Molecular Carcinogenesis. 1997;20(1):10–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9328432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higashikuni Y, Sainz J, Nakamura K, et al.  The ATP-binding cassette transporter BCRP1/ABCG2 plays a pivotal role in cardiac repair after myocardial infarction via modulation of microvascular endothelial cell survival and function. Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology. 2010;30(11):2128–2135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20829509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marcekova Z, Flaig MJ, Kekus M, Ruzicka T, Rupec RA. The potential role of c-Jun activation in patients with cutaneous Lichen Planus. Experimental Dermatology. 2010;19(1):74–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19758340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenberg E. Oral Lichen Planus: a benign lesion. Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery. 2000;58(11):1278–1285.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bombeccari GP, Guzzi G, Tettamanti M, et al.  Oral Lichen Planus and malignant transformation: a longitudinal cohort study. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontology. 2011;112(3):328–334.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21782485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo Muzio L, Mignogna MD, Favia G, Procaccini M, Testa NF, Bucci E. The possible association between oral Lichen Planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma: a clinical evaluation on 14 cases and a review of the literature. Oral Oncology. 1998;34(4):239–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9813716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorouhi F, Solhpour A, Beitollahi JM, et al.  Randomized trial of pimecrolimus cream versus triamcinolone acetonide paste in the treatment of oral Lichen Planus. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2007;57(5):806–813.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17658663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voute ABE, De Jong WFB, Schulten EAJM, Snow GB, Van Der Waal I. Possible premalignant character of oral Lichen Planus. The Amsterdam experience. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 1992;21(7):326–329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1522535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown RS, Bottomley WK, Puente E, Lavigne GJ. A retrospective evaluation of 193 patients with oral Lichen Planus. Journal of Oral Pathology and Medicine. 1993;22(2):69–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8445545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng T, Boyle P, Hu H, et al.  Dentition, oral hygiene, and risk of oral cancer: a case-control study in Beijing, People’s Republic of China. Cancer Causes and Control. 1990;1(3):235–241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2102296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
