<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">24982321</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2015</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-6618</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2014</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical microbiology reviews</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Microbiol Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Escherichia coli ST131, an intriguing clonal group.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>543</StartPage>
          <EndPage>574</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>543-74</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/CMR.00125-13</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>In 2008, a previously unknown Escherichia coli clonal group, sequence type 131 (ST131), was identified on three continents. Today, ST131 is the predominant E. coli lineage among extraintestinal pathogenic E. coli (ExPEC) isolates worldwide. Retrospective studies have suggested that it may originally have risen to prominence as early as 2003. Unlike other classical group B2 ExPEC isolates, ST131 isolates are commonly reported to produce extended-spectrum β-lactamases, such as CTX-M-15, and almost all are resistant to fluoroquinolones. Moreover, ST131 E. coli isolates are considered to be truly pathogenic, due to the spectrum of infections they cause in both community and hospital settings and the large number of virulence-associated genes they contain. ST131 isolates therefore seem to contradict the widely held view that high levels of antimicrobial resistance are necessarily associated with a fitness cost leading to a decrease in pathogenesis. Six years after the first description of E. coli ST131, this review outlines the principal traits of ST131 clonal group isolates, based on the growing body of published data, and highlights what is currently known and what we need to find out to provide public health authorities with better information to help combat ST131.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2014, American Society for Microbiology. All Rights Reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nicolas-Chanoine</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marie-Hélène</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Service de Microbiologie, Hôpital Beaujon AP-HP, Clichy, France Faculté de Médecine D. Diderot, Paris, France Institut National de la Santé et de la Recherche Médicale, U773, Centre de Recherche Biomédicale Bichat-Beaujon (CRB3), Université Paris 7, Paris, France mhn.chanoine@bjn.aphp.fr.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bertrand</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xavier</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Service d'Hygiène Hospitalière, CHRU, Besançon, France UMR 6249 Chrono-Environnement, Université de Franche-Comté, Besançon, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Madec</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean-Yves</ForeName>
            <Initials>JY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unité Antibiorésistance et Virulence Bactériennes, ANSES, Lyon, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Microbiol Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8807282</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0893-8512</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004927" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D023281" MajorTopicYN="N">Genomics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24982321</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4135899</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00125-13</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">27/3/543</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Croxen MA, Finlay BB.
2010. 
Molecular mechanisms of Escherichia coli pathogenicity. Nat. Rev. Microbiol.
8:26–38. 10.1038/nrmicro2265</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrmicro2265</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19966814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo TA, Johnson JR.
2003. 
Medical and economic impact of extraintestinal infections due to Escherichia coli: an overlook epidemic. Microbes Infect.
5:449–456. 10.1016/S1286-4579(03)00049-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1286-4579(03)00049-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12738001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta K, Scholes D, Stamm WE.
1999. 
Increasing prevalence of antimicrobial resistance among uropathogens causing acute uncomplicated cystitis in women. JAMA
281:736–738. 10.1001/jama.281.8.736</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.281.8.736</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10052444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones RN, Kehrberg EN, Erwin ME, Anderson SC.
1994. 
Prevalence of important pathogens and antimicrobial activity of parenteral drugs at numerous medical centers in the United States, I. Study on the threat of emerging resistances: real or perceived? Fluoroquinolone Resistance Surveillance Group
Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
19:203–215</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7851083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turnidge J.
1995. 
Epidemiology of quinolone resistance. Eastern hemisphere. Drugs
49:43–47</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8549389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hummers-Pradier E, Koch M, Ohse AM, Heizmann WR, Kochen MM.
2005. 
Antibiotic resistance of urinary pathogens in female general practice patients. Scand. J. Infect. Dis.
37:256–261. 10.1080/00365540410021009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00365540410021009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15871164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coque TM, Baquero F, Canton R.
2008. 
Increasing prevalence of ESBL-producing Enterobacteriaceae in Europe. Euro Surveill.
13(47):pii=19044</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19021958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolas-Chanoine MH, Blanco J, Leflon-Guibout V, Demarty R, Alonso MP, Canica MM, Park Y-J, Lavigne J-P, Pitout J, Johnson JR.
2008. 
Intercontinental emergence of Escherichia coli clone O25:H4-ST131 producing CTX-M-15. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
61:273–281
doi:10.1093/jac/dkm464</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkm464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18077311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coque TM, Novais A, Carattoli A, Poirel L, Pitout J, Peixe L, Baquero F, Canton R, Nordmann P.
2008. 
Dissemination of clonally related Escherichia coli strains expressing extended-spectrum β-lactamase CTX-M-15. Emerg. Infect. Dis.
14:195–200. 10.3201/eid1402.070350</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1402.070350</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2600198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18258110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Brian J, Connie C, Kuskowski MA, Mariana C.
2010. 
Escherichia coli sequence type ST131 as the major cause of serious multidrug-resistant E. coli infections in the United States. Clin. Infect. Dis.
51:286–294. 10.1086/653932</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/653932</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20572763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donnenberg M.
2002. 
Escherichia coli: virulence mechanism of a versatile pathogen. Academic Press, New York, NY</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobar-Paramo P, Grenet K, Le Menac'h A, Rode L, Salgado E, Amorin C, Gouriou S, Picard B, Rahimy MC, Andremont A, Denamur E, Raymond R.
2004. 
Large-scale population structure of human commensal Escherichia coli isolates. Appl. Environ. Microbiol.
70:5698–5700. 10.1128/AEM.70.9.5698-5700.2004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.70.9.5698-5700.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC520916</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15345464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobar-Paramo P, Le Menac'h A, Le Gall T, Amorin C, Gouriou S, Picard B, Skurnik D, Denamur E.
2006. 
Identification of forces shaping the commensal Escherichia coli genetic structure by comparing animal and human isolates. Environ. Microbiol. Rep.
8:1975–1984. 10.1111/j.1462-2920.2006.01077.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-2920.2006.01077.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17014496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Gall T, Clermont O, Gouriou S, Picard B, Nassif X, Denamur E, Tenaillon O.
2007. 
Extraintestinal virulence is a coincidental by-product of commensalism in B2 phylogenetic group Escherichia coli strains. Mol. Biol. Evol.
24:2373–2384. 10.1093/molbev/msm172</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/molbev/msm172</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17709333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clermont O, Dhanji H, Upton M, Gibreel T, Fox A, Boyd D, Mulvey MR, Nordmann P, Ruppe E, Sarthou JL, Frank T, Vimont S, Arlet G, Branger C, Woodford N, Denamur E.
2009. 
Rapid detection of the O25b-ST131 clone of Escherichia coli encompassing the CTX-M-15-producing strains. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
64:274–277. 10.1093/jac/dkp194</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkp194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19474064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brisse S, Diancourt L, Laouenan C, Vigan M, Caro V, Arlet G, Drieux L, Leflon-Guibout V, Mentre F, Jarlier V, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H.
2012. 
Phylogenetic distribution of CTX-M- and non-extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli isolates: group B2 isolates, except clone ST131, rarely produce CTX-M enzymes. J. Clin. Microbiol.
50:2974–2981. 10.1128/JCM.00919-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00919-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3421780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22760036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Croxall G, Hale J, Weston V, Manning G, Cheetham P, Achtman M, McNally A.
2011. 
Molecular epidemiology of extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli isolates from a regional cohort of elderly patients highlights the prevalence of ST131 strains with increased antimicrobial resistance in both community and hospital care settings. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:2501–2508. 10.1093/jac/dkr349</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr349</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dahbi G, Mora A, Lopez C, Alonso MP, Mamani R, Marzoa J, Coira A, Garicia-Garrote F, Pita J-M, Velasco D, Herrera A, Viso S, Blanco JE, Blanco M, Blanco J.
2013. 
Emergence of new variants of ST131 clonal group among extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli producing extended-spectrum β-lactamases. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
42:347–351. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2013.06.017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2013.06.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumura Y, Yamamoto M, Nagao M, Hotta G, Matsushima A, Ito Y, Takakura S, Ichiyama S.
2012. 
Emergence and spread of B2-ST131-O25b, B2-ST131-O16 and D-ST405 clonal groups among extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli in Japan. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:2612–2620. 10.1093/jac/dks278</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22843833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olesen B, Hansen DS, Nilsson F, Frimodt-Moller J, Leihof RF, Struve C, Scheutz F, Johnston B, Krogfelt KA, Johnson JR.
2013. 
Prevalence and characteristics of the epidemic multiresistant Escherichia coli ST131 clonal group among extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing E. coli isolates in Copenhagen, Denmark. J. Clin. Microbiol.
51:1779–1785. 10.1128/JCM.00346-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00346-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3716056</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23554186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Platell JL, Cobbold RN, Johnson JR, Heisig A, Heisig P, Clabots C, Kuskowski MA, Trott DJ.
2011. 
Commonality among fluoroquinolone-resistant sequence type ST131 extraintestinal Escherichia coli isolates from humans and companion animals in Australia. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
55:3782–3787. 10.1128/AAC.00306-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00306-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3147636</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21646486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kudinha T, Johnson JR, Andrew S, Kong F, Anderson P, Gilbert GL.
2013. 
Escherichia coli sequence type 131 (ST131) as a prominent cause of antibiotic resistance among urinary Escherichia coli isolates from reproductive-age women. J. Clin. Microbiol.
51:3270–3276. 10.1128/JCM.01315-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01315-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3811657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23885001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habeeb MA, Haque A, Iversen A, Giske CG.
14
September
2013. 
Occurrence of virulence genes, 16S rRNA methylases, and plasmid-mediated quinolone resistance genes in CTX-M-producing Escherichia coli from Pakistan. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
10.1007/s10096-013-1970-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-013-1970-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24036893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanc V, Leflon-Guibout V, Blanco J, Haenni M, Madec J-Y, Rafignon G, Bruno P, Mora A, Lopez C, Dahbi G, Dunais B, Anastasy M, Branger C, Moreau R, Pradier C, Nicolas-Chanoine MH.
8
January
2014. 
Prevalence of day-care centre children (France) with faecal CTX-M-producing Escherichia coli comprising O25b:H4 and O16:H5 ST131 strains. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
10.1093/jac/dkt519</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt519</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24402502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki S, Shibata N, Yamane K, Wachino J, Ito K, Arakawa Y.
2009. 
Change in the prevalence of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli in Japan by clonal spread. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
63:72–79. 10.1093/jac/dkn463</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkn463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19004839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo TA, Johnson JR.
2000. 
Proposal for a new inclusive designation for extraintestinal pathogenic isolates of Escherichia coli: ExPEC. J. Infect. Dis.
181:1753–1754. 10.1086/315418</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/315418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10823778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Bij AK, Peirano G, Pitondo-Silva A, Pitout JDD.
2012. 
The presence of genes encoding for different virulence factors in clonally related Escherichia coli that produce CTX-Ms. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
72:297–302. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2011.12.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2011.12.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22300954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karisik E, Ellington MJ, Livermore DM, Woodford N.
2008. 
Virulence factors in Escherichia coli with CTX-M-15 and other extended-spectrum β-lactamases in the UK. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
61:54–58. 10.1093/jac/dkm401</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkm401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17981835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mora A, Blanco M, Lopez C, Mamani R, Blanco JE, Alonso MP, Garcia-Garrote F, Dahbi G, Herrera A, Fernandez A, Fernandez B, Agulla A, Bou G, Blanco J.
2011. 
Emergence of clonal groups O1:HNM-D-ST59, O15:H1-D-ST393, O20:H34/HNM-D-ST354, O25b:H4-B2-ST131 and ONT:H21,42-B1-ST101 among CTX-M-14-producing Escherichia coli clinical isolates in Galicia, northwest Spain. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
37:16–21. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2010.09.012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2010.09.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21075606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Urban C, Weissman SJ, Jorgensen JH, Lewis JS, II, Hansen G, Edelstein PH, Robicsek A, Cleary T, Adachi J, Paterson D, Quinn J, Hanson ND, Johnston BD, Clabots C, Kuskowski MA.
2012. 
Molecular epidemiological analysis of Escherichia coli sequence type ST131 (O25:H4) and blaCTX-M-15 among extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing E. coli from the United States, 2000 to 2009. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:2364–2370. 10.1128/AAC.05824-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.05824-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3346636</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22354301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavigne JP, Vergunst AC, Goret L, Sotto A, Combescure C, Blanco J, O'Callaghan D, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H.
2012. 
Virulence potential and genomic mapping of the worldwide clone Escherichia coli ST131. PLoS One
7:e34294. 10.1371/journal.pone.0034294</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0034294</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22457832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanco J, Mora A, Mamani R, Lopez C, Blanco M, Dahbi G, Herrera A, Marzoa J, Fernandez V, de la Cruz F, Martinez-Martinez L, Alonso MP, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, Johnson JR, Johnston B, Lopez-Cerero L, Pascual A, Rodriguez-Bano J.
2013. 
Four main virotypes among extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing isolates of Escherichia coli O25b:H4-B2-ST131: bacterial, epidemiological, and clinical characteristics. J. Clin. Microbiol.
51:3358–3367. 10.1128/JCM.01555-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01555-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3811668</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23926164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Murray AC, Gajewski A, Sullivan M, Snippes P, Kuskowski MA.
2003. 
Isolation and molecular characterization of nalidixic acid-resistant extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli from retail chicken products. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
47:2161–2168. 10.1128/AAC.47.7.2161-2168.2003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.47.7.2161-2168.2003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC161843</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mora Gutierrez A, Dahbi G, Mamani R, Marzoa J, Dion S, Picard B, Blanco M, Alonso PM, Denamur E, Blanco J.
2014. 
Virulence patterns in a murine sepsis model of ST131 Escherichia coli clinical isolates belonging to serotypes O25b:H4 and O16:H5 are associated to specific virotypes. PLoS One
9:e87025. 10.1371/journal.pone.0087025</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0087025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24498015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mora A, Herrera A, Mamani R, Lopez C, Alonso MP, Blanco JE, Blanco M, Dahbi G, Garcia-Garrote F, Pita JM, Coira A, Bernardez MI, Blanco J.
2010. 
Recent emergence of clonal group O25b:K1:H4-B2-ST131 ibeA strains among Escherichia coli poultry isolates, including CTX-M-9-producing strains, and comparison with clinical human isolates. Appl. Environ. Microbiol.
76:6991–6997. 10.1128/AEM.01112-10</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.01112-10</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2976257</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20817805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, DebRoy C, Castanheira M, Robiscek A, Hansen G, Weissman S, Urban C, Platell J, Trott D, Zhanel G, Clabots C, Johnston BD, Kuskowski MA, The MASTER Investigators 
2012. 
Comparison of Escherichia coli ST131 pulsotypes, by epidemiologic traits, 1967-2009. Emerg. Infect. Dis.
18:598–607. 10.3201/eid1804.111627</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1804.111627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3309662</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22469129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, O'Bryan TT, Delavari P, Kuskowski M, Stapleton A, Carlino U, Russo TA.
2001. 
Clonal relationships and extended virulence genotypes among Escherichia coli isolates from women with a first or recurrent episode of cystitis. J. Infect. Dis.
183:1508–1517. 10.1086/320198</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/320198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11319687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz MA, Hernandez-Bello JR, Rodriguez-Bano J, Martinez-Martinez L, Calvo J, Blanco J, Pascual A.
2010. 
Diversity of Escherichia coli strains producing extended-spectrum beta-lactamases in Spain: second nationwide study. J. Clin. Microbiol.
48:2840–2845. 10.1128/JCM.02147-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02147-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916592</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tartof SY, Solberg OD, Riley LW.
2007. 
Genotypic analyses of uropathogenic Escherichia coli based on fimH single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs). J. Med. Microbiol.
56:1363–1369. 10.1099/jmm.0.47262-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.47262-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17893175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weissman S, Chattopadhyay S, Aprikian P, Obata-Yasuoka M, Yarova-Yarovaya Y, Stapleton A, Ba-Theim W, Dydhuizen D, Johnson J, Sokurenko E.
2006. 
Clonal analysis reveals high rate of structural mutations in fimbrial adhesins of extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli. Mol. Microbiol.
59:975–988. 10.1111/j.1365-2958.2005.04985.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2958.2005.04985.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1380272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16420365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weissman SJ, Johnson JR, Tchesnokova V, Billig M, Dykhuizen D, Riddell K, Rogers P, Qin X, Butler-Wu S, Cookson BT, Fang FC, Scholes D, Chattopadhyay S, Sokurenko E.
2012. 
High-resolution two-locus clonal typing of extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli. Appl. Environ. Microbiol.
78:1353–1360. 10.1128/AEM.06663-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.06663-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3294456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22226951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams-Sapper S, Diep BA, Perdreau-Remington F, Riley LW.
2013. 
Clonal composition and community clustering of drug-susceptible and -resistant Escherichia coli isolates from bloodstream infections. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
57:490–497. 10.1128/AAC.01025-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01025-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23147723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Tchesnokova V, Johnston B, Clabots C, Roberts PL, Billig M, Riddell K, Rogers P, Qin X, Butler-Wu S, Price LB, Aziz M, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, Debroy C, Robicsek A, Hansen G, Urban C, Platell J, Trott DJ, Zhanel G, Weissman SJ, Cookson BT, Fang FC, Limaye AP, Scholes D, Chattopadhyay S, Hooper DC, Sokurenko EV.
2013. 
Abrupt emergence of a single dominant multidrug-resistant strain of Escherichia coli. J. Infect. Dis.
207:919–928. 10.1093/infdis/jis933</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jis933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3571447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tchesnokova V, Billig M, Chattopadhyay S, Linardopoulou E, Aprikian P, Roberts PL, Skrivankova V, Johnston B, Gileva A, Igusheva I, Toland A, Riddell K, Rogers P, Qin X, Butler-Wu S, Cookson BT, Fang FC, Kahl B, Price LB, Weissman SJ, Limaye A, Scholes D, Johnson JR, Sokurenko EV.
2013. 
Predictive diagnostics for infections based on the clonal association of antimicrobial resistance and clinical outcome. J. Clin. Microbiol.
51:2991–2999. 10.1128/JCM.00984-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00984-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3754640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colpan A, Johnston B, Porter S, Clabots C, Anway R, Thao L, Kuskowski MA, Tchesnokova V, Sokurenko EV, Johnson JR.
2013. 
Escherichia coli sequence type 131 (ST131) subclone H30 as an emergent multidrug-resistant pathogen among US veterans. Clin. Infect. Dis.
57:1256–1265. 10.1093/cid/cit503</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cit503</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792724</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23926176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee R, Johnston B, Lohse C, Chattopadhyay S, Tchesnokova V, Sokurenko EV, Johnson JR.
2013. 
The clonal distribution and diversity of extraintestinal Escherichia coli isolates vary according to patient characteristics. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
57:5912–5917. 10.1128/AAC.01065-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01065-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837911</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24041881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clermont O, Bonacorsi S, Bingen E.
2000. 
Rapid and simple determination of the Escherichia coli phylogenetic group. Appl. Environ. Microbiol.
66:4555–4558. 10.1128/AEM.66.10.4555-4558.2000</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.66.10.4555-4558.2000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC92342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11010916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clermont O, Christenson JK, Denamur E, Gordon DM.
2013. 
The Clermont Escherichia coli phylo-typing method revisited: improvement of specificity and detection of new phylo-groups. Environ. Microbiol. Rep.
5:58–65. 10.1111/1758-2229.12019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1758-2229.12019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23757131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clermont O, Johnson JR, Menard M, Denamur E.
2007. 
Determination of Escherichia coli O types by allele-specific polymerase chain reaction: application to the O types involved in human septicemia. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
57:214–223</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17020797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Menard E, Johnston B, Kuskowski MA, Nichol KA, Zhanel GG.
2009. 
Epidemic clonal groups of Escherichia coli as a cause of antimicrobial-resistant urinary tract infections in Canada, 2002 to 2004. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
53:2733–2739. 10.1128/AAC.00297-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00297-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2704706</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19398649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cagnacci S, Gualco L, Debbia E, Schito GC, Marchese A.
2008. 
European emergence of ciprofloxacin-resistant Escherichia coli clonal groups O25:H4-ST131 and O15:K52:H1 causing community-acquired uncomplicated cystitis. J. Clin. Microbiol.
46:2605–2612. 10.1128/JCM.00640-08</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00640-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2519467</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18579721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golding GR, Persaud N, Levett PN, McDonald RR, Irvine J, Nsungu M, Woods S, Khan M, Mataseje LF, Mulvey MR.
2012. 
Characterization of Escherichia coli urinary tract infection isolates in remote northern Saskatchewan communities: the Northern Antibiotic Resistance Partnership. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
74:242–247. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2012.07.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2012.07.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22944458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leflon-Guibout V, Blanco J, Amaqdouf K, Mora A, Guize L, Nicolas-Chanoine MH.
2008. 
Absence of CTX-M enzymes but high prevalence of clones, including clone ST131, among fecal Escherichia coli isolates from healthy subjects living in the area of Paris, France. J. Clin. Microbiol.
46:3900–3905. 10.1128/JCM.00734-08</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00734-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2593250</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18842941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Cerero L, Navarro MD, Bellido M, Martin-Pena A, Vinas L, Cisneros JM, Gomez-Langley SL, Sanchez-Monteseirin H, Morales I, Pascual A, Rodriguez-Bano J.
11
October
2013. 
Escherichia coli belonging to the worldwide emerging epidemic clonal group O25b/ST131: risk factors and clinical implications. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
10.1093/jac/dkt405</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24123431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodford N, Carattoli A, Karisik E, Underwood A, Ellington MJ, Livermore DM.
2009. 
Complete nucleotide sequences of plasmids pEK204, pEK499, and pEK516, encoding CTX-M enzymes in three major Escherichia coli lineages from the United Kingdom, all belonging to the international O25:H4-ST131 clone. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
53:4472–4482. 10.1128/AAC.00688-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00688-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2764225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19687243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naseer U, Haldorsen B, Tofteland S, Hegstad K, Scheutz F, Simonsen GS, Sundsfjord A.
2009. 
Molecular characterization of CTX-M-15-producing clinical isolates of Escherichia coli reveals the spread of multidrug-resistant ST131 (O25:H4) and ST964 (O102:H6) strains in Norway. APMIS
117:526–536. 10.1111/j.1600-0463.2009.02465.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0463.2009.02465.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19594493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naseer U, Haldorsen B, Simonsen GS, Sundsfjord A.
2010. 
Sporadic occurrence of CMY-2-producing multidrug-resistant Escherichia coli of ST-complexes 38 and 448, and ST131 in Norway. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
16:171–178. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2009.02861.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2009.02861.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19548922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montesinos I, Rodriguez-Villalobos H, De Mendonca R, Bogaerts P, Deplano A, Glupczynski Y.
2010. 
Molecular characterization of plasmids encoding CTX-M-15 extended-spectrum β-lactamase associated with the ST131 Escherichia coli clone in Belgium. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:1828–1830. 10.1093/jac/dkq208</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20534625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cullik A, Pfeifer Y, Prager R, von Baum H, Witte W.
2010. 
A novel IS26 structure surrounds blaCTX-M genes in different plasmids from German clinical Escherichia coli isolates. J. Med. Microbiol.
59:580–587. 10.1099/jmm.0.016188-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.016188-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20093380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zong Z, Yu R, Wang X, Lu X.
2011. 
blaCTX-M-65 is carried by a Tn1722-like element on an IncN conjugative plasmid of ST131 Escherichia coli. J. Med. Microbiol.
60:435–441. 10.1099/jmm.0.026997-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.026997-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21163826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J, Bae IK, Jeong SH, Chang CL, Lee CH, Lee K.
2011. 
Characterization of IncF plasmids carrying the blaCTX-M-14 gene in clinical isolates of Escherichia coli from Korea. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:1263–1268. 10.1093/jac/dkr106</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr106</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novais A, Viana D, Baquero F, Martinez-Botas J, Canton R, Coque TM.
2012. 
Contribution of IncFII and broad-host IncA/C and IncN plasmids to the local expansion and diversification of phylogroup B2 Escherichia coli ST131 clones carrying blaCTX-M-15 and qnrS1 genes. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:2763–2766. 10.1128/AAC.06001-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.06001-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3346627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22330911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Partridge SR, Ellem JA, Tetu SG, Zong Z, Paulsen IT, Iredell JR.
2011. 
Complete sequence of pJIE143, a pir-type plasmid carrying ISEcp1-blaCTX-M-15 from an Escherichia coli ST131 isolate. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
55:5933–5935. 10.1128/AAC.00639-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00639-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3232798</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21911569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonnin RA, Poirel L, Carattoli A, Nordmann P.
2012. 
Characterization of an IncFII plasmid encoding NDM-1 from Escherichia coli ST131. PLoS One
7:34752. 10.1371/journal.pone.0034752</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0034752</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325265</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22511964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villa L, Garcia-Fernandez A, Fortini D, Carattoli A.
2010. 
Replicon sequence typing of IncF plasmids carrying virulence and resistance determinants. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:2518–2529. 10.1093/jac/dkq347</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq347</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20935300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson TJ, Nolan LK.
2009. 
Pathogenomics of the virulence plasmids of Escherichia coli. Microbiol. Mol. Biol. Rev.
73:750–774. 10.1128/MMBR.00015-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/MMBR.00015-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19946140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lau SH, Kaufmann ME, Livermore DM, Woodford N, Willshaw GA, Cheasty T, Stamper K, Reddy S, Cheesbrough J, Bolton FJ, Fox AJ, Upton M.
2008. 
UK epidemic Escherichia coli strains A-E, with CTX-M-15 β-lactamase, all belong to the international O25:H4-ST131 clone. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
62:1241–1244. 10.1093/jac/dkn380</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkn380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd DA, Tyler S, Christianson S, McGeer A, Muller MP, Willey BM, Bryce E, Gardam M, Nordmann P, Mulvey MR.
2004. 
Complete nucleotide sequence of a 92-kilobase plasmid harboring the CTX-M-15 extended-spectrum β-lactamase involved in an outbreak in long-term-care facilities in Toronto, Canada. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
48:3758–3764. 10.1128/AAC.48.10.3758-3764.2004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.48.10.3758-3764.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC521865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15388431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karisik E, Ellington MJ, Pike R, Warren RE, Livermore DM, Woodford N.
2006. 
Molecular characterization of plasmids encoding CTX-M-15 β-lactamases from Escherichia coli strains in the United Kingdom. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
58:665–668. 10.1093/jac/dkl309</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkl309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16870648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poirel L, Lartigue M, Decousser J, Nordmann P.
2005. 
ISEcp1B-mediated transposition of blaCTX-M in Escherichia coli. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
49:447–450. 10.1128/AAC.49.1.447-450.2005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.49.1.447-450.2005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC538921</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15616333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao X, Cavaco LM, Lv Y, Li Y, Zheng B, Wang P, Hasman H, Liu Y, Aarestrup FM.
2011. 
Molecular characterization and antimicrobial susceptibility testing of Escherichia coli isolates from patients with urinary tract infections in 20 Chinese hospitals. J. Clin. Microbiol.
49:2496–2501. 10.1128/JCM.02503-10</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02503-10</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3147837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hrabak J, Empel J, Bergerova T, Fajfrlik K, Urbaskova P, Kern-Zdanowicz I, Hryniewicz W, Gniadkowski M.
2009. 
International clones of Klebsiella pneumoniae and Escherichia coli with extended-spectrum β-lactamases in a Czech hospital. J. Clin. Microbiol.
47:3353–3357. 10.1128/JCM.00901-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00901-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756902</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19710276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hussain A, Ewers C, Nandanwar N, Guenther S, Jadhav S, Wieler LH, Ahmed N.
2012. 
Multiresistant uropathogenic Escherichia coli from a region in India where urinary tract infections are endemic: genotypic and phenotypic characteristics of sequence type 131 isolates of the CTX-M-15 extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing lineage. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:6358–6365. 10.1128/AAC.01099-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01099-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3497203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23045357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumura Y, Yamamoto M, Nagao M, Ito Y, Takakura S, Ichiyama S.
2013. 
Association of fluoroquinolone resistance, virulence genes, and IncF plasmids with extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli ST131 and ST405 clonal groups. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
57:4736–4742. 10.1128/AAC.00641-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00641-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3811414</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23856781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seiffert SN, Hilty M, Kronenberg A, Droz S, Perreten V, Endimiani A.
2013. 
Extended-spectrum cephalosporin-resistant Escherichia coli in community, specialized outpatient clinic and hospital settings in Switzerland. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:2249–2254. 10.1093/jac/dkt208</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23759671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mnif B, Harhour H, Jdidi J, Mahjoubi F, Genel N, Arlet G, Hammami A.
2013. 
Molecular epidemiology of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli in Tunisia and characterization of their virulence factors and plasmid addiction systems. BMC Microbiol.
13:147. 10.1186/1471-2180-13-147</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2180-13-147</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23800277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dimude JU, Amyes SG.
2013. 
Molecular diversity associated with the dissemination of CTX-M-15 β-lactamase gene in blood culture isolates of Escherichia coli from Edinburgh. Scand. J. Infect. Dis.
45:32–37. 10.3109/00365548.2012.708781</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365548.2012.708781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhanji H, Doumith M, Rooney PJ, O'Leary MC, Loughrey AC, Hope R, Woodford N, Livermore DM.
2011. 
Molecular epidemiology of fluoroquinolone-resistant ST131 Escherichia coli producing CTX-M extended-spectrum β-lactamases in nursing homes in Belfast, UK. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:297–303. 10.1093/jac/dkq463</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21131323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsh TR, Weeks J, Livermore DM, Toleman MA.
2011. 
Dissemination of NDM-1 positive bacteria in the New Delhi environment and its implications for human health: an environmental point prevalence study. Lancet Infect. Dis.
11:355–362. 10.1016/S1473-3099(11)70059-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(11)70059-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21478057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poirel L, Hombrouck-Alet C, Freneaux C, Bernabeu S, Nordmann P.
2010. 
Global spread of New Delhi metallo-β-lactamase 1. Lancet Infect. Dis.
10:832. 10.1016/S1473-3099(10)70279-6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(10)70279-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21109172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Schreckenberger PC, Pitout JDD.
2011. 
Characteristics of NDM-1-producing Escherichia coli isolates that belong to the successful and virulent clone ST131. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
55:2986–2988. 10.1128/AAC.01763-10</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01763-10</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3101395</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21444703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zong Z.
2013. 
Complete sequence of pJIE186-2, a plasmid carrying multiple virulence factors from a sequence type 131 Escherichia coli O25 strain. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
57:597–600. 10.1128/AAC.01081-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01081-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23070168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Villalobos H, Bogaerts P, Berhin C, Bauraing C, Deplano A, Montesinos I, de Mendonca R, Jans B, Glupczynski Y.
2011. 
Trends in production of extended-spectrum β-lactamases among Enterobacteriaceae of clinical interest: results of a nationwide survey in Belgian hospitals. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:37–47. 10.1093/jac/dkq388</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21036771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, van der Bij AK, Gregson DB, Pitout JD.
2012. 
Molecular epidemiology over an 11-year period (2000 to 2010) of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli causing bacteremia in a centralized Canadian region. J. Clin. Microbiol.
50:294–299. 10.1128/JCM.06025-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.06025-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22162555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Richardson D, Nigrin J, McGeer A, Loo V, Toye B, Alfa M, Pienaar C, Kibsey P, Pitout JD.
2010. 
High prevalence of ST131 producing CTX-M-15 and CTX-M-14 among extended-spectrum β-lactamase producing Escherichia coli across Canada. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
54:1327–1330. 10.1128/AAC.01338-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01338-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2825972</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20047913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arpin C, Quentin C, Grobost F, Cambau E, Robert J, Dubois V, Coulange L, Andre C.
2009. 
Nationwide survey of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae in the French community setting. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
63:1205–1214. 10.1093/jac/dkp108</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkp108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19329798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Izdebski R, Baraniak A, Fiett J, Adler A, Kazma M, Salomon J, Lawrence C, Rossini A, Salvia A, Vidal Samso J, Fierro J, Paul M, Lerman Y, Malhotra-Kumar S, Lammens C, Goossens H, Hryniewicz W, Brun-Buisson C, Carmeli Y, Gniadkowski M.
2013. 
Clonal structure, extended-spectrum β-lactamases, and acquired AmpC-type cephalosporinases of Escherichia coli populations colonizing patients in rehabilitation centers in four countries. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
57:309–316. 10.1128/AAC.01656-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01656-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3535924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23114774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voets GM, Platteel TN, Fluit AC, Scharringa J, Schapendonk CM, Stuart JC, Bonten MJ, Hall MA, National ESBL Surveillance Working Group 
2012. 
Population distribution of β-lactamase conferring resistance to third-generation cephalosporins in human clinical Enterobacteriaceae in the Netherlands. PLoS One
7:52102. 10.1371/journal.pone.0052102</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0052102</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3527366</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23284886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pomba C, Lopez-Cerero L, Bellido M, Serrano L, Belas A, Couto N, Cavaco-Silva P, Rodriguez-Bano J, Pascual A.
2014. 
Within-lineage variability of ST131 Escherichia coli isolates from humans and companion animals in the south of Europe. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
69:271–273. 10.1093/jac/dkt343</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24022069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oteo J, Diestra K, Juan C, Bautista V, Novais A, Perez-Vazquez M, Moya B, Miro E, Coque TM, Oliver A, Canton R, Navarro F, Campos J.
2009. 
Extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli in Spain belong to a large variety of multilocus sequence typing types, including ST10 complex/A, ST23 complex/A and ST131/B2. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
34:173–176. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2009.03.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2009.03.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19464856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilty M, Betsch BY, Bogli-Stuber K, Heiniger N, Stadler M, Kuffer M, Kronenberg A, Rohrer C, Aebi S, Endimiani A, Droz S, Muhlemann K.
2012. 
Transmission dynamics of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae in the tertiary care hospital and the household setting. Clin. Infect. Dis.
55:967–975. 10.1093/cid/cis581</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cis581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3436924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22718774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rooney PJ, O'Leary MC, Loughrey AC, McCalmont M, Smyth B, Donaghy P, Badri M, Woodford N, Karisik E, Livermore DM.
2009. 
Nursing homes as a reservoir of extended-spectrum β-lactamase (ESBL)-producing ciprofloxacin-resistant Escherichia coli. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
64:635–641. 10.1093/jac/dkp220</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkp220</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19549667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doi Y, Park YS, Rivera JI, Adams-Haduch JM, Hingwe A, Sordillo EM, Lewis JS, II, Howard WJ, Johnson LE, Polsky B, Jorgensen JH, Richter SS, Shutt KA, Paterson DL.
2013. 
Community-associated extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli infection in the United States. Clin. Infect. Dis.
56:641–648. 10.1093/cid/cis942</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cis942</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3563390</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23150211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Courpon-Claudinon A, Lefort A, Panhard X, Clermont O, Dornic Q, Fantin B, Mentre F, Wolff M, Denamur E, Branger C.
2011. 
Bacteraemia caused by third-generation cephalosporin-resistant Escherichia coli in France: prevalence, molecular epidemiology and clinical features. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
17:557–565. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2010.03298.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2010.03298.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20649802</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchida Y, Mochimaru T, Morokuma Y, Kiyosuke M, Fujise M, Eto F, Eriguchi Y, Nagasaki Y, Shimono N, Kang D.
2010. 
Clonal spread in Eastern Asia of ciprofloxacin-resistant Escherichia coli serogroup O25 strains, and associated virulence factors. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
35:444–450. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2009.12.012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2009.12.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20188525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coelho A, Mora A, Mamani R, Lopez C, Gonzalez-Lopez JJ, Larrosa MN, Quintero-Zarate JN, Dahbi G, Herrera A, Blanco JE, Blanco M, Alonso MP, Prats G, Blanco J.
2011. 
Spread of Escherichia coli O25b:H4-B2-ST131 producing CTX-M-15 and SHV-12 with high virulence gene content in Barcelona (Spain). J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:517–526. 10.1093/jac/dkq491</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq491</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim YA, Qureshi ZA, Adams-Haduch JM, Park YS, Shutt KA, Doi Y.
2012. 
Features of infections due to Klebsiella pneumoniae carbapenemase-producing Escherichia coli: emergence of sequence type 131. Clin. Infect. Dis.
55:224-231. 10.1093/cid/cis387</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cis387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3491773</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22491340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naas T, Cuzon G, Gaillot O, Courcol R, Nordmann P.
2011. 
When carbapenem-hydrolyzing β-lactamase KPC meets Escherichia coli ST131 in France. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
55:4933–4934. 10.1128/AAC.00719-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00719-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3186948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21768511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris D, Boyle F, Ludden C, Condon I, Hale J, O'Connell N, Power L, Boo TW, Dhanji H, Lavallee C, Woodford N, Cormican M.
2011. 
Production of KPC-2 carbapenemase by an Escherichia coli clinical isolate belonging to the international ST131 clone. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
55:4935–4936. 10.1128/AAC.05127-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.05127-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3186997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21768521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai JC, Zhang R, Hu YY, Zhou HW, Chen GX.
2014. 
Emergence of Escherichia coli sequence type 131 isolates producing KPC-2 carbapenemase in China. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
58:1146–1152. 10.1128/AAC.00912-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00912-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3910876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24323475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantengoli E, Luzzaro F, Pecile P, Cecconi D, Cavallo A, Attala L, Bartoloni A, Rossolini GM.
2011. 
Escherichia coli ST131 producing extended-spectrum β-lactamases plus VIM-1 carbapenemase: further narrowing of treatment options. Clin. Infect. Dis.
52:690–691. 10.1093/cid/ciq194</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciq194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21220769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan J-J, Tsai L-H, Wu J-J.
2012. 
Emergence of the IMP-8 metallo-β-lactamase in the Escherichia coli ST131 clone in Taiwan. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
40:281–282. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2012.05.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2012.05.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22789726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naseer U, Olsson-Liljequist BE, Woodford N, Dhanji H, Canton R, Sundsfjord A, Lindstedt BA.
2012. 
Multi-locus variable number of tandem repeat analysis for rapid and accurate typing of virulent multidrug resistant Escherichia coli clones. PLoS One
7:e41232. 10.1371/journal.pone.0041232</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0041232</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22859970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris D, McGarry E, Cotter M, Passet V, Lynch M, Ludden C, Hannan MM, Brisse S, Cormican M.
2012. 
Detection of OXA-48 carbapenemase in the pandemic clone Escherichia coli O25b:H4-ST131 in the course of investigation of an outbreak of OXA-48-producing Klebsiella pneumoniae. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:4030–4031. 10.1128/AAC.00638-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00638-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3393432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22564840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dimou V, Dhanji H, Pike R, Livermore DM, Woodford N.
2012. 
Characterization of Enterobacteriaceae producing OXA-48-like carbapenemases in the UK. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:1660–1665. 10.1093/jac/dks124</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks124</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22532467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birgy A, Mariani-Kurkdjian P, Bidet P, Doit C, Genel N, Courroux C, Arlet G, Bingen E.
2013. 
Characterization of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli strains involved in maternal-fetal colonization: prevalence of E. coli ST131. J. Clin. Microbiol.
51:1727-1732. 10.1128/JCM.03255-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.03255-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3716058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23515552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitout JD, Gregson DB, Campbell L, Laupland KB.
2009. 
Molecular characteristics of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli isolates causing bacteremia in the Calgary Health Region from 2000 to 2007: emergence of clone ST131 as a cause of community-acquired infections. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
53:2846–2851. 10.1128/AAC.00247-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00247-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2704701</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19380595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones GL, Warren RE, Skidmore SJ, Davies VA, Gibreel T, Upton M.
2008. 
Prevalence and distribution of plasmid-mediated quinolone resistance genes in clinical isolates of Escherichia coli lacking extended-spectrum β-lactamases. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
62:1245–1251. 10.1093/jac/dkn406</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkn406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18827034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibreel TM, Dodgson AR, Cheesbrough J, Fox AJ, Bolton FJ, Upton M.
2012. 
Population structure, virulence potential and antibiotic susceptibility of uropathogenic Escherichia coli from Northwest England. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:346–356. 10.1093/jac/dkr451</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22028202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee R, Strahilevitz J, Johnson JR, Nagwekar PP, Schora DM, Shevrin I, Du H, Peterson LR, Robicsek A.
2013. 
Predictors and molecular epidemiology of community-onset extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli infection in a midwestern community. Infect. Control. Hosp. Epidemiol.
34:947–953. 10.1086/671725</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/671725</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3916143</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vredenburg J, Varela AR, Hasan B, Bertilsson S, Olsen B, Narciso-da-Rocha C, Bonnedahl J, Stedt J, Da Costa PM, Manaia CM.
27
August
2013. 
Quinolone-resistant Escherichia coli isolated from birds of prey in Portugal are genetically distinct from those isolated from water environments and gulls in Portugal, Spain and Sweden. Environ. Microbiol. Rep.
10.1111/1462-2920.12231</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1462-2920.12231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24034690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novais A, Rodrigues C, Branquinho R, Antunes P, Grosso F, Boaventura L, Ribeiro G, Peixe L.
2012. 
Spread of an OmpK36-modified ST15 Klebsiella pneumoniae variant during an outbreak involving multiple carbapenem-resistant Enterobacteriaceae species and clones. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
31:3057–3063. 10.1007/s10096-012-1665-z</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-012-1665-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22706513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pomba C, da Fonseca JD, Baptista BC, Correia JD, Martinez-Martinez L.
2009. 
Detection of the pandemic O25-ST131 human virulent Escherichia coli CTX-M-15-producing clone harboring the qnrB2 and aac(6′)-Ib-cr genes in a dog. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
53:327–328. 10.1128/AAC.00896-08</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00896-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leflon-Guibout V, Jurand C, Bonacorsi S, Espinasse F, Guelfi MC, Duportail F, Heym B, Bingen E, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H.
2004. 
Emergence and spread of three clonally related virulent isolates of CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli with variable resistance to aminoglycosides and tetracycline in a French geriatric hospital. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
48:3736–3742. 10.1128/AAC.48.10.3736-3742.2004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.48.10.3736-3742.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC521882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15388428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price LB, Johnson JR, Aziz M, Clabots C, Johnston B, Tchesnokova V, Nordstrom L, Billig M, Chattopadhyay S, Stegger M, Andersen PS, Pearson T, Riddell K, Rogers P, Scholes D, Kahl B, Keim P, Sokurenko EV.
2013. 
The epidemice of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli ST131 is driven by a single highly pathogenic subclone, H30-Rx. mBio
4(6):e00377-13. 10.1128/mBio.00377-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mBio.00377-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3870262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24345742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirai I, Fukui N, Taguchi M, Yamauchi K, Nakamura T, Okano S, Yamamoto Y.
2013. 
Detection of chromosomal bla in Escherichia coli O25b-B2-ST131 isolates from the Kinki region of Japan. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
42:500–506. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2013.08.005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2013.08.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24091130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersen PS, Stegger M, Aziz M, Contente-Cuomo T, Gibbons HS, Keim P, Sokurenko EV, Johnson JR, Price LB.
2013. 
Complete genome sequence of the epidemic and highly virulent CTX-M-15-producing H30-Rx subclone of Escherichia coli ST131. Genome Announc.
1(6):e00988-13. 10.1128/genomeA.00988-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/genomeA.00988-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3853059</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24309736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamson DA, Freeman JT, Porter S, Roberts S, Wiles S, Paterson DL, Johnson JR.
2013. 
Clinical and molecular correlates of virulence in Escherichia coli causing bloodstream infection following transrectal ultrasound-guided (TRUS) prostate biopsy. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:2898–2906. 10.1093/jac/dkt276</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt276</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23833184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assimacopoulos A, Johnston B, Clabots C, Johnson JR.
2012. 
Post-prostate biopsy infection with Escherichia coli ST131 leading to epididymo-orchitis and meningitis caused by Gram-negative bacilli. J. Clin. Microbiol.
50:4157–4159. 10.1128/JCM.02026-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02026-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3502997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23015671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Anderson JT, Clabots C, Johnston B, Cooperstock M.
2010. 
Within-household sharing of a fluoroquinolone-resistant Escherichia coli sequence type ST131 strain causing pediatric osteoarticular infection. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J.
29:473–475. 10.1097/INF.0b013e3181c89bd7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0b013e3181c89bd7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19952857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vigil KJ, Johnson JR, Johnston BD, Kontoyiannis DP, Mulanovich VE, Raad II, Dupont HL, Adachi JA.
2010. 
Escherichia coli pyomyositis: an emerging infectious disease among patients with hematologic malignancies. Clin. Infect. Dis.
50:374–380. 10.1086/649866</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/649866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20038242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ender PT, Gajanana D, Johnston B, Clabots C, Tamarkin FJ, Johnson JR.
2009. 
Transmission of an extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli (sequence type ST131) strain between a father and daughter resulting in septic shock and emphysematous pyelonephritis. J. Clin. Microbiol.
47:3780–3782. 10.1128/JCM.01361-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01361-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772609</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19741070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens RCJ, Johnson JR, Stogsdill P, Yarmus L, Lolans K, Quinn J.
2011. 
Community transmission in the United States of a CTX-M-15-producing sequence type ST131 Escherichia coli strain resulting in death. J. Clin. Microbiol.
49:3406–3408. 10.1128/JCM.00993-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00993-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165609</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21752984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Miller S, Johnston B, Clabots C, Debroy C.
2009. 
Sharing of Escherichia coli sequence type ST131 and other multidrug-resistant and urovirulent E. coli strains among dogs and cats within a household. J. Clin. Microbiol.
47:3721–3725. 10.1128/JCM.01581-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01581-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772598</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19710261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clermont O, Lavollay M, Vimont S, Deschamps C, Forestier C, Branger C, Denamur E, Arlet G.
2008. 
The CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli diffusing clone belongs to a highly virulent B2 phylogenetic subgroup. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
61:1024–1028. 10.1093/jac/dkn084</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkn084</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18334490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibreel TM, Dodgson AR, Cheesbrough J, Bolton FJ, Fox AJ, Upton M.
2012. 
High metabolic potential may contribute to the success of ST131 uropathogenic Escherichia coli. J. Clin. Microbiol.
50:3202–3207. 10.1128/JCM.01423-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01423-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3457456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vimont S, Boyd A, Bleibtreu A, Bens M, Goujon JM, Garry L, Clermont O, Denamur E, Arlet G, Vandewalle A.
2012. 
The CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli clone O25b: H4-ST131 has high intestine colonization and urinary tract infection abilities. PLoS One
7:e46547. 10.1371/journal.pone.0046547</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0046547</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23029548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinez-Medina M, Mora A, Blanco M, Lopez C, Alonso MP, Bonacorsi S, Nicolas-Chanoine MH, Darfeuille-Michaud A, Garcia-Gil J, Blanco J.
2009. 
Similarity and divergence among adherent-invasive Escherichia coli and extraintestinal pathogenic E. coli strains. J. Clin. Microbiol.
47:3968–3979. 10.1128/JCM.01484-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01484-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Totsika M, Beatson SA, Sarkar S, Phan MD, Petty NK, Bachmann N, Szubert M, Sidjabat HE, Paterson DL, Upton M, Schrembi MA.
2011. 
Insights into a multidrug resistant Escherichia coli pathogen of the globally disseminated ST131 lineage: genome analysis and virulence mechanisms. PLoS One
6:e26578. 10.1371/journal.pone.0026578</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0026578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203889</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22053197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Mulvey GL, Armstrong GD, Pitout JD.
2013. 
Virulence potential and adherence properties of Escherichia coli that produce CTX-M and NDM beta-lactamases. J. Med. Microbiol.
62:525–530. 10.1099/jmm.0.048983-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.048983-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23319311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Porter SB, Zhanel G, Kuskowski MA, Denamur E.
2012. 
Virulence of Escherichia coli clinical isolates in a murine sepsis model in relation to sequence type ST131 status, fluoroquinolone resistance, and virulence genotype. Infect. Immun.
80:1554–1562. 10.1128/IAI.06388-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.06388-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3318413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22311928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avasthi TS, Kumar N, Baddam R, Hussain A, Nandanwar N, Jadhav S, Ahmed N.
2011. 
Genome of multidrug-resistant uropathogenic Escherichia coli strain NA114 from India. J. Bacteriol.
193:4272–4273. 10.1128/JB.05413-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JB.05413-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3147708</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21685291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark G, Paszkiewicz K, Hale J, Weston V, Constantinidou C, Penn C, Achtman M, McNally A.
2012. 
Genomic analysis uncovers a phenotypically diverse but genetically homogeneous Escherichia coli ST131 clone circulating in unrelated urinary tract infections. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:868–877. 10.1093/jac/dkr585</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr585</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22258927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jadhav S, Hussain A, Devi S, Kumar A, Parveen S, Gandham N, Wieler LH, Ewers C, Ahmed N.
2011. 
Virulence characteristics and genetic affinities of multiple drug resistant uropathogenic Escherichia coli from a semi urban locality in India. PLoS One
6:e18063. 10.1371/journal.pone.0018063</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0018063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064663</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phan M-D, Peters KM, Sarkar S, Lukowski SW, Allsopp LP, Gomes Moriel D, Achard MES, Totsika M, Marshall VM, Upton M, Beatson SA, Schembri MA.
2013. 
The serum resistome of a globally disseminated multidrug resistant uropathogenic Escherichia coli clone. PLoS Genet.
9:e1003834. 10.1371/journal.pgen.1003834</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pgen.1003834</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Croxall G, Weston V, Joseph S, Manning G, Cheetham P, McNally A.
2011. 
Increased human pathogenic potential of Escherichia coli from polymicrobial urinary tract infections in comparison to isolates from monomicrobial culture samples. J. Med. Microbiol.
60:102–109. 10.1099/jmm.0.020602-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.020602-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNally A, Cheng L, Harris SR, Corander J.
2013. 
The evolutionary path to extraintestinal pathogenic, drug-resistant Escherichia coli is marked by drastic reduction in detectable recombination within the core genome. Genome Biol. Evol.
5:699–710. 10.1093/gbe/evt038</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gbe/evt038</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23493634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanco M, Alonso MP, Nicolas-Chanoine MH, Dahbi G, Mora A, Blanco JE, Lopez C, Cortes P, Llagostera M, Leflon-Guibout V, Puentes B, Mamani R, Herrera A, Coira MA, Garcia-Garrote F, Pita JM, Blanco J.
2009. 
Molecular epidemiology of Escherichia coli producing extended-spectrum β-lactamases in Lugo (Spain): dissemination of clone O25b:H4-ST131 producing CTX-M-15. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
63:1135–1141. 10.1093/jac/dkp122</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkp122</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19351692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu L, Shabir S, Bodah T, McMurray C, Hardy K, Hawkey P, Nye K.
2011. 
Regional survey of CTX-M-type extended-spectrum β-lactamases among Enterobacteriaceae reveals marked heterogeneity in the distribution of the ST131 clone. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:505–511. 10.1093/jac/dkq482</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21183528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simner PJ, Zhanel GG, Pitout J, Tailor F, McCracken M, Mulvey MR, Lagace-Wiens PR, Adam HJ, Hoban DJ.
2011. 
Prevalence and characterization of extended-spectrum β-lactamase- and AmpC β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli: results of the CANWARD 2007-2009 study. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
69:326–334. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2010.10.029</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2010.10.029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21353961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chandramohan L, Revell PA.
2012. 
Prevalence and molecular characterization of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae in a pediatric patient population. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:4765–4770. 10.1128/AAC.00666-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00666-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3421901</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22733062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yano H, Uemura M, Endo S, Kanamori H, Inomata S, Kakuta R, Ichimura S, Ogawa M, Shimojima M, Ishibashi N, Aoyagi T, Hatta M, Gu Y, Yamada M, Tokuda K, Kunishima H, Kitagawa M, Hirakata Y, Kaku M.
2013. 
Molecular characteristics of extended-spectrum β-Lactamases in clinical isolates from Escherichia coli at a Japanese tertiary hospital. PLoS One
8:e64359. 10.1371/journal.pone.0064359</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0064359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3654959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23691204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brolund A, Edquist PJ, Makitalo B, Olsson-Liljequist B, Soderblom T, Tegmark Wisell K, Giske CG.
3
October
2013. 
Epidemiology of ESBL-producing Escherichia coli in Sweden 2007-2011. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
10.1111/1469-0691.12413</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1469-0691.12413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24118431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reyna-Flores F, Barrios H, Garza-Ramos U, Sanchez-Perez A, Rojas-Moreno T, Uribe-Salas FJ, Fagundo-Sierra R, Silva-Sanchez J.
2013. 
Molecular epidemiology of Escherichia coli O25b-ST131 isolates causing community-acquired UTIs in Mexico. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
76:396–398. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2013.03.026</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2013.03.026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23774006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Hung King Sang J, Pitondo-Silva A, Laupland KB, Pitout JDD.
2012. 
Molecular epidemiology of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Klebsiella pneumoniae over a 10 year period in Calgary, Canada. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:1114–1120. 10.1093/jac/dks026</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22334607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang CI, Cha MK, Kim SH, Ko KS, Wi YM, Chung DR, Peck KR, Lee NY, Song J-H.
2013. 
Clinical and molecular epidemiology of community-onset bacteremia caused by extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli over a 6-year period. J. Korean Med. Sci.
28:998–1004. 10.3346/jkms.2013.28.7.998</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3346/jkms.2013.28.7.998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3708098</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23853481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitout JD, Campbell L, Church DL, Gregson DB, Laupland KB.
2009. 
Molecular characteristics of travel-related extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli isolates from the Calgary Health Region. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
53:2539–2543. 10.1128/AAC.00061-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00061-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2687226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19364876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Laupland KB, Gregson DB, Pitout JD.
2011. 
Colonization of returning travelers with CTX-M-producing Escherichia coli. J. Travel Med.
18:299–303. 10.1111/j.1708-8305.2011.00548.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1708-8305.2011.00548.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21896092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee MY, Choi HJ, Choi JY, Song M, Song Y, Kim SW, Chang HH, Jung SI, Kim YS, Ki HK, Son JS, Kwon KT, Heo ST, Yeom JS, Shin SY, Chung DR, Peck KR, Song JH, Ko KS.
2010. 
Dissemination of ST131 and ST393 community-onset, ciprofloxacin-resistant Escherichia coli clones causing urinary tract infections in Korea. J. Infect.
60:146–153. 10.1016/j.jinf.2009.11.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2009.11.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19932131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers BA, Kennedy KJ, Sidjabat HE, Jones M, Collignon P, Paterson DL.
2012. 
Prolonged carriage of resistant E. coli by returned travellers: clonality, risk factors and bacterial characteristics. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
31:2413–2420. 10.1007/s10096-012-1584-z</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-012-1584-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22391758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tangden T, Cars O, Melhus A, Lowdin E.
2010. 
Foreign travel is a major risk factor for colonization with Escherichia coli producing extended-spectrum β-lactamases of the CTX-M type: a prospective study on Swedish volunteers. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
54:3564–3568. 10.1128/AAC.00220-10</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00220-10</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2934993</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20547788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman JT, McBride SJ, Hefferman H, Bathgate T, Pope C, Ellis-Pegler R.
2008. 
Community-onset genitourinary tract infection due to CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli travelers to the Indian Subcontinent in New Zeland. Clin. Infect. Dis.
47:689–692. 10.1086/590941</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/590941</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18665816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laupland KB, Church DL, Vidakovich J, Mucenski M, Pitout JD.
2008. 
Community-onset extended-spectrum β-lactamase (ESBL) producing Escherichia coli: importance of international travel. J. Infect.
57:441–448. 10.1016/j.jinf.2008.09.034</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2008.09.034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18990451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Johnston B, Clabots C, Kuskowski MA, Pendyala S, Debroy C, Nowicki B, Rice J.
2010. 
Escherichia coli sequence type ST131 as an emerging fluoroquinolone-resistant uropathogen among renal transplant recipients. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
54:546–550. 10.1128/AAC.01089-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01089-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798475</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19917759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanco J, Mora A, Mamani R, Lopez C, Blanco M, Dahbi G, Herrera A, Blanco JE, Alonso MP, Garcia-Garrote F, Chaves F, Orellana MA, Martinez-Martinez L, Calvo J, Prats G, Larrosa MN, Gonzalez-Lopez JJ, Lopez-Cerero L, Rodriguez-Bano J, Pascual A.
2011. 
National survey of Escherichia coli causing extraintestinal infections reveals the spread of drug-resistant clonal groups O25b:H4-B2-ST131, O15:H1-D-ST393 and CGA-D-ST69 with high virulence gene content in Spain. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:2011–2021. 10.1093/jac/dkr235</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr235</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21669946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee R, Johnston B, Lohse C, Porter SB, Clabots C, Johnson JR.
2013. 
Escherichia coli sequence type 131 is a dominant, antimicrobial-resistant clonal group associated with healthcare and elderly hosts. Infect. Control. Hosp. Epidemiol.
34:361–369. 10.1086/669865</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/669865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3916146</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23466908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bert F, Johnson JR, Ouattara B, Leflon-Guibout V, Johnston B, Marcon E, Valla D, Moreau R, Nicolas-Chanoine MH.
2010. 
Genetic diversity and virulence profiles of Escherichia coli isolates causing spontaneous bacterial peritonitis and bacteremia in patients with cirrhosis. J. Clin. Microbiol.
48:2709–2714. 10.1128/JCM.00516-10</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00516-10</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20519468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horner C, Fawley W, Morris K, Parnell P, Denton M, Wilcox M.
2014. 
Escherichia coli bacteraemia: 2 years of prospective regional surveillance (2010-12). J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
69:91–100. 10.1093/jac/dkt333</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt333</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24003184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kudinha T, Johnson JR, Andrew SD, Kong F, Anderson P, Gilbert GL.
2013. 
Genotypic and phenotypic characterization of Escherichia coli isolates from children with urinary tract infection and from healthy carriers. Pediatr. Infect. Dis. J.
32:543–548. 10.1097/INF.0b013e31828ba3f1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0b013e31828ba3f1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23429563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chmielarczyk A, Pobiega M, Wojkowska-Mach J, Romaniszyn D, Adamski P, Heczko PB, Bulanda M.
2013. 
Molecular epidemiology, plasmid analysis, virulence, and resistance of Escherichia coli isolated from neonatal intensive care units in Poland. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
76:542–545. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2013.04.016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2013.04.016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23711531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee R, Robicsek A, Kuskowski MA, Porter S, Johnston BD, Sokurenko E, Tchesnokova V, Price LB, Johnson JR.
2013. 
Molecular epidemiology of Escherichia coli sequence type 131 and its H30 and H30-Rx subclones among extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-positive and -negative E. coli clinical isolates from the Chicago region, 2007 to 2010. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
57:6385–6388. 10.1128/AAC.01604-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01604-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837873</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24080662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung H-C, Lai C-H, Lin J-N, Huang C-K, Liang S-H, Chen W-F, Shih Y-C, Lin H-H, Wang J-L.
2012. 
Bacteremia caused by extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli sequence type ST131 and non-ST131 clones: comparison of demographic data, clinical features, and mortality. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:618–622. 10.1128/AAC.05753-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.05753-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22123694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karfunkel D, Carmeli Y, Chmelnitsky I, Kotlovsky T, Navon-Venezia S.
2013. 
The emergence and dissemination of CTX-M-producing Escherichia coli sequence type 131 causing community-onset bacteremia in Israel. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
32:513–521. 10.1007/s10096-012-1765-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-012-1765-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23117265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li B, Sun JY, Liu QZ, Han LZ, Huang XH, Ni YX.
2011. 
High prevalence of CTX-M β-lactamases in feacal Escherichia coli strains from healthy humans in Fuzhou, China. Scand. J. Infect. Dis.
43:170–174. 10.3109/00365548.2010.538856</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365548.2010.538856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, Gruson C, Bialek-Davenet S, Bertrand X, Thomas-Jean F, Bert F, Moyat M, Meiller E, Marcon E, Danchin N, Noussair L, Moreau R, Leflon-Guibout V.
2013. 
10-Fold increase (2006-11) in the rate of healthy subjects with extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli faecal carriage in a Parisian check-up centre. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:562–568. 10.1093/jac/dks429</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks429</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23143897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arvand M, Moser V, Pfeifer Y.
2013. 
Prevalence of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli and spread of the epidemic clonal lineage ST131 in nursing homes in Hesse, Germany. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:2686–2688. 10.1093/jac/dkt226</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23759669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nuesch-Inderbinen MT, Abgottspon H, Zurfluh K, Nuesch HJ, Stephan R, Hachler H.
2013. 
Cross-sectional study on fecal carriage of Enterobacteriaceae with resistance to extended-spectrum cephalosporins in primary care patients. Microb. Drug Resist.
19:362–369. 10.1089/mdr.2013.0013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/mdr.2013.0013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23611297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Severin JA, Lestari ES, Kloezen W, Lemmens-den Toom N, Mertaniasih NM, Kuntaman K, Purwanta M, Offra Duerink D, Hadi U, van Belkum A, Verbrugh HA, Goessens WH.
2012. 
Faecal carriage of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae among humans in Java, Indonesia, in 2001-2002. Trop. Med. Int. Health
17:455–461. 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2011.02949.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3156.2011.02949.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22248076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JR, Clabots C.
2006. 
Sharing of virulent Escherichia coli clones among household members of a woman with acute cystitis. Clin. Infect. Dis.
43:101–108. 10.1086/508541</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/508541</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17051483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ewers C, Grobbel M, Stamm I, Kopp PA, Diehl I, Semmler T, Fruth A, Beutlich J, Guerra B, Wieler LH, Guenther S.
2010. 
Emergence of human pandemic O25:H4-ST131 CTX-M-15 extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli among companion animals. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:651–660. 10.1093/jac/dkq004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harada K, Nakai Y, Kataoka Y.
2012. 
Mechanisms of resistance to cephalosporin and emergence of O25b-ST131 clone harboring CTX-M-27 β-lactamase in extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli from dogs and cats in Japan. Microbiol. Immunol.
56:480–485. 10.1111/j.1348-0421.2012.00463.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1348-0421.2012.00463.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22486529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Platell JL, Cobbold RN, Johnson JR, Trott DJ.
2010. 
Clonal group distribution of fluoroquinolone-resistant Escherichia coli among humans and companion animals in Australia. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:1936–1938. 10.1093/jac/dkq236</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq236</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20570998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo S, Brouwers HJM, Cobbold RN, Platell JL, Chapman TA, Barrs VR, Johnson JR, Trott DJ.
2013. 
Fluoroquinolone-resistant extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli, including O25b-ST131, isolated from faeces of hospitalized dogs in an Australian veterinary referral centre. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:1025–1031. 10.1093/jac/dks515</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks515</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23299573</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huber H, Zweifel C, Wittenbrink MM, Stephan R.
2013. 
ESBL-producing uropathogenic Escherichia coli isolated from dogs and cats in Switzerland. Vet. Microbiol.
162:992–996. 10.1016/j.vetmic.2012.10.029</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetmic.2012.10.029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23177909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamang MD, Nam HM, Jang GC, Kim SR, Chae MH, Jung SC, Byun JW, Park YH, Lim SK.
2012. 
Molecular characterization of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing and plasmid-mediated AmpC β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli isolated from stray dogs in South Korea. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:2705–2712. 10.1128/AAC.05598-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.05598-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3346616</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22354297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dierikx CM, van Duijkeren E, Schoormans AH, van Essen-Zandbergen A, Veldman K, Kant A, Huijsdens XW, van der Zwaluw K, Wagenaar JA, Mevius DJ.
2012. 
Occurrence and characteristics of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase- and AmpC-producing clinical isolates derived from companion animals and horses. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:1368–1374. 10.1093/jac/dks049</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22382469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albrechtova K, Dolejska M, Cizek A, Tausova D, Klimes J, Bebora L, Literak I.
2012. 
Dogs of nomadic pastoralists in northern Kenya are reservoirs of plasmid-mediated cephalosporin- and quinolone-resistant Escherichia coli, including pandemic clone B2-O25-ST131. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:4013–4017. 10.1128/AAC.05859-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.05859-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3393422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22508313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schink AK, Kadlec K, Kaspar H, Mankertz J, Schwarz S.
2013. 
Analysis of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli isolates collected in the GERM-Vet. monitoring programme. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:1741–1749. 10.1093/jac/dkt123</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23599361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu G, Day MJ, Mafura MT, Nunez-Garcia J, Fenner JJ, Sharma M, van Essen-Zandbergen A, Rodriguez I, Dierikx C, Kadlec K, Schink AK, Wain J, Helmuth R, Guerra B, Schwarz S, Threlfall J, Woodward MJ, Woodford N, Coldham N, Mevius D.
2013. 
Comparative analysis of ESBL-positive Escherichia coli isolates from animals and humans from the UK, the Netherlands and Germany. PLoS One
8:75392. 10.1371/journal.pone.0075392</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0075392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3784421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24086522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Randall LP, Clouting C, Horton RA, Coldham NG, Wu G, Clifton-Hadley FA, Davies RH, Teale CJ.
2011. 
Prevalence of Escherichia coli carrying extended-spectrum β-lactamases (CTX-M and TEM-52) from broiler chickens and turkeys in Great Britain between 2006 and 2009. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:86–95. 10.1093/jac/dkq396</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq396</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cortes P, Blanc V, Mora A, Dahbi G, Blanco JE, Blanco M, Lopez C, Andreu A, Navarro F, Alonso MP, Bou G, Blanco J, Llagostera M.
2010. 
Isolation and characterization of potentially pathogenic antimicrobial-resistant Escherichia coli strains from chicken and pig farms in Spain. Appl. Environ. Microbiol.
76:2799–2805. 10.1128/AEM.02421-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.02421-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2863447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20228098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuffre M, Cipolla D, Bonura C, Geraci DM, Aleo A, Di Noto S, Nociforo F, Corsello G, Mammina C.
2013. 
Outbreak of colonizations by extended-spectrum b-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli sequence type 131 in a neonatal intensive care unit, Italy. Antimicrob. Resist. Infect. Control.
2:8. 10.1186/2047-2994-2-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2047-2994-2-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3614428</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dahmen S, Metayer V, Gay E, Madec JY, Haenni M.
2013. 
Characterization of extended-spectrum β-lactamase (ESBL)-carrying plasmids and clones of Enterobacteriaceae causing cattle mastitis in France. Vet. Microbiol.
162:793–799. 10.1016/j.vetmic.2012.10.015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetmic.2012.10.015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23127568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hordijk J, Wagenaar JA, van de Giessen A, Dierikx C, van Essen-Zandbergen A, Veldman K, Kant A, Mevius DJ.
2013. 
Increasing prevalence and diversity of ESBL/AmpC-type β-lactamase genes in Escherichia coli isolated from veal calves from 1997 to 2010. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:1970–1973. 10.1093/jac/dkt132</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt132</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leverstein-van Hall MA, Dierikx CM, Cohen Stuart J, Voets GM, van den Munckhof MP, van Essen-Zandbergen A, Platteel T, Fluit AC, van de Sande-Bruinsma N, Scharinga J, Bonten MJ, Mevius DJ.
2011. 
Dutch patients, retail chicken meat and poultry share the same ESBL genes, plasmids and strains. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
17:873–880. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03497.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03497.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21463397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Overdevest I, Willemsen I, Rijnsburger M, Eustace A, Xu L, Hawkey P, Heck M, Savelkoul P, Vandenbroucke-Grauls C, Van der Zwaluw K, Huijsdens X, Kluytmans J.
2011. 
Extended-spectrum β-lactamase genes of Escherichia coli in chicken meat and humans, the Netherlands. Emerg. Infect. Dis.
17:1216–1222. 10.3201/eid1707.110209</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1707.110209</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21762575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madec J-Y, Poirel L, Saras E, Gourguechon A, Girlich D, Nordmann P, Haenni M.
2012. 
Non-ST131 Escherichia coli from cattle harbouring human-like blaCTX-M-15-carrying plasmids. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:578–581. 10.1093/jac/dkr542</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22210752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng H, Zeng Z, Chen S, Liu Y, Yao Q, Deng Y, Chen X, Lv L, Zhuo C, Chen Z, Liu J-H.
2012. 
Prevalence and characterisation of CTX-M β-lactamases amongst Escherichia coli isolates from healthy food animals in China. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
39:305–310. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2011.12.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2011.12.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22325120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent C, Boerlin P, Daignault D, Dozois CM, Dutil L, Galanakis C, Reid-Smith RJ, Tellier PP, Tellis PA, Ziebell K, Manges AR.
2010. 
Food reservoir for Escherichia coli causing urinary tract infections. Emerg. Infect. Dis.
16:88–95. 10.3201/eid1601.091118</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1601.091118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2874376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhanji H, Murphy NM, Doumith M, Durmus S, Lee SS, Hope R, Woodford N, Livermore DM.
2010. 
Cephalosporin resistance mechanisms in Escherichia coli isolated from raw chicken imported into the UK. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:2534–2537. 10.1093/jac/dkq376</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20889530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egea P, Lopez-Cerero L, Torres E, Gomez-Sanchez Mdel C, Serrano L, Navarro Sanchez-Ortiz MD, Rodriguez-Bano J, Pascual A.
2012. 
Increased raw poultry meat colonization by extended spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli in the South of Spain. Int. J. Food Microbiol.
159:69–73. 10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2012.08.002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2012.08.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23072690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez J, Bonnedahl J, Eliasson I, Wallensten A, Comstedt P, Johansson A, Granholm S, Melhus A, Olsen B, Drobni M.
2010. 
Globally disseminated human pathogenic Escherichia coli of O25b-ST131 clone, harbouring blaCTX-M-15, found in Glaucous-winged gull at remote Commander Islands, Russia. Environ. Microbiol. Rep.
2:329–332. 10.1111/j.1758-2229.2010.00142.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1758-2229.2010.00142.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23766085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simoes RR, Poirel L, Da Costa PM, Nordmann P.
2010. 
Seagulls and beaches as reservoirs for multidrug-resistant Escherichia coli. Emerg. Infect. Dis.
16:110–112. 10.3201/eid1601.090896</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1601.090896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2874366</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tausova D, Dolejska M, Cizek A, Hanusova L, Hrusakova J, Svoboda O, Camlik G, Literak I.
2012. 
Escherichia coli with extended-spectrum β-lactamase and plasmid-mediated quinolone resistance genes in great cormorants and mallards in Central Europe. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:1103–1107. 10.1093/jac/dks017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22323500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guenther S, Grobbel M, Beutlich J, Guerra B, Ulrich RG, Wieler LH, Ewers C.
2010. 
Detection of pandemic B2-O25-ST131 Escherichia coli harbouring the CTX-M-9 extended-spectrum β-lactamase type in a feral urban brown rat (Rattus norvegicus). J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:582–584. 10.1093/jac/dkp496</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkp496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dahmen S, Haenni M, Châtre P, Madec J-Y.
2013. 
Characterization of blaCTX-M IncFII plasmids and clones of Escherichia coli from pets in France. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:2797–2801. 10.1093/jac/dkt291</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkt291</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giufre M, Graziani C, Accogli M, Luzzi I, Busani L, Cerquetti M.
2012. 
Escherichia coli of human and avian origin: detection of clonal groups associated with fluoroquinolone and multidrug resistance in Italy. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:860–867. 10.1093/jac/dkr565</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr565</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22267238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trobos M, Christensen H, Sunde M, Nordentoft S, Agerso Y, Simonsen GS, Hammerum AM, Olsen JE.
2009. 
Characterization of sulphonamide-resistant Escherichia coli using comparison of sul2 gene sequences and multilocus sequence typing. Microbiology
155:831–836. 10.1099/mic.0.024190-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/mic.0.024190-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19246754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guenther S, Ewers C, Wieler LH.
2011. 
Extended-spectrum β-lactamases producing E. coli in wildlife, yet another form of environmental pollution?
Front. Microbiol.
2:246. 10.3389/fmicb.2011.00246</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2011.00246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3244693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22203818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Platell JL, Johnson JR, Cobbold RN, Trott DJ.
2011. 
Multidrug-resistant extraintestinal pathogenic Escherichia coli of sequence type ST131 in animals and foods. Vet. Microbiol.
153:99–108. 10.1016/j.vetmic.2011.05.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vetmic.2011.05.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21658865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jakobsen L, Sandvang D, Hansen LH, Bagger-Skjot L, Westh H, Jorgensen C, Hansen DS, Pedersen BM, Monnet DL, Frimodt-Moller N, Sorensen SJ, Hammerum AM.
2008. 
Characterisation, dissemination and persistence of gentamicin resistant Escherichia coli from a Danish university hospital to the waste water environment. Environ. Int.
34:108–115. 10.1016/j.envint.2007.07.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envint.2007.07.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17804070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galvin S, Boyle F, Hickey P, Vellinga A, Morris D, Cormican M.
2010. 
Enumeration and characterization of antimicrobial-resistant Escherichia coli bacteria in effluent from municipal, hospital, and secondary treatment facility sources. Appl. Environ. Microbiol.
76:4772–4779. 10.1128/AEM.02898-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.02898-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20525867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mesa RJ, Blanc V, Blanch AR, Cortes P, Gonzalez JJ, Lavilla S, Miro E, Muniesa M, Saco M, Tortola MT, Mirelis B, Coll P, Llagostera M, Prats G, Navarro F.
2006. 
Extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae in different environments (humans, food, animal farms and sewage). J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
58:211–215. 10.1093/jac/dkl211</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkl211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16720567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zarfel G, Galler H, Feierl G, Haas D, Kittinger C, Leitner E, Grisold AJ, Mascher F, Posch J, Pertschy B, Marth E, Reinthaler FF.
2013. 
Comparison of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase (ESBL) carrying Escherichia coli from sewage sludge and human urinary tract infection. Environ. Pollut.
173:192–199. 10.1016/j.envpol.2012.09.019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.envpol.2012.09.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23202650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colomer-Lluch M, Mora A, Lopez C, Mamani R, Dahbi G, Marzoa J, Herrera A, Viso S, Blanco JE, Blanco M, Alonso MP, Jofre J, Muniesa M, Blanco J.
2013. 
Detection of quinolone-resistant Escherichia coli isolates belonging to clonal groups O25b:H4-B2-ST131 and O25b:H4-D-ST69 in raw sewage and river water in Barcelona, Spain. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
68:758–765. 10.1093/jac/dks477</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23221627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolejska M, Frolkova P, Florek M, Jamborova I, Purgertova M, Kutilova I, Guenther ACS, Literak I.
2011. 
CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli clone B2-O25b-ST131 and Klebsiella spp. isolates in municipal wastewater treatment plant effluents. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
66:2784–2786. 10.1093/jac/dkr363</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkr363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vignaroli C, Luna GM, Pasquaroli S, Di Cesare A, Petruzzella R, Paroncini P, Biavasco F.
2013. 
Epidemic Escherichia coli ST131 and Enterococcus faecium ST17 in coastal marine sediments from an Italian beach. Environ. Sci. Technol.
47:13772–13780. 10.1021/es4019139</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/es4019139</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24195439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, Robert J, Vigan M, Laouenan C, Brisse S, Mentre F, Jarlier V.
2013. 
Different factors associated with CTX-M-producing ST131 and non-ST131 Escherichia coli clinical isolates. PLoS One
8:e72191. 10.1371/journal.pone.0072191</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0072191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3762868</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24023730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kluytmans JA, Overdevest ITM, Willemsen I, Kluytmans-van den Bergh MF, van der Zwaluw K, Heck M, Rijnsburger M, Vandenbroucke-Grauls CM, Savelkoul PHM, Johnston BD, Gordon D, Johnson JR.
2013. 
Extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli from retail chicken meat and humans: comparison of strains, plasmids, resistance genes, and virulence factors. Clin. Infect. Dis.
56:478–487. 10.1093/cid/cis929</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cis929</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23243181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen Stuart J, van den Munckhof T, Voets G, Scharringa J, Fluit A, Hall ML.
2012. 
Comparison of ESBL contamination in organic and conventional retail chicken meat. Int. J. Food Microbiol.
154:212–214. 10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2011.12.034</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijfoodmicro.2011.12.034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22260927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, Jarlier V, Robert J, Arlet G, Drieux L, Leflon-Guibout V, Laouénan C, Larroque B, Caro V, Mentré F, Study Group Coli β 
2012. 
Patient's origin and lifestyle associated with CTX-M-producing Escherichia coli: a case-control-control study. PLoS One
7:e30498. 10.1371/journal.pone.0030498</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0030498</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3267726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22299043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Bano J, Picon E, Gijon P, Hernandez JR, Cisneros JM, Pena C, Almela M, Almirante B, Grill F, Colomina J, Molinos S, Oliver A, Fernandez-Mazarrasa C, Navarro G, Coloma A, Lopez-Cerero L, Pascual A.
2010. 
Risk factors and prognosis of nosocomial bloodstream infections caused by extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli. J. Clin. Microbiol.
48:1726–1731. 10.1128/JCM.02353-09</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.02353-09</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2863889</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20181897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Bano J, Picon E, Gijon P, Hernandez JR, Ruiz M, Pena C, Almela M, Almirante B, Grill F, Colomina J, Gimenez M, Oliver A, Horcajada JP, Navarro G, Coloma A, Pascual A.
2010. 
Community-onset bacteremia due to extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli: risk factors and prognosis. Clin. Infect. Dis.
50:40–48. 10.1086/649537</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/649537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19995215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta K, Hooton TM, Naber KG, Wullt B, Colgan R, Miller LG, Moran GJ, Nicolle LE, Raz R, Schaeffer AJ, Soper DE.
2011. 
International clinical practice guidelines for the treatment of acute uncomplicated cystitis and pyelonephritis in women: a 2010 update by the Infectious Diseases Society of America and the European Society for Microbiology and Infectious Diseases. Clin. Infect. Dis.
52:103–120. 10.1093/cid/ciq257</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciq257</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oteo J, Orden B, Bautista V, Cuevas O, Arroyo M, Martinez-Ruiz R, Perez-Vazquez M, Alcaraz M, Garcia-Cobos S, Campos J.
2009. 
CTX-M-15-producing urinary Escherichia coli O25b-ST131-phylogroup B2 has acquired resistance to fosfomycin. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
64:712–717. 10.1093/jac/dkp288</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkp288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19671590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pouillot F, Chomton M, Blois H, Courroux C, Noelig J, Bidet P, Bingen E, Bonacorsi S.
2012. 
Efficacy of bacteriophage therapy in experimental sepsis and meningitis caused by a clone O25b:H4-ST131 Escherichia coli strain producing CTX-M-15. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:3568–3575. 10.1128/AAC.06330-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.06330-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3393425</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22491690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Totsika M, Kostakioti M, Hannan TJ, Upton M, Beatson SA, Janetka JW, Hultgren SJ, Schembri MA.
2013. 
A FimH inhibitor prevents acute bladder infection and treats chronic cystitis caused by multidrug-resistant uropathogenic Escherichia coli ST131. J. Infect. Dis.
208:921–928. 10.1093/infdis/jit245</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jit245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3749003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23737602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitout JD.
2010. 
Infections with ESBL-producing Enterobacteriaceae: changing epidemiology and drug treatment choices. Drugs
70:313–333. 10.2165/11533040-000000000-00000</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11533040-000000000-00000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20166768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Pitout JD.
2010. 
Molecular epidemiology of Escherichia coli producing CTX-M β-lactamases: the worldwide emergence of clone ST131 O25:H4. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents.
35:316–321. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2009.11.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2009.11.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20060273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Literacka E, Bedenic B, Baraniak A, Fiett J, Tonkic M, Jajic-Bencic I, Gniadkowski M.
2009. 
blaCTX-M genes in Escherichia coli strains from Croatian hospitals are located in new (blaCTX-M-3a) and widely spread (blaCTX-M-3a and blaCTX-M-15) genetic structures. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
53:1630–1635. 10.1128/AAC.01431-08</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.01431-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2663074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nielsen JB, Albayati A, Jorgensen RL, Hansen KH, Lundgren B, Schonning K.
2013. 
An abbreviated MLVA identifies Escherichia coli ST131 as the major extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing lineage in the Copenhagen area. Eur. J. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
32:431–436. 10.1007/s10096-012-1764-x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-012-1764-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23129461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerquetti M, Giufre M, Garcia-Fernandez A, Accogli M, Fortini D, Luzzi I, Carattoli A.
2010. 
Ciprofloxacin-resistant, CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli ST131 clone in extraintestinal infections in Italy. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
16:1555–1558. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2010.03162.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2010.03162.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20121822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Bij AK, Peirano G, Goessens WH, van der Vorm ER, van Westreenen M, Pitout JD.
2011. 
Clinical and molecular characteristics of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli causing bacteremia in the Rotterdam area, Netherlands. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
55:3576–3578. 10.1128/AAC.00074-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00074-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3122469</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woksepp H, Jernberg C, Tarnberg M, Ryberg A, Brolund A, Nordvall M, Olsson-Liljequist B, Wisell KT, Monstein H-J, Nilsson L, Schon T.
2011. 
High-resolution melting-curve analysis of ligation-mediated real-time PCR for rapid evaluation of an epidemiological outbreak of extended-spectrum-β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli. J. Clin. Microbiol.
49:4032–4039. 10.1128/JCM.01042-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.01042-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3232983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21956981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zong Z, Yu R.
2011. 
blaCTX-M-carrying Escherichia coli of the O25b ST131 clonal group have emerged in China. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
69:228–231. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2010.10.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2010.10.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21251572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ho P-L, Lo WU, Lai EL, Chow K-H, Yam W-C.
2012. 
Escherichia coli O25b-ST131 is an important cause of antimicrobial-resistant infections in women with uncomplicated cystitis. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
67:2534–2535. 10.1093/jac/dks248</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22729922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy S, Krishnan R, Mukherjee S, Schneiders T, Niyogi SK, Basu S.
2013. 
Prevalence of ST131 virulence-associated strains among CTX-M-producing Escherichia coli in the gut of hospitalized neonates in India. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
77:158–159. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2013.06.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2013.06.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23891225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adler A, Gniadkowski M, Baraniak A, Izdebski R, Fiett J, Hryniewicz W, Malhotra-Kumar S, Goossens H, Lammens C, Lerman Y, Kazma M, Kotlovsky T, Carmeli Y, groups MWaWs 
2012. 
Transmission dynamics of ESBL-producing Escherichia coli clones in rehabilitation wards at a tertiary care centre. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
18:E497–E505</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22963432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokota S-i, Sato T, Okubo T, Ohkoshi Y, Okabayashi T, Kuwahara O, Tamura Y, Fujii N.
2012. 
Prevalence of fluoroquinolone-resistant Escherichia coli O25:H4-ST131 (CTX-M-15-nonproducing) strains isolated in Japan. Chemotherapy
58:52–59. 10.1159/000336129</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000336129</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22343392</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yumuk Z, Afacan G, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H, Sotto A, Lavigne JP.
2008. 
Turkey: a further country concerned by community acquired Escherichia coli clone O25-ST131 producing CTX-M-15. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
62:284–288. 10.1093/jac/dkn181</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkn181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18453527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szijarto V, Pal T, Nagy G, Nagy E, Ghazawi A, al-Haj M, El Kurdi S, Sonnevend A.
2012. 
The rapidly emerging ESBL-producing Escherichia coli O25-ST131 clone carries LPS core synthesis genes of the K-12 type. FEMS Microbiol. Lett.
332:131–136. 10.1111/j.1574-6968.2012.02585.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1574-6968.2012.02585.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22537083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiruvury H, Johnson JR, Mariano N, Grenner L, Colon-Urban R, Erritouni M, Wehbeh W, Segal-Maurer S, Rahal JJ, Johnston B, Urban C.
2012. 
Identification of CTX-M β-lactamases among Escherichia coli from the community in New York City. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
72:248–252. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2011.11.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2011.11.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22257571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sennati S, Santella G, Di Conza J, Pallecchi L, Pino M, Ghiglione B, Rossolini GM, Radice M, Gutkind G.
2012. 
Changing epidemiology of extended-spectrum β-lactamases in Argentina: emergence of CTX-M-15. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother.
56:6003–6005. 10.1128/AAC.00745-12</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00745-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3486548</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22908156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, Asensi MD, Pitondo-Silva A, Pitout JD.
2011. 
Molecular characteristics of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli from Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
17:1039–1043. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2010.03440.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2010.03440.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21722255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz SJ, Montealegre MC, Ruiz-Garbajosa P, Correa A, Briceno DF, Martinez E, Rosso F, Munoz M, Quinn JP, Canton R, Villegas MV.
2011. 
First characterization of CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli ST131 and ST405 clones causing community-onset infections in South America. J. Clin. Microbiol.
49:1993–1996. 10.1128/JCM.00045-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00045-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3122632</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21325548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molina-Lopez J, Aparicio-Ozores G, Ribas-Aparicio RM, Gavilanes-Parra S, Chavez-Berrocal ME, Hernandez-Castro R, Manjarrez-Hernandez HA.
2011. 
Drug resistance, serotypes, and phylogenetic groups among uropathogenic Escherichia coli including O25-ST131 in Mexico City. J. Infect. Dev. Ctries.
5:840–849. 10.3855/jidc.1703</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3855/jidc.1703</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22169782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magoue CL, Melin P, Gangoue-Pieboji J, Okomo Assoumou MC, Boreux R, De Mol P.
2013. 
Prevalence and spread of extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae in Ngaoundere, Cameroon. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
19:E416–E420. 10.1111/1469-0691.12239</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1469-0691.12239</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23647948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fam N, Leflon-Guibout V, Fouad S, Aboul-Fadl L, Marcon E, Desouky D, El-Defrawy I, Abou-Aitta A, Klena J, Nicolas-Chanoine M-H.
2011. 
CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli clinical isolates in Cairo (Egypt), including isolates of clonal complex ST10 and clones ST131, ST73, and ST405 in both community and hospital settings. Microb. Drug Resist.
17:67–73. 10.1089/mdr.2010.0063</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/mdr.2010.0063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rakotonirina HC, Garin B, Randrianirina F, Richard V, Talarmin A, Arlet G.
2013. 
Molecular characterization of multidrug-resistant extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae isolated in Antananarivo, Madagascar. BMC Microbiol.
13:85. 10.1186/1471-2180-13-85</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2180-13-85</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3639105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23594374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aibinu I, Odugbemi T, Koenig W, Ghebremedhin B.
2012. 
Sequence type ST131 and ST10 complex (ST617) predominant among CTX-M-15-producing Escherichia coli isolates from Nigeria. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
18:E49–E51. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03730.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03730.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22192452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peirano G, van Greune CHJ, Pitout JDD.
2011. 
Characteristics of infections caused by extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Escherichia coli from community hospitals in South Africa. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
69:449–453. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2010.11.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2010.11.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21396544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mshana SE, Imirzalioglu C, Hain T, Domann E, Lyamuya EF, Chakraborty T.
2011. 
Multiple ST clonal complexes, with a predominance of ST131, of Escherichia coli harbouring blaCTX-M-15 in a tertiary hospital in Tanzania. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
17:1279–1282. 10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03518.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03518.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21595794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dahmen S, Bettaieb D, Mansour W, Boujaafar N, Bouallegue O, Arlet G.
2010. 
Characterization and molecular epidemiology of extended-spectrum β-lactamases in clinical isolates of Enterobacteriaceae in a Tunisian university hospital. Microb. Drug Resist.
16:163–170. 10.1089/mdr.2009.0108</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/mdr.2009.0108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20438347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kudinha T, Johnson JR, Andrew SD, Kong F, Anderson P, Gilbert GL.
2013. 
Distribution of phylogenetic groups, sequence type ST131, and virulence-associated traits among Escherichia coli isolates from men with pyelonephritis or cystitis and healthy controls. Clin. Microbiol. Infect.
19:E173–E180. 10.1111/1469-0691.12123</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1469-0691.12123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23398521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidjabat HE, Derrington P, Nimmo GR, Paterson DL.
2010. 
Escherichia coli ST131 producing CTX-M-15 in Australia. J. Antimicrob. Chemother.
65:1301–1303. 10.1093/jac/dkq098</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkq098</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20378669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamson DA, Roberts SA, Paterson DL, Sidjabat H, Silvey A, Masters J, Rice M, Freeman JT.
2012. 
Escherichia coli bloodstream infection after transrectal ultrasound-guided prostate biopsy: implications of fluoroquinolone-resistant sequence type 131 as a major causative pathogen. Clin. Infect. Dis.
54:1406–1412. 10.1093/cid/cis194</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/cis194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22419681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
