<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">25028535</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1177-8881</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>8</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2014</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Drug design, development and therapy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Drug Des Devel Ther</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Quetiapine for acute bipolar depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>827</StartPage>
          <EndPage>838</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>827-38</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/DDDT.S63779</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Precise estimated risks and benefits of quetiapine for acute bipolar depression are needed for clinical practice.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To systematically review the efficacy and the tolerability of quetiapine, either as monotherapy or combination therapy, for acute bipolar depression.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We included all randomized, controlled trials (RCTs) comparing quetiapine with other treatments, including placebo, in patients with acute bipolar depression (bipolar I or II disorder, major depressive episode). Published and unpublished RCTs were identified using the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, MEDLINE, Web of Knowledge, CINAHL, PsycINFO, the EU Clinical Trials Register database, and ClinicalTrials.gov. The primary outcome was the change scores of depression rating scales.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eleven RCTs (n=3,488) were included. Two of them were conducted in children and adolescents. The change in depression scores was significantly greater in the quetiapine group compared with the placebo group (mean difference, [MD] =-4.66, 95% confidence interval [CI] -5.59 to -3.73). The significant difference was observed from week 1. Compared with placebo, quetiapine had higher incidence rates of extrapyramidal side effects, sedation, somnolence, dizziness, fatigue, constipation, dry mouth, increased appetite, and weight gain but lower risks of treatment-emergent mania and headache. Quetiapine treatment was associated with significant improvement of clinical global impression, quality of life, sleep quality, anxiety, and functioning.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Quetiapine monotherapy is effective for acute bipolar depression and the prevention of mania/hypomania switching. Its common adverse effects are extrapyramidal side effects, sedation, somnolence, dizziness, fatigue, constipation, dry mouth, increased appetite, and weight gain. The lower risk of headache in quetiapine-treated patients with acute bipolar depression should be further investigated. The evidence for the use of quetiapine combined with mood stabilizers in children and adolescents with acute bipolar depression is too small to support the clinical practice.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suttajit</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sirijit</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Srisurapanont</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manit</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maneeton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Narong</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maneeton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Benchalak</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Faculty of Medicine, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Drug Des Devel Ther</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101475745</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1177-8881</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>2S3PL1B6UJ</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000069348">Quetiapine Fumarate</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000208" MajorTopicYN="N">Acute Disease</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001714" MajorTopicYN="N">Bipolar Disorder</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069348" MajorTopicYN="N">Quetiapine Fumarate</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antipsychotic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dropout</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">efficacy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">remission</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">response</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">side effects</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028535</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077390</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DDDT.S63779</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">dddt-8-827</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merikangas KR, Akiskal HS, Angst J, et al.  Lifetime and 12-month prevalence of bipolar spectrum disorder in the National Comorbidity Survey replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2007;64(5):543–552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1931566</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17485606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods SW. The economic burden of bipolar disease. J Clin Psychiatry. 2000;61(Supp 13):S38–S41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11153811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angst F, Stassen HH, Clayton PJ, Angst J. Mortality of patients with mood disorders: follow-up over 34–38 years. J Affect Disord. 2002;68(2–3):167–181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12063145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodwin FK, Jamison KR.  Manic-Depressive Illness. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 1990. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suttajit S, Srisurapanont M, Xia J, Suttajit S, Maneeton B, Maneeton N. Quetiapine versus typical antipsychotic medications for schizophrenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013;5:CD007815.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grunze H, Vieta E, Goodwin GM, et al. WFSBP Task Force On Treatment Guidelines For Bipolar Disorders  The World Federation of Societies of Biological Psychiatry (WFSBP) Guidelines for the Biological Treatment of Bipolar Disorders: Update 2010 on the treatment of acute bipolar depression. World J Biol Psychiatry. 2010;11(2):81–109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yatham LN, Kennedy SH, Parikh SV, et al.  Canadian Network for Mood and Anxiety Treatments (CANMAT) and International Society for Bipolar Disorders (ISBD) collaborative update of CANMAT guidelines for the management of patients with bipolar disorder: update 2013. Bipolar Disord. 2013;15(1):1–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23237061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen NH, Rodriguiz RM, Caron MG, Wetsel WC, Rothman RB, Roth BL. N-desalkylquetiapine, a potent norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor and partial 5-HT1A agonist, as a putative mediator of quetiapine’s antidepressant activity. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2008;33(10):2303–2312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18059438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yatham LN, Goldstein JM, Vieta E, et al.  Atypical antipsychotics in bipolar depression: potential mechanisms of action. J Clin Psychiatry. 2005;66( Suppl 5):40–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16038601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montgomery SA, Asberg M. A new depression scale designed to be sensitive to change. Br J Psychiatry. 1979;134(4):382–389.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">444788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayes TL, Bernstein IH, Haley CL, Kennard BD, Emslie GJ. Psychometric properties of the Children’s Depression Rating Scale-Revised in adolescents. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2010;20(6):513–516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3003451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21186970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guy W, editor. ECDEU Assessment Manual for Psychopharmacology. Rockville, MD: US Department of Heath, Education, and Welfare Public Health Service Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Administration; 1976. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spearing MK, Post RM, Leverich GS, et al.  Modification of the Clinical Global Impressions (CGI) Scale for use in bipolar illness (BP): the CGI-BP. Psychiatry Res. 1997;73(3):159–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9481807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamilton M. The assessment of anxiety states by rating. Br J Med Psychol. 1959;32:50–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13638508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Endicott J, Nee J, Harrison W, Blumenthal R. Quality of Life Enjoyment and Satisfaction Questionnaire: a new measure. Psychopharmacol Bull. 1993;29(2):321–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8290681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buysse DJ, Reynolds CF, 3rd, Monk TH, Berman SR, Kupfer DJ. The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index: a new instrument for psychiatric practice and research. Psychiatry Res. May. 1989;28(2):193–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2748771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheehan DV.  The Anxiety Disease. New York: Scribner’s; 1983. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S, editors. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0. Oxford: The Cochrane Collaboration; Mar, 2011. 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boissel JP, Cucherat M, Li W, et al.  The problem of therapeutic efficacy indices. 3. Comparison of the indices and their use. Thérapie. 1999;54(4):405–411. French.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10667106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deeks JJ. Issues in the selection of a summary statistic for meta-analysis of clinical trials with binary outcomes. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1575–1600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557–560.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AstraZeneca [Webpage on Internet]  Effectiveness of Quetiapine XR versus Sertraline in acute depression as add-on therapy to previous mood stabilizer treatment: a pilot study. 2012.  [Accessed September 17, 2013].  Available from:  http://www.astrazenecaclinicaltrials.com/Submission/View?id=1406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AstraZeneca [Webpage on Internet]  A Randomised, Multi-Centre Study to Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Extended Release Quetiapine Fumarate (Seroquel XR) Tablets as Mono-Therapy or in Combination with Lithium in the Treatment of Patients with Acute Bipolar Depression. 2012.  [Accessed September 17, 2013].  Available from:  http://astrazenecagrouptrials.pharmacm.com/Submission/View?id=1405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calabrese JR, Keck PE, Jr, Macfadden W, et al.  A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of quetiapine in the treatment of bipolar I or II depression. Am J Psychiatry. 2005 Jul;162(7):1351–1360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15994719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McElroy SL, Weisler RH, Chang W, et al.  EMBOLDEN II (Trial D1447C00134) Investigators. A double-blind, placebo-controlled study of quetiapine and paroxetine as monotherapy in adults with bipolar depression (EMBOLDEN II) J Clin Psychiatry. 2010;71(2):163–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20122366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riesenberg RA, Baldytcheva I, Datto C. Self-reported sedation profile of quetiapine extended-release and quetiapine immediate-release during 6-day initial dose escalation in bipolar depression: a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, phase IV study. Clin Ther. 2012;34(11):2202–2211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23059166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suppes T, Datto C, Minkwitz M, Nordenhem A, Walker C, Darko D. Effectiveness of the extended release formulation of quetiapine as monotherapy for the treatment of acute bipolar depression. J Affect Disord. 2010;121(1–2):106–115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19903574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swartz HA, Frank E, Cheng Y. A randomized pilot study of psychotherapy and quetiapine for the acute treatment of bipolar II depression. Bipolar Disord. 2012;14(2):211–216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3307150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22420597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thase ME, Macfadden W, Weisler RH, et al. BOLDER II Study Group  Efficacy of quetiapine monotherapy in bipolar I and II depression: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study (the BOLDER II study) J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2006;26(6):600–609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17110817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young AH, McElroy SL, Bauer M, et al. EMBOLDEN I (Trial 001) Investigators  A double-blind, placebo-controlled study of quetiapine and lithium monotherapy in adults in the acute phase of bipolar depression (EMBOLDEN I) J Clin Psychiatry. 2010;71(2):150–162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20122369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AstraZeneca [Webpage on Internet]  An 8-week, Multicenter, Double-blind, Randomized, Parallel-group, Placebo-controlled Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Quetiapine Fumarate (SEROQUEL) Extended-Release in Children and Adolescent Subjects with Bipolar Depression. 2011.  [Accessed September 17, 2013].  Available from:  http://www.astrazenecaclinicaltrials.com/Submission/View?id=1464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DelBello MP, Chang K, Welge JA, et al.  A double-blind, placebo-controlled pilot study of quetiapine for depressed adolescents with bipolar disorder. Bipolar Disord. 2009;11(5):483–493.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19624387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bond A, Lader M. The use of analogue scales in rating subjective feelings. British Journal of Medical Psychology. 1974;47(3):211–218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seeman P. Atypical antipsychotics: mechanism of action. Can J Psychiatry. 2002;47(1):27–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11873706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marmura MJ. Use of dopamine antagonists in treatment of migraine. Curr Treat Options Neurol. 2012;14(1):27–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22012659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krymchantowski AV, Jevoux C, Moreira PF. An open pilot study assessing the benefits of quetiapine for the prevention of migraine refractory to the combination of atenolol, nortriptyline, and flunarizine. Pain Med. 2010;11(1):48–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20002594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lexchin J, Bero LA, Djulbegovic B, Clark O. Pharmaceutical industry sponsorship and research outcome and quality: systematic review. BMJ. 2003;326(7400):1167–1170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12775614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
