<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">25226064</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2014</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-087X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Issue>91</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2014</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of visualized experiments : JoVE</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Vis Exp</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Primary culture of mouse dopaminergic neurons.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e51751</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e51751</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">51751</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3791/51751</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Dopaminergic neurons represent less than 1% of the total number of neurons in the brain. This low amount of neurons regulates important brain functions such as motor control, motivation, and working memory. Nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurons selectively degenerate in Parkinson's disease (PD). This progressive neuronal loss is unequivocally associated with the motors symptoms of the pathology (bradykinesia, resting tremor, and muscular rigidity). The main agent responsible of dopaminergic neuron degeneration is still unknown. However, these neurons appear to be extremely vulnerable in diverse conditions. Primary cultures constitute one of the most relevant models to investigate properties and characteristics of dopaminergic neurons. These cultures can be submitted to various stress agents that mimic PD pathology and to neuroprotective compounds in order to stop or slow down neuronal degeneration. The numerous transgenic mouse models of PD that have been generated during the last decade further increased the interest of researchers for dopaminergic neuron cultures. Here, the video protocol focuses on the delicate dissection of embryonic mouse brains. Precise excision of ventral mesencephalon is crucial to obtain neuronal cultures sufficiently rich in dopaminergic cells to allow subsequent studies. This protocol can be realized with embryonic transgenic mice and is suitable for immunofluorescence staining, quantitative PCR, second messenger quantification, or neuronal death/survival assessment.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gaven</LastName>
            <ForeName>Florence</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CNRS, UMR-5203, Institut de Génomique Fonctionnelle, Montpellier; Inserm, U661, Montpellier; Universités de Montpellier.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Philippe</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CNRS, UMR-5203, Institut de Génomique Fonctionnelle, Montpellier; Inserm, U661, Montpellier; Universités de Montpellier.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Claeysen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sylvie</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CNRS, UMR-5203, Institut de Génomique Fonctionnelle, Montpellier; Inserm, U661, Montpellier; Universités de Montpellier; Sylvie.Claeysen@igf.cnrs.fr.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D059040">Video-Audio Media</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Vis Exp</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101313252</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1940-087X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018929" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Culture Techniques</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059290" MajorTopicYN="N">Dopaminergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004622" MajorTopicYN="N">Embryo, Mammalian</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008636" MajorTopicYN="N">Mesencephalon</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000196" MajorTopicYN="N">embryology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25226064</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4828056</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/51751</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glowinski J, Cheramy A, Romo R, Barbeito L. Presynaptic regulation of dopaminergic transmission in the striatum. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 1988;8:7–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2900072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iversen SD, Iversen LL. Dopamine: 50 years in perspective. Trends Neurosci. 2007;30:188–193.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17368565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dahlstroem A, Fuxe K. Evidence for the Existence of Monoamine-Containing Neurons in the Central Nervous System I. Demonstration of Monoamines in the Cell Bodies of Brain Stem Neurons. Acta Physiol Scand Suppl. SUPPL. 1964. pp. 231–255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14229500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chinta SJ, Andersen JK. Dopaminergic neurons. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2005;37:942–946.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15743669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bjorklund A, Dunnett SB. Dopamine neuron systems in the brain: an update. Trends Neurosci. 2007;30:194–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17408759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegarty SV, Sullivan AM, O'Keeffe GW. Midbrain dopaminergic neurons: a review of the molecular circuitry that regulates their development. Dev Biol. 2013;379:123–138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23603197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samii A, Nutt JG, Ransom BR. Parkinson's disease. Lancet. 2004;363:1783–1793.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15172778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santini E, Heiman M, Greengard P, Valjent E, Fisone G. Inhibition of mTOR signaling in Parkinson's disease prevents L-DOPA-induced dyskinesia. Sci Signal. 2009;2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohlin KE, et al.  Vascular endothelial growth factor is upregulated by L-dopa in the parkinsonian brain: implications for the development of dyskinesia. Brain. 2011;134:2339–2357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155708</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21771855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obeso JA, et al.  Missing pieces in the Parkinson's disease puzzle. Nat Med. 2010;16:653–661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20495568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper O, et al.  Pharmacological rescue of mitochondrial deficits in iPSC-derived neural cells from patients with familial Parkinson's disease. Sci Transl Med. 2012;4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22764206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michel PP, Toulorge D, Guerreiro S, Hirsch EC. Specific needs of dopamine neurons for stimulation in order to survive: implication for Parkinson disease. FASEB J. 2013;27:3414–3423.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23699175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decressac M, Volakakis N, Bjorklund A, Perlmann T. NURR1 in Parkinson disease-from pathogenesis to therapeutic potential. Nat Rev Neurol. 2013. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jouve L, Salin P, Melon C, Le Goff LKerkerian- Deep brain stimulation of the center median-parafascicular complex of the thalamus has efficient anti-parkinsonian action associated with widespread cellular responses in the basal ganglia network in a rat model of Parkinson's disease. J Neurosci. 2010;30:9919–9928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6632817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20660274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch EC, Jenner P, Przedborski S. Pathogenesis of Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2013;28:24–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22927094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>di Porzio U, Daguet MC, Glowinski J, Prochiantz A. Effect of striatal cells on in vitro maturation of mesencephalic dopaminergic neurones grown in serum-free conditions. Nature. 1980;288:370–373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7432535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denis-Donini S, Glowinski J, Prochiantz A. Glial heterogeneity may define the three-dimensional shape of mouse mesencephalic dopaminergic neurones. Nature. 1984;307:641–643.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6694754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbin G, Mallat M, Prochiantz A. In vitro studies on the maturation of mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons. Dev Neurosci. 1985;7:296–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3915291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marey-Semper I, Gelman M, Levi-Strauss M. A selective toxicity toward cultured mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons is induced by the synergistic effects of energetic metabolism impairment and NMDA receptor activation. J Neurosci. 1995;15:5912–5918.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6577653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7666176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salthun-Lassalle B, Hirsch EC, Wolfart J, Ruberg M, Michel PP. Rescue of mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons in culture by low-level stimulation of voltage-gated sodium channels. J Neurosci. 2004;24:5922–5930.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15229240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toulorge D, et al.  Neuroprotection of midbrain dopamine neurons by nicotine is gated by cytoplasmic Ca2. FASEB J. 2011;25:2563–2573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21507900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rousseau E, Michel PP, Hirsch EC. The Iron-Binding Protein Lactoferrin Protects Vulnerable Dopamine Neurons from Degeneration by Preserving Mitochondrial Calcium Homeostasis. Mol Pharmacol. 2013;84</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24077968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orme RP, Bhangal MS, Fricker RA. Calcitriol imparts neuroprotection in vitro to midbrain dopaminergic neurons by upregulating GDNF expression. PLoS One. 2013;8(e62040)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3633905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23626767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi WS, Kruse SE, Palmiter RD, Xia Z. Mitochondrial complex I inhibition is not required for dopaminergic neuron death induced by rotenone, MPP+, or paraquat. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105:15136–15141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2567505</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18812510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trancikova A, Ramonet D, Moore DJ. Genetic mouse models of neurodegenerative diseases. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci. 2011;100:419–482.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao HM, Liu B, Zhang W, Hong JS. Critical role of microglial NADPH oxidase-derived free radicals in the in vitro MPTP model of Parkinson's disease. FASEB J. 2003;17:1954–1956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12897068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin X, et al.  Conditional expression of Parkinson's disease-related mutant alpha-synuclein in the midbrain dopaminergic neurons causes progressive neurodegeneration and degradation of transcription factor nuclear receptor related 1. J Neurosci. 2012;32:9248–9264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3417246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22764233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bye CR, Thompson LH, Parish CL. Birth dating of midbrain dopamine neurons identifies A9 enriched tissue for transplantation into parkinsonian mice. Exp Neurol. 2012;236:58–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22524988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramonet D, et al.  Dopaminergic neuronal loss, reduced neurite complexity and autophagic abnormalities in transgenic mice expressing G2019S mutant LRRK2. PLoS One. 2011;6(e18568)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3071839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21494637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prestoz L, Jaber M, Gaillard A. Dopaminergic axon guidance: which makes what. Front Cell Neurosci. 2012;6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3408579</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22866028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunes I, Tovmasian LT, Silva RM, Burke RE, Goff SP. Pitx3 is required for development of substantia nigra dopaminergic neurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1073;100:4245–4250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12655058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferri AL, et al.  Foxa1 and Foxa2 regulate multiple phases of midbrain dopaminergic neuron development in a dosage-dependent manner. Development. 2007;134:2761–2769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17596284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rayport S, et al.  Identified postnatal mesolimbic dopamine neurons in culture: morphology and electrophysiology. J Neurosci. 1992;12:4264–4280.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6575995</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1359033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim KM, Nakajima S, Nakajima Y. Dopamine and GABA receptors in cultured substantia nigra neurons: correlation of electrophysiology and immunocytochemistry. Neuroscience. 1997;78:759–769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9153656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nefzger CM, et al.  Lmx1a allows context-specific isolation of progenitors of GABAergic or dopaminergic neurons during neural differentiation of embryonic stem cells. Stem Cells. 2012;30:1349–1361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22495882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su H, et al.  Immediate expression of Cdh2 is essential for efficient neural differentiation of mouse induced pluripotent stem cells. Stem Cell Res. 2013;10:338–348.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23416351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
