<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">25418913</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2015</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4652</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>230</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of cellular physiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Physiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The role of Notch receptors in transcriptional regulation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>982</StartPage>
          <EndPage>988</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>982-8</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcp.24872</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Notch signaling has pleiotropic context-specific functions that have essential roles in many processes, including embryonic development and maintenance and homeostasis of adult tissues. Aberrant Notch signaling (both hyper- and hypoactive) is implicated in a number of human developmental disorders and many cancers. Notch receptor signaling is mediated by tightly regulated proteolytic cleavages that lead to the assembly of a nuclear Notch transcription complex, which drives the expression of downstream target genes and thereby executes Notch's functions. Thus, understanding regulation of gene expression by Notch is central to deciphering how Notch carries out its many activities. Here, we summarize the recent findings pertaining to the complex interplay between the Notch transcriptional complex and interacting factors involved in transcriptional regulation, including co-activators, cooperating transcription factors, and chromatin regulators, and discuss emerging data pertaining to the role of Notch-regulated noncoding RNAs in transcription.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2014 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hongfang</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chongzhi</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>X Shirley</ForeName>
            <Initials>XS</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aster</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jon C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P01 CA119070</GrantID>
            <Acronym>CA</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Cell Physiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0050222</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9541</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051819">Immunoglobulin J Recombination Signal Sequence-Binding Protein</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051880">Receptors, Notch</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005786" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gene Expression Regulation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051819" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin J Recombination Signal Sequence-Binding Protein</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051880" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Notch</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020218" MajorTopicYN="N">Response Elements</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014158" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transcription, Genetic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25418913</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS691774</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442318</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.24872</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson ER, Sandberg R, Lendahl U. Notch signaling: Simplicity in design, versatility in function. Development. 2011;138:3593–3612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnett KL, Hass M, McArthur DG, Ilagan MX, Aster JC, Kopan R, Blacklow SC. Structural and mechanistic insights into cooperative assembly of dimeric Notch transcription complexes. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2010;17:1312–1317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024583</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20972443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aster JC, Pear WS, Blacklow SC. Notch signaling in leukemia. Annu Rev Pathol. 2008;3:587–613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5934586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18039126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borggrefe T, Oswald F. The Notch signaling pathway: Transcriptional regulation at Notch target genes. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2009;66:1631–1646.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bray S, Musisi H, Bienz M. Bre1 is required for Notch signaling and histone modification. Dev Cell. 2005;8:279–286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brimer N, Lyons C, Wallberg AE, Vande Pol Cutaneous papillomavirus E6 oncoproteins associate with MAML1 to repress transactivation and NOTCH signaling. Oncogene. 2012;31:4639–4646.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3330202</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22249263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castel D, Mourikis P, Bartels SJ, Brinkman AB, Tajbakhsh S, Stunnenberg HG. Dynamic binding of RBPJ is determined by Notch signaling status. Genes Dev. 2013;27:1059–1071.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3656323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23651858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins KJ, Yuan Z, Kovall RA. Structure and function of the CSL-KyoT2 corepressor complex: A negative regulator of Notch signaling. Structure. 2014;22:70–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24290140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuddapah S, Jothi R, Schones DE, Roh TY, Cui K, Zhao K. Global analysis of the insulator binding protein CTCF in chromatin barrier regions reveals demarcation of active and repressive domains. Genome Res. 2009;19:24–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612964</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Stefano L, Walker JA, Burgio G, Corona DF, Mulligan P, Naar AM, Dyson NJ. Functional antagonism between histone H3K4 demethylases in vivo. Genes Dev. 2011;25:17–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21205864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowen JM, Fan ZP, Hnisz D, Ren G, Abraham BJ, Zhang LN, Weintraub AS, Schuijers J, Lee TI, Zhao K, Young RA. Control of cell identity genes occurs in insulated neighborhoods in mammalian chromosomes. Cell. 2014;159:374–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4197132</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durinck K, Wallaert A, Van de Walle I, Van Loocke W, Volders P-J, Vanhauwaert S, Geerdens E, Benoit Y, Van Roy N, Poppe B, Soulier J, Cools J, Mestdagh P, Vandesompele J, Rondou P, Van Vlierberghe P, Taghon T, Speleman F. The Notch driven long non-coding RNA repertoire in T-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Haematologica. 2014;99:1799–1807.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4258754</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fryer CJ, White JB, Jones KA. Mastermind recruits CycC: CDK8 to phosphorylate the Notch ICD and coordinate activation with turnover. Mol Cell. 2004;16:509–520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15546612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Lay Geimer, Oravecz AS, Mastio A, Jung J, Marchal C, Ebel P, Dembele C, Jost D, Le Gras B, Thibault S, Borggrefe C, Kastner T, Chan P. The tumor suppressor Ikaros shapes the repertoire of notch target genes in T cells. Sci Signaling. 2014;7:28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24643801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guarani V, Deflorian G, Franco CA, Kruger M, Phng LK, Bentley K, Toussaint L, Dequiedt F, Mostoslavsky R, Schmidt MH, Zimmermann B, Brandes RP, Mione M, Westphal CH, Braun T, Zeiher AM, Gerhardt H, Dimmeler S, Potente M. Acetylation-dependent regulation of endothelial Notch signalling by the SIRT1 deacetylase. Nature. 2011;473:234–238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4598045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21499261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Handoko L, Xu H, Li G, Ngan CY, Chew E, Schnapp M, Lee CW, Ye C, Ping JL, Mulawadi F, Wong E, Sheng J, Zhang Y, Poh T, Chan CS, Kunarso G, Shahab A, Bourque G, Cacheux-Rataboul V, Sung WK, Ruan Y, Wei CL. CTCF-mediated functional chromatin interactome in pluripotent cells. Nat Genetics. 2011;43:630–638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3436933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21685913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawkins RD, Hon GC, Yang C, Antosiewicz-Bourget JE, Lee LK, Ngo QM, Klugman S, Ching KA, Edsall LE, Ye Z, Kuan S, Yu P, Liu H, Zhang X, Green RD, Lobanenkov VV, Stewart R, Thomson JA, Ren B. Dynamic chromatin states in human ES cells reveal potential regulatory sequences and genes involved in pluripotency. Cell Res. 2011;21:1393–1409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3193447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21876557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herranz D, Ambesi-Impiombato A, Palomero T, Schnell SA, Belver L, Wendorff AA, Xu L, Castillo-Martin M, Llobet-Navas D, Cordon-Cardo C, Clappier E, Soulier J, Ferrando AA. A NOTCH1-driven MYC enhancer promotes T cell development, transformation and acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Nat Med. 2014;20:1130–1137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4192073</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25194570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hnisz D, Abraham BJ, Lee TI, Lau A, Saint-Andre V, Sigova AA, Hoke HA, Young RA. Super-enhancers in the control of cell identity and disease. Cell. 2013;155:934–947.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3841062</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hori K, Cholewa-Waclaw J, Nakada Y, Glasgow SM, Masui T, Henke RM, Wildner H, Martarelli B, Beres TM, Epstein JA, Magnuson MA, Macdonald RJ, Birchmeier C, Johnson JE. A nonclassical bHLH Rbpj transcription factor complex is required for specification of GABAergic neurons independent of Notch signaling. Genes Dev. 2008;22:166–178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192752</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18198335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeannet R, Mastio J, Macias-Garcia A, Oravecz A, Ashworth T, Le Lay Geimer, Jost AS, Le Gras B, Ghysdael S, Gridley J, Honjo T, Radtke T, Aster F, Chan JC, Kastner S. Oncogenic activation of the Notch1 gene by deletion of its promoter in Ikaros-deficient T-ALL. Blood. 2010;116:5443–5454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20829372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kagey MH, Newman JJ, Bilodeau S, Zhan Y, Orlando DA, van Berkum NL, Ebmeier CC, Goossens J, Rahl PB, Levine SS, Taatjes DJ, Dekker J, Young RA. Mediator and cohesin connect gene expression and chromatin architecture. Nature. 2010;467:430–435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20720539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopan R, Ilagan MX. The canonical Notch signaling pathway: Unfolding the activation mechanism. Cell. 2009;137:216–233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2827930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19379690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krejci A, Bray S. Notch activation stimulates transient and selective binding of Su(H)/CSL to target enhancers. Genes Dev. 2007;21:1322–1327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1877745</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17545467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lake RJ, Tsai P-F, Choi I, Won K-J, Fan H-Y. RBPJ, the major transcriptional effector of Notch signaling, remains associated with chromatin throughout mitosis, suggesting a role in mitotic bookmarking. PLoS Genetics. 2014;10:e1004204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3945225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24603501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lan K, Verma SC, Murakami M, Bajaj B, Kaul R, Robertson ES. Kaposi’s sarcoma herpesvirus-encoded latency-associated nuclear antigen stabilizes intracellular activated Notch by targeting the Sel10 protein. Proc Nat Acad Sci USA. 2007;104:16287–16292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1997218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li N, Fassl A, Chick J, Inuzuka H, Li X, Mansour MR, Liu L, Wang H, King B, Shaik S, Gutierrez A, Ordureau A, Otto T, Kreslavsky T, Baitsch L, Bury L, Meyer CA, Ke N, Mulry KA, Kluk MJ, Roy M, Kim S, Zhang X, Geng Y, Zagozdzon A, Jenkinson S, Gale RE, Linch DC, Zhao JJ, Mullighan CG, Harper JW, Aster JC, Aifantis I, von Boehmer H, Gygi SP, Wei W, Look AT, Sicinski P. Cyclin C is a haploinsufficient tumour suppressor. Nat Cell Biol. 2014;16:1080–1091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4235773</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liefke R, Oswald F, Alvarado C, Ferres-Marco D, Mittler G, Rodriguez P, Dominguez M, Borggrefe T. Histone demethylase KDM5A is an integral part of the core Notch-RBP-J repressor complex. Genes Dev. 2010;24:590–601.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2841336</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20231316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu H, Chi AW, Arnett KL, Chiang MY, Xu L, Shestova O, Wang H, Li YM, Bhandoola A, Aster JC, Blacklow SC, Pear WS. Notch dimerization is required for leukemogenesis and T-cell development. Genes Dev. 2010;24:2395–2407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2964750</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20935071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loven J, Hoke HA, Lin CY, Lau A, Orlando DA, Vakoc CR, Bradner JE, Lee TI, Young RA. Selective inhibition of tumor oncogenes by disruption of super-enhancers. Cell. 2013;153:320–334.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3760967</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23582323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medyouf H, Gusscott S, Wang H, Tseng JC, Wai C, Nemirovsky O, Trumpp A, Pflumio F, Carboni J, Gottardis M, Pollak M, Kung AL, Aster JC, Holzenberger M, Weng AP. High-level IGF1R expression is required for leukemia-initiating cell activity in T-ALL and is supported by Notch signaling. J Exp Med. 2011;208:1809–1822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3171095</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21807868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyers JM, Spangle JM, Munger K. The human papillomavirus type 8 E6 protein interferes with NOTCH activation during keratinocyte differentiation. J Virol. 2013;87:4762–4767.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624394</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23365452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulligan P, Yang F, Di Stefano L, Ji JY, Ouyang J, Nishikawa JL, Toiber D, Kulkarni M, Wang Q, Najafi-Shoushtari SH, Mostoslavsky R, Gygi SP, Gill G, Dyson NJ, Naar AM. A SIRT1-LSD1 corepressor complex regulates Notch target gene expression and development. Mol Cell. 2011;42:689–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21596603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Neil J, Grim J, Strack P, Rao S, Tibbitts D, Winter C, Hardwick J, Welcker M, Meijerink JP, Pieters R, Draetta G, Sears R, Clurman BE, Look AT. FBW7 mutations in leukemic cells mediate NOTCH pathway activation and resistance to gamma-secretase inhibitors. J Exp Med. 2007;204:1813–1824.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2118656</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17646409</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtani Y, Wang H, Zang C, Arnett KL, Bailis W, Ho Y, Knoechel B, Lanauze C, Louis L, Chung Y, Schug J, Blobel G, Liebhaber SA, Bernstein BE, Blacklow SC, Liu XS, Aster JC, Pear WS. Long-range enhancer activity determines Myc sensitivity to Notch inhibitors in T cell leukemia. Proc Nat Acad Sci USA. 2014 epublished 11/03/2014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4246292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25369933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parker SCJ, Stitzel ML, Taylor DL, Orozco JM, Erdos MR, Akiyama JA, van Bueren KL, Chines PS, Narisu N, Black BL, Visel A, Collins FS. Chromatin stretch enhancer stated drive cell-specific gene regulation and harbor human disease risk variants. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2013;110:17921–17926.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3816444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24127591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Popko-Scibor AE, Lindberg MJ, Hansson ML, Holmlund T, Wallberg AE. Ubiquitination of Notch1 is regulated by MAML1-mediated p300 acetylation of Notch1. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 2011;416:300–306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22100894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin H, Wang J, Liang Y, Taniguchi Y, Tanigaki K, Han H. RING1 inhibits transactivation of RBP-J by Notch through interaction with LIM protein KyoT2. Nucl Acids Res. 2004;32:1492–1501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC390284</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14999091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Just Saint, Ribeiro M, Hansson ML, Wallberg AE. A proline repeat domain in the Notch co-activator MAML1 is important for the p300-mediated acetylation of MAML1. Biochem J. 2007;404:289–298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1868802</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17300219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>South AP, Cho RJ, Aster JC. The double-edged sword of Notch signaling in cancer. Sem Cell Dev Biol. 2012;23:458–464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3360804</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22309843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephens PJ, Davies HR, Mitani Y, Van Loo P, Shlien A, Tarpey PS, Papaemmanuil E, Cheverton A, Bignell GR, Butler AP, Gamble J, Gamble S, Hardy C, Hinton J, Jia M, Jayakumar A, Jones D, Latimer C, McLaren S, McBride DJ, Menzies A, Mudie L, Maddison M, Raine K, Nik-Zainal S, O’Meara S, Teague JW, Varela I, Wedge DC, Whitmore I, Lippman SM, McDermott U, Stratton MR, Campbell PJ, El-Naggar AK, Futreal PA. Whole exome sequencing of adenoid cystic carcinoma. J Clin Inv. 2013;123:2965–2968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3999050</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23778141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stoeck A, Lejnine S, Truong A, Pan L, Wang H, Zang C, Yuan J, Ware C, MacLean J, Garrett-Engele PW, Kluk M, Laskey J, Haines BB, Moskaluk C, Zawel L, Fawell S, Gilliland G, Zhang T, Kremer BE, Knoechel B, Bernstein BE, Pear WS, Liu XS, Aster JC, Sathyanarayanan S. Discovery of biomarkers predictive of GSI response in triple-negative breast cancer and adenoid cystic carcinoma. Cancer Discov. 2014;4:1154–1167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4184927</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan MJ, White EA, Sowa ME, Harper JW, Aster JC, Howley PM. Cutaneous beta-human papillomavirus E6 proteins bind Mastermind-like coactivators and repress Notch signaling. Proc Nat Acad Sci USA. 2012;109:E1473–E1480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22547818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terriente-Felix A, Li J, Collins S, Mulligan A, Reekie I, Bernard F, Krejci A, Bray S. Notch cooperates with Lozenge/Runx to lock haemocytes into a differentiation programme. Development. 2013;140:926–937.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3557782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23325760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trimarchi T, Bilal E, Ntziachristos P, Fabbri G, Dalla-Favera R, Tsirigos A, Aifantis I. Genome-wide mapping and characterization of notch-regulated long noncoding RNAs in acute leukemia. Cell. 2014;158:593–606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4131209</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25083870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Scully K, Zhu X, Cai L, Zhang J, Prefontaine GG, Krones A, Ohgi KA, Zhu P, Garcia-Bassets I, Liu F, Taylor H, Lozach J, Jayes FL, Korach KS, Glass CK, Fu XD, Rosenfeld MG. Opposing LSD1 complexes function in developmental gene activation and repression programmes. Nature. 2007;446:882–887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17392792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Zou J, Zhao B, Johannsen E, Ashworth T, Wong H, Pear WS, Schug J, Blacklow SC, Arnett KL, Bernstein BE, Kieff E, Aster JC. Genome-wide analysis reveals conserved and divergent features of Notch1/RBPJ binding in human and murine T-lymphoblastic leukemia cells. Proc Nat Acad Sci USA. 2011;108:14908–14913.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21737748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Zang C, Taing L, Arnett KL, Wong YJ, Pear WS, Blacklow SC, Liu XS, Aster JC. NOTCH1-RBPJ complexes drive target gene expression through dynamic interactions with superenhancers. Proc Nat Acad Sci USA. 2014;111:705–710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3896193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24374627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yatim A, Benne C, Sobhian B, Laurent-Chabalier S, Deas O, Judde JG, Lelievre JD, Levy Y, Benkirane M. NOTCH1 nuclear interactome reveals key regulators of its transcriptional activity and oncogenic function. Mol Cell. 2012;48:445–458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3595990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23022380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
