<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">25496901</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2015</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-4465</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Lancet. Neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Wilson's disease and other neurological copper disorders.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>103</StartPage>
          <EndPage>113</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>103-13</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70190-5</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1474-4422(14)70190-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The copper metabolism disorder Wilson's disease was first defined in 1912. Wilson's disease can present with hepatic and neurological deficits, including dystonia and parkinsonism. Early-onset presentations in infancy and late-onset manifestations in adults older than 70 years of age are now well recognised. Direct genetic testing for ATP7B mutations are increasingly available to confirm the clinical diagnosis of Wilson's disease, and results from biochemical and genetic prevalence studies suggest that Wilson's disease might be much more common than previously estimated. Early diagnosis of Wilson's disease is crucial to ensure that patients can be started on adequate treatment, but uncertainty remains about the best possible choice of medication. Furthermore, Wilson's disease needs to be differentiated from other conditions that also present clinically with hepatolenticular degeneration or share biochemical abnormalities with Wilson's disease, such as reduced serum ceruloplasmin concentrations. Disordered copper metabolism is also associated with other neurological conditions, including a subtype of axonal neuropathy due to ATP7A mutations and the late-onset neurodegenerative disorders Alzheimer's disease and Parkinson's disease.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bandmann</LastName>
            <ForeName>Oliver</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN), University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK. Electronic address: o.bandmann@sheffield.ac.uk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Weiss</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karl Heinz</ForeName>
            <Initials>KH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University Hospital Heidelberg, Department of Internal Medicine IV, Heidelberg, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephen G</ForeName>
            <Initials>SG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section on Translational Neuroscience, Molecular Medicine Program, Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>Z01 HD008892</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HD</Acronym>
            <Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>ZIA HD008892-05</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>ZIA HD008768-10</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>G-1202</GrantID>
            <Acronym>PUK_</Acronym>
            <Agency>Parkinson's UK</Agency>
            <Country>United Kingdom</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>Z01 HD008768</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052060">Research Support, N.I.H., Intramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Lancet Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101139309</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1474-4422</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>789U1901C5</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003300">Copper</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003300" MajorTopicYN="N">Copper</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006527" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hepatolenticular Degeneration</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009422" MajorTopicYN="N">Nervous System Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of interest:</b> OB - none. KHW – none. SGK – none.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25496901</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS648222</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4336199</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70190-5</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1474-4422(14)70190-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broussolle E, Trocello JM, Woimant F, Lachaux A, Quinn N. Samuel Alexander Kinnier Wilson. Wilson’s disease, Queen Square and neurology. Revue neurologique. 2013;169(12):927–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24125461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Compston A. Progressive lenticular degeneration: a familial nervous disease associated with cirrhosis of the liver, by S. A. Kinnier Wilson, (From the National Hospital, and the Laboratory of the National Hospital, Queen Square, London) Brain 1912:34; 295–509. Brain. 2009;132(Pt 8):1997–2001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19634211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cumings JN. The copper and iron content of Brain and liver in the normal and in hepato-lenticular degeneration. Brain. 1948;71(Pt. 4):410–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18124738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bull PC, Thomas GR, Rommens JM, Forbes JR, Cox DW. The Wilson disease gene is a putative copper transporting P-type ATPase similar to the Menkes gene. Nat Genet. 1993;5(4):327–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8298639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrukhin K, Fischer SG, Pirastu M, Tanzi RE, Chernov I, Devoto M, et al.  Mapping, cloning and genetic characterization of the region containing the Wilson disease gene. Nat Genet. 1993;5(4):338–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8298640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanzi RE, Petrukhin K, Chernov I, Pellequer JL, Wasco W, Ross B, et al.  The Wilson disease gene is a copper transporting ATPase with homology to the Menkes disease gene. Nat Genet. 1993;5(4):344–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8298641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coffey AJ, Durkie M, Hague S, McLay K, Emmerson J, Lo C, et al.  A genetic study of Wilson’s disease in the United Kingdom. Brain. 2013;136(Pt 5):1476–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3634195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23518715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moller LB, Ott P, Lund C, Horn N. Homozygosity for a gross partial gene deletion of the C-terminal end of ATP7B in a Wilson patient with hepatic and no neurological manifestations. J Med Genet A. 2005;138(4):340–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16222684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferenci P. Regional distribution of mutations of the ATP7B gene in patients with Wilson disease: impact on genetic testing. Hum Genet. 2006;120(2):151–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16791614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merle U, Weiss KH, Eisenbach C, Tuma S, Ferenci P, Stremmel W. Truncating mutations in the Wilson disease gene ATP7B are associated with very low serum ceruloplasmin oxidase activity and an early onset of Wilson disease. BMC Gastroenterol. 2010;10:8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20082719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas GR, Forbes JR, Roberts EA, Walshe JM, Cox DW. The Wilson disease gene: spectrum of mutations and their consequences. Nat Genet. 1995;9(2):210–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7626145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah AB, Chernov I, Zhang HT, Ross BM, Das K, Lutsenko S, et al.  Identification and analysis of mutations in the Wilson disease gene (ATP7B): population frequencies, genotype-phenotype correlation, and functional analyses. Am J Hum Genet. 1997;61(2):317–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1715895</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9311736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tarnacka B, Gromadzka G, Rodo M, Mierzejewski P, Czloonkowska A. Frequency of His1069Gln and Gly1267Lys mutations in Polish Wilson’s disease population. Eur J Neurol. 2000;7(5):495–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruha R, Marecek Z, Pospisilova L, Nevsimalova S, Vitek L, Martasek P, et al.  Long-term follow-up of Wilson disease: natural history, treatment, mutations analysis and phenotypic correlation. Liver Int. 2011;31(1):83–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20958917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stapelbroek JM, Bollen CW, van Amstel JK, van Erpecum KJ, van Hattum J, van den Berg LH, et al.  The H1069Q mutation in ATP7B is associated with late and neurologic presentation in Wilson disease: results of a meta-analysis. J Hepatol. 2004;41(5):758–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15519648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gromadzka G, Rudnicka M, Chabik G, Przybylkowski A, Czlonkowska A. Genetic variability in the methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase gene (MTHFR) affects clinical expression of Wilson’s disease. J Hepatol. 2011;55(4):913–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiefermeier M, Kollegger H, Madl C, Polli C, Oder W, Kuhn H, et al.  The impact of apolipoprotein E genotypes on age at onset of symptoms and phenotypic expression in Wilson’s disease. Brain. 2000;123(Pt 3):585–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10686180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huster D, Kuhne A, Bhattacharjee A, Raines L, Jantsch V, Noe J, et al.  Diverse functional properties of Wilson disease ATP7B variants. Gastroenterology. 2012;142(4):947–56. e5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3461965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22240481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu M, Cooper JM, Butler P, Walker AP, Mistry PK, Dooley JS, et al.  Oxidative-phosphorylation defects in liver of patients with Wilson’s disease. Lancet. 2000;356(9228):469–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10981891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zischka H, Lichtmannegger J, Schmitt S, Jagemann N, Schulz S, Wartini D, et al.  Liver mitochondrial membrane crosslinking and destruction in a rat model of Wilson disease. J Clin Invest. 2011;121(4):1508–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3068979</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21364284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park RH, McCabe P, Fell GS, Russell RI. Wilson’s disease in Scotland. Gut. 1991;32 (12):1541–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1379259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1773964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hahn SH, Lee SY, Jang YJ, Kim SN, Shin HC, Park SY, et al.  Pilot study of mass screening for Wilson’s disease in Korea. Mol Genet Metab. 2002;76(2):133–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12083810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohura T, Abukawa D, Shiraishi H, Yamaguchi A, Arashima S, Hiyamuta S, et al.  Pilot study of screening for Wilson disease using dried blood spots obtained from children seen at outpatient clinics. J Inherit Metab Dis. 1999;22(1):74–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10070620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zappu A, Magli O, Lepori MB, Dessi V, Diana S, Incollu S, et al.  High incidence and allelic homogeneity of Wilson disease in 2 isolated populations: a prerequisite for efficient disease prevention programs. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2008;47(3):334–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18728530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walshe JM. Cause of death in Wilson disease. Mov Disord. 2007;22(15):2216–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machado A, Chien HF, Deguti MM, Cancado E, Azevedo RS, Scaff M, et al.  Neurological manifestations in Wilson’s disease: Report of 119 cases. Mov Disord. 2006;21(12):2192–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17078070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferenci P, Czlonkowska A, Merle U, Ferenc S, Gromadzka G, Yurdaydin C, et al.  Late-onset Wilson’s disease. Gastroenterology. 2007;132(4):1294–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17433323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ala A, Borjigin J, Rochwarger A, Schilsky M. Wilson disease in septuagenarian siblings: Raising the bar for diagnosis. Hepatology. 2005;41(3):668–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15723329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JW, Kim JH, Seo JK, Ko JS, Chang JY, Yang HR, et al.  Genetically confirmed Wilson disease in a 9-month old boy with elevations of aminotransferases. World J Hepatol. 2013;5(3):156–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3612577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23556051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosen JM, Kuntz N, Melin-Aldana H, Bass LM. Spasmodic muscle cramps and weakness as presenting symptoms in Wilson disease. Pediatrics. 2013;132(4):e1039–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23999958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Svetel M, Kozic D, Stefanova E, Semnic R, Dragasevic N, Kostic VS. Dystonia in Wilson’s disease. Mov Disord. 2001;16(4):719–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11481698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Risvoll H, Kerty E. To test or not? The value of diagnostic tests in cervical dystonia. Mov Disord. 2001;16(2):286–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11295782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taly AB, Meenakshi-Sundaram S, Sinha S, Swamy HS, Arunodaya GR. Wilson disease: description of 282 patients evaluated over 3 decades. Medicine. 2007;86(2):112–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17435591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dening TR, Berrios GE, Walshe JM. Wilson’s disease and epilepsy. Brain. 1988;111 (Pt 5):1139–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3052696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verma R, Patil TB, Lalla RS. Acute extrapyramidal syndrome and seizures as heralding manifestation of Wilson disease. Neurol India. 2012;60(3):363–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22824716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingster-Moati I, Bui Quoc E, Pless M, Djomby R, Orssaud C, Guichard JP, et al.  Ocular motility and Wilson’s disease: a study on 34 patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(11):1199–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117600</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Svetel M, Potrebic A, Pekmezovic T, Tomic A, Kresojevic N, Jesic R, et al.  Neuropsychiatric aspects of treated Wilson’s disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2009;15 (10):772–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19559640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimbrean PC, Schilsky ML. Psychiatric aspects of Wilson disease: a review. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2014;36(1):53–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srinivas K, Sinha S, Taly AB, Prashanth LK, Arunodaya GR, Janardhana Reddy YC, et al.  Dominant psychiatric manifestations in Wilson’s disease: a diagnostic and therapeutic challenge! J Neurol Sci. 2008;266(1–2):104–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17904160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wenish E, De Tassigny A, Trocello JM, Beretti J, Giradot-Tinant N, Woimant F. Cognitive profile in Wilson’s disease: a case series of 31 patients. Rev Neurol. 2013;169(12):944–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24120329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwanski S, Seniow J, Lesniak M, Litwin T, Czlonkowska A. Diverse attention deficits in patients with neurologically symptomatic and asymptomatic Wilson’s disease. Neuropsychology. 2014 [epub ahead of print]</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24885450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines: Wilson’s disease. J Hepatol. 2012;56(3):671–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22340672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss KH, Gotthardt DN, Klemm D, Merle U, Ferenci-Foerster D, Schaefer M, et al.  Zinc monotherapy is not as effective as chelating agents in treatment of Wilson disease. Gastroenterology. 2011;140(4):1189–98. e1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21185835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicastro E, Ranucci G, Vajro P, Vegnente A, Iorio R. Re-evaluation of the diagnostic criteria for Wilson disease in children with mild liver disease. Hepatology. 2010;52(6):1948–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20967755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martins da Costa C, Baldwin D, Portmann B, Lolin Y, Mowat AP, Mieli-Vergani G. Value of urinary copper excretion after penicillamine challenge in the diagnosis of Wilson’s disease. Hepatology. 1992;15(4):609–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1551638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferenci P, Steindl-Munda P, Vogel W, Jessner W, Gschwantler M, Stauber R, et al.  Diagnostic value of quantitative hepatic copper determination in patients with Wilson’s Disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2005;3(8):811–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16234011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prashanth LK, Sinha S, Taly AB, Vasudev MK. Do MRI features distinguish Wilson’s disease from other early onset extrapyramidal disorders? An analysis of 100 cases. Mov Disord. 2010;25(6):672–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20437536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trocello JM, Woimant F, El Balkhi S, Guichard JP, Poupon J, Chappuis P, et al.  Extensive striatal, cortical, and white matter Brain MRI abnormalities in Wilson disease. Neurology. 2013;81(17):1557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24145882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fritzsch D, Reiss-Zimmermann M, Trampel R, Turner R, Hoffmann KT, Schafer A. Seven-Tesla Magnetic Resonance Imaging in Wilson Disease Using Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping for Measurement of Copper Accumulation. Invest Radiol. 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24220252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oertel WH, Tatsch K, Schwarz J, Kraft E, Trenkwalder C, Scherer J, et al.  Decrease of D2 Receptors Indicated by I-123 Iodobenzamide Single-Photon Emission Computed-Tomography Relates to Neurological Deficit in Treated Wilsons-Disease. Annals of Neurology. 1992;32(6):743–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1471864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page RA, Davie CA, MacManus D, Miszkiel KA, Walshe JM, Miller DH, et al.  Clinical correlation of Brain MRI and MRS abnormalities in patients with Wilson disease. Neurology. 2004;63(4):638–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15326235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skowronska M, Litwin T, Dziezyc K, Wierzchowska A, Czlonkowska A. Does Brain degeneration in Wilson disease involve not only copper but also iron accumulation? Neurol Neurochir Pol. 2013;47(6):542–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24374999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litwin T, Dziezyc K, Poniatowska R, Czlonkowska A. Effect of liver transplantation on Brain magnetic resonance imaging pathology in Wilson disease: a case report. Neurol Neurochir Pol. 2013;47(4):393–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23986430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis D, Durkie M, Balac P, Sheard D, Goodeve A, Peake I, et al.  A study of Wilson disease mutations in Britain. Hum Mutat. 1999;14(4):304–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10502777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dufernez F, Lachaux A, Chappuis P, De Lumley L, Bost M, Woimant F, et al.  Wilson disease in offspring of affected patients: Report of four French families. Clin Res Hepatol Gas. 2013;37(3):240–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23567103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss KH, Stremmel W. Evolving perspectives in Wilson disease: diagnosis, treatment and monitoring. Curr Gastroenterol Rep. 2012;14(1):1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22083169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss KH, Thurik F, Gotthardt DN, Schafer M, Teufel U, Wiegand F, et al.  Efficacy and safety of oral chelators in treatment of patients with Wilson disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2013;11(8):1028–35. e1–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23542331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewer GJ, Askari F, Dick RB, Sitterly J, Fink JK, Carlson M, et al.  Treatment of Wilson’s disease with tetrathiomolybdate: V. control of free copper by tetrathiomolybdate and a comparison with trientine. Transl Res. 2009;154(2):70–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19595438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen DB, Feng L, Lin XP, Zhang W, Li FR, Liang XL, et al.  Penicillamine Increases Free Copper and Enhances Oxidative Stress in the Brain of Toxic Milk Mice. Plos One. 2012;7(5)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3357430</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22629446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewer GJ, Askari F, Dick RB, Sitterly J, Fink JK, Carlson M, et al.  Treatment of Wilson’s disease with tetrathiomolybdate: V. Control of free copper by tetrathiomolybdate and a comparison with trientine. Transl Res. 2009;154(2):70–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19595438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewer GJ, Dick RD, Johnson VD, Brunberg JA, Kluin KJ, Fink JK. Treatment of Wilson’s disease with zinc: XV - Long-term follow-up studies. J Lab Clin Med. 1998;132(4):264–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9794697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linn FHH, Houwen RHJ, van Hattum J, van der Kleij S, van Erpecum KJ. Long-Term Exclusive Zinc Monotherapy in Symptomatic Wilson Disease: Experience in 17 Patients. Hepatology. 2009;50(5):1442–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19731238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dziezyc K, Karlinski M, Litwin T, Czlonkowska A. Compliant treatment with anti-copper agents prevents clinically overt Wilson’s disease in pre-symptomatic patients. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21(2):332–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24313946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walshe JM, Dixon AK. Dangers of non-compliance in Wilson’s disease. Lancet. 1986;1 (8485):845–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2870324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medici V, Mirante VG, Fassati LR, Pompili M, Forti D, Del Gaudio M, et al.  Liver transplantation for Wilson’s disease: The burden of neurological and psychiatric disorders. Liver Transpl. 2005;11(9):1056–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16123950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schilsky ML. Transplantation for inherited metabolic disorders of the liver. Transplant Proc. 2013;45(2):455–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23498779</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss KH, Schafer M, Gotthardt DN, Angerer A, Mogler C, Schirmacher P, et al.  Outcome and development of symptoms after orthotopic liver transplantation for Wilson disease. Clin Transplant. 2013;27(6):914–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24118554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holscher S, Leinweber B, Hefter H, Reuner U, Gunther P, Weiss KH, et al.  Evaluation of the symptomatic treatment of residual neurological symptoms in Wilson disease. Eur Neurol. 2010;64(2):83–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20606453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pal PK, Sinha S, Pillai S, Taly AB, Abraham RG. Successful treatment of tremor in Wilson’s disease by thalamotomy: A case report. Mov Disord. 2007;22(15):2287–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17914724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaler SG. ATP7A-related copper transport diseases-emerging concepts and future trends. Nat Rev Neurol. 2011;7(1):15–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214867</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21221114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaler SG, Holmes CS, Goldstein DS, Tang J, Godwin SC, Donsante A, et al.  Neonatal diagnosis and treatment of Menkes disease. N Engl J Med. 2008;358(6):605–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3477514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18256395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donsante A, Yi L, Zerfas PM, Brinster LR, Sullivan P, Goldstein DS, et al.  ATP7A gene addition to the choroid plexus results in long-term rescue of the lethal copper transport defect in a Menkes disease mouse model. Mol Ther. 2011;19(12):2114–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3242653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21878905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kennerson ML, Nicholson GA, Kaler SG, Kowalski B, Mercer JF, Tang J, et al.  Missense mutations in the copper transporter gene ATP7A cause X-linked distal hereditary motor neuropathy. Am J Hum Genet. 2010;86(3):343–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2833394</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20170900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaler SG. Inborn errors of copper metabolism. Handb Clin Neurol. 2013;113:1745–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214864</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23622398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi L, Donsante A, Kennerson ML, Mercer JF, Garbern JY, Kaler SG. Altered intracellular localization and valosin-containing protein (p97 VCP) interaction underlie ATP7A-related distal motor neuropathy. Hum Mol Genet. 2012;21(8):1794–807.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3313796</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22210628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JO, Mandrioli J, Benatar M, Abramzon Y, Van Deerlin VM, Trojanowski JQ, et al.  Exome sequencing reveals VCP mutations as a cause of familial ALS. Neuron. 2010;68(5):857–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3032425</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21145000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montpetit A, Cote S, Brustein E, Drouin CA, Lapointe L, Boudreau M, et al.  Disruption of AP1S1, causing a novel neurocutaneous syndrome, perturbs development of the skin and spinal cord. PLoS Genet. 2008;4(12):e1000296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2585812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinelli D, Travaglini L, Drouin CA, Ceballos-Picot I, Rizza T, Bertini E, et al.  MEDNIK syndrome: a novel defect of copper metabolism treatable by zinc acetate therapy. Brain. 2013;136(Pt 3):872–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23423674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huppke P, Brendel C, Kalscheuer V, Korenke GC, Marquardt I, Freisinger P, et al.  Mutations in SLC33A1 cause a lethal autosomal-recessive disorder with congenital cataracts, hearing loss, and low serum copper and ceruloplasmin. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;90(1):61–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3257879</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22243965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stamelou M, Tuschl K, Chong WK, Burroughs AK, Mills PB, Bhatia KP, et al.  Dystonia with Brain manganese accumulation resulting from SLC30A10 mutations: a new treatable disorder. Mov Disord. 2012;27(10):1317–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3664426</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quadri M, Federico A, Zhao T, Breedveld GJ, Battisti C, Delnooz C, et al.  Mutations in SLC30A10 cause parkinsonism and dystonia with hypermanganesemia, polycythemia, and chronic liver disease. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;90(3):467–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3309204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuschl K, Clayton PT, Gospe SM, Jr, Gulab S, Ibrahim S, Singhi P, et al.  Syndrome of hepatic cirrhosis, dystonia, polycythemia, and hypermanganesemia caused by mutations in SLC30A10, a manganese transporter in man. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;90(3):457–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3309187</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Toro Mammarella L, Mignarri A, Battisti C, Monti L, Bonifati V, Rasi F, et al.  Two-year follow-up after chelating therapy in a patient with adult-onset parkinsonism and hypermanganesaemia due to SLC30A10 mutations. J Neurol. 2014;261(1):227–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24276520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerkhof M, Honkoop P. Never forget aceruloplasminemia in case of highly suggestive Wilson’s disease score. Hepatology. 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24002824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfeiffenberger J, Gotthardt DN, Herrmann T, Seessle J, Merle U, Schirmacher P, et al.  Iron metabolism and the role of HFE gene polymorphisms in Wilson disease. Liver Int. 2012;32(1):165–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22098612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kono S. Aceruloplasminemia: an update. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2013;110:125–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24209437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNeill A, Pandolfo M, Kuhn J, Shang H, Miyajima H. The neurological presentation of ceruloplasmin gene mutations. Eur Neurol. 2008;60(4):200–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18667828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogimoto M, Anzai K, Takenoshita H, Kogawa K, Akehi Y, Yoshida R, et al.  Criteria for early identification of aceruloplasminemia. Intern Med. 2011;50(13):1415–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21720062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jellinger KA. The relevance of metals in the pathophysiology of neurodegeneration, pathological considerations. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2013;110:1–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24209432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noda Y, Asada M, Kubota M, Maesako M, Watanabe K, Uemura M, et al.  Copper enhances APP dimerization and promotes Abeta production. Neurosci Lett. 2013;547:10–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23669644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squitti R, Simonelli I, Ventriglia M, Siotto M, Pasqualetti P, Rembach A, et al.  Meta-analysis of serum non-ceruloplasmin copper in Alzheimer’s disease. J Alzheimers Dis. 2014;38(4):809–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24072069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ventriglia M, Bucossi S, Panetta V, Squitti R. Copper in Alzheimer’s disease: a meta-analysis of serum, plasma, and cerebrospinal fluid studies. J Alzheimers Dis. 2012;30 (4):981–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22475798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squitti R, Bressi F, Pasqualetti P, Bonomini C, Ghidoni R, Binetti G, et al.  Longitudinal prognostic value of serum “free” copper in patients with Alzheimer disease. Neurology. 2009;72(1):50–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19122030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh I, Sagare AP, Coma M, Perlmutter D, Gelein R, Bell RD, et al.  Low levels of copper disrupt Brain amyloid-beta homeostasis by altering its production and clearance. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2013;110(36):14771–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3767519</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squitti R, Polimanti R, Bucossi S, Ventriglia M, Mariani S, Manfellotto D, et al.  Linkage disequilibrium and haplotype analysis of the ATP7B gene in Alzheimer’s disease. Rejuvenation Res. 2013;16(1):3–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3582274</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22950421</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert JC, Ibrahim-Verbaas CA, Harold D, Naj AC, Sims R, Bellenguez C, et al.  Meta-analysis of 74,046 individuals identifies 11 new susceptibility loci for Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Genet. 2013;45(12):1452–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3896259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24162737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies P, Wang X, Sarell CJ, Drewett A, Marken F, Viles JH, et al.  The synucleins are a family of redox-active copper binding proteins. Biochemistry. 2011;50(1):37–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21117662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Binolfi A, Rodriguez EE, Valensin D, D’Amelio N, Ippoliti E, Obal G, et al.  Bioinorganic chemistry of Parkinson’s disease: structural determinants for the copper-mediated amyloid formation of alpha-synuclein. Inorg Chem. 2010;49(22):10668–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20964419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dexter DT, Carayon A, Javoy-Agid F, Agid Y, Wells FR, Daniel SE, et al.  Alterations in the levels of iron, ferritin and other trace metals in Parkinson’s disease and other neurodegenerative diseases affecting the basal ganglia. Brain. 1991;114 (Pt 4):1953–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1832073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao HW, Lin J, Wang XB, Cheng X, Wang JY, Hu BL, et al.  Assessing plasma levels of selenium, copper, iron and zinc in patients of Parkinson’s disease. Plos One. 2013;8 (12):e83060.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3858355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24340079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin L, Wang J, Zhao L, Jin H, Fei G, Zhang Y, et al.  Decreased serum ceruloplasmin levels characteristically aggravate nigral iron deposition in Parkinson’s disease. Brain. 2011;134(Pt 1):50–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21109502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bharucha KJ, Friedman JK, Vincent AS, Ross ED. Lower serum ceruloplasmin levels correlate with younger age of onset in Parkinson’s disease. J Neurol. 2008;255(12):1957–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19159062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayton S, Lei P, Duce JA, Wong BX, Sedjahtera A, Adlard PA, et al.  Ceruloplasmin dysfunction and therapeutic potential for parkinson disease. Ann Neurol. 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23424051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olivieri S, Conti A, Iannaccone S, Cannistraci CV, Campanella A, Barbariga M, et al.  Ceruloplasmin oxidation, a feature of Parkinson’s disease CSF, inhibits ferroxidase activity and promotes cellular iron retention. J Neurosci. 2011;31(50):18568–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6623910</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22171055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lutsenko S. Atp7b−/− mice as a model for studies of Wilson’s disease. Biochem Soc T. 2008;36(Pt 6):1233–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19021531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lang PA, Schenck M, Nicolay JP, Becker JU, Kempe DS, Lupescu A, et al.  Liver cell death and anemia in Wilson disease involve acid sphingomyelinase and ceramide. Nat Med. 2007;13(2):164–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17259995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leinweber B, Moller JC, Scherag A, Reuner U, Gunther P, Lang CJ, et al.  Evaluation of the Unified Wilson’s Disease Rating Scale (UWDRS) in German patients with treated Wilson’s disease. Mov Disord. 2008;23(1):54–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17960799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Chen S, Li W, Guo X, Zhao P, Xu J, et al.  Rescue of ATP7B function in hepatocyte-like cells from Wilson’s disease induced pluripotent stem cells using gene therapy or the chaperone drug curcumin. Hum Mol Genet. 2011;20(16):3176–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roybal JL, Endo M, Radu A, Gray L, Todorow CA, Zoltick PW, et al.  Early gestational gene transfer with targeted ATP7B expression in the liver improves phenotype in a murine model of Wilson’s disease. Gene Ther. 2012;19(11):1085–1094.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruha R, Vitek L, Marecek Z, Pospisilova L, Nevsimalova S, Martasek P, et al.  Decreased serum antioxidant capacity in patients with Wilson disease is associated with neurological symptoms. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2012;35(3):541–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22139496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
