<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">25632292</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1742-058X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>8</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2011</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Du Bois review : social science research on race</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Du Bois Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>STRUCTURAL RACISM AND HEALTH INEQUITIES: Old Issues, New Directions.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>115</StartPage>
          <EndPage>132</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>115-132</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Racial minorities bear a disproportionate burden of morbidity and mortality. These inequities might be explained by racism, given the fact that racism has restricted the lives of racial minorities and immigrants throughout history. Recent studies have documented that individuals who report experiencing racism have greater rates of illnesses. While this body of research has been invaluable in advancing knowledge on health inequities, it still locates the experiences of racism at the individual level. Yet, the health of social groups is likely most strongly affected by structural, rather than individual, phenomena. The structural forms of racism and their relationship to health inequities remain under-studied. This article reviews several ways of conceptualizing structural racism, with a focus on social segregation, immigration policy, and intergenerational effects. Studies of disparities should more seriously consider the multiple dimensions of structural racism as fundamental causes of health disparities.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gilbert C</ForeName>
            <Initials>GC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of California, Los Angeles.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ford</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chandra L</ForeName>
            <Initials>CL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of California, Los Angeles.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R24 HD041022</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HD</Acronym>
            <Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Du Bois Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101560184</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1742-058X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Discrimination</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethnicity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health Disparity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immigrant</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inequity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Race</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Racism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social Determinants</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2011</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25632292</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS645189</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306458</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1742058X11000130</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acevedo-Garcia D. Residential Segregation and the Epidemiology of Infectious Diseases. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2000;51(8):1143–1161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11037206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almond DV, Chay KY, Greenstone M. Civil Rights, the War on Poverty, and Black-White Convergence in Infant Mortality in the Rural South and Mississippi; Working Paper No. 07-04, Department of Economics, Massachusetts Institute of Technology; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angelon-Gaetz KA, Richardson DB, Wing S. Inequalities in the Nuclear Age: Impact of Race and Gender on Radiation Exposure at the Savannah River Site (1951–1999) New Solutions. 2010;20(2):195–210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3534859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20621884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araujo BY, Borrell LN. Understanding the Link between Discrimination, Mental Health Outcomes, and Life Chances Among Latinos. Hispanic Journal of Behavioral Sciences. 2006;28(2):245–266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barkan ER, Diner H, Kraut AM.  From Arrival to Incorporation: Migrants to the US in a Global Era. New York: New York University Press; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barker DJP. Fetal Programming of Coronary Heart Disease. Trends in Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2002;13(9):364–368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12367816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker MH. The Tyranny of Health Promotion. Public Health Review. 1986;14(1):15–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3775038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bell JF, Zimmerman FJ, Almgren GR, Mayer JD, Huebner CE. Birth Outcomes among Urban African American Women: A Multilevel Analysis of the Role of Racial Residential Segregation. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2006;63(12):3030–3045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16997438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bobo L.  Racial Attitudes and Relations at the Close of the Twentieth Century. In: Smelser N, Wilson WJ, Mitchell F, editors. America Becoming: Racial Trends and Their Implications. Washington, DC: National Academy Press; 2000. pp. 262–299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonilla-Silva E. Rethinking Racism: Toward a Structural Interpretation. American Sociological Review. 1997;62(3):465–480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borrell LN. Racial Identity among Hispanics: Implications for Health and Well-Being. American Journal of Public Health. 2005;95(3):379–381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1449186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15727961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boswell RA. Racism and U.S. Immigration Law: Prospects for Reform after “9/11”? Immigration and Nationality Law Review. 2003;7:315–356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd D.  White Flight in Networked Public Places? How Race and Class Shaped American Teen Engagement with MySpace and Facebook. In: Nakamura L, Chow-White P, editors. Digital Race Anthology. New York: Routledge Press; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brave Heart M, DeBruyn LM. The American Indian Holocaust: Healing Historical Unresolved Grief. American Indian and Alaska Native Mental Health Research. 1998;8(2):60–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9842066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brondolo E, Brady ver Halen N, Pencille M, Beatty D, Contrada R. Coping with Racism: A Selective Review of the Literature and a Theoretical and Methodological Critique. Journal of Behavioral Medicine. 2009;32(1):64–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3258496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19127420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruch E, Mare R. Neighborhood Choice and Neighborhood Change. American Journal of Sociology. 2006;112:667–709.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmichael S, Hamilton CV.  Black Power: The Politics of Liberation in America. New York: Vintage Books; 1967. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catanzarite L. Brown-Collar Jobs: Occupational Segregation and Earnings of Recent-Immigrant Latinos. Sociological Perspectives. 2000;43(1):45–75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chae Chang Ping v. United States. 1889 130 U.S. 581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chae DH, Walters KL. Racial Discrimination and Racial Identity Attitudes in Relation to Self-Rated Health and Physical Pain and Impairment among Two-Spirit American Indians/Alaska Natives. American Journal of Public Health. 2009;99(S1):S144–S151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2724927</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19218182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarke SP, Davis BL, Nailon RE. Racial Segregation and Differential Outcomes in Hospital Care. Western Journal of Nursing Research. 2007;29(6):739–757.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17630385</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins WJ, Margo RA. Race and Home Ownership: A Century-Long View. Explorations in Economic History. 2001;38(1):68–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniels J.  Race, Civil Rights, and Hate Speech in the Digital Era. In: Everett A, editor. Learning Race and Ethnicity: Youth and Digital Media. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press; 2010. pp. 129–154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darity WA., Jr Employment Discrimination, Segregation, and Health. American Journal of Public Health. 2003;93(2):226–231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1447721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12554574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darity W, Dietrich J, Guilkey DK. Persistent Advantage or disadvantage?: Evidence in Support of the Intergenerational Drag Hypothesis. American Journal of Economics and Sociology. 2003;60(2):435–470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Castro AB, Fujishiro K, Schweitzer E, Olivia J. How Immigrant Workers Experience Workplace Problems: A Qualitative Study. Archives of Environmental and Occupational Health: An International Journal. 2006;61(6):249–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17967746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du Bois WEB. The Health and Physique of the Negro American. American Journal of Public Health. 2003;93:272–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1449799</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12554583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliott JR, Smith RA. Ethnic Matching of Supervisors to Subordinate Work Groups: Findings on “Bottom-Up” Ascription and Social Closure. Social Problems. 2001;48:258–276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finch BK, Frank R, Vega WA. Acculturation and Acculturation Stress: A Social-Epidemiological Approach to Mexican Migrant Farmworkers’ Health. International Migration Review. 2004;38(1):236–262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ford CL, Airhihenbuwa CO. The Public Health Critical Race Methodology: Praxis for Antiracism Research. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2010;71(8):1390–1398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20822840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ford CL, Harawa NT. A New Conceptualization of Ethnicity for Social Epidemiologic and Health Equity Research. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2010;71(2):251–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2908006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20488602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman LC. Segregation in Social Networks. Sociological Methods and Research. 1978;6(4):411–429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaskin DJ, Price A, Brandon DT, LaVeist TA. Segregation and Disparities in Health Services Use. Medical Care Research and Review. 2009;66(5):578–589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3099538</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19460811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gee GC. A Multilevel Analysis of the Relationship between Institutional and Individual Racial Discrimination and Health Status. American Journal of Public Health. 2002;92(4):615–623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1447127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11919062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gee GC, Payne-Sturges DC. Environmental Health Disparities: A Framework Integrating Psychosocial and Environmental Concepts. Environmental Health Perspectives. 2004;112(17):1645–1653.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1253653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15579407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gee GC, Ro A, Shariff-Marco S, Chae DH. Racial Discrimination and Health among Asian Americans: Evidence, Assessment, and Directions for Future Research. Epidemiologic Reviews. 2009;31(1):130–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4933297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldman DP, Smith JP, Sood N. Legal Status and Health Insurance among Immigrants. Health Affairs. 2005;24(6):1640–1653.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heckler MM.  Report of the Secretary’s Task Force on Black and Minority Health. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; 1985. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heckman JJ, Payner BS. Determining the Impact of Federal Antidiscrimination Policy on the Economic Status of Blacks: A Study of South Carolina. The American Economic Review. 1989;79(1):138–177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute of Medicine. Race, Ethnicity, and Language Data: Standardization for Health Care Quality Improvement. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James SA. Confronting the Moral Economy of US Racial/Ethnic Health Disparities. American Journal of Public Health. 2008;98(Supplement 1):S16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2518590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18687604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones CP. Levels of Racism: A Theoretic Framework and a Gardener’s Tale. American Journal of Public Health. 2000;90(8):1212–1215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1446334</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10936998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaushal N, Kaestner R. Welfare Reform and Health Insurance of Immigrants. Health Services Research. 2005;40(3):697–722.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1361164</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15960687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelaher M, Jessop DJ. Differences in Low-Birthweight among Documented and Undocumented Foreign-Born and US-born Latinas. Social Science and Medicine. 2002;55:2171–2175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12409130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kramer MR, Hogue CR. Is Segregation Bad for Your Health? Epidemiologic Reviews. 2009;31(1):178–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4362512</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19465747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger N. Embodying Inequality: A Review of Concepts, Measures, and Methods for Studying Health Consequences of Discrimination. International Journal of Health Services. 1999;29(2):295–352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10379455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger N, Williams DR, Moss NE. Measuring Social Class in US Public Health Research: Concepts, Methodologies, and Guidelines. Annual Review of Public Health. 1997;18:341–378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9143723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauderdale DS. Birth Outcomes for Arabic-Named Women in California Before and After September 11. Demography. 2006;43(1):185–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16579214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauderdale DS, Wen M, Jacobs EA, Kandula NR. Immigrant Perceptions of Discrimination in Health Care: the California Health Interview Survey 2003. Medical Care. 2006;44(10):914–920.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17001262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laumann EO, Youm Y. Racial/Ethnic Group Differences in the Prevalence of Sexually Transmitted Diseases in the United States: A Network Explanation. Sexually Transmitted Diseases. 1999;26:250–261.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10333277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LaVeist TA. Beyond Dummy Variables and Sample Selection: What Health Services Researchers Ought to Know about Race as a Variable. Health Services Research. 1994;29(1):1–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1069985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8163376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee BA, Reardon SF, Firebaugh G, Farrell CR, Matthews SA, O’Sullivan D. Beyond the Census Tract: Patterns and Determinants of Racial Residential Segregation at Multiple Scales. American Sociological Review. 2008;73:766–791.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4196718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25324575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonard D. Young, Black (&amp; Brown) and Don’t Give a Fuck. Cultural Studies Gåö Critical Methodologies. 2009;9(2):248–272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Link BG, Phelan J. Social Conditions as Fundamental Causes of Disease. Journal of Health and Social Behavior. 1995;35(extra issue):80–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7560851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margo RA.  Race and Schooling in the South, 1880–1950: An Economic History. Chicago, IL: University of Chicago Press; 1990. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mays VM, Cochran SD, Barnes NW. Race, Race-Based Discrimination, and Health Outcomes among African Americans. Annual Review of Psychology. 2006;58:201–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4181672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16953796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molina N.  Fit to Be Citizens. Berkeley, CA: University of California Press; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morello-Frosch R, Jesdale BM. Separate and Unequal: Residential Segregation and Estimated Cancer Risks Associated with Ambient Air Toxics in U.S. Metropolitan Areas. Environmental Health Perspectives. 2006;114(3):386–393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1392233</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16507462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nacos BL, Torres-Reyna O.  Fueling Our Fears: Stereotyping, Media Coverage, and Public Opinion of Muslim Americans. Lanham, MD: Rowman and Littlefield; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nevins J.  Operation Gatekeeper: The Rise of the “Illegal Alien” and the Making of the US-Mexico boundary. New York: Routledge; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Revisions to the Standards for the Classification of Federal Data on Race and Ethnicity. Federal Register. 1997;62:58781–58790.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortega AN, Fang H, Perez VH, Rizzo JA, Carter-Pokras O. Health Care Access, Use of Services, and Experiences among Undocumented Mexicans and Other Latinos. Archives of Internal Medicine. 2007;167(21):2354–2360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18039995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padela AI, Heisler M. The Association of Perceived Abuse and Discrimination after September 11, 2001, with Psychological Distress, Level of Happiness, and Health Status among Arab Americans. American Journal of Public Health. 2010;100(2):284–291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804633</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park JSW.  Elusive Citizenship: Immigration, Asian Americans, and the Paradox of Civil Rights. New York: New York University Press; 2004. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pembrey ME, Bygren LO, Kaati G, Edvinsson S, Northstone K. Sex-specific, Male-line Transgenerational Responses in Humans. European Journal of Human Genetics. 2005;14(2):159–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16391557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powell JA. Structural Racism: Building upon the Insights of John Calmore. North Carolina Law Review. 2008;86:791–816.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quadagno J. Promoting Civil Rights through the Welfare State: How Medicare Integrated Southern Hospitals. Social Problems. 2000;47(1):68–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18050538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reardon SF, Farrell CR, Matthews SA, O’Sullivan D, Bischoff K, Firebaugh G. Race and Space in the 1990s: Changes in the Geographic Scale of Racial Residential Segregation, 1990–2000. Social Science Research. 2009;38(1):55–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4057018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19569292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ross SL, Turner MA. Housing Discrimination in Metropolitan America: Explaining Changes between 1989 and 2000. Social Problems. 2005;52(2):152–180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sacerdote B. Slavery and the Intergenerational Transmission of Human Capital. Review of Economics and Statistics. 2005;87(2):217–234.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seckl JR, Holmes MC. Mechanisms of Disease: Glucocorticoids, their Placental Metabolism and Fetal ‘Programming’ of Adult Pathophysiology. Nature Clinical Practice Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 2007;3(6):479–488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17515892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith Aaron. Technology Trends Among People of Color.  [(accessed December 17, 2010)];Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project, September 17. 2010  〈 http://www.pewinternet.org/Commentary/2010/September/ Technology-Trends-Among-People-of-Color.aspx〉.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith DB. Racial and Ethnic Health Disparities and the Unfinished Civil Rights Agenda. Health Affairs. 2005;24(2):317–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15757914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith DB, Feng Z, Fennell ML, Zinn JS, Mor V. Separate and Unequal: Racial Segregation and Disparities in Quality across U.S. Nursing Homes. Health Affairs. 2007;26(5):1448–1458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sommers BD. Targeting in Medicaid: The Costs and Enrollment Effects of Medicaid’s Citizenship Documentation Experiment. Journal of Public Economics. 2010;94(1–2):174–182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sondik EJ, Huang DT, Klein RJ, Satcher D. Progress toward the Healthy People: 2010 Goals and Objectives. Annual Review of Public Health. 2010;31(1):271–281.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20070194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subramanian SV, Acevedo-Garcia D, Osypuk TL. Racial Residential Segregation and Geographic Heterogeneity in Black/White Disparity in Poor Self-Rated Health in the US: A Multilevel Statistical Analysis. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2005;60(8):1667–1679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15686800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner MA, Freiberg F, Godfrey E, Herbig C, Levy DK, Smith RR.  All Other Things Being Equal: A Paired Testing Study of Mortgage Lending Institutions. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanderbilt D, Augustyn M. The Effects of Bullying. Paediatrics and Child Health. 2010;20(7):315–320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viruell-Fuentes EA. Beyond Acculturation: Immigration, Discrimination, and Health Research among Mexicans in the United States. Social Science &amp;Medicine. 2007;65(7):1524–1535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17602812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakefield S, Uggen C. Incarceration and Stratification. Annual Review of Sociology. 2010;36:387–406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsemann KM, Bell BA. Integrated Schools, Segregated Curriculum: Effects of Within-School Segregation on Adolescent Health Behaviors and Educational Aspirations. American Journal of Public Health. 2010;100(9):1687–1695.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2920985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20634462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Iannotti RJ, Nansel TR. School Bullying among Adolescents in the United States: Physical, Verbal, Relational, and Cyber. Journal of Adolescent Health. 2009;45(4):368–375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19766941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White TK. Initial Conditions at Emancipation: The Long-Run Effect on Black-White Wealth and Earnings Inequality. Journal of Economic Dynamics and Control. 2007;31:3370–3395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams DR, Collins CA. Racial Residential Segregation: A Fundamental Cause of Racial Disparities in Health. Public Health Reports. 2001;116:404–416.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1497358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12042604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams DR, Costa MV, Odunlami AO, Mohammed SA. Moving Upstream: How Interventions That Address the Social Determinants of Health Can Improve Health and Reduce Disparities. Journal of Public Health Management and Practice. 2008;14(6):S8–S17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3431152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18843244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams DR, Mohammed SA. Discrimination and Racial Disparities in Health: Evidence and Needed Research. Journal of Behavioral Medicine. 2009;32:20–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821669</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19030981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright RO.  Chronology of Immigration in the United States. Jefferson, NC: McFarland &amp; Company, Inc; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoo HC, Gee GC, Takeuchi D. Discrimination and Health among Asian American Immigrants: Disentangling Racial from Language Discrimination. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2009;68(4):726–732.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3897711</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19095340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu SM, Huang ZJ, Schwalberg RH, Nyman RM. Parental English Proficiency and Children’s Health Services Access. American Journal of Public Health. 2006;96(8):1449–1455.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1522110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16809589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
