<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">25803845</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>PloS one</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Brand discrimination: an implicit measure of the strength of mental brand representations.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0121373</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0121373</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0121373</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0121373</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>While mental associations between a brand and its marketing elements are an important part of brand equity, previous research has yet to provide a sound methodology to measure the strength of these links. The following studies present the development and validation of an implicit measure to assess the strength of mental representations of brand elements in the mind of the consumer. The measure described in this paper, which we call the Brand Discrimination task, requires participants to identify whether images of brand elements (e.g. color, logo, packaging) belong to a target brand or not. Signal detection theory (SDT) is used to calculate a Brand Discrimination index which gives a measure of overall recognition accuracy for a brand's elements in the context of its competitors. A series of five studies shows that the Brand Discrimination task can discriminate between strong and weak brands, increases when mental representations of brands are experimentally strengthened, is relatively stable across time, and can predict brand choice, independently and while controlling for other explicit and implicit brand evaluation measures. Together, these studies provide unique evidence for the importance of mental brand representations in marketing and consumer behavior, along with a research methodology to measure this important consumer-based brand attribute.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Friedman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mike</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research on Consumers and Marketing Strategy (CCMS), Louvain School of Management, Catholic University of Louvain, Mons, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leclercq</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research on Consumers and Marketing Strategy (CCMS), Louvain School of Management, Catholic University of Louvain, Mons, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003210" MajorTopicYN="Y">Concept Formation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003258" MajorTopicYN="Y">Consumer Behavior</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004192" MajorTopicYN="N">Discrimination, Psychological</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D040541" MajorTopicYN="N">Marketing</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010775" MajorTopicYN="N">Photic Stimulation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017603" MajorTopicYN="Y">Signal Detection, Psychological</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2014</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25803845</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4372428</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0121373</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-14-19701</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cohen JB. Attitude, affect and consumer’s behaviors In: Moore B, Isen A, editors. Affect and Social Behavior. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 1990.  pp. 152–197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cohen JB, Pham MT, Andrade EB. The nature and role of affect in consumer behavior In: Haugtvedt CP, Herr PM, Kardes FR, editors. Handbook of consumer psychology. New-York: Psychology Press; 2008.  pp. 297–348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aaker J. Dimensions of Brand Personality. J Mark Res. 1997; 34: 347–356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Keller KL. Brand Synthesis: The Multidimensionality of Brand Knowledge. J Consum Res. 2003; 29: 595–600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Henderson GR, Iacobucci D, Calder BJ. Brand diagnostics: Mapping branding effects using consumer associative networks. Eur J Oper Res. 1998; 111: 306–327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Keller KL. Conceptualizing, Measuring, and Managing Customer-Based Brand Equity. J Mark. 1993; 57: 1–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Petty RE, Haugtvedt CP. Elaboration as a determinant of attitude strength: Creating attitudes that are persistent, resistant, and predictive of behavior In: Petty RE, Krosnick JA, editors. Attitude strength: Antecedents and consequences. New-York: Psychology Press; 1995.  pp. 93–138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Priester JR, Nayakankuppam D, Fleming MA, Godek J. The A 2 SC 2 Model: The Influence of Attitudes and Attitude Strength on Consideration and Choice. J Consum Res. 2004; 30: 574–587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Grohmann B. Gender Dimensions of Brand Personality. J Mark Res. 2009; 46: 105–119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brakus JJ, Schmitt BH, Zarantonello L. Brand Experience: What Is It? How Is It Measured? Does It Affect Loyalty?
J Mark. 2009; 73: 52–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Whan Park C, MacInnis DJ, Priester J, Eisingerich AB, Iacobucci D. Brand Attachment and Brand Attitude Strength: Conceptual and Empirical Differentiation of Two Critical Brand Equity Drivers. J Mark. 2010; 74: 1–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Anderson JR, Bower GH. Human Associative memory. 1st ed
Washington: Winston and sons Inc; 1973.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Krishnan HS. Characteristics of memory associations: A consumer-based brand equity perspective. Int J Res Mark. 1996; 13: 389–405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Henderson G, Iacobucci D, Calder BJ. Using Network Analysis to Understand Brands. Adv Consum Res. 2002; 29: 397–405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
John DR, Loken B, Kim K, Monga AB. Brand Concept Maps: A Methodology for Identifying Brand Association Networks. J Mark Res. 2006; 43: 549–563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aaker D, Shansby G. Positioning your product. Bus Horiz. 1982; May-Jun: 56–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Keller KL, Lehmann DR. Brands and Branding: Research Findings and Future Priorities. Mark Sci. 2006; 25: 740–759.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ries A, Trout J. How to be seen and heard in the overcrowded marketplace. 2nd ed
New-York: McGraw Hill Company; 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jones C, Fazio RH. Associative strength and consumer choice behavior In: Haugtvedt, Herr PM, Kardes FR, editors. Handbook of consumer psychology; New-York: Psychology Press; 2008.  pp. 437–459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Smith E, Queller S. Mental Representations In: Tesser A, Schwarz N, editors. Blackwell Handbook of Social Psychology: Intraindividual Processes. Oxford: Blackwell Publishing; 2001.  pp. 111–133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Higgins ET. Knowledge activation: Accessibility, applicability, and salience In: Higgins ET, Kruglanski AW, editors. Social psychology: Handbook of basic principles. New York: The Guilford Press; 1996.  pp. 133–168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nedungadi P. Recall and Consumer Consideration Sets: Influencing Choice without Altering Brand Evaluations. J Consum Res. 1990; 17: 263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fazio RH. On the automatic activation of associated evaluations: An overview. Cogn Emot. 2001; 15: 115–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hoeffler S, Keller KL. The marketing advantages of strong brands. J Brand Manag. 2003; 10: 421–445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Christensen GL, Olson JC. Mapping consumers’ mental models with ZMET. Psychol Mark. 2002; 19: 477–501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Payne BK, Gawronski B. A history of implicit social cognition: Where is it coming from? Where is it now? Where is it going? In: Payne BK, Gawronski B, editors. Handbook of implicit social cognition: Measurement, theory, and applications. New York: Guilford Press; 2010.  pp. 1–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nosek BA, Greenwald AG. (Part of) the case for a pragmatic approach to validity: comment on De Houwer, Teige-Mocigemba, Spruyt, and Moors (2009). Psychol Bull. 2009; 135: 373–376. 10.1037/a0015047
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0015047</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19379020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
De Houwer J, Teige-Mocigemba S, Spruyt A, Moors A. Implicit measures: A normative analysis and review. Psychol Bull. 2009; 135: 347–368. 10.1037/a0014211
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0014211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19379018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gawronski B. Ten frequently asked questions about implicit measures and their frequently supposed, but not entirely correct answers. Can Psychol Can. 2009; 50: 141–150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Perkins A, Forehand M, Greenwald A, Maison D. Measuring the nonconscious In: Haugtverdt CP, Herr PM, Kardes FR, editors. Handbook of Consumer Psychology. New-York: Psychology Press; 2008.  pp. 461–477
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vargas PT. Implicit Consumer Cognition In: Haugtverdt CP, Herr PM, Kardes FR, editors. Handbook of Consumer Psychology. New-York: Psychology Press; 2008.  pp. 477–505
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greenwald AG, Nosek BA, Banaji MR. Understanding and using the Implicit Association Test: I. An improved scoring algorithm. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2003; 85: 197–216.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12916565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Payne BK, Cheng CM, Govorun O, Stewart BD. An inkblot for attitudes: affect misattribution as implicit measurement. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2005; 89: 277–293.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16248714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nosek BA, Banaji MR. The Go/No-Go Association Task. Soc Cogn. 2001; 19: 625–666.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Green D, Swets J. Signal Detection Theory and Psychophysics. 1st ed
New York: Wiley &amp; Sons; 1966.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stanislaw H, Todorov N. Calculation of signal detection theory measures. Behav Res Methods, Instruments, Comput. 1999; 31: 137–149.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10495845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wickens CD. Multiple resources and performance prediction. Theor Issues Ergon Sci. 2002; 3: 159–177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
De Houwer J, Teige-Mocigemba S, Spruyt A, Moors A. Implicit measures: A normative analysis and review. Psychol Bull. 2009; 135: 347–368. 10.1037/a0014211
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0014211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19379018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Borsboom D, Mellenbergh GJ, van Heerden J. The concept of validity. Psychol Rev. 2004; 111: 1061–1071.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15482073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kosslyn SM. Measuring the visual angle of the mind’s eye. Cogn Psychol. 1978; 10: 356–389.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">688748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Spruyt A, Clarysse J, Vansteenwegen D, Baeyens F, Hermans D. Affect 4.0: a free software package for implementing psychological and psychophysiological experiments. Exp Psychol. 2010; 57: 36–45. 10.1027/1618-3169/a000005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1027/1618-3169/a000005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20178962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Pleyers G, Corneille O, Yzerbyt V, Luminet O. Evaluative conditioning may incur attentional costs. J Exp Psychol Anim Behav Process. 2009; 35: 279–285. 10.1037/a0013429
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0013429</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19364237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gawronski B, Deutsch R, Mbirkou S, Seibt B, Strack F. When “Just Say No” is not enough: Affirmation versus negation training and the reduction of automatic stereotype activation. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2008; 44: 370–377.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kawakami K, Dovidio JF, Moll J, Hermsen S, Russin A. Just say no (to stereotyping): Effects of training in the negation of stereotypic associations on stereotype activation. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2000; 78: 871–888.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10821195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nosek BA, Greenwald AG, Banaji MR. The Implicit Association Test At age 7: A methodological and conceptual review In: Bargh JA, editor. Social Psychology and the Unconscious. New-York: Psychology Press; 2007.  pp. 265–292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Egloff B, Schwerdtfeger A, Schmukle SC. Temporal stability of the implicit association test-anxiety. J Pers Assess. 2005; 84: 82–88.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15639771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lindgren KP, Neighbors C, Teachman BA, Wiers RW, Westgate E, Greenwald AG. I drink therefore I am: validating alcohol-related implicit association tests. Psychol Addict Behav. 2013; 27: 1–13. 10.1037/a0027640
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0027640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3604126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22428863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greenwald AG, Nosek BA. Health of the Implicit Association Test at Age 3. Exp Psychol. 2001; 48: 85–93.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11392985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Williams BJ, Kaufmann LM. Reliability of the Go/No Go Association Task. J Exp Soc Psychol. 2012; 48: 879–891.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Martin IM, Stewart DW. The Differential Impact of Goal Congruency on Attitudes, Intentions, and the Transfer of Brand Equity. J Mark Res. 2001; 38: 471–484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chaudhuri A, Holbrook MB. The Chain of Effects from Brand Trust and Brand Affect to Brand Performance: The Role of Brand Loyalty. J Mark. 2001; 65: 81–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Teachman BA. Evaluating implicit spider fear associations using the Go/No-go Association Task. J Behav Ther Exp Psychiatry. 2007; 38: 156–167.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17101115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Teichert TA, Schöntag K. Exploring consumer knowledge structures using associative network analysis. Psychol Mark. 2010; 27: 369–398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kiyonaga A, Egner T. The Working Memory Stroop Effect: When Internal Representations Clash With External Stimuli. Psychol Sci. 2014; 25: 1619–1629.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275427</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24958685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bajaj JS, Thacker LR, Heuman DM, Fuchs M, Sterling RK, Sanyal AJ
et al.
The Stroop smartphone application is a short and valid method to screen for minimal hepatic encephalopathy. Hepatology. 2013; 58: 1122–1132. 10.1002/hep.26309
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.26309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3657327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23389962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
