<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">26068698</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1935-2735</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>PLoS neglected tropical diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Rising Dominance of Shigella sonnei: An Intercontinental Shift in the Etiology of Bacillary Dysentery.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0003708</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0003708</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0003708</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pntd.0003708</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Shigellosis is the major global cause of dysentery. Shigella sonnei, which has historically been more commonly isolated in developed countries, is undergoing an unprecedented expansion across industrializing regions in Asia, Latin America, and the Middle East. The precise reasons underpinning the epidemiological distribution of the various Shigella species and this global surge in S. sonnei are unclear but may be due to three major environmental pressures. First, natural passive immunization with the bacterium Plesiomonas shigelloides is hypothesized to protect populations with poor water supplies against S. sonnei. Improving the quality of drinking water supplies would, therefore, result in a reduction in P. shigelloides exposure and a subsequent reduction in environmental immunization against S. sonnei. Secondly, the ubiquitous amoeba species Acanthamoeba castellanii has been shown to phagocytize S. sonnei efficiently and symbiotically, thus allowing the bacteria access to a protected niche in which to withstand chlorination and other harsh environmental conditions in temperate countries. Finally, S. sonnei has emerged from Europe and begun to spread globally only relatively recently. A strong selective pressure from localized antimicrobial use additionally appears to have had a dramatic impact on the evolution of the S. sonnei population. We hypothesize that S. sonnei, which exhibits an exceptional ability to acquire antimicrobial resistance genes from commensal and pathogenic bacteria, has a competitive advantage over S. flexneri, particularly in areas with poorly regulated antimicrobial use. Continuing improvement in the quality of global drinking water supplies alongside the rapid development of antimicrobial resistance predicts the burden and international distribution of S. sonnei will only continue to grow. An effective vaccine against S. sonnei is overdue and may become one of our only weapons against this increasingly dominant and problematic gastrointestinal pathogen.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thompson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Corinne N</ForeName>
            <Initials>CN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Hospital for Tropical Diseases, Wellcome Trust Major Overseas Programme, Oxford University Clinical Research Unit, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam; Centre for Tropical Medicine, Nuffield Department of Clinical Medicine, Oxford University, Oxford, United Kingdom; The London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Duy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pham Thanh</ForeName>
            <Initials>PT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Hospital for Tropical Diseases, Wellcome Trust Major Overseas Programme, Oxford University Clinical Research Unit, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Baker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephen</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Hospital for Tropical Diseases, Wellcome Trust Major Overseas Programme, Oxford University Clinical Research Unit, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam; Centre for Tropical Medicine, Nuffield Department of Clinical Medicine, Oxford University, Oxford, United Kingdom; The London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>089276</GrantID>
            <Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency>
            <Country>United Kingdom</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>100087</GrantID>
            <Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency>
            <Country>United Kingdom</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>PLoS Negl Trop Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101291488</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1935-2727</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001208" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Asia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004405" MajorTopicYN="N">Dysentery, Bacillary</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007114" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunization</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007843" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Latin America</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008877" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Middle East</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012764" MajorTopicYN="N">Shigella sonnei</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26068698</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4466244</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0003708</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">PNTD-D-14-02187</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Thapar N, Sanderson IR (2004) Diarrhoea in children: an interface between developing and developed countries. Lancet
363: 641–653.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14987892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kotloff KL, Nataro JP, Blackwelder WC, Nasrin D, Farag TH, et al. (2013) Burden and aetiology of diarrhoeal disease in infants and young children in developing countries (the Global Enteric Multicenter Study, GEMS): a prospective, case-control study. Lancet
382: 209–222. 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60844-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60844-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23680352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bardhan P, Faruque A, Naheed A, Sack DA (2010) Decrease in shigellosis-related deaths without Shigella spp.-specific interventions, Asia. Emerg Infect Dis
16: 1718–1723. 10.3201/eid1611.090934
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid1611.090934</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3294502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21029529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
DuPont HL, Levine MM, Hornick RB, Formal SB (1989) Inoculum Size in Shigellosis and Implications for Expected Mode of Transmission. J Infect Dis
159: 1126–1128.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2656880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gu B, Cao Y, Pan S, Zhuang L, Yu R, et al. (2012) Comparison of the prevalence and changing resistance to nalidixic acid and ciprofloxacin of Shigella between Europe-America and Asia-Africa from 1998 to 2009. Int J Antimicrob Agents
40: 9–17. 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2012.02.005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2012.02.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vinh H, Baker S, Campbell J, Hoang NVM, Loan HT, et al. (2009) Rapid emergence of third generation cephalosporin resistant Shigella spp. in Southern Vietnam. J Med Microbiol
58: 281–283. 10.1099/jmm.0.002949-0
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.002949-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19141753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Germani Y, Sansonetti PJ (2011) Replicating Vaccines In: Dormitzer PR, Mandl CW, Rappuoli R, editors. Replicating Vaccines. Basel: Springer Basel;  pp. 99–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Livio S, Strockbine NA, Panchalingam S, Tennant SM, Barry EM, et al. (2014) Shigella isolates from the global enteric multicenter study inform vaccine development. Clin Infect Dis
59: 933–941. 10.1093/cid/ciu468
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciu468</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24958238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tuttle J, Ries A, Chimba R, Perera C, Bean N, et al. (1995) Antimicrobial-resistant epidemic Shigella dysenteriae type 1 in Zambia: modes of transmission. J Infect Dis
171: 371–375.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7844374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kotloff K, Winickoff J, Ivanoff B, Clemens J, Swerdlow D, et al. (1999) Global burden of Shigella infections: implications for vaccine development and implementation of control strategies. Bull World Health Organ
77: 651–666.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2557719</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10516787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Levine MM, Kotloff KL, Barry EM, Pasetti MF, Sztein MB (2007) Clinical trials of Shigella vaccines: two steps forward and one step back on a long, hard road. Nat Rev Microbiol
5: 540–553.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3771495</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ram P, Crump J, Gupta S, Miller M, Mintz E (2008) Part II. Analysis of data gaps pertaining to Shigella infections in low and medium human development index countries, 1984–2005. Epidemiol Infect
136: 577–603.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17686195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Keusch GT (2009) Bacterial Infections of Humans. Brachman PS, Abrutyn E, editors Boston, MA: Springer US.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Feil E (2012) The emergence and spread of dysentery. Nat Genet
44: 964–965. 10.1038/ng.2389
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.2389</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22932498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vinh H, Nhu NTK, Nga TVT, Duy PT, Campbell JI, et al. (2009) A changing picture of shigellosis in southern Vietnam: shifting species dominance, antimicrobial susceptibility and clinical presentation. BMC Infect Dis
9: 204–216. 10.1186/1471-2334-9-204
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-9-204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2803792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20003464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Qu F, Bao C, Chen S, Cui E, Guo T, et al. (2012) Genotypes and antimicrobial profiles of Shigella sonnei isolates from diarrheal patients circulating in Beijing between 2002 and 2007. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis
74: 166–170. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2012.06.026
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2012.06.026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7127854</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22858547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fullá N, Prado V, Durán C, Lagos R, Levine MM (2005) Surveillance for antimicrobial resistance profiles among Shigella species isolated from a semirural community in the northern administrative area of Santiago, Chile. Am J Trop Med Hyg
72: 851–854.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15964975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sousa MÂB, Mendes EN, Collares GB, Péret-Filho LA, Penna FJ, et al. (2013) Shigella in Brazilian children with acute diarrhoea: prevalence, antimicrobial resistance and virulence genes. Memorias Inst Oswaldo Cruz
108: 30–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3974317</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tajbakhsh M, García Migura L, Rahbar M, Svendsen CA, Mohammadzadeh M, et al. (2012) Antimicrobial-resistant Shigella infections from Iran: an overlooked problem?
J Antimicrob Chemother
67: 1128–1133. 10.1093/jac/dks023
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dks023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22345385</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ashkenazi S, Levy I, Kazaronovski V, Samra Z (2003) Growing antimicrobial resistance of Shigella isolates. J Antimicrob Chemother
51: 427–429.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12562716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Van de Verg L, Herrington D, Boslego J, Lindberg A, Levine M (1992) Age-specific prevalence of serum antibodies to the invasion plasmid and lipopolysaccharide antigens of Shigella species in Chilean and North American populations. J Infect Dis
166: 158–161.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1607690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kubler-Kielb J, Schneerson R, Mocca C, Vinogradov E (2008) The elucidation of the structure of the core part of the LPS from Plesiomonas shigelloides serotype O17 expressing O-polysaccharide chain identical to the Shigella sonnei O-chain. Carbohydr Res
343: 3123–3127. 10.1016/j.carres.2008.09.017
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.carres.2008.09.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2593084</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18954864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cohen D, Ashkenazi S, Green M, Gdalevich M, Robin G, et al. (1997) Double-blind vaccine-controlled randomised efficacy trial of an investigational Shigella sonnei conjugate vaccine in young adults. Lancet
349: 155–159.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9111538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Passwell JH, Ashkenazi S, Harlev E, Miron D, Ramon R, et al. (2003) Safety and immunogenicity of Shigella sonnei-CRM 9 and Shigella flexneri type 2a-rEPA succ conjugate vaccines in one- to four-year-old children. Pediatr Infect Dis J
22: 701–706.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12913770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Watanabe H, Nakamura A (1986) Identification of Shigella sonnei form I plasmid genes necessary for cell invasion and their conservation among Shigella species and enteroinvasive Escherichia coli. Infect Immun
53: 352–358.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC260882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3015801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shepherd JG, Wang L, Reeves P (2000) Comparison of O-antigen gene clusters of Echerichia coli (Shigella) Sonnei and Plesiomonas shigelloides O17: Sonnei gained its current plasmid-borne O-antigen genes from P. shigelloides in a recent event. Infect Immun
68: 6056–6061.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10992522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sack D, Hoque A, Huq A, Etheridge M (1994) Is protection against shigellosis induced by natural infection with Plesiomonas shigelloides?
Lancet
343: 1413–1415.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7910890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Krovacek K, Eriksson LM, González-Rey C, Rosinsky J, Ciznar I (2000) Isolation, biochemical and serological characterisation of Plesiomonas shigelloides from freshwater in Northern Europe. Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis
23: 45–51.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10660257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kwaga J, Adesiyun A, Bello C, Abdullahi S (1988) Occurrence of Plesiomonas shigelloides in humans and water in Zaria, Nigeria. Microbiologica
11: 165–167.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3405099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tsukamoto T, Kinoshita Y, Shimada T, Sakazaki R (1978) Two epidemics of diarrhoeal disease possibly caused by Plesiomonas shigelloides. J Hyg (Lond)
80: 275–280.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2130002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">632567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
González-Rey C, Svenson SB, Bravo L, Siitonen A, Pasquale V, et al. (2004) Serotypes and anti-microbial susceptibility of Plesiomonas shigelloides isolates from humans, animals and aquatic environments in different countries. Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis
27: 129–139.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14690722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bravo LF, Correa Y, Clausell JF, Fernandez A, Ramírez M, et al. (2009) Caracterización de factores de virulencia y susceptibilidad antimicrobiana en cepas de Plesiomonas shigelloides aisladas de pacientes con diarrea aguda en Cuba. Microbiol Clin
26: 233–238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aldova E (1987) Serotyping of Plesiomonas shigelloides strains with our own antigenic scheme: an attempted epidemiology study. Zentralblatt fur Bakteriol Mikrobiol un Hyg
265: 253–262.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3673335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Holt KE, Baker S, Weill F-X, Holmes EC, Kitchen A, et al. (2012) Shigella sonnei genome sequencing and phylogenetic analysis indicate recent global dissemination from Europe. Nat Genet
44: 1056–1059. 10.1038/ng.2369
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.2369</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3442231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22863732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Trabelsi H, Dendana F, Sellami A, Sellami H, Cheikhrouhou F, et al. (2012) Pathogenic free-living amoebae: epidemiology and clinical review. Pathol Biol
60: 399–405. 10.1016/j.patbio.2012.03.002
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patbio.2012.03.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22520593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jeong HJ, Jang ES, Han BI, Lee KH, Ock MS, et al. (2007) Acanthamoeba: could it be an environmental host of Shigella?
Exp Parasitol
115: 181–186.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16978610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Abd H, Weintraub A, Sandström G (2005) Intracellular survival and replication of Vibrio cholerae O139 in aquatic free-living amoebae. Environ Microbiol
7: 1003–1008.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15946296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Winiecka-Krusnell J, Wreiber K, von Euler A, Engstrand L, Linder E (2002) Free-living amoebae promote growth and survival of Helicobacter pylori. Scand J Infect Dis
34: 253–256.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12064686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aksozek A, Mcclellan K, Howardt K, Niederkornt JY, Alizadehtt H (2002) Resistance of Acanthamoeba castellanii cysts to physical, chemical and radiological conditions. J Parasitol
88: 621–623.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12099437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dupuy M, Berne F, Herbelin P, Binet M, Berthelot N, et al. (2013) Sensitivity of free-living amoeba trophozoites and cysts to water disinfectants. Int J Hyg Environ Health 12711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23932411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Marciano-Cabral F, Cabral G (2003) Acanthamoeba spp. as agents of disease in humans. Clin Microbiol Rev
16: 273–307.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC153146</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12692099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang H, Edwards M, Falkinham JO, Pruden A (2012) Molecular survey of the occurrence of Legionella spp., Mycobacterium spp., Pseudomonas aeruginosa, and amoeba hosts in two chloraminated drinking water distribution systems. Appl Environ Microbiol
78: 6285–6294. 10.1128/AEM.01492-12
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.01492-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3416603</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22752174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ovrutsky AR, Chan ED, Kartalija M, Bai X, Jackson M, et al. (2013) Cooccurrence of free-living amoebae and nontuberculous Mycobacteria in hospital water networks, and preferential growth of Mycobacterium avium in Acanthamoeba lenticulata. Appl Environ Microbiol
79: 3185–3192. 10.1128/AEM.03823-12
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.03823-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3685249</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23475613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanveer T, Hameed A, Muazzam AG, Jung S-Y, Gul A, et al. (2013) Isolation and molecular characterization of potentially pathogenic Acanthamoeba genotypes from diverse water resources including household drinking water from Khyber Pakhtunkhwa, Pakistan. Parasitol Res
112: 2925–2932. 10.1007/s00436-013-3465-5
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00436-013-3465-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23749088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Saeed A, Abd H, Edvinsson B, Sandström G (2009) Acanthamoeba castellanii an environmental host for Shigella dysenteriae and Shigella sonnei. Arch Microbiol
191: 83–88. 10.1007/s00203-008-0422-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00203-008-0422-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18712360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saeed A, Johansson D, Sandström G, Abd H (2012) Temperature Depended Role of Shigella flexneri Invasion Plasmid on the Interaction with Acanthamoeba castellanii. Int J Microbiol: 917031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22518151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zychlinsky A, Prevost MC, Sansonetti P (1992) Shigella flexneri induces apoptosis in infected macrophages. Nature
358: 167–169.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1614548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fernandez-Prada CM, Hoover DL, Tall BD, Hartman AB, Kopelowitz J, et al. (2000) Shigella flexneri IpaH(7.8) facilitates escape of virulent bacteria from the endocytic vacuoles of mouse and human macrophages. Infect Immun
68: 3608–3619.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97650</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10816519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ismail N, Olano JP, Feng H-M, Walker DH (2002) Current status of immune mechanisms of killing of intracellular microorganisms. FEMS Microbiol Lett
207: 111–120.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11958927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Harb OS, Gao L, Kwaik YA (2000) From protozoa to mammalian cells: a new paradigm in the life cycle of intracellular bacterial pathogens. Environ Microbiol
2: 251–265.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11200426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greub G, Raoult D (2004) Microorganisms resistant to free-living amoebae. Clin Microbiol Rev
17: 413–433.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15084508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Goebel W, Gross R (2001) Intracellular survival strategies of mutualistic and parasitic prokaryotes. Trends Microbiol
9: 267–273.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11390241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Barker J, Scaife H, Brown MR (1995) Intraphagocytic growth induces an antibiotic-resistant phenotype of Legionella pneumophila. Antimicrob Agents Chemother
39: 2684–2688.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC163012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8593002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
King CH, Shotts EB, Wooley RE, Porter KG (1988) Survival of coliforms and bacterial pathogens within protozoa during chlorination. Appl Environ Microbiol
54: 3023–3033.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC204422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3223766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ke X, Gu B, Pan S, Tong M (2011) Epidemiology and molecular mechanism of integron-mediated antibiotic resistance in Shigella. Arch Microbiol
193: 767–774. 10.1007/s00203-011-0744-3
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00203-011-0744-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21842348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Holt K, Thieu Nga T, Thanh D, Vinh H, Kim D, et al. (2013) Tracking the establishment of local endemic populations of an emergent enteric pathogen. Proc Natl Acad Sci
110: 17522–17527. 10.1073/pnas.1308632110
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1308632110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3808646</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24082120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ochman H, Lawrence JG, Groisman E a (2000) Lateral gene transfer and the nature of bacterial innovation. Nature
405: 299–304.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10830951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Juhas M (2015) Horizontal gene transfer in human pathogens. Crit Rev Microbiol
7828: 101–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23862575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lawrence JG, Ochman H (1998) Molecular archaeology of the Escherichia coli genome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
95: 9413–9417.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC21352</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9689094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
White PA, Iver CJMC, Rawlinson WD (2001) Integrons and Gene Cassettes in the Enterobacteriaceae. Antimicrob Agents Chemother
45: 2658–2661.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC90711</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11502548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cergole-Novella MC, Pignatari ACC, Castanheira M, Guth BEC (2011) Molecular typing of antimicrobial-resistant Shiga-toxin-producing Escherichia coli strains (STEC) in Brazil. Res Microbiol
162: 117–123. 10.1016/j.resmic.2010.09.022
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.resmic.2010.09.022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21126577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Le TMV, Baker S, Le TPT, Le TPT, Cao TT, et al. (2009) High prevalence of plasmid-mediated quinolone resistance determinants in commensal members of the Enterobacteriaceae in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. J Med Microbiol
58: 1585–1592. 10.1099/jmm.0.010033-0
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.010033-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2884939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization: Guidelines for the control of shigellosis, including epidemics due to Shigella dysenteriae type 1 (2005). Geneva.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Traa BS, Walker CLF, Munos M, Black RE (2010) Antibiotics for the treatment of dysentery in children. Int J Epidemiol
39
Suppl 1: i70–4. 10.1093/ije/dyq024
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyq024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845863</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20348130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zaidi MB, Estrada-Garcia T (2014) Shigella: A Highly Virulent and Elusive Pathogen. Curr Trop Med Reports
1: 81–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4126259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25110633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nandy S, Mitra U, Rajendran K, Dutta P, Dutta S (2010) Subtype prevalence, plasmid profiles and growing fluoroquinolone resistance in Shigella from Kolkata, India (2001–2007): a hospital-based study. Trop Med Int Heal
15: 1499–1507. 10.1111/j.1365-3156.2010.02656.x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-3156.2010.02656.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20955371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Toro CS, Farfán M, Contreras I, Flores O, Navarro N, et al. (2005) Genetic analysis of antibiotic-resistance determinants in multidrug-resistant Shigella strains isolated from Chilean children. Epidemiol Infect
133: 81–86.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15724714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dutta S, Rajendran K, Roy S, Chatterjee A, Dutta P, et al. (2002) Shifting serotypes, plasmid profile analysis and antimicrobial resistance pattern of shigellae strains isolated from Kolkata, India during 1995–2000. Epidemiol Infect
129: 235–243.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2869882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12403099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Von Seidlein L, Kim DR, Ali M, Lee H, Wang X, et al. (2006) A multicentre study of Shigella diarrhoea in six Asian countries: disease burden, clinical manifestations, and microbiology. PLoS Med
3: e353
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1564174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16968124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ghosh S, Pazhani GP, Chowdhury G, Guin S, Dutta S, et al. (2011) Genetic characteristics and changing antimicrobial resistance among Shigella spp. isolated from hospitalized diarrhoeal patients in Kolkata, India. J Med Microbiol
60: 1460–1466. 10.1099/jmm.0.032920-0
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jmm.0.032920-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21659504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Replogle M, Fleming D, Cieslak P (2000) Emergence of antimicrobial-resistant shigellosis in Oregon. Clin Infect Dis
30: 515–519.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Pai H, Choi E, Lee H, Yun J, Jacoby GA (2001) Identification of CTX-M-14 Extended-Spectrum β -Lactamase in Clinical Isolates of Shigella sonnei, Escherichia coli, and Klebsiella pneumoniae in Korea. J Clin Microbiol
39: 3747–3749.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11574608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stecher B, Denzler R, Maier L, Bernet F, Sanders MJ, et al. (2012) Gut inflammation can boost horizontal gene transfer between pathogenic and commensal Enterobacteriaceae. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
109: 1269–1274. 10.1073/pnas.1113246109
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1113246109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3268327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22232693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paciello I, Silipo A, Lembo-Fazio L, Curcurù L, Zumsteg A, et al. (2013) Intracellular Shigella remodels its LPS to dampen the innate immune recognition and evade inflammasome activation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A: 4345–4354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3832022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24167293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Balbi KJ, Rocha EPC, Feil EJ (2009) The temporal dynamics of slightly deleterious mutations in Escherichia coli and Shigella spp. Genome Biol
26: 345–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18984902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hershberg R, Tang H, Petrov DA (2007) Reduced selection leads to accelerated gene loss in Shigella. Genome Biol
8: R164
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2374995</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17686180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Thomas CM, Nielsen KM (2005) Mechanisms of, and barriers to, horizontal gene transfer between bacteria. Nat Rev Microbiol
3: 711–721.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16138099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Green M, Block C, Cohen D, Slater P (1991) Four decades of shigellosis in Israel: epidemiology of a growing public health problem. Rev Infect Dis
13: 248–253.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2041956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rosenberg ML, Weissman JB, Gangarosa EJ, Reller LB, Beasley RP, et al. (1976) Shigellosis in the United States: Ten-year review of nationwide surveillance, 1964–1973. Am J Epidemiol
104: 543–551.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">790947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Baker S, Duy PT, Nga TVT, Dung TTN, Phat VV, et al. (2013) Fitness benefits in fluoroquinolone-resistant Salmonella Typhi in the absence of antimicrobial pressure. Elife
2: e01229
10.7554/eLife.01229
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.01229</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3857714</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24327559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
