<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">26203280</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2015</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1357</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>7</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical, cosmetic and investigational dentistry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Cosmet Investig Dent</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: clinical presentation and management options.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>75</StartPage>
          <EndPage>81</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>75-81</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/CCIDE.S76080</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome (PLS) is a rare autosomal recessive disorder, characterized by diffuse palmoplantar keratoderma and precocious aggressive periodontitis, leading to premature loss of deciduous and permanent dentition at a very young age. Various etiopathogenic factors are associated with the syndrome, like immunologic alterations, genetic mutations, and the role of bacteria. Dentists play a significant role in the diagnosis and management of PLS as there are characteristic manifestations like periodontal destruction at an early age and an early eruption of permanent teeth. Here, we are presenting an elaborate review of PLS, its etiopathogenesis, clinical presentation, and management options.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sreeramulu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Basapogu</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Government Dental College and Hospital, Hyderabad, Telangana State, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shyam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naragani Dvn</ForeName>
            <Initials>ND</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oral Pathology, Government Dental College and Hospital, Hyderabad, Telangana State, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ajay</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pilla</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Government Dental College and Hospital, Hyderabad, Telangana State, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pathipaka</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Government Dental College and Hospital, Hyderabad, Telangana State, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Cosmet Investig Dent</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101579785</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1179-1357</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deciduous and permanent dentition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">modified complete dentures</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palmoplantar keratoderma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">periodontitis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26203280</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4507741</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CCIDE.S76080</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">ccide-7-075</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sreeramulu B, Haragopal S, Shalini K, Sudha MD, Kiran G. The prosthodontic management of a young edentulous patient with the papillon lefevre syndrome-a rare case report. J Clin Diagn Res. 2012;6(10):1808–1811.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3552236</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23373060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullbro C, Crossner CG, Nederfors T, Alfadley A, Thestrup-Pedersen K. Dermatologic and oral findings in a cohort of 47 patients with Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2003;48:345–351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12637913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wani AA, Devkar N, Patole MS, Shouche YS. Description of two new cathepsin C gene mutations in patients with Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Periodontol. 2006;77:233–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16460249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James WD, Berger T, Elston D.  Andrews’ Diseases of the Skin: Clinical Dermatology. 10th ed. Philadelphia: Saunders; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hattab FN, Rawashdeh MA, Yassin OM, al-Momani AS, al-Ubosi M. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: a review of the literature and report of 4 cases. J Periodontol. 1995;66:413–420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7623262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sollecito TP, Sullivan KE, Pinto A, Steward J, Korostoff J. Systemic conditions associated with periodontits in childhood and adolescence. A review of diagnostic possibilities. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2005;10:142–150. English, Spanish.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart TC, Shapira L. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. Periodontol 2000. 1994;6:88–100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9673173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haneke E. The Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: keratosis palmoplantaris with periodontopathy. Report of a case and review of the cases in the literature. Hum Genet. 1979;51:1–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">159254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cury VF, Costa JE, Gomez RS, Boson WL, Loures CG, De ML. A novel mutation of the cathepsin C gene in Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Periodontol. 2002;73:307–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11922261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan FY, Jan SM, Mushtaq M. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: Case report and review of the literature. J Indian Soc Periodontol. 2012;16(2):261–265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23055596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almuneef M, Al Khenaizan S, Al Ajaji S, Al Anazi A. Pyogenic liver abscess and Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: not a rare association. Pediatrics. 2003;111:e85–e88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12509601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart TC, Hart PS, Bowden DW, et al.  Mutation of the cathepsin C gene are responsible for Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Med Genet. 1999;36:881–887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734286</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10593994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toomes C, James J, Wood AJ, et al.  Loss-of-function mutations in the cathepsin C gene result in periodontal disease and palmoplantar keratosis. Nat Genet. 1999;23:421–424.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10581027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oğuzkurt P, Tanyel FC, Büyükpamukçu N, Hiçsönmez A. Increased risk of liver abscess in children with Papillon-Lefevre syndrome. J Pediatr Surg. 1996;31:955–956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8811566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bullon P, Pascual A, Fernandez-Novoa MC, Borobio MV, Muniain MA, Camacho F. Late onset Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome? A chromosomic, neutrophil function and microbiological study. J Clin Periodontol. 1993;20:662–667.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8227454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghaffer KA, Zahran FM, Fahmy HM, Brown RS. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: neutrophil function in 15 cases from 4 families in Egypt. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod. 1999;88:320–325.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10503862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu R, Cao C, Meng H, Tang Z. Leukocyte function in 2 cases of Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Clin Periodontol. 2000;27:69–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10674964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Celenligil H, Kansu E, Ruacan S, Eratalay K. Papillon–Lefèvre syndrome. Characterization of peripheral blood and gingival lymphocytes with monoclonal antibodies. J Clin Periodontol. 1992;19:392–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1353082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Góngora R, Corell A, Regueriro JR, Carasol M, Rodriguez-Gallego C, Paz-Artal Peripheral blood reduction of memory (CD29+, CD45RO+, and “bright” CD2+ and LFA-1+) T lymphocytes in Papillon–Lefèvre syndrome. Hum Immunol. 1994;41:185–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7532641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyberg T. Immunological and metabolic studies in two siblings with Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Periodontal Res. 1982;17:563–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6219203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeder HE, Seger RA, Keller HU, Rateitschak-Plüss EM. Behavior of neutrophilic granulocytes in a case of Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Clin Periodontol. 1983;10:618–635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6228567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishikawa I, Umeda M, Laosrisin N. Clinical, bacteriological, and immunological examination and the treatment process of two Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome patients. J Periodontol. 1994;65:364–371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8195982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleinfelder JW, Topoll HH, Preus HR, Müller RF, Lange DE, Böcker W. Microbiological and immunohistological findings in a patient with Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Clin Periodontol. 1996;23:1032–1038.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8951633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clerehugh V, Drucker DB, Seymour GJ, Bird PS. Microbiological and serological investigation of oral lesions in Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Clin Pathol. 1996;49:255–257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC500410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8675741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velazco CH, Coelho C, Salzar F, Contreras A, Slots J, Pacheco JJ. Microbiological features of Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome periodontitis. J Clin Periodontol. 1999;26:622–627.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10487314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drucker DB, Marshall R, Bird PS. Aetiology of Papillon LeFèvre syndrome. Anaerobe. 2001;7:151–158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cagli NA, Hakki SS, Dursun R, et al.  Clinical, genetic, and biochemical findings in two siblings with Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Periodontol. 2005;76:2322–2329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16332247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel S, Davidson LE. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: a report of two cases. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2004;14:288–294.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15242386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angel TA, Hsu S, Kornbleuth SI, Kornbleuth J, Kramer EM. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: a case report of four affected siblings. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2002;46:S8–S10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11807457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundgren T, Parhar RS, Renvert S, Tatakis DN. Impaired cytotoxicity in Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Dent Res. 2005;84:414–417.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15840775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryu OH, Choi SJ, Firatli E, et al.  Proteolysis of macrophage inflammatory protein-1alpha isoforms LD78beta and LD78alpha by neutrophil-derived serine proteases. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:17415–17421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15728180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Haar SF, Hiemstra PS, van Steenbergen MT, Everts V, Beertsen W. Role of polymorphonuclear leukocyte-derived serine proteinases in defense against Actinobacillus actinomycetemcomitans. Infect Immun. 2006;74:5284–5291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1594863</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16926422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Umeda M, Zhang VJ, Koseki T, Ishikawa I. Clinical, bacteriological and immunological examination and treatment of two Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome patients. Kokubyo Gakkai Zasshi. 1990;57(3):430–440. Japanese.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2258685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albandar JM, Khattab R, Monem F, Barbuto SM, Paster BJ. The subgingival microbiota of Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. J Periodontol. 2012;83:902–908.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22141356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baghdady VS. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: report of four cases. ASDC J Dent Child. 1982;49:147–150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6460796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahmy MS. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: Report of four cases in two families with a strong tie of consanguinity. A clinical, radiographic, haematological and genetic study. J Oral Med. 1987;42:263–268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joshi HN, Dayal PK, Kansagra PJ. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: report of case. ASDC J Dent Child. 1985;52(6):461–463.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2933435</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glenwright HD, Rock WP. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: A discussion of aetiology and a case report. Br Dent J. 1990;168:27–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2137346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kola MZ. Prosthodontic Management of Papillon-Lefevre syndrome with special focus on its characterization and diagnosis: A Clinical Report. Journal of Advanced Medical and Dental Sciences Research. 2014;2(4):97–104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pareek SS, Al-Aska AK. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome. A report of six cases in one family. Int J Dermatol. 1986;25:638–641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2948927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah J, Goel S. Papillon–Lefèvre syndrome: two case reports. Indian J Dent Res. 2007;18:210–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajendran R, Sivapathasundharam B, editors. Shafer’s text book of oral pathology. 7th ed. New Delhi: Elsevier; 2012. Diseases of the periodontium; p. 411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munford AG. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: report of two cases in the same family. J Am Dent Assoc. 1976;93:121–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">132466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu HK, Lin CT, Kwan HW. Treatment of a patient with Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. A case report. J Periodontol. 1987;58:789–793.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2961877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagaveni NB, Suma R, Shashikiran ND, Subba Reddy VV. The Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: Report of two cases in the same family. J Indian Soc Pedod Prev Dent. 2008;26:78–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18603734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhanrajani PJ. Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: clinical presentation and a brief review. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod. 2009;108:e1–e7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19540439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kellum RE. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome in four siblings treated with Etretinate. A nine-year evaluation. Int J Dermatol. 1989;28:605–608.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2531126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain V, Gupta R, Prakash H. Prosthodonti rehabilitation in Papillon-Lefevre syndrome: a case report. J Indian Soc Pedod Prev Dent. 2005;23(2):96–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16012214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oesterle LJ, Cronin RJ, Jr, Ranly DM. Maxillary implants and the growing patient. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 1993;8:377–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8270306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brugnolo E, Mazzocco C, Cordioll G, Majzoub Z. Clinical and radiographic findings following placement of single-tooth implants in young patients – case reports. Int J Periodontics Restorative Dent. 1996;16:421–433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9084315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adell R, Eriksson B, Lekholm U, Brånemark PI, Jemt T. Long-term follow-up study of osseointegrated implants in the treatment of totally edentulous jaws. Int J Oral Maxillofac Implants. 1990;5:347–359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2094653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullbro C, Brown A, Twetman S. Preventive periodontal regimen in Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome. Pediatr Dent. 2005;27:226–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16173228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khenaizan S. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: the response to Acitretin. Int J Dermatol. 2002;41:938–941.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12492996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh R, Nor M, Ghazali W. Atypical Papiilon-Lefèvre syndrome: keratosis palmoplantaris with periodontopathy. Int J Dermatol. 1993;32:450–452.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8320031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berman R, Friedman-Birnbaum R. Papillon-Lefèvre syndrome: a study of the long-term clinical course of recurrent pyogenic infections and the effects of etretinate treatment. Br J Dermatol. 1988;119:731–736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2974305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundgren T, Crossner CG, Twetman S, Ullbro C. Systemic retinoid medication and periodontal health in patients with Papillon-Lefevre syndrome. J Clin Periodontol. 1996;23(3 Pt 1):176–179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8707975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prendiville J, Bingham EA, Burrows D. Premature epiphyseal closure – a complication of etretinate therapy in children. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1986;15:1259–1262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3805366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
