<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">26267006</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-1770</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>29</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Best practice &amp; research. Clinical rheumatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Physical exercise as non-pharmacological treatment of chronic pain: Why and when.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>120</StartPage>
          <EndPage>130</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>120-30</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.berh.2015.04.022</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1521-6942(15)00029-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Chronic pain broadly encompasses both objectively defined conditions and idiopathic conditions that lack physical findings. Despite variance in origin or pathogenesis, these conditions are similarly characterized by chronic pain, poor physical function, mobility limitations, depression, anxiety, and sleep disturbance, and they are treated alone or in combination by pharmacologic and non-pharmacologic approaches, such as physical activity (aerobic conditioning, muscle strengthening, flexibility training, and movement therapies). Physical activity improves general health, disease risk, and progression of chronic illnesses such as cardiovascular disease, type 2 diabetes, and obesity. When applied to chronic pain conditions within appropriate parameters (frequency, duration, and intensity), physical activity significantly improves pain and related symptoms. For chronic pain, strict guidelines for physical activity are lacking, but frequent movement is preferable to sedentary behavior. This gives considerable freedom in prescribing physical activity treatments, which are most successful when tailored individually, progressed slowly, and account for physical limitations, psychosocial needs, and available resources.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ambrose</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kirsten R</ForeName>
            <Initials>KR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Thurston Arthritis Research Center, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA. Electronic address: kirsten_ambrose@med.unc.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Golightly</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yvonne M</ForeName>
            <Initials>YM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Thurston Arthritis Research Center, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA; Department of Epidemiology, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA; Injury Prevention Research Center, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>KL2 TR001109</GrantID>
            <Acronym>TR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>UL1 TR001111</GrantID>
            <Acronym>TR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>UL1 TR002489</GrantID>
            <Acronym>TR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>KL2TR001109/UL1TR001111</GrantID>
            <Acronym>TR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101121149</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1521-6942</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059350" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Pain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aerobic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arthritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic pain</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic widespread pain</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-pharmacological treatment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strength</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26267006</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS693834</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4534717</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2015.04.022</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1521-6942(15)00029-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe F, Clauw DJ, Fitzcharles MA, Goldenberg DL, Hauser W, Katz RS, et al.  Fibromyalgia criteria and severity scales for clinical and epidemiological studies: a modification of the ACR Preliminary Diagnostic Criteria for Fibromyalgia. J Rheumatol. 2011;38:1113–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson KO, Green CR, Payne R. Racial and ethnic disparities in pain: causes and consequences of unequal care. J Pain. 2009;10:1187–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19944378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pain Management: A Global Strategic Business Report. 2011 Jan 10; Report No.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute of Medicine (U.S.) Committee on Advancing Pain Research Care and Education. Relieving pain in America: a blueprint for transforming prevention, care, education, and research. xvii. Washington, D.C.: National Academies Press; 2011. p. 364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) National and state medical expenditures and lost earnings attributable to arthritis and other rheumatic conditions--United States, 2003. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2007;56:4–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17218935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Prevalence of doctor-diagnosed arthritis and arthritis-attributable activity limitation--United States, 2010-2012. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2013;62:869–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4585589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24196662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J, Dunlop D, Ehrlich-Jones L, Semanik P, Song J, Manheim L, et al.  Public health impact of risk factors for physical inactivity in adults with rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2012;64:488–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22278986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hootman JM, Macera CA, Ham SA, Helmick CG, Sniezek JE. Physical activity levels among the general US adult population and in adults with and without arthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2003;15:1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12579604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan MS, Huguet N, Newsom JT, McFarland BH. Characteristics of physically inactive older adults with arthritis: results of a population-based study. Prev Med. 2003;37:61–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12799130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehrotra C, Chudy N, Thomas V. Obesity and physical inactivity among Wisconsin adults with arthritis. WMJ. 2003;102:24–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14711020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fontaine KR, Heo M, Bathon J. Are US adults with arthritis meeting public health recommendations for physical activity? Arthritis Rheum. 2004;50:624–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14872507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shih M, Hootman JM, Kruger J, Helmick CG. Physical activity in men and women with arthritis National Health Interview Survey, 2002. Am J Prev Med. 2006;30:385–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16627126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badley EM, Ansari H. Arthritis and arthritis-attributable activity limitations in the United States and Canada: a cross-border comparison. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2010;62:308–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20391476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Chronic Diseases. Report of WHO expert consultation. 2015 Feb 19; Available from:  http://www.who.int/topics/noncommunicable_diseases/en/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Division of Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Obesity. 2015 Feb 19; Available from:  http://www.cdc.gov/nccdphp/dnpao/index.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durstine JL, Gordon B, Wang Z, Luo X. Chronic disease and the link to physical activity. Journal of Sport and Health Science. 2013;2(1):3–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flynn MA, McNeil DA, Maloff B, Mutasingwa D, Wu M, Ford C, et al.  Reducing obesity and related chronic disease risk in children and youth: a synthesis of evidence with ‘best practice’ recommendations. Obes Rev. 2006;7(Suppl 1):7–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16371076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunlop D, Song J, Arnston E, Semanik P, Lee J, Chang R, et al.  Sedentary Time in U.S Older Adults Associated With Disability in Activities of Daily Living Independent of Physical Activity. J Phys Act Health. 2014 Epub ahead of print.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4153790</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24510000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semanik PA, Lee J, Song J, Chang RW, Sohn MW, Ehrlich-Jones LS, et al.  Accelerometer-monitored sedentary behavior and observed physical function loss. Am J Public Health. 2015;105:560–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4330824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25602883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J, Chang RW, Ehrlich-Jones L, Kwoh CK, Nevitt M, Semanik PA, et al.  Sedentary behavior and physical function: Objective Evidence from the Osteoarthritis Initiative. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2014 Epub ahead of print.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4336845</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sohn MW, Manheim LM, Chang RW, Greenland P, Hochberg MC, Nevitt MC, et al.  Sedentary behavior and blood pressure control among osteoarthritis initiative participants. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2014;22:1234–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4159385</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25042550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American College of Rheumatology. Methotrexate (Rheumatrex, Trexall) 2015 Feb 25; Available from:  https://www.rheumatology.org/Practice/Clinical/Patients/Medications/Methotrexate_(Rheumatrex,_Trexall)/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroenke K, Krebs EE, Bair MJ. Pharmacotherapy of chronic pain: a synthesis of recommendations from systematic reviews. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2009;31:206–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19410099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauser W, Wolfe F, Tolle T, Uceyler N, Sommer C. The role of antidepressants in the management of fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. CNS drugs. 2012;26:297–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22452526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen L, Fredheim O. Opioids for chronic noncancer pain: still no evidence for superiority of sustained-release opioids. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2015;97:114–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25670511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nuesch E, Hauser W, Bernardy K, Barth J, Juni P. Comparative efficacy of pharmacological and non-pharmacological interventions in fibromyalgia syndrome: network meta-analysis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2013;72:955–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22739992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hassett AL, Williams DA. Non-pharmacological treatment of chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2011;25:299–309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22094203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busch AJ, Webber SC, Brachaniec M, Bidonde J, Bello-Haas VD, Danyliw AD, et al.  Exercise Therapy for Fibromyalgia. Current Pain and Headache Reports. 2011;15:358–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165132</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21725900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Koulil S, van Lankveld W, Kraaimaat FW, van Helmond T, Vedder A, van Hoorn H, et al.  Tailored cognitive-behavioral therapy and exercise training for high-risk patients with fibromyalgia. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2010;62:1377–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20521308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langhorst J, Klose P, Dobos GJ, Bernardy K, Hauser W. Efficacy and safety of meditative movement therapies in fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Rheumatol Int. 2013;33:193–207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22350253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltran-Carrillo VJ, Tortosa-Martinez J, Jennings G, Sanchez ES. Contributions of a group-based exercise program for coping with fibromyalgia: a qualitative study giving voice to female patients. Women Health. 2013;53:612–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23937732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang NK, Sanborn AN. Better quality sleep promotes daytime physical activity in patients with chronic pain? A multilevel analysis of the within-person relationship. PLoS One. 2014;9:e92158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3965418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24667276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobson JL, McMillan J, Li L. Benefits of exercise intervention in reducing neuropathic pain. Front Cell Neurosci. 2014;8:102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3983517</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24772065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Amelsvoort LG, Spigt MG, Swaen GM, Kant I. Leisure time physical activity and sickness absenteeism; a prospective study. Occup Med (Lond) 2006;56:210–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16641504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zavanela PM, Crewther BT, Lodo L, Florindo AA, Miyabara EH, Aoki MS. Health and fitness benefits of a resistance training intervention performed in the workplace. J Strength Cond Res. 2012;26:811–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambeek LC, Bosmans JE, Van Royen BJ, Van Tulder MW, Van Mechelen W, Anema JR. Effect of integrated care for sick listed patients with chronic low back pain: economic evaluation alongside a randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2010;341:c6414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2995018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21118874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busch AJ, Webber SC, Richards RS, Bidonde J, Schachter CL, Schafer LA, et al.  Resistance exercise training for fibromyalgia. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2013;12:Cd010884.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544808</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24362925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hagen KB, Dagfinrud H, Moe RH, Osteras N, Kjeken I, Grotle M, et al.  Exercise therapy for bone and muscle health: an overview of systematic reviews. BMC Med. 2012;10:167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568719</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23253613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones KD, Sherman CA, Mist SD, Carson JW, Bennett RM, Li F. A randomized controlled trial of 8-form Tai chi improves symptoms and functional mobility in fibromyalgia patients. Clin Rheumatol. 2012;31:1205–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5571653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22581278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS, Hootman JM, Jones DL. Effects of community-deliverable exercise on pain and physical function in adults with arthritis and other rheumatic diseases: a meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2011:6379–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20824798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaleth AS, Saha CK, Jensen MP, Slaven JE, Ang DC. Effect of moderate to vigorous physical activity on long-term clinical outcomes and pain severity in fibromyalgia. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2013;65:1211–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3672379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23401486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kayo AH, Peccin MS, Sanches CM, Trevisani VF. Effectiveness of physical activity in reducing pain in patients with fibromyalgia: a blinded randomized clinical trial. Rheumatol Int. 2012:322285–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21594719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanudo B, Carrasco L, de Hoyo M, McVeigh JG. Effects of exercise training and detraining in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome: a 3-yr longitudinal study. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2012;91:561–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22469880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C. Role of Tai Chi in the treatment of rheumatologic diseases. Current rheumatology reports. 2012;14:598–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23055009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westcott WL. Resistance training is medicine: effects of strength training on health. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2012;11:209–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS, Hootman JM, Jones DL. Exercise and global well-being in community-dwelling adults with fibromyalgia: a systematic review with meta-analysis. BMC Public Health. 2010;10:198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2874776</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20406476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Messier SP, Gutekunst DJ, Davis C, DeVita P. Weight loss reduces knee-joint loads in overweight and obese older adults with knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;52:2026–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15986358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patrick DL, Ramsey SD, Spencer AC, Kinne S, Belza B, Topolski TD. Economic evaluation of aquatic exercise for persons with osteoarthritis. Med Care. 2001;39:413–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11317090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van den Hout WB, de Jong Z, Munneke M, Hazes JM, Breedveld FC, Vliet Vlieland TP. Cost-utility and cost-effectiveness analyses of a long-term, high-intensity exercise program compared with conventional physical therapy in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;53:39–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15696568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juhakoski R, Tenhonen S, Malmivaara A, Kiviniemi V, Anttonen T, Arokoski JP. A pragmatic randomized controlled study of the effectiveness and cost consequences of exercise therapy in hip osteoarthritis. Clin Rehabil. 2011;25:370–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21078702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brady TJ, Jernick SL, Hootman JM, Sniezek JE. Public health interventions for arthritis: expanding the toolbox of evidence-based interventions. J Womens Health (Larchmt) 2009;18:1905–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20044851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Physical Activity Guidelines for Americans: Be Active, Healthy, and Happy! U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; 2008.   http://www.health.gov/paguidelines.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones KD, Adams D, Winters-Stone K, Burckhardt CS. A comprehensive review of 46 exercise treatment studies in fibromyalgia (1988-2005) Health and quality of life outcomes. 2006;4:67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1590013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16999856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staud R, Robinson ME, Price DD. Isometric exercise has opposite effects on central pain mechanisms in fibromyalgia patients compared to normal controls. Pain. 2005;118:176–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16154700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vierck CJ, Jr, Staud R, Price DD, Cannon RL, Mauderli AP, Martin AD. The effect of maximal exercise on temporal summation of second pain (windup) in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. J Pain. 2001;2:334–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14622813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bidonde J, Busch AJ, Webber SC, Schachter CL, Danyliw A, Overend TJ, et al.  Aquatic exercise training for fibromyalgia. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2014;10:Cd011336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25350761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauser W, Klose P, Langhorst J, Moradi B, Steinbach M, Schiltenwolf M, et al.  Efficacy of different types of aerobic exercise in fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Arthritis Res Ther. 2010;12:R79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2911859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20459730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mannerkorpi K, Henriksson C. Non-pharmacological treatment of chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2007;21:513–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17602997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson ME, Rejeski WJ, Blair SN, Duncan PW, Judge JO, King AC, et al.  Physical activity and public health in older adults: recommendation from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1435–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gavi MB, Vassalo DV, Amaral FT, Macedo DC, Gava PL, Dantas EM, et al.  Strengthening exercises improve symptoms and quality of life but do not change autonomic modulation in fibromyalgia: a randomized clinical trial. PLoS One. 2014;9:e90767.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3961245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24651512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baillet A, Vaillant M, Guinot M, Juvin R, Gaudin P. Efficacy of resistance exercises in rheumatoid arthritis: meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2012;51:519–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22120463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hooten WM, Qu W, Townsend CO, Judd JW. Effects of strength vs aerobic exercise on pain severity in adults with fibromyalgia: a randomized equivalence trial. Pain. 2012;153:915–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sener U, Ucok K, Ulasli AM, Genc A, Karabacak H, Coban NF, et al.  Evaluation of health-related physical fitness parameters and association analysis with depression, anxiety, and quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia. Int J Rheum Dis. 2013 Nov 30; doi: 10.1111/1756-185X.12237..</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.12237.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24289723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C, Schmid CH, Rones R, Kalish R, Yinh J, Goldenberg DL, et al.  A randomized trial of tai chi for fibromyalgia. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:743–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20818876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carson JW, Carson KM, Jones KD, Bennett RM, Wright CL, Mist SD. A pilot randomized controlled trial of the Yoga of Awareness program in the management of fibromyalgia. Pain. 2010;151:530–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568071</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20946990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stavropoulos-Kalinoglou A, Metsios GS, Veldhuijzen van Zanten JJ, Nightingale P, Kitas GD, Koutedakis Y. Individualised aerobic and resistance exercise training improves cardiorespiratory fitness and reduces cardiovascular risk in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2013;72:1819–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23155222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez Gonzalez J, Del Teso Rubio MD, Walino Paniagua CN, Criado-Alvarez JJ, Sanchez Holgado J. Symptomatic pain and fibromyalgia treatment through multidisciplinary approach for Primary Care. Reumatol Clin. 2015;11:22–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24837647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segura-Jimenez V, Carbonell-Baeza A, Aparicio VA, Samos B, Femia P, Ruiz JR, et al.  A warm water pool-based exercise program decreases immediate pain in female fibromyalgia patients: uncontrolled clinical trial. Int J Sports Med. 2013;34:600–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23258608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giannotti E, Koutsikos K, Pigatto M, Rampudda ME, Doria A, Masiero S. Medium-/long-term effects of a specific exercise protocol combined with patient education on spine mobility, chronic fatigue, pain, aerobic fitness and level of disability in fibromyalgia. BioMed research international. 2014;2014:474029.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3925511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24616894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koele R, Volker G, van Vree F, van Gestel M, Koke A, Vliet Vlieland T. Multidisciplinary rehabilitation for chronic widespread musculoskeletal pain: results from daily practice. Musculoskeletal care. 2014;12:210–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24916665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett RM, Schein J, Kosinski MR, Hewitt DJ, Jordan DM, Rosenthal NR. Impact of fibromyalgia pain on health-related quality of life before and after treatment with tramadol/acetaminophen. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;53:519–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16082646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latorre PA, Santos MA, Heredia-Jimenez JM, Delgado-Fernandez M, Soto VM, Manas A, et al.  Effect of a 24-week physical training programme (in water and on land) on pain, functional capacity, body composition and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2013;31(6 Suppl 79):S72–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mutlu B, Paker N, Bugdayci D, Tekdos D, Kesiktas N. Efficacy of supervised exercise combined with transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation in women with fibromyalgia: a prospective controlled study. Rheumatol Int. 2013;33:649–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22527135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortega E, Bote ME, Giraldo E, Garcia JJ. Aquatic exercise improves the monocyte pro-and anti-inflammatory cytokine production balance in fibromyalgia patients. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2012;22:104–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20536907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mease P, Arnold LM, Choy EH, Clauw DJ, Crofford LJ, Glass JM, et al.  Fibromyalgia syndrome module at OMERACT 9: domain construct. J Rheumatol. 2009;36:2318–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3419373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19820221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleinman L, Mannix S, Arnold LM, Burbridge C, Howard K, McQuarrie K, et al.  Assessment of sleep in patients with fibromyalgia: qualitative development of the fibromyalgia sleep diary. Health and quality of life outcomes. 2014;12:111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4110695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25017455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ablin JN, Clauw DJ, Lyden AK, Ambrose K, Williams DA, Gracely RH, et al.  Effects of sleep restriction and exercise deprivation on somatic symptoms and mood in healthy adults. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2013;31(6 Suppl 79):S53–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giesecke T, Gracely RH, Williams DA, Geisser ME, Petzke FW, Clauw DJ. The relationship between depression, clinical pain, and experimental pain in a chronic pain cohort. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;52:1577–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15880832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gracely RH, Ceko M, Bushnell MC. Fibromyalgia and depression. Pain research and treatment. 2012;2012:486590.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3236322</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22191023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguglia A, Salvi V, Maina G, Rossetto I, Aguglia E. Fibromyalgia syndrome and depressive symptoms: comorbidity and clinical correlates. J Affect Disord. 2011;128:262–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20674985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harden RN, Song S, Fasen J, Saltz SL, Nampiaparampil D, Vo A, et al.  Home-based aerobic conditioning for management of symptoms of fibromyalgia: a pilot study. Pain Med. 2012;13:835–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22568761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gauffin J, Hankama T, Hannonen P, Kautiainen H, Pohjolainen T, Haanpaa M. Do fibromyalgia patients use active pain management strategies? A cohort study. J Rehabil Med. 2013;45:477–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23532255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irwin MR, Olmstead R. Mitigating cellular inflammation in older adults: a randomized controlled trial of Tai Chi Chih. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2012;20(9):764–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3247625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21934474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart LK, Flynn MG, Campbell WW, Craig BA, Robinson JP, Timmerman KL, et al.  The influence of exercise training on inflammatory cytokines and C-reactive protein. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39:1714–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loprinzi PD. Frequency of moderate-to-vigorous physical activity (MVPA) is a greater predictor of systemic inflammation than total weekly volume of MVPA: Implications for physical activity promotion. Physiol Behav. 2015;141:46–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25575691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Hondzinski JM. Select exercise modalities may reverse movement dysfunction because of peripheral neuropathy. Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2012;40:133–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22653276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metsios GS, Stavropoulos-Kalinoglou A, Veldhuijzen van Zanten JJ, Nightingale P, Sandoo A, Dimitroulas T, et al.  Individualised exercise improves endothelial function in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73:748–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23904472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Effects of exercise on depressive symptoms in adults with arthritis and other rheumatic disease: a systematic review of meta-analyses. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2014;15:121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24708605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fransen M, McConnell S. Exercise for osteoarthritis of the knee. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2008;4 Internet. Available from:  http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD004376.pub2/abstract.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004376.pub2/abstract</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18843657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fransen M, McConnell S. Land-based exercise for osteoarthritis of the knee: a metaanalysis of randomized controlled trials (Structured abstract) J Rheumatol. 2009;36(6):1109–17. Internet. Available from:  http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/o/cochrane/cldare/articles/DARE-12009106741/frame.html.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19447940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallis JA, Taylor NF. Pre-operative interventions (non-surgical and non-pharmacological) for patients with hip or knee osteoarthritis awaiting joint replacement surgery--a systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2011;19:1381–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21959097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basler HD, Luckmann J, Wolf U, Quint S. Fear-avoidance beliefs, physical activity, and disability in elderly individuals with chronic low back pain and healthy controls. Clin J Pain. 2008;24:604–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18716499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scopaz KA, Piva SR, Wisniewski S, Fitzgerald GK. Relationships of fear, anxiety, and depression with physical function in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2009;90:1866–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4878692</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19887210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stubbs B, Patchay S, Soundy A, Schofield P. The avoidance of activities due to fear of falling contributes to sedentary behavior among community-dwelling older adults with chronic musculoskeletal pain: a multisite observational study. Pain Med. 2014;15:1861–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25224385</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nijs J, Kosek E, Van Oosterwijck J, Meeus M. Dysfunctional endogenous analgesia during exercise in patients with chronic pain: to exercise or not to exercise? Pain physician. 2012;15(3 Suppl):Es205–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22786458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nijs J, Roussel N, Van Oosterwijck J, De Kooning M, Ickmans K, Struyf F, et al.  Fear of movement and avoidance behaviour toward physical activity in chronic-fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia: state of the art and implications for clinical practice. Clin Rheumatol. 2013;32:1121–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23639990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Washington, DC: IOM (Institute of Medicine), The National Academies Press; 2015. Beyond Myalgic Encephalomyelitis/Chronic Fatigue Syndrome: Redefining an Illness. Available from:  http://www.iom.edu/mecfs.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huffman K, Pieper C, Hall K, St Clair E, Kraus W. Self-efficacy for exercise, more than disease-related factors, is associated with objectively assessed exercise time and sedentary behaviour in rheumatoid arthritis. Scand J Rheumatol. 2014 Epub ahead of print.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4356639</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25222824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imayama I, Alfano CM, Mason CE, Wang C, Xiao L, Duggan C, et al.  Exercise adherence, cardiopulmonary fitness and anthropometric changes improve exercise self-efficacy and health-related quality of life. J Phys Act Health. 2013;10:676–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3923574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23036856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
