<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">26545070</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1752-8526</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2015</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
              <Day>05</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMJ clinical evidence</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMJ Clin Evid</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Menière's disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">0505</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Menière's disease causes feelings of fullness or pressure in the ear, hearing loss, tinnitus, and recurrent bouts of vertigo, and mainly affects people aged 30-60 years. Menière's disease is at first progressive but fluctuating, and episodes can occur in clusters. Vertigo usually resolves eventually, but the hearing deteriorates and the tinnitus and pressure may persist regardless of treatment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS AND OUTCOMES" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a systematic overview, aiming to answer the following clinical questions: What are the effects of combination treatment (betahistine plus thiazide diuretic) to prevent attacks and delay disease progression of Menière's disease? What are the effects of intratympanic interventions to prevent attacks and delay disease progression of Menière's disease? What are the effects of non-drug interventions to prevent attacks and delay disease progression of Menière's disease? What are the effects of dietary interventions to prevent attacks and delay disease progression of Menière's disease? We searched: Medline, Embase, The Cochrane Library, and other important databases up to July 2014 (Clinical Evidence overviews are updated periodically; please check our website for the most up-to-date version of this overview).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At this update, searching of electronic databases retrieved 200 studies. After deduplication and removal of conference abstracts, 151 records were screened for inclusion in the overview. Appraisal of titles and abstracts led to the exclusion of 100 studies and the further review of 51 full publications. Of the 51 full articles evaluated, five systematic reviews and four RCTs were added at this update. We performed a GRADE evaluation for eight PICO combinations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this systematic overview, we categorised the efficacy for seven interventions based on information about the effectiveness and safety of betahistine plus thiazide diuretic, caffeine restriction, intratympanic corticosteroids, intratympanic gentamicin, psychological support, salt restriction, and vestibular rehabilitation.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wright</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tony</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>UCL Ear Institute, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMJ Clin Evid</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101294314</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1462-3846</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008575" MajorTopicYN="N">Meniere Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26545070</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4636025</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">0505</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friberg U, Stahle J, Svedberg A. The natural course of Menière's disease. Acta Otolaryngol Suppl 1984;406:72–77.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6591717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitahara M. Concepts and diagnostic criteria of Menière's disease. In: Kitahara M, ed. Menière's disease. Tokyo: Springer-Verlag, 1990:3–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alford BR. Menière's disease: criteria for diagnosis and evaluation of therapy for reporting. Report of subcommittee on equilibrium and its measurement. Trans Am Acad Ophthalmol Otolaryngol 1972;76:1462–1464.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4666434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearson BW, Brackmann DE. Committee on Hearing and Equilibrium guidelines for reporting treatment results in Menière's disease. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 1985;93:578–581.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2932668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Committee on Hearing and Equilibrium. Guidelines for the diagnosis and evaluation of therapy in Menière's disease. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 1995;113:181–185.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7675476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moffat DA, Ballagh RH. Menière's disease. In: Kerr AG, Booth JB, eds. Scott-Brown's otolaryngology. 6th ed. Oxford: Butterworth-Heinemann, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe Y, Mizukoshi K, Shojaku H, et al. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of Menière's disease in Japan. Acta Otolaryngol Suppl 1995;519:206–210.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7610869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cawthorne T, Hewlett AB. Menière's disease. Proc Royal Soc Med 1954;47:663–670.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1918735</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13194658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stahle J, Stahle C, Arenberg IK. Incidence of Menière's disease. Arch Otolaryngol 1978;104:99–102.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">629706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nsamba C. A comparative study of the aetiology of vertigo in the African. J Laryngol Otol 1972;86:917–925.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5070302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruckenstein MJ, Harrison RV. Cochlear pathology in Menière's disease. In: Harris JP, ed. Menière's disease. The Hague: Kugler Publications, 1999:195–202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt JT, Huizing EH. The clinical drug trial in Menière's disease with emphasis on the effect of betahistine SR. Acta Otolaryngol Suppl 1992;497:1–189.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1496890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moser M, Ranacher G, Wilmot TJ, et al. A double-blind clinical trial of hydroxyethylrutosides in Menière's disease. J Laryngol Otol 1984;98:265–272.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6366100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stokroos R, Kingma H. Selective vestibular ablation by intratympanic gentamicin in patients with unilateral active Ménière's disease: a prospective, double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized clinical trial. Acta Otolaryngol 2004;124:172–175.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15072419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Postema RJ, Kingma CM, Wit HP, et al. Intratympanic gentamicin therapy for control of vertigo in unilateral Meniere's disease: a prospective, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Acta Otolaryngol 2008;128:876–880.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18607963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein H, Smouha E, Jones R. Natural history versus surgery for Menière's disease. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 1989;100:6–16.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2493618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torok N. Old and new in Menière's disease. Laryngoscope 1977;87:1870–1877.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">916781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pullens B, Bentham PP. Intratympanic gentamicin for Ménière's disease or syndrome. In: The Cochrane Library, Issue 7, 2014. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Search date 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huon LK, Fang TY, Wang PC. Outcomes of intratympanic gentamicin injection to treat Ménière's disease. Otol Neurotol 2012;33:706–714.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22699980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips JS, Westerberg B. Intratympanic steroids for Ménière's disease or syndrome. In: The Cochrane Library, Issue 7, 2014. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Search date 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu A, Parnes LS. Intratympanic steroids for inner ear disorders: a review. Audiol Neurootol 2009;14:373–382.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19923807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garduño-Anaya MA, Couthino De Toledo H, Hinojosa-González R, et al. Dexamethasone inner ear perfusion by intratympanic injection in unilateral Ménière's disease: a two-year prospective, placebo-controlled, double-blind, randomized trial. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg 2005;133:285–294.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16087029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein H, Isaacson JE, Olds MJ, et al. Dexamethasone inner ear perfusion for the treatment of Meniere's disease: a prospective, randomized, double-blind, crossover trial. Am J Otol 1998;19:196–201.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9520056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert PR, Nguyen S, Maxwell KS, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical study to assess safety and clinical activity of OTO-104 given as a single intratympanic injection in patients with unilateral Ménière's disease. Otol Neurotol 2012;33:1257–1265.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22858715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomsen J, Bech P, Prytz S, et al. Menière's disease: lithium treatment (demonstration of placebo effect in a double blind cross-over trial). Clin Otolaryngol 1979;4:119–123.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">378474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerr AG, Toner JG. A new approach to surgery for Menière's disease: talking about surgery. Clin Otolaryngol Allie Sci 1998;23:263–264.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9669078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillier SL, McDonnell M. Vestibular rehabilitation for unilateral peripheral vestibular dysfunction. In: The Cochrane Library, Issue 7, 2014. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd. Search date 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yardley L, Kirby S. Evaluation of booklet-based self-management of symptoms in Ménière disease: a randomized controlled trial. Psychosom Med 2006;68:762–769.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17012531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia AP, Ganança MM, Cusin FS, et al. Vestibular rehabilitation with virtual reality in Ménière's disease. Braz J Otorhinolaryngol 2013;79:366–374.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23743754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furstenburg AC, Richardson G, Lathrop FD. Menière's disease. Addenda to medical therapy. Arch Otolaryngol 1941;34:1083–1092.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dix MR. The rationale and technique of head exercises in the treatment of vertigo. Acta Otorhinolaryngol Belg 1979;33:370–384.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">314722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clendaniel RA, Tucci DL. Vestibular rehabilitation strategies in Menière's disease. Otolaryngol Clin North Am 1997;30:1145–1158.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9386249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
