<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">26583190</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK327153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter">Baraitser-Winter Cerebrofrontofacial Syndrome</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verloes</LastName><ForeName>Alain</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Université Paris Cité; Department of Genetics APHP-Hôpital Robert Debré Paris, France</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drunat</LastName><ForeName>Séverine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genetics APHP-Hôpital Robert Debré Paris, France</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pilz</LastName><ForeName>Daniela</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Genetics University Hospital of Wales Cardiff, United Kingdom</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Di Donato</LastName><ForeName>Nataliya</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut für Klinische Genetik Universitätsklinikum Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, Germany</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS">Baraitser-Winter cerebrofrontofacial (BWCFF) syndrome is a multiple congenital anomaly syndrome characterized by typical craniofacial features and intellectual disability. Many (but not all) affected individuals have pachygyria that is predominantly frontal, wasting of the shoulder girdle muscles, and sensory impairment due to iris or retinal coloboma and/or sensorineural deafness. Intellectual disability, which is common but variable, is related to the severity of the brain malformations. Seizures, congenital heart defects, renal malformations, and gastrointestinal dysfunction are also common.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of BWCFF syndrome is established in a proband with suggestive findings and a heterozygous missense pathogenic variant in either <i>ACTB</i> or <i>ACTG1</i> identified by molecular genetic testing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Standard treatment for medical concerns in conjunction with the associated specialist; management of developmental delay and intellectual disability is tailored to the individual. <i>Surveillance:</i> Routine follow up recommended for neurodevelopmental assessment in all; follow up as needed for those with seizures (neurologic evaluation), coloboma or microphthalmia (ophthalmologic evaluation), hearing loss (audiologic evaluation), cardiac defects, renal tract anomalies, and gastrointestinal dysfunction.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">BWCFF syndrome is an autosomal dominant disorder. Most individuals with BWCFF syndrome reported to date have the disorder as the result of a <i>de novo</i> <i>ACTB</i> or <i>ACTG1</i> pathogenic variant. If a parent of the proband has the pathogenic variant identified in the proband, the risk to the sibs of inheriting the pathogenic variant is 50%. Once the <i>ACTB</i> or <i>ACTG1</i> pathogenic variant has been identified in an affected family member, prenatal and preimplantation genetic testing for BWCFF syndrome are possible.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Clinical_Characteristic">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Genetically_Related_All">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="baraitser-winter" sec="baraitser-winter.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Actin, cytoplasmic 1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Actin, cytoplasmic 2</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACTB</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACTG1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Baraitser-Winter Cerebrofrontofacial Syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Baumann M, Beaver EM, Palomares-Bralo M, Santos-Simarro F, Holzer P, Povysil G, Müller T, Valovka T, Janecke AR. Further delineation of putative ACTB loss-of-function variants: a 4-patient series. Hum Mutat. 2020;41:753–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7155001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31898838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chacon-Camacho OF, Barragán-Arévalo T, Villarroel CE, Almanza-Monterrubio M, Zenteno JC. Previously undescribed phenotypic findings and novel ACTG1 gene pathogenic variants in Baraitser-Winter cerebrofrontofacial syndrome. Eur J Med Genet. 2020;63:103877. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32028042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cianci P, Fazio G, Casagranda S, Spinelli M, Rizzari C, Cazzaniga G, Selicorni A. Acute myeloid leukemia in Baraitser-Winter cerebrofrontofacial syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2017;2017;173:546–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27868373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuvertino S, Stuart HM, Chandler KE, Roberts NA, Armstrong R, Bernardini L, Bhaskar S, Callewaert B, Clayton-Smith J, Davalillo CH, Deshpande C, Devriendt K, Digilio MC, Dixit A, Edwards M, Friedman JM, Gonzalez-Meneses A, Joss S, Kerr B, Lampe AK, Langlois S, Lennon R, Loget P, Ma DYT, McGowan R, Des Medt M, O'Sullivan J, Odent S, Parker MJ, Pebrel-Richard C, Petit F, Stark Z, Stockler-Ipsiroglu S, Tinschert S, Vasudevan P, Villa O, White SM, Zahir FR, Study DDD, Woolf AS, Banka S. ACTB loss-of-function mutations result in a pleiotropic developmental disorder. Am J Hum Genet. 2017;101:1021–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29220674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Donato N, Rump A, Koenig R, Der Kaloustian VM, Halal F, Sonntag K, Krause C, Hackmann K, Hahn G, Schrock E, Verloes A. Severe forms of Baraitser-Winter syndrome are caused by ACTB mutations rather than ACTG1 mutations. Eur J Hum Genet. 2014;22:179–83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3895648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23756437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diets IJ, Waanders E, Ligtenberg MJ, van Bladel DAG, Kamping EJ, Hoogerbrugge PM, Hopman S, Olderode-Berends MJ, Gerkes EH, Koolen DA, Marcelis C, Santen GW, van Belzen MJ, Mordaunt D, McGregor L, Thompson E, Kattamis A, Pastorczak A, Mlynarski W, Ilencikova D, van Silfhout AV, Gardeitchik T, de Bont ES, Loeffen J, Wagner A, Mensenkamp AR, Kuiper RP, Hoogerbrugge N, Jongmans MC. High yield of pathogenic germline mutations causative or likely causative of the cancer phenotype in selected children with cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2018;24:1594–603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugina VB, Shagieva GS, Kopnin PB. Biological role of actin isoforms in mammalian cells. Biochemistry (Mosc) 2019;84:583–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31238858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugina VB, Shagieva GS, Shakhov AS, Alieva IB. The cytoplasmic actins in the regulation of endothelial cell function. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:7836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8345992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34360602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitas JL, Vale TC, Barsottini OGP, Pedroso JL. Expanding the phenotype of dystonia-deafness syndrome caused by ACTB gene mutation. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2019;7:86–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6962673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31970217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampshire K, Martin PM, Carlston C, Slavotinek A. Baraitser-Winter cerebrofrontofacial syndrome: Report of two adult siblings. Am J Med Genet A. 2020;182:1923–32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32506774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latham SL, Ehmke N, Reinke PYA, Taft MH, Eicke D, Reindl T, Stenzel W, Lyons MJ, Friez MJ, Lee JA, Hecker R, Frühwald MC, Becker K, Neuhann TM, Horn D, Schrock E, Niehaus I, Sarnow K, Grützmann K, Gawehn L, Klink B, Rump A, Chaponnier C, Figueiredo C, Knöfler R, Manstein DJ, Di Donato N. Variants in exons 5 and 6 of ACTB cause syndromic thrombocytopenia. Nat Commun. 2018;9:4250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6185941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30315159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunoi H, Yamazaki T, Tsuchiya H, Kato S, Malech HL, Matsuda I, Kanegasaki S. A heterozygous mutation of beta-actin associated with neutrophil dysfunction and recurrent infection. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1999;96:8693–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC17578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10411937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poirier K, Martinovic J, Laquerrière A, Cavallin M, Fallet-Bianco C, Desguerre I, Valence S, Grande-Goburghun J, Francannet C, Deleuze JF, Boland A, Chelly J, Bahi-Buisson N. Rare ACTG1 variants in fetal microlissencephaly. Eur J Med Genet. 2015;58:416–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26188271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rainger J, Williamson KA, Soares DC, Truch J, Kurian D, Gillessen-Kaesbach G, Seawright A, Prendergast J, Halachev M, Wheeler A, McTeir L, Gill AC, van Heyningen V, Davey MG, FitzPatrick DR, et al.  A recurrent de novo mutation in ACTG1 causes isolated ocular coloboma. Hum Mutat. 2017;38:942–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5518294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28493397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rossi M, Guerrini R, Dobyns WB, Andria G, Winter RM. Characterization of brain malformations in the Baraitser-Winter syndrome and review of the literature. Neuropediatrics. 2003;34:287–92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14681753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandestig A, Green A, Jonasson J, Vogt H, Wahlström J, Pepler A, Ellnebo K, Biskup S, Stefanova M. Could dissimilar phenotypic effects of ACTB missense mutations reflect the actin conformational change? Two novel mutations and literature review. Mol Syndromol. 2019;9:259–65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6362929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30733661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimojima K, Narai S, Togawa M, Doumoto T, Sangu N, Vanakker OM, de Paepe A, Edwards M, Whitehall J, Brescianini S, Petit F, Andrieux J, Yamamoto T. 7p22.1 microdeletions involving ACTB associated with developmental delay, short stature, and microcephaly. Eur J Med Genet. 2016;59:502–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skogseid IM, Røsby O, Konglund A, Connelly JP, Nedregaard B, Jablonski GE, Kvernmo N, Stray-Pedersen A, Glover JC. Dystonia-deafness syndrome caused by ACTB p.Arg183Trp heterozygosity shows striatal dopaminergic dysfunction and response to pallidal stimulation. J Neurodev Disord. 2018;10:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29788902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenson PD, Mort M, Ball EV, Chapman M, Evans K, Azevedo L, Hayden M, Heywood S, Millar DS, Phillips AD, Cooper DN. The Human Gene Mutation Database (HGMD®): optimizing its use in a clinical diagnostic or research setting. Hum Genet. 2020;139:1197–207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32596782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verloes A, Di Donato N, Masliah-Planchon J, Jongmans M, Abdul-Raman OA, Albrecht B, Allanson J, Brunner H, Bertola D, Chassaing N, David A, Devriendt K, Eftekhari P, Drouin-Garraud V, Faravelli F, Faivre L, Giuliano F, Guion Almeida L, Juncos J, Kempers M, Eker HK, Lacombe D, Lin A, Mancini G, Melis D, Lourenço CM, Siu VM, Morin G, Nezarati M, Nowaczyk MJ, Ramer JC, Osimani S, Philip N, Pierpont ME, Procaccio V, Roseli ZS, Rossi M, Rusu C, Sznajer Y, Templin L, Uliana V, Klaus M, Van Bon B, Van Ravenswaaij C, Wainer B, Fry AE, Rump A, Hoischen A, Drunat S, Rivière JB, Dobyns WB, Pilz DT. Baraitser-Winter cerebrofrontofacial syndrome: delineation of the spectrum in 42 cases. Eur J Hum Genet. 2015;23:292–301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4326722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25052316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vontell R, Supramaniam VG, Davidson A, Thornton C, Marnerides A, Holder-Espinasse M, Lillis S, Yau S, Jansson M, Hagberg HE, Rutherford MA. Post-mortem characterisation of a case with an ACTG1 variant, agenesis of the corpus callosum and neuronal heterotopia. Front Physiol. 2019;10:623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31231230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witjes L, Van Troys M, Verhasselt B, Ampe C. Prevalence of cytoplasmic actin mutations in diffuse large B-cell lymphoma and multiple myeloma: a functional assessment based on actin three-dimensional structures. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:3093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32349449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates TM, Turner CL, Firth HV, Berg J, Pilz DT. Baraitser-Winter cerebrofrontofacial syndrome. Clin Genet. 2017;92:3–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27625340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang K, Cox E, Strom S, Xu ZL, Disilvestro A, Usrey K. Prenatal presentation and diagnosis of Baraitser-Winter syndrome using exome sequencing. Am J Med Genet A. 2020;182:2124–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32588558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26583190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
