<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">26680560</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1753-9455</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>11</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Therapeutic advances in cardiovascular disease</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Cardiovasc Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Edoxaban in patients with atrial fibrillation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>81</StartPage>
          <EndPage>90</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>81-90</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/1753944715622130</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Edoxaban, a direct factor Xa inhibitor, was extensively studied in the prevention and treatment of venous thromboembolism and in patients with nonvalvular atrial fibrillation (AF). The aim of this review is to focus specifically on the efficacy and safety profile of edoxaban in patients with AF from preclinical development through the phase III trial that led to regulatory approval.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eisen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alon</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ruff</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christian T</ForeName>
            <Initials>CT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital and Harvard Medical School Boston, TIMI Study Group, 350 Longwood Avenue, 1st Floor Offices, Boston, MA 02115, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ther Adv Cardiovasc Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316343</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1753-9447</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D065427">Factor Xa Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011725">Pyridines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013844">Thiazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>NDU3J18APO</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C552171">edoxaban</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001281" MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial Fibrillation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D065427" MajorTopicYN="N">Factor Xa Inhibitors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011725" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyridines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013844" MajorTopicYN="N">Thiazoles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Novel oral anticoagulants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">edoxaban</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">factor xa inhibitor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-vitamin K oral anticoagulants</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of interest statement:</b> Dr Eisen reports no disclosures. Dr Ruff reports grant support through his institution (Brigham and Women’s Hospital) from Daiichi Sankyo and has served as a consultant and received honoraria from Daiichi Sankyo, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bayer, and Portola; and grant support through his institution outside the submitted work from AstraZeneca, Eisai, Intarcia, and Glaxo Smith Kline.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26680560</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5942795</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1753944715622130</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">1753944715622130</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ansell J., Bakhru S., Laulicht B., Steiner S., Grosso M., Brown K., et al.  (2014) Use of PER977 to reverse the anticoagulant effect of edoxaban. N Engl J Med
371: 2141–2142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25371966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Camm A., Bounameaux H. (2011) Edoxaban: a new oral direct factor Xa inhibitor. Drugs
71: 1503–1526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Crowther M., Crowther M. (2015) Antidotes for novel oral anticoagulants: current status and future potential. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol
35(8): 1736–1745.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26088576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Giugliano R., Ruff C., Braunwald E., Murphy S., Wiviott S., Halperin J., et al.  (2013) Edoxaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med
369: 2093–2104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24251359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Giugliano R., Ruff C., Rost N., Silverman S., Wiviott S., Lowe C., et al.  (2014) Cerebrovascular events in 21 105 patients with atrial fibrillation randomized to edoxaban versus warfarin: Effective Anticoagulation with Factor Xa Next Generation in Atrial Fibrillation-Thrombolysis in Myocardial Infarction 48. Stroke
45: 2372–2378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24947287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Granger C., Alexander J., McMurray J., Lopes R., Hylek E., Hanna M., et al.  (2011) Apixaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med
365: 981–992.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21870978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Granger C., Lopes R., Hanna M., Ansell J., Hylek E., Alexander J., et al.  (2015) Clinical events after transitioning from apixaban versus warfarin to warfarin at the end of the Apixaban for Reduction in Stroke and Other Thromboembolic Events in Atrial Fibrillation (ARISTOTLE) trial. Am Heart J
169: 25–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25497244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Halim A., Samama M., Mendell J. (2014) Ex vivo reversal of the anticoagulant effect of edoxaban. Thromb Res
134: 909–913.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25179520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Heidbuchel H., Verhamme P., Alings M., Antz M., Diener H., Hacke W., et al.  (2015) Updated European Heart Rhythm Association Practical Guide on the use of non-vitamin K antagonist anticoagulants in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation. Europace
17(10): 1467–1507.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26324838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Holbrook A., Pereira J., Labiris R., McDonald H., Douketis J., Crowther M., et al.  (2005) Systematic overview of warfarin and its drug and food interactions. Arch Intern Med
165: 1095–1106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15911722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
January C., Wann L., Alpert J., Calkins H., Cigarroa J., Clevland J., et al.  (2014) 2014 AHA/ACC/HRS guideline for the management of patients with atrial fibrillation: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on practice guidelines and the Heart Rhythm Society. J Am Coll Cardiol
130: 2071–2104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24682348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kato E., Giugliano R., Ruff C., Murphy S., Nordio F., Kimura T., et al.  (2014) Efficacy and safety of edoxaban for the management of elderly patients with atrial fibrillation: ENGAGE AF- TIMI 48. Circulation
130: A16612 (abstract).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kovacs R., Flaker G., Saxonhouse S., Doherty J., Birtcher K., Cuker A., et al.  (2015) Practical management of anticoagulation in patients with atrial fibrillation. J Am Coll Cardiol
65: 1340–1360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25835447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Krejczy M., Harenberg J., Wehling M., Obermann K., Lip G. (2015) Cost-effectiveness of anticoagulation in patients with nonvalvular atrial fibrillation with edoxaban compared to warfarin in Germany. Biomed Res Int
17
March [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4380099</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25853142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lip G., Agnelli G. (2014) Edoxaban: a focused review of its clinical pharmacology. Eur Heart J
35: 1844–1855.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24810388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lip G., Merino J., Ezekowitz M., Ellenbogen K., Zamoryakhin D., Lanz H., et al.  (2015) A prospective evaluation of edoxaban compared to warfarin in subjects undergoing cardioversion of atrial fibrillation: The Edoxaban vs. Warfarin in Subjects Undergoing Cardioversion of Atrial Fibrillation (ENSURE-AF) study. Am Heart J
169: 597–604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25965706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Magnani G., Giugliano R., Ruff C., Murphy S., Nordio F., Metra M., et al.  (2014) Efficacy and safety of edoxaban compared with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation and heart failure: insights from ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48. Circulation
130: A12680 (abstract).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27349698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Magnuson E., Vilain K., Wang K., Li H., Kwong W., Antman E., et al.  (2015) Cost-effectiveness of edoxaban vs. warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: results from the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 economic study. Am Heart J
170(6): 1140–1150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26678636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mahaffey K., Hellkamp A., Patel M., Hannan K., Schwabe K., Nessel C., et al.  (2013) End of study transition from study drug to open-label vitamin K antagonist therapy: the ROCKET AF experience. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes
6: 470–478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23759472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mega J., Walker J., Ruff C., Vandell A., Nordio F., Deenadayalu N., et al.  (2015) Genetics and the clinical response to warfarin and edoxaban: findings from the randomised, double-blind ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Lancet
385: 2280–2287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25769357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
O’Donoghue M., Ruff C., Giugliano R., Murphy S., Grip L., Mercuri M., et al.  (2015) Edoxaban vs. warfarin in vitamin K antagonist experienced and naive patients with atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J
36: 1470–1477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ogata K., Mendell-Harary J., Tachibana M., Masumoto H., Oguma T., Kojima M., et al.  (2010) Clinical safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics of the novel factor Xa inhibitor edoxaban in healthy volunteers. J Clin Pharmacol
50: 743–753.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20081065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rognoni C., Marchetti M., Quaglini S., Liberato N. (2015) Edoxaban versus warfarin for stroke prevention in non-valvular atrial fibrillation: a cost-effectiveness analysis. J Thromb Thrombolysis
39: 149–154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24973057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ruff C., Giugliano R., Antman E., Crugnale S., Bocanegra T., Mercuri M., et al.  (2010) Evaluation of the novel factor Xa inhibitor edoxaban compared with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: design and rationale for the Effective Anticoagulation with Factor Xa Next Generation in Atrial Fibrillation-Thrombolysis in Myocardial Infarction study 48 (ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48). Am Heart J
160: 635-641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20934556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ruff C., Giugliano R., Braunwald E., Mercuri M., Curt V., Betcher J., et al.  (2014a) Transition of patients from blinded study drug to open-label anticoagulation: the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial.J Am Coll Cardiol
64: 576–584.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ruff C., Giugliano R., Braunwald E., Hoffman E., Deenadayalu N., Ezekowitz M., et al.  (2014b) Comparison of the efficacy and safety of new oral anticoagulants with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: a meta-analysis of randomised trials. Lancet
383: 955–962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24315724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ruff C., Giugliano R., Braunwald E., Morrow D., Murphy S., Kuder J., et al.  (2015) Association between edoxaban dose, concentration, anti-Factor Xa activity, and outcomes: an analysis of data from the randomised, double-blind ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Lancet
385: 2288–2295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25769361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Salazar D., Mendell J., Kastrissios H., Green M., Carrothers T., Song S., et al.  (2012) Modelling and simulation of edoxaban exposure and response relationships in patients with atrial fibrillation. Thromb Haemost
107: 925–936.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22398655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schulman S., Kearon C. (2005) Definition of major bleeding in clinical investigations of antihemostatic medicinal products in non-surgical patients. J Thromb Haemost
3: 692–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15842354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Steffel J., Giugliano R., Braunwald E., Murphy S., Atar D., Heidbuchel H., et al.  (2015) Edoxaban vs. warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation on amiodarone: a subgroup analysis of the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Eur Heart J
13
May [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25971288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Weitz J., Connolly S., Patel I., Salazar D., Rohatagi S., Mendell J., et al.  (2010) Randomised, parallel group, multicentre, multinational phase 2 study comparing edoxaban, an oral factor Xa inhibitor, with warfarin for stroke prevention in patients with atrial fibrillation. Thromb Haemost
104: 633–641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20694273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yamashita T., Koretsune Y., Yasaka M., Inoue H., Kawai Y., Yamaguchi T., et al.  (2012) Randomized, multicenter, warfarin controlled phase II study of edoxaban in Japanese patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation. Circ J
76: 1840–1847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22664798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zahir H., Brown K., Vandell A., Desai M., Maa J., Dishy V., et al.  (2015) Edoxaban effects on bleeding following punch biopsy and reversal by a 4-factor prothrombin complex concentrate. Circulation
131: 82–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25403645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
