<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">26719778</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1915-7398</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>20</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2015</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ontario health technology assessment series</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ont Health Technol Assess Ser</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Paclitaxel Drug-Eluting Stents in Peripheral Arterial Disease: A Health Technology Assessment.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1</StartPage>
          <EndPage>62</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1-62</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Peripheral arterial disease is a condition in which atherosclerotic plaques partially or completely block blood flow to the legs. Although percutaneous transluminal angioplasty and metallic stenting have high immediate success rates in treating peripheral arterial disease, long-term patency and restenosis rates in long and complex lesions remain unsatisfactory.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this analysis was to evaluate the clinical effectiveness, safety, cost-effectiveness and budget impact of Zilver paclitaxel self-expanding drug-eluting stents for the treatment of de novo or restenotic lesions in above-the-knee peripheral arterial disease.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Literature searches were performed using Ovid MEDLINE, Ovid MEDLINE In-Process and Other Non-Indexed Citations, Ovid Embase, EBSCO Cumulative Index to Nursing &amp; Allied Health Literature (CINAHL), and EBM Reviews. For the economic review, a search filter was applied to limit search results to economics-related literature. Data sources for the budget impact analysis included expert opinion, published literature, and Ontario administrative data.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="REVIEW METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic reviews, meta-analyses, randomized controlled trials, and observational studies were included in the clinical effectiveness review, and full economic evaluations were included in the economic literature review. Studies were included if they examined the effect of Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents in de novo or restenotic lesions in above-the-knee arteries. For the budget impact analysis, 3 scenarios were constructed based on different assumptions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">One randomized controlled trial reported a significantly higher patency rate with Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents for lesions ≤ 14 cm than with angioplasty or bare metal stents. One observational study showed no difference in patency rates between Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents and paclitaxel drug-coated balloons. Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents were associated with a significantly higher event-free survival rate than angioplasty, but the event-free survival rate was similar for Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents and paclitaxel drug-coated balloons. No economic evaluations compared Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents with bare metal stents or angioplasty for peripheral arterial disease. A budget impact analysis showed that the cost savings associated with funding of Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents would be $470,000 to $640,000 per year, assuming that the use of the Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stent was associated with a lower risk of subsequent revascularization.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Based on evidence of low to moderate quality, Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents were associated with a higher patency rate than angioplasty or bare metal stents, and with fewer adverse events than angioplasty. The effectiveness and safety of Zilver paclitaxel drug-eluting stents and paclitaxel drug-coated balloons were similar.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <CollectiveName>Health Quality Ontario</CollectiveName>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ont Health Technol Assess Ser</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101521610</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1915-7398</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000972">Antineoplastic Agents, Phytogenic</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>P88XT4IS4D</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017239">Paclitaxel</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000972" MajorTopicYN="N">Antineoplastic Agents, Phytogenic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003362" MajorTopicYN="N">Cost-Benefit Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054855" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug-Eluting Stents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017239" MajorTopicYN="N">Paclitaxel</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="Y">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="Y">economics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058729" MajorTopicYN="N">Peripheral Arterial Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013673" MajorTopicYN="Y">Technology Assessment, Biomedical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719778</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4688325</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouriel K.
Peripheral arterial disease. Lancet. 2001; 358(9289):1257–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11675083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norgren L, Hiatt WR, Dormandy JA, Nehler MR, Harris KA, Fowkes FG, et al. Inter-society consensus for the management of peripheral arterial disease (TASC II). J Vasc Surg. 2007; 45
Suppl S:S5–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17223489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litsky J, Chanda A, Stilp E, Lansky A, Mena C.
Critical evaluation of stents in the peripheral arterial disease of the superficial femoral artery - Focus on the paclitaxel eluting stent. Med Devices (Auckl). 2014; 7(1):149–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4045256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24920940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsanos K, Tepe G, Tsetis D, Fanelli F.
Standards of practice for superficial femoral and popliteal artery angioplasty and stenting. Cardiovasc Intervent Radiol. 2014; 37(3):592–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24722891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scheinert D, Scheinert S, Sax J, Piorkowski C, Braunlich S, Ulrich M, et al. Prevalence and clinical impact of stent fractures after femoropopliteal stenting. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005; 45(2): 312–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15653033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schillinger M, Exner M, Mlekusch W, Haumer M, Ahmadi R, Rumpold H, et al. Balloon angioplasty and stent implantation induce a vascular inflammatory reaction. J Endovasc Ther. 2002; 9(1): 59–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11958327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fowkes FG, Rudan D, Rudan I, Aboyans V, Denenberg JO, McDermott MM, et al. Comparison of global estimates of prevalence and risk factors for peripheral artery disease in 2000 and 2010: a systematic review and analysis. Lancet. 2013; 382(9901):1329–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23915883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovell M, Harris K, Forbes T, Twillman G, Abramson B, Criqui MH, et al. Peripheral arterial disease: lack of awareness in Canada. Can J Cardiol. 2009; 25(1): 39–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2691879</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19148341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch AT, Criqui MH, Treat-Jacobson D, Regensteiner JG, Creager MA, Olin JW, et al. Peripheral arterial disease detection, awareness, and treatment in primary care. JAMA. 2001; 286(11): 1317–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CIHI Portal. Release 8.1 [Internet]. Ottawa (ON): Canadian Institute for Health Information; c2003.  [cited 2015]. Available from: http://www.cihi.ca/cihi-ext-portal/internet/en/document/types+of+care/hospital+care/cihi_portal</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dvir D, Torguson R, Waksman R.
Overview of the 2011 Food and Drug Administration's circulatory system devices panel of the medical devices advisory committee meeting on the Zilver PTX drug-eluting peripheral stent. Cardiovasc Revasc Med. 2012; 13(5): 281–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22898055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dake MD, Van Alstine WG, Zhou Q, Ragheb AO.
Polymer-free paclitaxel-coated Zilver PTX stents–evaluation of pharmacokinetics and comparative safety in porcine arteries. J Vasc Interv Radiol. 2011; 22(5): 603–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21419649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axel DI, Kunert W, Goggelmann C, Oberhoff M, Herdeg C, Kuttner A, et al. Paclitaxel inhibits arterial smooth muscle cell proliferation and migration in vitro and in vivo using local drug delivery. Circulation. 1997; 96(2): 636–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9244237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavigne MC, Eppihimer MJ, Cheng R, Barry JJ.
Anti-proliferative compounds for the prevention of restenosis: Anti-restenotic mechanisms of paclitaxel action. Curr Pharm Des. 2010; 16(36): 3989–4001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21208187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elens M, Verbist J, Keirse K, Van Den Eynde W, Peeters P.
Which is currently the best strategy for treatment of SFA in-stent restenosis?
J Cardiovasc Surg (Torino). 2014;55(4):477–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24941234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rooke TW, Hirsch AT, Misra S, Sidawy AN, Beckman JA, Findeiss L, et al. Management of patients with peripheral artery disease (compilation of 2005 and 2011 ACCF/AHA Guideline Recommendations): a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013; 61(14): 1555–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492473</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23473760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abramson S, Huckeel V, Anand S, Forbes T, Gupta A, Harris K, et al. Canadian Cardiovascular Society Consensus Conference: peripheral arterial disease - executive summary. Can J Cardiol. 2005; 21(12): 997–1006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16234879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Stroke Organisation, Tendera M, Aboyans V, Bartelink ML, Baumgartner I, Clement D, et al. ESC guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of peripheral artery diseases: document covering atherosclerotic disease of extracranial carotid and vertebral, mesenteric, renal, upper and lower extremity arteries: the Task Force on the Diagnosis and Treatment of Peripheral Artery Diseases of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J. 2011; 32(22): 2851–906.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21873417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Schunemann HJ, Tugwell P, Knottnerus A.
GRADE guidelines: a new series of articles in the Journal of Clinical Epidemiology. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011; 64(4): 380–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21185693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodman C.
Literature searching and evidence interpretation for assessing health care practices. Stockholm, Sweden: Swedish Council on Technology Assessment in Health Care; 
1996. 
81 p. SBU Report No. 119E.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7843894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dake MD, Ansel GM, Jaff MR, Ohki T, Saxon RR, Smouse HB, et al. Sustained safety and effectiveness of paclitaxel-eluting stents for femoropopliteal lesions: 2-year follow-up from the Zilver PTX randomized and single-arm clinical studies. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013; 61(24): 2417–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dake MD, Ansel GM, Jaff MR, Ohki T, Saxon RR, Smouse HB, et al. Paclitaxel-eluting stents show superiority to balloon angioplasty and bare metal stents in femoropopliteal disease: twelve-month zilver PTX randomized study results. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2011; 4(5): 495–504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21953370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dake MD, Scheinert D, Tepe G, Tessarek J, Fanelli F, Bosiers M, et al. Nitinol stents with polymer-free paclitaxel coating for lesions in the superficial femoral and popliteal arteries above the knee: twelve-month safety and effectiveness results from the Zilver PTX single-arm clinical study. J Endovasc Ther. 2011; 18(5): 613–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21992630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fanelli F, Di Primo M, Boatta E, Johnston K, Sapoval M.
Drug-eluting nitinol stent treatment of the superficial femoral artery and above-the-knee popliteal artery (the Zilver PTX single-arm clinical study): a comparison between diabetic and nondiabetic patients. Cardiovasc Intervent Radiol. 2013; 36(5): 1232–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23299704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosiers M, Peeters P, Tessarek J, Deloose K, Strickler S, Zilver PTXS-ASI. The Zilver(R) PTX(R) Single Arm Study: 12-month results from the TASC C/D lesion subgroup. J Cardiovasc Surg (Torino). 2013; 54(1): 115–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23296421</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeller T, Dake MD, Tepe G, Brechtel K, Noory E, Beschorner U, et al. Treatment of femoropopliteal in-stent restenosis with paclitaxel-eluting stents. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2013; 6(3): 274–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jens S, Conijn AP, Koelemay MJW, Bipat S, Reekers JA.
Randomized trials for endovascular treatment of infrainguinal arterial disease: Systematic review and meta-analysis (part 1: Above the knee). Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2014; 47(5): 524–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24656874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsanos K, Spiliopoulos S, Karunanithy N, Krokidis M, Sabharwal T, Taylor P.
Bayesian network meta-analysis of nitinol stents, covered stents, drug-eluting stents, and drug-coated balloons in the femoropopliteal artery. J Vasc Surg. 2014; 59(4): 1123–33.e8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24661896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Kearns B, Stevenson MD, Cantrell AJ, Littlewood C, Michaels JA.
Enhancements to angioplasty for peripheral arterial occlusive disease: Systematic review, cost-effectiveness assessment and expected value of information analysis. Health Technol Assess. 2014; 18(10):I-XX+1–251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4781277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24524731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schachter H. Zilver PTX drug-eluting peripheral stents to treat peripheral arterial disease of the femoropopliteal vessels [Issues in emerging health technologies, Issue 128] [Internet]. Ottawa (ON): Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technologies in Health; 2014 [cited 2015.  May]. Available from: https://www.cadth.ca/media/pdf/EH0017_ZilverPTX_e.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeller T, Rastan A, Macharzina R, Tepe G, Kaspar M, Chavarria J, et al. Drug-coated balloons vs. drug-eluting stents for treatment of long femoropopliteal lesions. J Endovasc Ther. 2014; 21(3): 359–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24915582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujihara M, Utsunomiya M, Higashimori A, Yokoi Y, Nakamura M.
Outcomes of Zilver PTX stent implantation for the treatment of complex femoropopliteal artery disease. Heart Vessels. Forthcoming 2015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25351136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leopardi M, Houbballah R, Becquemin JP.
Effectiveness of Zilver PTX eluting stent in TASC C/D lesions and restenosis. J Cardiovasc Surg (Torino). 2014; 55(2): 229–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24670831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aboyans V, Criqui MH, Abraham P, Allison MA, Creager MA, Diehm C, et al. Measurement and interpretation of the ankle-brachial index: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2012; 126(24): 2890–909.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rutherford RB, Baker JD, Ernst C, Johnston KW, Porter JM, Ahn S, et al. Recommended standards for reports dealing with lower extremity ischemia: revised version. J Vasc Surg. 1997; 26(3): 517–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9308598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiatt WR, Hirsch AT, Regensteiner JG, Brass EP.
Clinical trials for claudication. Assessment of exercise performance, functional status, and clinical end points. Vascular Clinical Trialists. Circulation. 1995; 92(3): 614–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7634476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Process and methods guides. The guidelines manual: appendix G: methodology checklist [Internet]. London, UK: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence; 2012.  [cited 2015 May 27]. Available from: http://publications.nice.org.uk/the-guidelines-manual-appendices-bi-pmg6b/appendix-g-methodology-checklist-economic-evaluations</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, the PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009; 6(6):e1000097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Cock E, Sapoval M, Julia P, de Lissovoy G, Lopes S.
A budget impact model for paclitaxel-eluting stent in femoropopliteal disease in France. Cardiovasc Intervent Radiol. 2013; 36(2): 362–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3595477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23073560</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canadian Institute for Health Information. Canadian classification of health interventions. Ottawa (ON): The Institute; 2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wodchis WP, Bushmeneva K, Nikitovic M, McKillop I.
Guidelines on person-level costing using administrative databases in Ontario [Internet]. Toronto (ON): Health System Performance Research Network; 2013.  [cited 2015]. Available from: http://www.hsprn.ca/uploads/files/Guidelines_on_PersonLevel_Costing_May_2013.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorenkamp M, Boldt J, Leber AW, Sohns C, Roser M, Boldt LH, et al. Cost-effectiveness of paclitaxel-coated balloon angioplasty in patients with drug-eluting stent restenosis. Clin Cardiol. 2013; 36(7): 407–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6649637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23595957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development. PPPs and exchange rates [Internet]. Paris, France: The Organisation; 2015.  [cited 2015.  May 27]. Available from: https://stats.oecd.org/Index.aspx?DataSetCode=SNA_TABLE4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bank of Canada. Inflation calculator [Internet]. Ottawa (ON): Bank of Canada; 2015.  [cited 2015.  May 28]. Available from: http://www.bankofcanada.ca/rates/related/inflation-calculator/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ontario Ministry of Health and Long Term Care. Schedule of benefits: physician services under the Health Insurance Act [Internet]. Toronto (ON): The Ministry; 2005.  [cited 2015 Jun 1]. Available from: http://www.health.gov.on.ca/english/providers/program/ohip/sob/physserv/sob_master08052015.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pietzsch JB, Geisler BP, Garner AM, Zeller T, Jaff MR.
Economic analysis of endovascular interventions for femoropopliteal arterial disease: a systematic review and budget impact model for the United States and Germany. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2014; 84(4): 546–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24782424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
