<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">26866234</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK333433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Oklahoma City (OK)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="spyogenes"><i>Streptococcus pyogenes</i>: Basic Biology to Clinical Manifestations</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2016</Year></BeginningDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferretti</LastName><ForeName>Joseph J.</ForeName><Initials>JJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center, Oklahoma City, OK</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stevens</LastName><ForeName>Dennis L.</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA Medical Center, Boise, ID</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fischetti</LastName><ForeName>Vincent A.</ForeName><Initials>VA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Rockefeller University, New York, NY</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="spyogenes" part="pandas">Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated with Streptococcal Infections (PANDAS)</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orefici</LastName><ForeName>Graziella</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituto Superiore di Sanità, Rome; and Department of Pediatrics,Child and Adolescent Neuropsychiatry, University La Sapienza-Rome</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cardona</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Child &amp; Adolescent Neuropsychiatry, University of Rome, ‘La Sapienza,’ Rome</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cox</LastName><ForeName>Carol J.</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center, Biomedical Research Center, Oklahoma City, OK 73104</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cunningham</LastName><ForeName>Madeleine W.</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center, Biomedical Research Center, Oklahoma City, OK 73104</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>The inclusion of a chapter on pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections (or PANDAS) is essential to provide a history of the disease and provide current information about its association with <i>Streptococcus pyogenes</i> (group A streptococci), tics, obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) and its relationship to Sydenham chorea (SC), which is the neurologic manifestation of acute rheumatic fever. PANDAS has been misunderstood and confusing to doctors since its discovery, but the original group of the first 50 cases as described by Dr Susan Swedo (Swedo, et al., 1998) has a similarity to Sydenham chorea that distinguishes this initial group from tic and OCD cases. As this chapter will examine, the acute onset is an important feature of these disorders, as are their piano-playing choreiform movements, enuresis, night-time fears, separation anxiety, learning regression, and handwriting disabilities. The most current literature, which has been recently published in the <i>Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology</i> (Murphy, et al., 2015b; Murphy, Parker-Athill, Lewin, Storch, &amp; Mutch, 2015a; Toufexis, et al., 2015; Gerardi, Casadonte, Patel, &amp; Murphy, 2015; Chang, et al., 2015), provides new insight into the clinical phenotype of PANDAS; namely, a subgroup of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS), which has been proposed to have multiple etiologies, including those that are genetic and immunologic, and that present either with or without preceding infections, such as with <i>Streptococcus pyogenes</i> (Toufexis, et al., 2015). PANS is a subtype of obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD) that presents with an abrupt onset or exacerbation of neuropsychiatric symptoms (Murphy, et al., 2015b), including moderate or severe OCD. Elevated anti-streptococcal antibody titers tended to have higher OCD severity and the symptoms tended to lead to sudden and severe impairment, due to comorbidities, such as anxiety, behavioral regression, depression, and suicidality. Comorbid tics in PANS were associated with decline in school performance, visuomotor impairment, eating disorders, deterioration of handwriting skills, and lower quality of life, as compared to children without tics (Murphy, et al., 2015b). In addition, clinical evaluation of youth with PANS and PANDAS and recommendations for diagnosis were reported from the 2013 PANS conference held at Stanford University where a group of clinicians and researchers who were academicians with clinical and research interest in PANDAS and PANS (Chang, et al., 2015). PANDAS is clearly a subtype of PANS (Murphy, et al., 2015b; Murphy, Parker-Athill, Lewin, Storch, &amp; Mutch, 2015a; Chang, et al., 2015) and not all PANS cases have an underlying streptococcal infection—but all PANDAS cases are associated with streptococcal infections, at least temporally. When these diseases appear, treatment with antibiotics can be successful, and a treatment trial of cefdinir by Murphy and colleagues indicated that therapy with cefdinir, a β lactam antibiotic, provided notable improvements in tic symptoms rated by the Yale Global Tic Severity Scale (YGTSS) and OCD symptoms rated by the Children’s Yale-Brown Obsessive Compulsive Scale (CY-BOCS). However, the differences within the groups as a whole were not significant. β-lactam antibiotics have been proposed to be neuroprotective above and beyond their antibiotic efficacy (Murphy, Parker-Athill, Lewin, Storch, &amp; Mutch, 2015a). Anti-neuronal autoantibodies against the brain in SC and PANDAS react with brain antigens including dopamine receptors (Cox, et al., 2013; Brimberg, et al., 2012), lysoganglioside (Kirvan, Swedo, Heuser, &amp; Cunningham, 2003; Kirvan, Swedo, Snider, &amp; Cunningham, 2006a), and tubulin (Kirvan, Cox, Swedo, &amp; Cunningham, 2007), as well as the activation of the calcium calmodulin-dependent protein kinase II (CaM KII) in human neuronal cells (Kirvan, Swedo, Heuser, &amp; Cunningham, 2003). Human anti-brain antibodies expressed in Tg mice targeted dopaminergic neurons and signaled the dopamine D2 receptor (D2R) (Cox, et al., 2013). Evidence strongly suggests that human anti-brain autoantibodies induced by <i>Streptococcus pyogenes</i> infections target the dopamine receptors (Cox, et al., 2013; Brimberg, et al., 2012) and that animal models immunized with the <i>S. pyogenes</i> antigen develop obsessive behaviors and movement problems, along with antibodies that react with the dopamine receptors and signal the CaMKII, similar to antibodies found in humans with SC and PANDAS (Brimberg, et al., 2012; Lotan, et al., 2014a).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>© The University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="spyogenes" part="pandas" sec="pandas.Foreword">Foreword</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="spyogenes" part="pandas" sec="pandas.Introduction_and_Background">Introduction and Background</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="spyogenes" part="pandas" sec="pandas.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Allen A. J., Leonard H. L., Swedo S. E. Case study: a new infection-triggered, autoimmune subtype of pediatric OCD and Tourette's syndrome. Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry. 1995;34(3):307–311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7896671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aron A. R., Behrens T. E., Smith S., Frank M. J., Poldrack R. A. Triangulating a cognitive control network using diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and functional MRI. The Journal of Neuroscience. 2007;27(14):3743–3752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17409238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashbaugh C. D., Moser T. J., Shearer M. H., White G. L., Kennedy R. C., Wessels M. R. Bacterial determinants of persistent throat colonization and the associated immune response in a primate model of human group A streptococcal pharyngeal infection. Cellular Microbiology. 2000;2(4):283–292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11207585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bencivenga J. F., Johnson D. R., Kaplan E. L. Determination of Group A Streptococcal Anti-M Type-Specific Antibody in Sera of Rheumatic Fever Patients after 45 Years. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2009;49(8):1237–1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19761409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Pazi H., Stoner J. A., Cunningham M. W. Dopamine Receptor Autoantibodies Correlate with Symptoms in Sydenham's Chorea. PLoS One. 2013;8(9):e73516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24073196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein G. A., Victor A. M., Pipal A. J., Williams K. A. Comparison of clinical characteristics of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections and childhood obsessive-compulsive disorder. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2010;20(4):333–340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3678581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloch M. H., Leckman J. F., Zhu H., Peterson B. S. Caudate volumes in childhood predict symptom severity in adults with Tourette syndrome. Neurology. 2005;65(8):1253–1258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2367161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16247053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bombaci M., Grifantini R., Mora M., Reguzzi V., Petracca R., Meoni E., et al.  Protein array profiling of tic patient sera reveals a broad range and enhanced immune response against Group A Streptococcus antigens. PLoS One. 2009;4(7):e6332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2709431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19623252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brimberg L., Benhar I., Mascaro-Blanco A., Alvarez K., Lotan D., Winter C., et al.  Behavioral, pharmacological, and immunological abnormalities after streptococcal exposure: a novel rat model of Sydenham chorea and related neuropsychiatric disorders. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2012;37(9):2076–2087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3398718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22534626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant P. A., Smyth G. K., Gooding T., Oshlack A., Harrington Z., Currie B., et al.  Susceptibility to acute rheumatic fever based on differential expression of genes involved in cytotoxicity, chemotaxis, and apoptosis. Infection and Immunity. 2014;82(2):753–761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3911372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24478089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budman C., Coffey B., Dure L., Gilbert D. L., Juncos J., Kaplan E. Regarding "Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders". Biological Psychiatry. 2005;58(11):917–919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16242121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buse J., Kirschbaum C., Leckman J. F., Münchau A., Roessner V. The Modulating Role of Stress in the Onset and Course of Tourette's Syndrome: A Review. Behavior Modification. 2014;38(2):184–216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24516255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardona F., Orefici G. Group A streptococcal infections and tic disorders in an Italian pediatric population. The Journal of Pediatrics. 2001;138(1):71–75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardona F., Ventriglia F., Cipolla O., Romano A., Creti R., Orefici G. A post-streptococcal pathogenesis in children with tic disorders is suggested by a color Doppler echocardiographic study. European Journal of Paediatric Neurology. 2007;11(5):270–276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17403609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso F., Vargas A. P., Oliveira L. D., Guerra A. A., Amaral S. V. Persistent Sydenham's chorea. Movement Disorders. 1999;14(5):805–807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10495042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang K., Frankovich J., Cooperstock M., Cunningham M. W., Latimer M. E., Murphy T. K., et al.  Clinical evaluation of youth with pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS): recommendations from the 2013 PANS Consensus Conference. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2015;25(1):3–13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25325534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chappell P., Riddle M., Anderson G., Scahill L., Hardin M., Walker D., et al.  Enhanced stress responsivity of Tourette syndrome patients undergoing lumbar puncture. Biological Psychiatry. 1994;36(1):35–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8080901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Church A. J., Dale R. C., Lees A. J., Giovannoni G., Robertson M. M. Tourette's syndrome: a cross sectional study to examine the PANDAS hypothesis. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry. 2003;74(5):602–607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1738462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12700302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbett B. A., Mendoza S. P., Baym C. L., Bunge S. A., Levine S. Examining cortisol rhythmicity and responsivity to stress in children with Tourette syndrome. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2008;33(6):810–820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2547137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18487023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox C. J., Sharma M., Leckman J. F., Zuccolo J., Zuccolo A., Kovoor A., et al.  Brain human monoclonal autoantibody from Sydenham chorea targets dopaminergic neurons in transgenic mice and signals dopamine D2 receptor: Implications in human disease. The Journal of Immunology. 2013;191(11):5524–5541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3848617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox C. J., Zuccolo A. J., Edwards E. V., Mascaro-Blanco A., Alvarez K., Stoner J., et al.  Antineuronal antibodies in a heterogeneous group of youth and young adults with tics and obsessive-compulsive disorder. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2015;25(1):76–85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25658702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creti R., Cardona F., Pataracchia M., Hunolstein C. V., Cundari G., Romano A., et al.  Characterisation of group A streptococcal (GAS) isolates from children with tic disorders. Indian Journal of Medical Research. 2004;119 Suppl:174–178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15232189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creti R., Imperi M., Baldassari L., Pataracchia M., Recchia S., Alfarone G., et al.  emm types, virulence factors, and antibiotic resistance of invasive Streptococcus pyogenes isolates from Italy: what has changed in 11 years? Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2007;45(7):2249–2256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1933002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cubo E., Gabriel y Galán J. M., Villaverde V. A., Velasco S. S., Benito V. D., Macarrón J. V., et al.  Prevalence of tics in schoolchildren in central Spain: a population-based study. Pediatric Neurology. 2011;45(2):100–108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21763950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham M. W. Streptococcus and rheumatic fever. Current Opinion in Rheumatology. 2012;24(4):408–416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3645882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22617826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale R. C., Church A. J., Cardoso F., Goddard E., Cox T. C., Chong W. K., et al.  Poststreptococcal acute disseminated encephalomyelitis with basal ganglia involvement and auto-reactive antibasl ganglia antibodies. Annals of Neurology. 2001;50(5):588–595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11706964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale R. C., Merheb V., Pillai S., Wang D., Cantrill L., Murphy T. K., et al.  Antibodies to surface dopamine-2 receptor in autoimmune movement and psychiatric disorders. Brain. 2012;135(Pt 11):3453–3468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23065479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeGiorgio L. A., Konstantinov K. N., Lee S. C., Hardin J. A., Volpe B. T., Diamond B. A subset of lupus anti-DNA antibodies cross-reacts with theNR2 glutamate receptor in systemic lupus erythematosus. Nature Medicine. 2001;7(11):1189–1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11689882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicuonzo G., Gherardi G., Lorino G., Angeletti S., De Cesaris M., Fiscarelli E., et al.  Group A streptococcal genotypes from pediatric throat isolates in Rome, Italy. Journal of Clinical Microbiology. 2001;39(5):1687–1690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11325974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabbay V., Coffey B. J., Babb J. S., Meyer L., Wachtel C., Anam S., et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus: Comparison of diagnosis and treatment in the community and at a Specialty clinic. Pediatrics. 2008;122(2):273–278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadow K. D., Nolan E. E., Sprafkin J., Schwartz J. Tics and psychiatric comorbidity in children and adolescents. Developmental Medicine &amp; Child Neurology. 2002;44(5):330–338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12033719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvin J. E., Hemric M. E., Ward K., Cunningham M. W. Cytotoxic monoclonal antibody from rheumatic carditis reacts with human endothelium: implications in rheumatic heart disease. The Journal of Clinical Investigation. 2000;106(2):217–224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC314302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10903337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey M. A., Swedo S. E. Sydenham's chorea. Clinical and therapeutic update. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology. 1997;418:115–120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9331612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey M. A., Giedd J., Swedo S. E. PANDAS: the search for environmental triggers of pediatric neuropsychiatric disorders. Lessons from rheumatic fever. Journal of Child Neurology. 1998;13(9):413–423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9733286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey M. A., Perlmutter S. J., Allen A. J., Hamburger S., Lougee L., Leonard H. L., et al.  A pilot study of penicillin prophylaxis for neuropsychiatric exacerbations triggered by streptococcal infections. Biological Psychiatry. 1999;45(12):1564–1571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10376116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garvey M. A., Snider L. A., Leitman S. F., Werden R., Swedo S. E. Treatment of Sydenham's chorea with intravenous immunoglobulin, plasma exchange, or prednisone. Journal of Child Neurology. 2005;20(5):424–429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15968928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geller D. A. Obsessive compulsive and spectrum disorders in children and adolescents. Psychiatric Clinics of North America. 2006;29(2):353–370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16650713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerardi D. M., Casadonte J., Patel P., Murphy T. K. PANDAS and comorbid Kleine-Levin syndrome. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2015;25(1):93–98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25329605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graybiel A. M. Habits, rituals, and the evaluative brain. Annual Review of Neuroscience. 2008;31:359–387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampson M., Tokoglu F., King R. A., Constable R. T., Leckman J. F. Brain areas coactivating with motor cortex during chronic motor tics and intentional movements. Biological Psychiatry. 2009;65(7):594–599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2679868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19111281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertzén E., Johansson L., Kansal R., Hecht A., Dahesh S., Janos M., et al.  Intracellular Streptococcus pyogenes in Human Macrophages Display an Altered Gene Expression Profile. PLoS One. 2012;7(4):e35218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22511985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertzén E., Johansson L., Wallin R., Schmidt H., Kroll M., Rehn A. P., et al.  M1 protein-dependent intracellular trafficking promotes persistence and replication of Streptococcus pyogenes in macrophages. Journal of Innate Immunity. 2010;2(6):534–545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoekstra P. J., Manson W. L., Steenhuis M. P., Kallenberg C. G., Minderaa R. B. Association of common cold with exacerbations in pediatric but not adult patients with tic disorder: A prospective longitudinal study. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2005;15(2):285–292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15910212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman K. L., Hornig M., Yaddanapudi K., Jabado O., Lipkin W. I. A murine model for neuropsychiatric disorders associated with group A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection. The Journal of Neuroscience. 2004;24(7):1780–1791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14973249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huerta P. T., Kowal C., DeGiorgio L. A., Volpe B. T., Diamond B. Immunity and behavior: Antibodies alter emotion. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2006;103(3):678–683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1334673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husby G., van de Rijn I., Zabriskie J. B., Abdin Z. H., Williams R. C., Jr Antibodies reacting with cytoplasm of subthalamic and caudate nuclei neurons in chorea and acute rheumatic fever. The Journal of Experimental Medicine. 1976;144(4):1094–1110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2190435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">789810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, D. R., Kaplan, E. L., Sramek, J., Bicova, R., Havlicek, J., Havlickova, H., et al. (1997). Laboratory diagnosis of group A streptococcal infections. Geneva: World Health Organization.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson D. R., Kurlan R., Leckman J., Kaplan E. L. The Human Immune Response to Streptococcal Extracellular Antigens: Clinical, Diagnostic, and Potential Pathogenetic Implications. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2010;50(4):481–490.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20067422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan E. L. The group A streptococcal upper respiratory tract carrier state: an enigma. The Journal of Pediatrics. 1980;97(3):337–345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6997450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan E. L., Chhatwal G. S., Rohde M. Reduced ability of penicillin to eradicate ingested group A streptococci from epithelial cells: Clinical and pathogenetic implications. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2006;43(11):1398–1406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17083011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan E. L., Gastanaduy A. S., Huwe B. B. The role of the carrier in treatment failures after antibiotic for group A streptococci in the upper respiratory tract. Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine. 1981;98(3):326–335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7021717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerbeshian J., Burd L., Pettit R. A possible post-streptococcal movement disorder with chorea and tics. Developmental Medicine &amp; Child Neurology. 1990;32(7):642–644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2391015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiessling L. S., Marcotte A. C., Culpepper L. Anti-neuronal antibodies in movement disorders. Pediatrics. 1993;92(1):39–43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8516083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirvan C. A., Cox C. J., Swedo S. E., Cunningham M. W. Tubulin is a neuronal target of autoantibodies in Sydenham's chorea. The Journal of Immunology. 2007;178(11):7412–7421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17513792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirvan C. A., Swedo S. E., Heuser J. S., Cunningham M. W. Mimicry and autoantibody-mediated neuronal cell signaling in Sydenham chorea. Nature Medicine. 2003;9(7):914–920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12819778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirvan C. A., Swedo S. E., Kurahara D., Cunningham M. W. Streptococcal mimicry and antibody-mediated cell signaling in the pathogenesis of Sydenham's chorea. Autoimmunity. 2006b;39(1):21–29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16455579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirvan C. A., Swedo S. E., Snider L. A., Cunningham M. W. Antibody-mediated neuronal cell signaling in behavior and movement disorders. Journal of Neuroimmunology. 2006a;179(1-2):173–179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16875742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo K., Kabasawa T. Improvement in Gilles de la Tourette syndrome after corticosteroid therapy. Annals of Neurology. 1978;4(4):387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">281893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotb M., Fathey N., Aziz R., Rowe S., Williams R. W., Lu L. Unbiased forward genetics and systems biology approaches to understanding how gene-environment interactions work to predict susceptibility and outcomes of infections. Novartis Foundation Symposia. 2008;293:156–165, 181-183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18972751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowal C., DeGiorgio L. A., Nakaoka T., Hetherington H., Huerta P. T., Diamond B., et al.  Cognition and immunity: antibody impairs memory. Immunity. 2004;21(2):179–188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15308099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause D., Matz J., Weidinger E., Wagner J., Wildenauer A., Obermeier M., et al.  Association between intracellular infectious agents and Tourette's syndrome. European Archives of Psychiatry and Clinical Neuroscience. 2010;260(4):359–363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurlan R., Johnson D., Kaplan E. L., Tourette Syndrome Study Group  Streptococcal infection and exacerbations of childhood tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective blinded cohort study. Pediatrics. 2008;121(6):1188–1197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurlan R., McDermott M. P., Deeley C., Como P. G., Brower C., Eapen S., et al.  Prevalence of tics in schoolchildren and association with placement in special education. Neurology. 2001;57(8):1383–1388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langlois M., Force L. Revue Neurologique. 1965;113(6):641–645. [Nosologic and clinical revision of Gilles de la Tourette disease evoked by the action of certain neuroleptics on its course]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4379216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leckman J. F., King R. A., Gilbert D. L., Coffey B. J., Singer H. S., Dure L. S., et al.  Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and exacerbations of tic and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective longitudinal study. Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry. 2011;50(2):108–118.e3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie D. L., Kozma L., Martin A., Landeros A., Katsovich L., King R. A., et al.  Neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection: A case-control study among privately insured children. Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry. 2008;47(10):1166–1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2783578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18724258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H., Katsovich L., Ghebremichael M., Findley D. B., Grantz H., Lombroso P. J., et al.  Psychosocial stress predicts future symptom severities in children and adolescents with Tourette syndrome and/or obsessive-compulsive disorder. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry. 2007;48(2):157–166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3073143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17300554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H., Williams K. A., Katsovich L., Findley D. B., Grantz H., Lombroso P. J., et al.  Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and psychosocial stress predict future tic and obsessive-compulsive symptom severity in children and adolescents with Tourette syndrome and obsessive-compulsive disorder. Biological Psychiatry. 2010;67(7):684–691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2843763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H., Yeh C. B., Peterson B. S., Scahill L., Grantz H., Findley D. B., et al.  Assessment of symptom exacerbations in a longitudinal study of children with Tourette's syndrome or obsessive-compulsive disorder. Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry. 2002;41(9):1070–1077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12218428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linazasoro G., Van Blercom N., de Zárate C. O. Prevalence of tic disorder in two schools in the Basque country: Results and methodological caveats. Movement Disorders. 2006;21(12):2106–2109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17013915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loiselle C. R., Wendlandt J. T., Rohde C. A., Singer H. S. Antistreptococcal, neuronal, and nuclear antibodies in Tourette syndrome. Pediatric Neurology. 2003;28(2):119–125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12699862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotan D., Benhar I., Alvarez K., Mascaro-Blanco A., Brimberg L., Frenkel D., et al.  Behavioral and neural effects of intra-striatal infusion of anti-streptococcal antibodies in rats. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity. 2014a;38:249–262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotan D., Cunningham M. W., Joel D. Antibiotic treatment attenuates behavioral and neurochemical changes induced by exposure of rats to group a streptococcal antigen. PLoS One. 2014b;9(6):e101257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4076315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo F., Leckman J. F., Katsovich L., Findley D., Grantz H., Tucker D. M., et al.  Prospective longitudinal study of children with tic disorders and/or obsessive-compulsive disorder: relationship of symptom exacerbations to newly acquired streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2004;113(6):e578–e585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15173540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macerollo A., Martino D. Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated with Streptococcal Infections (PANDAS): An Evolving Concept. Tremor and Other Hyperkinetic Movements. 2013;3:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3783973</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24106651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martino D., Cavanna A. E., Robertson M. M., Orth M. Prevalence and phenomenology of eye tics in Gilles de la Tourette syndrome. Journal of Neurology. 2012;259(10):2137–2140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22434162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martino D., Chiarotti F., Buttglione M., Cardona F., Creti R., Nardocci N., et al.  The relationship between group A streptococcal infections and Tourette syndrome: a study on a large service-based cohort. Developmental Medicine &amp; Child Neurology. 2011;53(10):951–957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21679362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins T. B., Hoffman J. L., Augustine N. H., Phansalkar A. R., Fischetti V. A., Zabriskie J. B., et al.  Comprehensive analysis of antibody responses to streptococcal and tissue antigens in patients with acute rheumatic fever. International Immunology. 2008;20(3):445–452.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18245783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mell L. K., Davis R. L., Owens D. Association between streptococcal infection and obsessive-compulsive disorder, Tourette's syndrome, and tic disorder. Pediatrics. 2005;116(1):56–60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menzies L., Chamberlain S. R., Laird A. R., Thelen S. M., Sahakian B. J., Bullmore E. T. Integrating evidence from neuroimaging and neuropsychological studies of obsessive-compulsive disorder: The orbitofronto-striatal model revisited. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews. 2008;32(3):525–549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2889493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18061263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C. M., Pardo-Villamizar C., Gause C. D., Singer H. S. Serum autoantibodies measured by immunofluorescence confirm a failure to differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. Journal of the Neurological Sciences. 2009;276(1-2):45–48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18823914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris-Berry C. M., Pollard M., Gao S., Thompson C., Tourette Syndrome Study Group Singer, H. S2013Anti-streptococcal, tubulin, and dopamine receptor 2 antibodies in children with PANDAS and Tourette syndrome: Single-point and longitundinal assessments. Journal of Neuroimmunology 2641-2106–113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24080310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morshed S. A., Parveen S., Leckman J. F., Mercadante M. T., Bittencourt Kiss M. H., Miguel E. C., et al.  Antibodies against neural, nuclear, cytoskeletal, and streptococcal epitopes in children and adults with Tourette's syndrome, Sydenham's chorea, and autoimmune disorders. Biological Psychiatry. 2001;50(8):566–577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11690591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Müller N., Kroll B., Schwarz M. J., Riedel M., Straube A., Lütticken R., et al.  Increased titers of antibodies against streptococcal M12 and M19 proteins in patients with Tourette's syndrome. Psychiatry Research. 2001;101(2):187–193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11286821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Müller N., Riedel M., Blendinger C., Oberle K., Jacobs E., Abele-Horn M. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection and Tourette's syndrome. Psychiatry Research. 2004;129(2):119–125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15590039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy M. L., Pichichero M. E. Prospective identification and treatment of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with group A streptococcal infection (PANDAS). Archives of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine. 2002;156(4):356–361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11929370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy, T. K. (2013). Infections and tic disorders. In D. Martino, &amp; J. F. Leckman (Eds.), Tourette Syndrome (pp. 168-201). New York: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy T. K., Parker-Athill E. C., Lewin A. B., Storch E. A., Mutch P. J. Cefdinir for recent-onset pediatric neuropsychiatric disorders: a pilot randomized trial. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2015a;25(1):57–64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25299463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy T. K., Patel P. D., McGuire J. F., Kennel A., Mutch P. J., Parker-Athill E. C., et al.  Characterization of the pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome phenotype. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2015b;25(1):14–25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25314221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy T. K., Sajid M., Soto O., Shapira N., Edge P., Yang M., et al.  Detecting pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus in children with obsessive-compulsive disorder and tics. Biological Psychiatry. 2004;55(1):61–68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14706426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy T. K., Snider L. A., Mutch P. J., Harden E., Zaytoun A., Edge P. J., et al.  Relationship of movements and behaviors to Group A Streptococcus infections in elementary school children. Biological Psychiatry. 2007;61(3):279–284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17126304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy T. K., Storch E. A., Lewin A. B., Edge P. J., Goodman W. K. Clinical factors associated with Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorders Associated with Streptococcal Infections. Journal of Pediatrics. The Journal of Pediatrics. 2012;160(2):314–319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3227761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21868033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park H. S., Francis K. P., Yu J., Cleary P. P. Membranous cells in nasal-associated lymphoid tissue: A portal of entry for the respiratory mucosal pathogen group A streptococcus. The Journal of Immunology. 2003;171(5):2532–2537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12928403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlmutter S. J., Leitman S. F., Garvey M. A., Hamburger S., Feldman E., Leonard H. L., et al.  Therapeutic plasma exchange and intravenous immunoglobulin for obsessive-compulsive disorder and tic disorders in childhood. Lancet. 1999;354(9185):1153–1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10513708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterson B., Riddle M. A., Cohen D. J., Katz L. D., Smith J. C., Hardin M. T., et al.  Reduced basal ganglia volumes in Tourette's syndrome using three-dimensional reconstruction techniques from magnetic resonance images. Neurology. 1993;43(5):941–949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8492950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichichero M. E., Marsocci S. M., Murphy M. L., Hoeger W., Green J. L., Sorrento A. Incidence of streptococcal carriers in private pediatric practice. Archives of Pediatric and Adolescent Medicine. 1999;153(6):624–628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10357305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedel M., Straube A., Schwatz M. J., Wilske B., Müller N. Lyme disease presenting as Tourette's syndrome. Lancet. 1998;351(9100):418–419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9482302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts A. L., Connolly K. L., Kirse D. J., Evans A. K., Poehling K. A., Peters T. R., et al.  Detection of group A Streptococcus in tonsils from pediatric patients reveals high rate of asymptomatic streptococcal carriage. BMC Pediatrics. 2012;12:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22230361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxena S., Rauch S. L. Functional neuroimaging and the neuroanatomy of obsessive-compulsive disorder. Psychiatric Clinics of North America. 2000;23(3):563–586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10986728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrag A., Gilbert R., Giovannoni G., Robertson M. M., Metcalfe C., Ben-Shlomo Y. Streptococcal infection, Tourette syndrome, and OCD: is there a connection? Neurology. 2009;73(16):1256–1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2889814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19794128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segarra A. R., Murphy T. K. Cardiac involvement in children with PANDAS. Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry. 2008;47(5):603–604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sela S., Neeman R., Keller N., Barzilai A. Relationship between asymptomatic carriage of Streptococcus pyogenes and the ability of the strains to adhere to and be internalised by cultured epithelial cells. Journal of Medical Microbiology. 2000;49(6):499–502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10847202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selling L. The role of infection in the etiology of tics. Archives of Neurology &amp; Psychiatry. 1929;22:1163–1171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh N., Leonard E., Martin J. M. Prevalence of streptococcal pharyngitis and streptococcal carriage in children: a meta-anaylsis. Pediatrics. 2010;126(3):e557–e564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20696723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shulman S. T., Stollerman G., Beall B., Dale J. B., Tanz R. R. Temporal changes in streptococcal M protein types and the near-disappearance of acute rheumatic fever in the United States. Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2006;42(4):441–447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16421785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer H. S., Giuliano J. D., Zimmerman A. M., Walkup J. T. Infection: a stimulus for tic disorders. Pediatric Neurology. 2000;22(5):380–383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10913730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer H. S., Mascaro-Blanco A., Alvarez K., Morris-Berry C., Kawikova I., Ben-Pazi H., et al.  Neuronal antibody biomarkers for Sydenham's chorea identify a new group of children with chronic recurrent episodic acute exacerbations of tic and obsessive compulsive symptoms following a streptococcal infection. PLoS One. 2015;10(3):e0120499.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4368605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25793715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sjöholm K., Karlsson C., Linder A., Malmström J. A comprehensive analysis of the Streptococcus pyogenes and human plasma protein interaction network. Molecular BioSystems. 2014;10(7):1698–1708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24525632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snider L. A., Swedo S. E. PANDAS: current status and directions for research. Molecular Psychiatry. 2004;9(10):900–907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15241433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snider L. A., Lougee L., Slattery M., Grant P., Swedo S. E. Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biological Psychiatry. 2005;57(7):788–792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snider L. A., Sachdev V., MacKaronis J. E., St Peter M., Swedo S. E. Echocardiographic findings in the PANDAS subgroup. Pediatrics. 2004;114(6):e748–e751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15545618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snider L. A., Seligman L. D., Ketchen B. R., Levitt S. J., Bates L. R., Garvey M. A., et al.  Tics and problem behaviors in schoolchildren: prevalence, characterization, and associations. Pediatrics. 2002;110(2 Pt 1):331–336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12165586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sowell E. R., Kan E., Yoshii J., Thompson P. M., Bansal R., Xu D., et al.  Thinning of sensorimotor cortices in children with Tourette syndrome. Nature Neuroscience. 2008;11(6):637–639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2605107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18488025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staali L., Mörgelin M., Björck L., Tapper H. Streptococcus pyogenes expressing M and M-like surface proteins are phagocytosed but survive inside human neutrophils. Cellular Microbiology. 2003;5(4):253–265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedo S. E. Sydenham's chorea: A model for childhood autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders. JAMA. 1994;272(22):1788–1791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7661914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedo S. E., Leckman J. F., Rose N. R. From research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome). Pediatrics &amp; Therapeutics. 2012;2:113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedo S. E., Leonard H. L., Garvey M., Mittleman B., Allen A. J., Perlmutter S., et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. American Journal of Psychiatry. 1998;155(2):264–271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedo S. E., Rapoport J. L., Cheslow D. L., Leonard H. L., Ayoub E. M., Hosier D. M., et al.  High prevalence of obsessive-compulsive symptoms in patients with Sydenham's chorea. The American Journal of Psychiatry. 1989;146(2):246–249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2912267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanz R. R., Shulman S. T. Chronic pharyngeal carriage of group A streptococci. The Pediatric Infectious Disease Journal. 2007;26(2):175–176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17259882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taranta A., Moody M. D. Diagnosis of streptococcal pharyngitis and rheumatic fever. Pediatric Clinics of North America. 1971;18(1):125–143. viii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25868179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taranta A., Stollerman G. H. The relationship of Sydenham's chorea to infection with group A streptococci. The American Journal of Medicine. 1956;20(2):170–175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13282936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toufexis M. D., Hommer R., Gerardi D. M., Grant P., Rothschild L., D'Souza P., et al.  Disordered eating and food restrictions in children with PANDAS/PANS. Journal of Child and Adolescent Psychopharmacology. 2015;25(1):48–56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25329522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Economo, C. (1931). Encephalitis lethargica, its sequelae and treatment. Oxford: Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang B., Li S., Southern P. J., Cleary P. P. Streptococcal modulation of cellular invasion via TGF-beta1 signaling. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 2006;103(7):2380–2385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1413688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16467160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaddanapudi K., Hornig M., Serge R., De Miranda J., Baghban A., Villar G., et al.  Passive transfer of streptococcus-induced antibodies reproduces behavioral disturbances in a mouse model of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection. Molecular Psychiatry. 2010;15(7):712–726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19668249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuccolo. (2015). Manuscript in preparation.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26866234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
