<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27165051</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-7899</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>152</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2016</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Reproduction (Cambridge, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Reproduction</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Endometriosis: where are we and where are we going?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>R63</StartPage>
          <EndPage>R78</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>R63-78</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1530/REP-16-0052</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Endometriosis currently affects ~5.5 million reproductive-aged women in the U.S. with symptoms such as painful periods (dysmenorrhea), chronic pelvic pain, pain with intercourse (dyspareunia), and infertility. It is defined as the presence of endometrial tissue outside the uterine cavity and is found predominately attached to sites within the peritoneal cavity. Diagnosis for endometriosis is solely made through surgery as no consistent biomarkers for disease diagnosis exist. There is no cure for endometriosis and treatments only target symptoms and not the underlying mechanism(s) of disease. The nature of individual predisposing factors or inherent defects in the endometrium, immune system, and/or peritoneal cavity of women with endometriosis remains unclear. The literature over the last 5 years (2010-2015) has advanced our critical knowledge related to hormones, hormone receptors, immune dysregulation, hormonal treatments, and the transformation of endometriosis to ovarian cancer. In this review, we cover the aforementioned topics with the goal of providing the reader an overview and related references for further study to highlight the progress made in endometriosis research, while concluding with critical areas of endometriosis research that are urgently needed.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2016 Society for Reproduction and Fertility.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Greene</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexis D</ForeName>
            <Initials>AD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and GynecologyUniversity of Cincinnati Center for Reproductive Health, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephanie A</ForeName>
            <Initials>SA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental HealthUniversity of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kendziorski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jessica A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental HealthUniversity of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sroga-Rios</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julie M</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and GynecologyUniversity of Cincinnati Center for Reproductive Health, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Herzog</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas J</ForeName>
            <Initials>TJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and GynecologyUniversity of Cincinnati Center for Reproductive Health, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA University of Cincinnati Cancer InstituteUniversity of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Burns</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katherine A</ForeName>
            <Initials>KA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental HealthUniversity of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio, USA Katherine.Burns@uc.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R00 ES021737</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ES</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Reproduction</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100966036</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1470-1626</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004715" MajorTopicYN="N">Endometriosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Declaration of Interest</b>: ADG, SAL, JAK, JMS-R, and KAB do not have any conflict of interests to disclose. TJH, in the last two years, has served on Advisory boards to: Roche/Genentech, AstraZeneca, Caris Life Sciences, Clovis Oncology, and Johnson &amp; Johnson.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27165051</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS789174</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4958554</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/REP-16-0052</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">REP-16-0052</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Revised American Society for Reproductive Medicine classification of endometriosis: 1996. Fertil Steril. 1997;67:817–821.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9130884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abu Hashim H. Potential role of aromatase inhibitors in the treatment of endometriosis. Int J Womens Health. 2014;6:671–680.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acien P, Velasco I, Acien M, Capello C, Vela P. Epithelial ovarian cancers and endometriosis. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 2015;79:126–135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25634648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal S, Fraser MA, Chen I, Singh SS. Dienogest for the treatment of deep endometriosis: case report and literature review. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2015;41:309–313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn S, Monsanto S, Miller C, Singh S, Thomas R, Tayade C. Pathophysiology and Immune Dysfunction in Endometriosis. Biomed Res Int. 2015a;2015:795976.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4515278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26247027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn SH, Edwards AK, Singh SS, Young SL, Lessey BA, Tayade C. IL-17A Contributes to the Pathogenesis of Endometriosis by Triggering Proinflammatory Cytokines and Angiogenic Growth Factors. J Immunol. 2015b;195:2591–2600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4561197</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26259585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akbarzadeh-Jahromi M, Shekarkhar G, Sari Aslani F, Azarpira N, Heidari Esfahani M, Momtahan M. Prevalence of Endometriosis in Malignant Epithelial Ovarian Tumor. Arch Iran Med. 2015;18:844–848.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26621017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almassinokiani F, Almasi A, Akbari P, Saberifard M. Effect of Letrozole on endometriosis-related pelvic pain. Med J Islam Repub Iran. 2014;28:107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4301232</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25664308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreoli CG, Genro VK, Souza CA, Michelon T, Bilibio JP, Scheffel C, Cunha-Filho JS. T helper (Th)1, Th2, and Th17 interleukin pathways in infertile patients with minimal/mild endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2011;95:2477–2480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21392744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andres Mde P, Lopes LA, Baracat EC, Podgaec S. Dienogest in the treatment of endometriosis: systematic review. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2015;292:523–529.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25749349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angioni S, Cofelice V, Pontis A, Tinelli R, Socolov R. New trends of progestins treatment of endometriosis. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2014;30:769–773.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anglesio MS, Bashashati A, Wang YK, Senz J, Ha G, Yang W, Aniba MR, Prentice LM, Farahani H, Li Chang H, Karnezis AN, Marra MA, Yong PJ, Hirst M, Gilks B, Shah SP, Huntsman DG. Multifocal endometriotic lesions associated with cancer are clonal and carry a high mutation burden. J Pathol. 2015;236:201–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6680210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25692284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aoki D, Katsuki Y, Shimizu A, Kakinuma C, Nozawa S. Successful heterotransplantation of human endometrium in SCID mice. Obstet Gynecol. 1994;83:220–228.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8290184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aris A. Endometriosis-associated ovarian cancer: A ten-year cohort study of women living in the Estrie Region of Quebec, Canada. J Ovarian Res. 2010;3:2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2822768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20205767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayhan A, Mao TL, Seckin T, Wu CH, Guan B, Ogawa H, Futagami M, Mizukami H, Yokoyama Y, Kurman RJ, Shih Ie M. Loss of ARID1A expression is an early molecular event in tumor progression from ovarian endometriotic cyst to clear cell and endometrioid carcinoma. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2012;22:1310–1315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460070</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22976498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barcz E, Milewski L, Dziunycz P, Kaminski P, Ploski R, Malejczyk J. Peritoneal cytokines and adhesion formation in endometriosis: an inverse association with vascular endothelial growth factor concentration. Fertil Steril. 2012;97:1380–1386 e1381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22542989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedaiwy MA, Dahoud W, Skomorovska-Prokvolit Y, Yi L, Liu JH, Falcone T, Hurd WW, Mesiano S. Abundance and Localization of Progesterone Receptor Isoforms in Endometrium in Women With and Without Endometriosis and in Peritoneal and Ovarian Endometriotic Implants. Reprod Sci. 2015;22:1153–1161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5933169</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26037298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedaiwy MA, Patterson B, Mahajan S. Prevalence of myofascial chronic pelvic pain and the effectiveness of pelvic floor physical therapy. J Reprod Med. 2013;58:504–510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568045</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellelis P, Barbeiro DF, Rizzo LV, Baracat EC, Abrao MS, Podgaec S. Transcriptional changes in the expression of chemokines related to natural killer and T-regulatory cells in patients with deep infiltrative endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2013;99:1987–1993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bersinger NA, Dechaud H, McKinnon B, Mueller MD. Analysis of cytokines in the peritoneal fluid of endometriosis patients as a function of the menstrual cycle stage using the Bio-Plex(R) platform. Arch Physiol Biochem. 2012;118:210–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22632541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beste MT, Pfaffle-Doyle N, Prentice EA, Morris SN, Lauffenburger DA, Isaacson KB, Griffith LG. Molecular network analysis of endometriosis reveals a role for c-Jun-regulated macrophage activation. Sci Transl Med. 2014;6:222ra216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4118592</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24500404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonocher CM, Montenegro ML, Rosa ESJC, Ferriani RA, Meola J. Endometriosis and physical exercises: a systematic review. Reprod Biol Endocrinol. 2014;12:4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3895811</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24393293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourlev V, Iljasova N, Adamyan L, Larsson A, Olovsson M. Signs of reduced angiogenic activity after surgical removal of deeply infiltrating endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2010;94:52–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyraz G, Selcuk I, Yazicioglu A, Tuncer ZS. Ovarian carcinoma associated with endometriosis. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2013;170:211–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23849309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braza-Boils A, Gilabert-Estelles J, Ramon LA, Gilabert J, Mari-Alexandre J, Chirivella M, Espana F, Estelles A. Peritoneal fluid reduces angiogenesis-related microRNA expression in cell cultures of endometrial and endometriotic tissues from women with endometriosis. PLoS One. 2013;8:e62370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23620826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braza-Boils A, Mari-Alexandre J, Gilabert J, Sanchez-Izquierdo D, Espana F, Estelles A, Gilabert-Estelles J. MicroRNA expression profile in endometriosis: its relation to angiogenesis and fibrinolytic factors. Hum Reprod. 2014;29:978–988.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24608518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braza-Boils A, Salloum-Asfar S, Mari-Alexandre J, Arroyo AB, Gonzalez-Conejero R, Barcelo-Molina M, Garcia-Oms J, Vicente V, Estelles A, Gilabert-Estelles J, Martinez C. Peritoneal fluid modifies the microRNA expression profile in endometrial and endometriotic cells from women with endometriosis. Hum Reprod. 2015;30:2292–2302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26307093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinton LA, Gridley G, Persson I, Baron J, Bergqvist A. Cancer risk after a hospital discharge diagnosis of endometriosis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1997;176:572–579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9077609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinton LA, Sakoda LC, Sherman ME, Frederiksen K, Kjaer SK, Graubard BI, Olsen JH, Mellemkjaer L. Relationship of benign gynecologic diseases to subsequent risk of ovarian and uterine tumors. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev. 2005;14:2929–2935.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown J, Farquhar C. An overview of treatments for endometriosis. JAMA. 2015;313:296–297.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruner-Tran K, McConaha M, Osteen K. Models of Endometriosis: Animal Models I - Rodent-based Chimeric Models. Endometriosis: Science and Practice 2012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bukulmez O, Hardy DB, Carr BR, Word RA, Mendelson CR. Inflammatory status influences aromatase and steroid receptor expression in endometriosis. Endocrinology. 2008;149:1190–1204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2275353</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18048499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bulun SE. Endometriosis. N Engl J Med. 2009;360:268–279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19144942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bulun SE, Monsavais D, Pavone ME, Dyson M, Xue Q, Attar E, Tokunaga H, Su EJ. Role of estrogen receptor-beta in endometriosis. Semin Reprod Med. 2012;30:39–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4034571</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bulun SE, Monsivais D, Kakinuma T, Furukawa Y, Bernardi L, Pavone ME, Dyson M. Molecular biology of endometriosis: from aromatase to genomic abnormalities. Semin Reprod Med. 2015;33:220–224.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26036904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burney RO, Talbi S, Hamilton AE, Vo KC, Nyegaard M, Nezhat CR, Lessey BA, Giudice LC. Gene expression analysis of endometrium reveals progesterone resistance and candidate susceptibility genes in women with endometriosis. Endocrinology. 2007;148:3814–3826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17510236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burns KA, Rodriguez KF, Hewitt SC, Janardhan KS, Young SL, Korach KS. Role of estrogen receptor signaling required for endometriosis-like lesion establishment in a mouse model. Endocrinology. 2012;153:3960–3971.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22700766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmona F, Chapron C, Martinez-Zamora MA, Santulli P, Rabanal A, Martinez-Florensa M, Lozano F, Balasch J. Ovarian endometrioma but not deep infiltrating endometriosis is associated with increased serum levels of interleukin-8 and interleukin-6. J Reprod Immunol. 2012;95:80–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22819248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carr B, Dmowski WP, O'Brien C, Jiang P, Burke J, Jimenez R, Garner E, Chwalisz K. Elagolix, an oral GnRH antagonist, versus subcutaneous depot medroxyprogesterone acetate for the treatment of endometriosis: effects on bone mineral density. Reprod Sci. 2014;21:1341–1351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4212335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carr BJ, Ochoa L, Rankin D, Owens BD. Biologic response to orthopedic sutures: a histologic study in a rabbit model. Orthopedics. 2009;32:828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19902886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen S, Wu RF, Su L, Zhou WD, Zhu MB, Chen QH. Lipoxin A4 regulates expression of the estrogen receptor and inhibits 17beta-estradiol induced p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase phosphorylation in human endometriotic stromal cells. Fertil Steril. 2014;102:264–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24835059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen SQ, Li JB, Jiang HY, Yuan L, Niu G, Yao SZ. Expression of human beta-defensin-2 in the eutopic and ectopic endometrial tissues in patients with endometriosis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2013a;287:1151–1157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23269356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YJ, Wu HH, Liau WT, Tsai CY, Tsai HW, Chao KC, Sung YJ, Li HY. A tumor necrosis factor-alpha inhibitor reduces the embryotoxic effects of endometriotic peritoneal fluid. Fertil Steril. 2013b;100:1476–1485.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24012198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chene G, Ouellet V, Rahimi K, Barres V, Provencher D, Mes-Masson AM. The ARID1A pathway in ovarian clear cell and endometrioid carcinoma, contiguous endometriosis, and benign endometriosis. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2015;130:27–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25912412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colette S, Defrere S, Lousse JC, Van Langendonckt A, Gotteland JP, Loumaye E, Donnez J. Inhibition of steroid sulfatase decreases endometriosis in an in vivo murine model. Hum Reprod. 2011;26:1362–1370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21441545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cummings A, Metcalf J. Induction of Endometriosis in Mice: A New Model Sensitive to Estrogen. Repro Toxicol. 1995;9:233–238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7579907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'hooghe T, Bambra C, De Jonge I, Lauweryns J, Koninckx P. The prevalence of spontaneous endometriosis in the baboon (Papio anubis, Papio cynocephalus) increases with the duration of captivity. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 1996;75:98–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8604618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Hooghe T, Bambra C, Raeymaekers B, De Jonge I, Lauweryns J, Koninckx P. Intrapelvic injection of menstrual endometrium causes endometriosis in baboons (Papio cynocephalus and Papio anubis) Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1995;173:125–134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7631669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Hooghe T, Bambra C, Suleman M, Dunselman G, Evers H, Koninckx P. Development of a model of retrograde menstruation in baboons (Papio anubis) Fertil Steril. 1994;62:635–638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8062962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniels JP, Middleton L, Xiong T, Champaneria R, Johnson NP, Lichten EM, Sutton C, Vercellini P, Gray R, Hills RK, Jones KD, Aimi G, Khan KS International LIPDM-aCG. Individual patient data meta-analysis of randomized evidence to assess the effectiveness of laparoscopic uterosacral nerve ablation in chronic pelvic pain. Hum Reprod Update. 2010;16:568–576.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20634210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis M, Rauh-Hain JA, Andrade C, Boruta DM, 2nd, Schorge JO, Horowitz NS, May T, del Carmen MG. Comparison of clinical outcomes of patients with clear cell and endometrioid ovarian cancer associated with endometriosis to papillary serous carcinoma of the ovary. Gynecol Oncol. 2014;132:760–766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24440832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delbandi AA, Mahmoudi M, Shervin A, Akbari E, Jeddi-Tehrani M, Sankian M, Kazemnejad S, Zarnani AH. Eutopic and ectopic stromal cells from patients with endometriosis exhibit differential invasive, adhesive, and proliferative behavior. Fertil Steril. 2013;100:761–769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23721717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duffy JM, Arambage K, Correa FJ, Olive D, Farquhar C, Garry R, Barlow DH, Jacobson TZ. Laparoscopic surgery for endometriosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;4:CD011031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24696265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunselman GA, Vermeulen N, Becker C, Calhaz-Jorge C, D'Hooghe T, De Bie B, Heikinheimo O, Horne AW, Kiesel L, Nap A, Prentice A, Saridogan E, Soriano D, Nelen W European Society of Human R &amp; Embryology. ESHRE guideline: management of women with endometriosis. Hum Reprod. 2014;29:400–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24435778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyson MT, Roqueiro D, Monsivais D, Ercan CM, Pavone ME, Brooks DC, Kakinuma T, Ono M, Jafari N, Dai Y, Bulun SE. Genome-wide DNA methylation analysis predicts an epigenetic switch for GATA factor expression in endometriosis. PLoS Genet. 2014;10:e1004158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3945170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24603652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dzatic-Smiljkovic O, Vasiljevic M, Djukic M, Vugdelic R, Vugdelic J. Frequency of ovarian endometriosis in epithelial ovarian cancer patients. Clin Exp Obstet Gynecol. 2011;38:394–398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22268283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elgafor El, Sharkwy IA. Combination of non-invasive and semi-invasive tests for diagnosis of minimal to mild endometriosis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2013;288:793–797.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23545836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ezzati M, Carr BR. Elagolix, a novel, orally bioavailable GnRH antagonist under investigation for the treatment of endometriosis-related pain. Womens Health (Lond Engl) 2015;11:19–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25581052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fassbender A, Vodolazkaia A, Saunders P, Lebovic D, Waelkens E, De Moor B, D'Hooghe T. Biomarkers of endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2013;99:1135–1145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23414923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernando S, Soh PQ, Cooper M, Evans S, Reid G, Tsaltas J, Rombauts L. Reliability of visual diagnosis of endometriosis. J Minim Invasive Gynecol. 2013;20:783–789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24183270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flower A, Liu JP, Lewith G, Little P, Li Q. Chinese herbal medicine for endometriosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;5:CD006568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22592712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fritz MA, S L. Clinical Gynecologic Endocrinology and Infertility 2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Funamizu A, Fukui A, Kamoi M, Fuchinoue K, Yokota M, Fukuhara R, Mizunuma H. Expression of natural cytotoxicity receptors on peritoneal fluid natural killer cell and cytokine production by peritoneal fluid natural killer cell in women with endometriosis. Am J Reprod Immunol. 2014;71:359–367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24495049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadducci A, Lanfredini N, Tana R. Novel insights on the malignant transformation of endometriosis into ovarian carcinoma. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2014;30:612–617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24905724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galic V, Coleman RL, Herzog TJ. Unmet needs in ovarian cancer: dividing histologic subtypes to exploit novel targets and pathways. Curr Cancer Drug Targets. 2013;13:698–707.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23675882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goncalves HF, Zendron C, Cavalcante FS, Aiceles V, Oliveira MA, Manaia JH, Babinski MA, Ramos CF. Leptin, its receptor and aromatase expression in deep infiltrating endometriosis. J Ovarian Res. 2015;8:53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26242176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granese R, Perino A, Calagna G, Saitta S, De Franciscis P, Colacurci N, Triolo O, Cucinella G. Gonadotrophin-releasing hormone analogue or dienogest plus estradiol valerate to prevent pain recurrence after laparoscopic surgery for endometriosis: a multi-center randomized trial. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2015;94:637–645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25761587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greaves E, Cousins FL, Murray A, Esnal-Zufiaurre A, Fassbender A, Horne AW, Saunders PT. A novel mouse model of endometriosis mimics human phenotype and reveals insights into the inflammatory contribution of shed endometrium. Am J Pathol. 2014;184:1930–1939.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4076466</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenberg LH, Slayden OD. Human endometriotic xenografts in immunodeficient RAG-2/gamma(c)KO mice. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004;190:1788–1795. discussion 1795-1786.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15284801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grummer R. Models of Endometriosis: In vitro and In vivo Models. Endometriosis: Science and Practice 2012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo Y, Chen Y, Liu LB, Chang KK, Li H, Li MQ, Shao J. IL-22 in the endometriotic milieu promotes the proliferation of endometrial stromal cells via stimulating the secretion of CCL2 and IL-8. Int J Clin Exp Pathol. 2013;6:2011–2020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3796222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24133578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han SJ, Hawkins SM, Begum K, Jung SY, Kovanci E, Qin J, Lydon JP, DeMayo FJ, O'Malley BW. A new isoform of steroid receptor coactivator-1 is crucial for pathogenic progression of endometriosis. Nat Med. 2012;18:1102–1111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3541027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22660634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han SJ, Jung SY, Wu SP, Hawkins SM, Park MJ, Kyo S, Qin J, Lydon JP, Tsai SY, Tsai MJ, DeMayo FJ, O'Malley BW. Estrogen Receptor beta Modulates Apoptosis Complexes and the Inflammasome to Drive the Pathogenesis of Endometriosis. Cell. 2015;163:960–974.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4640214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26544941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansen SO, Knudsen UB. Endometriosis, dysmenorrhoea and diet. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2013;169:162–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23642910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harada T, Momoeda M, Taketani Y, Hoshiai H, Terakawa N. Low-dose oral contraceptive pill for dysmenorrhea associated with endometriosis: a placebo-controlled, double-blind, randomized trial. Fertil Steril. 2008;90:1583–1588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healey M, Cheng C, Kaur H. To excise or ablate endometriosis? A prospective randomized double-blinded trial after 5-year follow-up. J Minim Invasive Gynecol. 2014;21:999–1004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24768960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herington JL, Crispens MA, Carvalho-Macedo AC, Camargos AF, Lebovic DI, Bruner-Tran KL, Osteen KG. Development and prevention of postsurgical adhesions in a chimeric mouse model of experimental endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2011;95:1295–1301 e1291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3038191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20934690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hickey M, Ballard K, Farquhar C. Endometriosis. BMJ. 2014;348:g1752.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24647161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu AL, Khachikyan I, Stratton P. Invasive and noninvasive methods for the diagnosis of endometriosis. Clin Obstet Gynecol. 2010;53:413–419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880548</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang HN, Lin MC, Huang WC, Chiang YC, Kuo KT. Loss of ARID1A expression and its relationship with PI3K-Akt pathway alterations and ZNF217 amplification in ovarian clear cell carcinoma. Mod Pathol. 2014;27:983–990.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24336158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hull ML, Johan MZ, Hodge WL, Robertson SA, Ingman WV. Host-derived TGFB1 deficiency suppresses lesion development in a mouse model of endometriosis. Am J Pathol. 2012;180:880–887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22210480</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ilad RS, Fleming SD, Murphy CR, Fazleabas AT. Immunohistochemical study of the ubiquitin-nuclear factor-kB pathway in the endometrium of the baboon (Papio anubis) with and without endometriosis. Reprod Fertil Dev. 2010;22:1118–1130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20797350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imai A, Matsunami K, Takagi H, Ichigo S. Levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine device used for dysmenorrhea: five-year literature review. Clin Exp Obstet Gynecol. 2014;41:495–498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25864246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juhasz-Boss I, Hofele A, Lattrich C, Buchholz S, Ortmann O, Malik E. Matrix metalloproteinase messenger RNA expression in human endometriosis grafts cultured on a chicken chorioallantoic membrane. Fertil Steril. 2010;94:40–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19345347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang YJ, Jeung IC, Park A, Park YJ, Jung H, Kim TD, Lee HG, Choi I, Yoon SR. An increased level of IL-6 suppresses NK cell activity in peritoneal fluid of patients with endometriosis via regulation of SHP-2 expression. Hum Reprod. 2014;29:2176–2189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25035432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keita M, AinMelk Y, Pelmus M, Bessette P, Aris A. Endometrioid ovarian cancer and endometriotic cells exhibit the same alteration in the expression of interleukin-1 receptor II: to a link between endometriosis and endometrioid ovarian cancer. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2011;37:99–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21083841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keita M, Bessette P, Pelmus M, Ainmelk Y, Aris A. Expression of interleukin-1 (IL-1) ligands system in the most common endometriosis-associated ovarian cancer subtypes. J Ovarian Res. 2010;3:3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2832771</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20181040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan KN, Kitajima M, Inoue T, Fujishita A, Nakashima M, Masuzaki H. 17beta-estradiol and lipopolysaccharide additively promote pelvic inflammation and growth of endometriosis. Reprod Sci. 2015;22:585–594.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4519769</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25355803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HS, Kim TH, Chung HH, Song YS. Risk and prognosis of ovarian cancer in women with endometriosis: a meta-analysis. Br J Cancer. 2014;110:1878–1890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3974076</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24518590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King C, Barbara C, Prentice A, Brenton J, Charnock-Jones D. Models of endometriosis and their utility in studying progression to ovarian clear cell carcinoma. J Pathol 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855629</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26456077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kinugasa S, Shinohara K, Wakatsuki A. Increased asymmetric dimethylarginine and enhanced inflammation are associated with impaired vascular reactivity in women with endometriosis. Atherosclerosis. 2011;219:784–788.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21880316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi H, Yamada Y, Kanayama S, Furukawa N, Noguchi T, Haruta S, Yoshida S, Sakata M, Sado T, Oi H. The role of hepatocyte nuclear factor-1beta in the pathogenesis of clear cell carcinoma of the ovary. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2009;19:471–479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19407577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondi-Pafiti A, Papakonstantinou E, Iavazzo C, Grigoriadis C, Salakos N, Gregoriou O. Clinicopathological characteristics of ovarian carcinomas associated with endometriosis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2012;285:479–483.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21717140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kong S, Zhang YH, Liu CF, Tsui I, Guo Y, Ai BB, Han FJ. The complementary and alternative medicine for endometriosis: a review of utilization and mechanism. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2014;2014:146383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3950373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24701237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kulak J, Jr, Fischer C, Komm B, Taylor HS. Treatment with bazedoxifene, a selective estrogen receptor modulator, causes regression of endometriosis in a mouse model. Endocrinology. 2011;152:3226–3232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3138238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21586552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar R, Clerc AC, Gori I, Russell R, Pellegrini C, Govender L, Wyss JC, Golshayan D, Canny GO. Lipoxin A(4) prevents the progression of de novo and established endometriosis in a mouse model by attenuating prostaglandin E(2) production and estrogen signaling. PLoS One. 2014;9:e89742.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3933674</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24587003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Munkarah A, Arabi H, Bandyopadhyay S, Semaan A, Hayek K, Garg G, Morris R, Ali-Fehmi R. Prognostic analysis of ovarian cancer associated with endometriosis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011;204:63 e61–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21074136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai CR, Hsu CY, Chen YJ, Yen MS, Chao KC, Li AF. Ovarian cancers arising from endometriosis: a microenvironmental biomarker study including ER, HNF1ss, p53, PTEN, BAF250a, and COX-2. J Chin Med Assoc. 2013;76:629–634.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23962610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebovic DI, Kavoussi SK, Lee J, Banu SK, Arosh JA. PPARgamma activation inhibits growth and survival of human endometriotic cells by suppressing estrogen biosynthesis and PGE2 signaling. Endocrinology. 2013;154:4803–4813.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5398600</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24064359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leconte M, Chouzenoux S, Nicco C, Chereau C, Arkwright S, Santulli P, Weill B, Chapron C, Dousset B, Batteux F. Role of the CXCL12-CXCR4 axis in the development of deep rectal endometriosis. J Reprod Immunol. 2014;103:45–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24534089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee AW, Templeman C, Stram DA, Beesley J, Tyrer J, Berchuck A, Pharoah PP, Chenevix-Trench G, Pearce CL Ovarian Cancer Association C. Evidence of a genetic link between endometriosis and ovarian cancer. Fertil Steril. 2016;105:35–43 e10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5068352</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee DH, Kim SC, Joo JK, Kim HG, Na YJ, Kwak JY, Lee KS. Effects of 17beta-estradiol on the release of monocyte chemotactic protein-1 and MAPK activity in monocytes stimulated with peritoneal fluid from endometriosis patients. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2012;38:516–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22381103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leone Roberti Maggiore U, Scala C, Remorgida V, Venturini PL, Del Deo F, Torella M, Colacurci N, Salvatore S, Ferrari S, Papaleo E, Candiani M, Ferrero S. Triptorelin for the treatment of endometriosis. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2014;15:1153–1179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin W, Chen S, Li M, Wang B, Qu X, Zhang Y. Expression of macrophage migration inhibitory factor in human endometriosis: relation to disease stage, menstrual cycle and infertility. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2010;36:344–351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20492386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lowery WJ, Schildkraut JM, Akushevich L, Bentley R, Marks JR, Huntsman D, Berchuck A. Loss of ARID1A-associated protein expression is a frequent event in clear cell and endometrioid ovarian cancers. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2012;22:9–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3263359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22193641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu Z, Zhang W, Jiang S, Zou J, Li Y. Effect of lesion location on endometriotic adhesion and angiogenesis in SCID mice. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2014a;289:823–830.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24150520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu Z, Zhang W, Jiang S, Zou J, Li Y. Effect of oxygen tensions on the proliferation and angiogenesis of endometriosis heterograft in severe combined immunodeficiency mice. Fertil Steril. 2014b;101:568–576.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24290003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luk J, Seval Y, Ulukus M, Ulukus EC, Arici A, Kayisli UA. Regulation of monocyte chemotactic protein-1 expression in human endometrial endothelial cells by sex steroids: a potential mechanism for leukocyte recruitment in endometriosis. Reprod Sci. 2010;17:278–287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maas J, Groothuis P, Dunselman G, de Goeij A, Struijker-Boudier H, Evers J. Development of endometriosis-like lesions after transplantation of human endometrial fragments onto the chick embryo chorioallantoic membrane. Hum Reprod. 2001;16:627–631.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11278208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machado DE, Berardo PT, Palmero CY, Nasciutti LE. Higher expression of vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) and its receptor VEGFR-2 (Flk-1) and metalloproteinase-9 (MMP-9) in a rat model of peritoneal endometriosis is similar to cancer diseases. J Exp Clin Cancer Res. 2010;29:4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2826344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20085636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machado DE, Palumbo A, Jr, Santos JM, Mattos RM, dos Santos TA, Seabra SH, Boldrini Lda C, Perini JA, Nasciutti LE. A GFP endometriosis model reveals important morphological characteristics of the angiogenic process that govern benign and malignant diseases. Histol Histopathol. 2014;29:903–912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24385307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malhotra N, Karmakar D, Tripathi V, Luthra K, Kumar S. Correlation of angiogenic cytokines-leptin and IL-8 in stage, type and presentation of endometriosis. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2012;28:224–227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21848410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margari KM, Zafiropoulos A, Hatzidaki E, Giannakopoulou C, Arici A, Matalliotakis I. Peritoneal fluid concentrations of beta-chemokines in endometriosis. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2013;169:103–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23474119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto T, Yamazaki M, Takahashi H, Kajita S, Suzuki E, Tsuruta T, Saegusa M. Distinct beta-catenin and PIK3CA mutation profiles in endometriosis-associated ovarian endometrioid and clear cell carcinomas. Am J Clin Pathol. 2015;144:452–463.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26276776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McConechy MK, Ding J, Senz J, Yang W, Melnyk N, Tone AA, Prentice LM, Wiegand KC, McAlpine JN, Shah SP, Lee CH, Goodfellow PJ, Gilks CB, Huntsman DG. Ovarian and endometrial endometrioid carcinomas have distinct CTNNB1 and PTEN mutation profiles. Mod Pathol. 2014;27:128–134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3915240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23765252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mier-Cabrera J, Jimenez-Zamudio L, Garcia-Latorre E, Cruz-Orozco O, Hernandez-Guerrero C. Quantitative and qualitative peritoneal immune profiles, T-cell apoptosis and oxidative stress-associated characteristics in women with minimal and mild endometriosis. BJOG. 2011;118:6–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21083865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewski L, Dziunycz P, Barcz E, Radomski D, Roszkowski PI, Korczak-Kowalska G, Kaminski P, Malejczyk J. Increased levels of human neutrophil peptides 1, 2, and 3 in peritoneal fluid of patients with endometriosis: association with neutrophils, T cells and IL-8. J Reprod Immunol. 2011;91:64–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21831449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monsivais D, Dyson MT, Yin P, Coon JS, Navarro A, Feng G, Malpani SS, Ono M, Ercan CM, Wei JJ, Pavone ME, Su E, Bulun SE. ERbeta- and prostaglandin E2-regulated pathways integrate cell proliferation via Ras-like and estrogen-regulated growth inhibitor in endometriosis. Mol Endocrinol. 2014;28:1304–1315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4116594</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24992181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munksgaard PS, Blaakaer J. The association between endometriosis and ovarian cancer: a review of histological, genetic and molecular alterations. Gynecol Oncol. 2012;124:164–169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22032835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munoz-Hernando L, Munoz-Gonzalez JL, Marqueta-Marques L, Alvarez-Conejo C, Tejerizo-Garcia A, Lopez-Gonzalez G, Villegas-Munoz E, Martin-Jimenez A, Jimenez-Lopez JS. Endometriosis: alternative methods of medical treatment. Int J Womens Health. 2015;7:595–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4468987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26089705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muzii L, Di Tucci C, Achilli C, Di Donato V, Musella A, Palaia I, Panici PB. Continuous versus cyclic oral contraceptives after laparoscopic excision of ovarian endometriomas: a systematic review and metaanalysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26364832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nap AW, Dunselman GA, de Goeij AF, Evers JL, Groothuis PG. Inhibiting MMP activity prevents the development of endometriosis in the chicken chorioallantoic membrane model. Hum Reprod. 2004;19:2180–2187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15242997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nap AW, Dunselman GA, Griffioen AW, Mayo KH, Evers JL, Groothuis PG. Angiostatic agents prevent the development of endometriosis-like lesions in the chicken chorioallantoic membrane. Fertil Steril. 2005;83:793–795.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15749522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naqvi H, Sakr S, Presti T, Krikun G, Komm B, Taylor HS. Treatment with bazedoxifene and conjugated estrogens results in regression of endometriosis in a murine model. Biol Reprod. 2014;90:121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4093999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24740602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ness RB. Endometriosis and ovarian cancer: thoughts on shared pathophysiology. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2003;189:280–294.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12861175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nezhat F, Datta MS, Hanson V, Pejovic T, Nezhat C, Nezhat C. The relationship of endometriosis and ovarian malignancy: a review. Fertil Steril. 2008;90:1559–1570.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18993168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novella-Maestre E, Herraiz S, Vila-Vives JM, Carda C, Ruiz-Sauri A, Pellicer A. Effect of antiangiogenic treatment on peritoneal endometriosis-associated nerve fibers. Fertil Steril. 2012;98:1209–1217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22921078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page-McCaw A, Ewald AJ, Werb Z. Matrix metalloproteinases and the regulation of tissue remodelling. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8:221–233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17318226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palmer SS, Altan M, Denis D, Tos EG, Gotteland JP, Osteen KG, Bruner-Tran KL, Nataraja SG. Bentamapimod (JNK Inhibitor AS602801) Induces Regression of Endometriotic Lesions in Animal Models. Reprod Sci 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5933194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26335175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearce CL, Templeman C, Rossing MA, Lee A, Near AM, Webb PM, Nagle CM, Doherty JA, Cushing-Haugen KL, Wicklund KG, Chang-Claude J, Hein R, Lurie G, Wilkens LR, Carney ME, Goodman MT, Moysich K, Kjaer SK, Hogdall E, Jensen A, Goode EL, Fridley BL, Larson MC, Schildkraut JM, Palmieri RT, Cramer DW, Terry KL, Vitonis AF, Titus LJ, Ziogas A, Brewster W, Anton-Culver H, Gentry-Maharaj A, Ramus SJ, Anderson AR, Brueggmann D, Fasching PA, Gayther SA, Huntsman DG, Menon U, Ness RB, Pike MC, Risch H, Wu AH, Berchuck A Ovarian Cancer Association C. Association between endometriosis and risk of histological subtypes of ovarian cancer: a pooled analysis of case-control studies. Lancet Oncol. 2012;13:385–394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3664011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22361336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellegrini C, Gori I, Achtari C, Hornung D, Chardonnens E, Wunder D, Fiche M, Canny GO. The expression of estrogen receptors as well as GREB1, c-MYC, and cyclin D1, estrogen-regulated genes implicated in proliferation, is increased in peritoneal endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 2012;98:1200–1208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22884659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Podgaec S, Rizzo LV, Fernandes LF, Baracat EC, Abrao MS. CD4(+) CD25(high) Foxp3(+) cells increased in the peritoneal fluid of patients with endometriosis. Am J Reprod Immunol. 2012;68:301–308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22817851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Posadzka E, Jach R, Pitynski K, Jablonski MJ. Treatment efficacy for pain complaints in women with endometriosis of the lesser pelvis after laparoscopic electroablation vs. CO2 laser ablation. Lasers Med Sci. 2015;30:147–152.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4289154</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25053520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Practice Committee of the American Society for Reproductive M. Treatment of pelvic pain associated with endometriosis: a committee opinion. Fertil Steril. 2014;101:927–935.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24630080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathore N, Kriplani A, Yadav RK, Jaiswal U, Netam R. Distinct peritoneal fluid ghrelin and leptin in infertile women with endometriosis and their correlation with interleukin-6 and vascular endothelial growth factor. Gynecol Endocrinol. 2014;30:671–675.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricci AG, Olivares CN, Bilotas MA, Meresman GF, Baranao RI. Effect of vascular endothelial growth factor inhibition on endometrial implant development in a murine model of endometriosis. Reprod Sci. 2011;18:614–622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossing MA, Cushing-Haugen KL, Wicklund KG, Doherty JA, Weiss NS. Risk of epithelial ovarian cancer in relation to benign ovarian conditions and ovarian surgery. Cancer Causes Control. 2008;19:1357–1364.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2751585</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18704718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubi-Klein K, Kucera-Sliutz E, Nissel H, Bijak M, Stockenhuber D, Fink M, Wolkenstein E. Is acupuncture in addition to conventional medicine effective as pain treatment for endometriosis? A randomised controlled cross-over trial. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2010;153:90–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20728977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz A, Salvo VA, Ruiz LA, Baez P, Garcia M, Flores I. Basal and steroid hormone-regulated expression of CXCR4 in human endometrium and endometriosis. Reprod Sci. 2010;17:894–903.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4495731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20720261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabbaghi M, Aram R, Roustaei H, Fadavi Islam M, Daneshvar M, Castano AR, Haghparast A. IL-17A concentration of seminal plasma and follicular fluid in infertile men and women with various clinical diagnoses. Immunol Invest. 2014;43:617–626.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24927491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samartzis EP, Samartzis N, Noske A, Fedier A, Caduff R, Dedes KJ, Fink D, Imesch P. Loss of ARID1A/BAF250a-expression in endometriosis: a biomarker for risk of carcinogenic transformation? Mod Pathol. 2012;25:885–892.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22301703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sampson J. Metastatic or Embolic Endometriosis, due to the Menstrual Dissemination of Endometrial Tissue into the Venous Circulation. Am J Pathol. 1927a;3:93–110.143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1931779</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19969738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sampson J. Peritoneal endometriosis due to the menstrual dissemination of endometrial tissue into the peritoneal cavity. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1927b;14:422–469.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1931779</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19969738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sampson JA. Endometrial carcinoma of the ovary, arising in endometrial tissue in that organ. Archives of Surgery. 1925;10:1–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santulli P, Borghese B, Chouzenoux S, Streuli I, Borderie D, de Ziegler D, Weill B, Chapron C, Batteux F. Interleukin-19 and interleukin-22 serum levels are decreased in patients with ovarian endometrioma. Fertil Steril. 2013;99:219–226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23025883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scarfone G, Bergamini A, Noli S, Villa A, Cipriani S, Taccagni G, Vigano P, Candiani M, Parazzini F, Mangili G. Characteristics of clear cell ovarian cancer arising from endometriosis: a two center cohort study. Gynecol Oncol. 2014;133:480–484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24642093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schorge JO, Modesitt SC, Coleman RL, Cohn DE, Kauff ND, Duska LR, Herzog TJ. SGO White Paper on ovarian cancer: etiology, screening and surveillance. Gynecol Oncol. 2010;119:7–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20692025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott R, Te Linde R, Wharton L. Further studies on experimental endometriosis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1953;66:1082–1103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13104506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott RB. Malignant changes in endometriosis. Obstet Gynecol. 1953;2:283–289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13087921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sikora J, Mielczarek-Palacz A, Kondera-Anasz Z. Imbalance in cytokines from interleukin-1 family - role in pathogenesis of endometriosis. Am J Reprod Immunol. 2012;68:138–145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22537218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sillem M, Hahn U, Coddington C, Gordon K, Runnebaum B, Hodgen G. Ectopic growth of endometrium depends on its structural integrity and proteolytic activity in the cynomolgus monkey (Macaca fascicularis) model of endometriosis. Fertil Steril. 1996;66:468–473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8751750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Somigliana E, Vigano P, Rossi G, Carinelli S, Vignali M, Panina-Bordignon P. Endometrial ability to implant in ectopic sites can be prevented by interleukin-12 in a murine model of endometriosis. Hum Reprod. 1999;14:2944–2950.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10601076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strowitzki T, Faustmann T, Gerlinger C, Schumacher U, Ahlers C, Seitz C. Safety and tolerability of dienogest in endometriosis: pooled analysis from the European clinical study program. Int J Womens Health. 2015;7:393–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4403681</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Styer AK, Sullivan BT, Puder M, Arsenault D, Petrozza JC, Serikawa T, Chang S, Hasan T, Gonzalez RR, Rueda BR. Ablation of leptin signaling disrupts the establishment, development, and maintenance of endometriosis-like lesions in a murine model. Endocrinology. 2008;149:506–514.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2219296</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suganuma I, Mori T, Ito F, Tanaka Y, Sasaki A, Matsuo S, Kusuki I, Kitawaki J. Peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor gamma, coactivator 1alpha enhances local estrogen biosynthesis by stimulating aromatase activity in endometriosis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014;99:E1191–1198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24654751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syrop CH, Halme J. Peritoneal fluid environment and infertility. Fertil Steril. 1987;48:1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3109960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szubert M, Suzin J, Duechler M, Szulawska A, Czyz M, Kowalczyk-Amico K. Evaluation of selected angiogenic and inflammatory markers in endometriosis before and after danazol treatment. Reprod Fertil Dev. 2014;26:414–420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23544741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanmahasamut P, Rattanachaiyanont M, Angsuwathana S, Techatraisak K, Indhavivadhana S, Leerasiri P. Postoperative levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine system for pelvic endometriosis-related pain: a randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2012;119:519–526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22314873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tao Y, Zhang Q, Huang W, Zhu H, Zhang D, Luo W. The peritoneal leptin, MCP-1 and TNF-alpha in the pathogenesis of endometriosis-associated infertility. Am J Reprod Immunol. 2011;65:403–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20825374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Te Linde R, Scott R. Experimental endometriosis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1950;60:1147–1173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14789879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tirado-Gonzalez I, Barrientos G, Tariverdian N, Arck P, Garcia M, Klapp B, Blois S. Endometriosis research: animal models for the study of a complex disease. J Reprod Immunol. 2010;86:141–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20594597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veillat V, Sengers V, Metz CN, Roger T, Leboeuf M, Mailloux J, Akoum A. Macrophage migration inhibitory factor is involved in a positive feedback loop increasing aromatase expression in endometriosis. Am J Pathol. 2012;181:917–927.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22759564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velasco I, Acien P, Campos A, Acien MI, Ruiz-Macia E. Interleukin-6 and other soluble factors in peritoneal fluid and endometriomas and their relation to pain and aromatase expression. J Reprod Immunol. 2010;84:199–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20074813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vernon M, Wilson E. Studies on the surgical induction of endometriosis in the rat. Fertil Steril. 1985;44:684–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4054348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virani S, Edwards AK, Thomas R, Childs T, Tayade C. Blocking of stromal cell-derived factor-1 reduces neoangiogenesis in human endometriosis lesions in a mouse model. Am J Reprod Immunol. 2013;70:386–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23650939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang XQ, Yu J, Luo XZ, Shi YL, Wang Y, Wang L, Li DJ. The high level of RANTES in the ectopic milieu recruits macrophages and induces their tolerance in progression of endometriosis. J Mol Endocrinol. 2010;45:291–299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20732991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei JJ, William J, Bulun S. Endometriosis and ovarian cancer: a review of clinical, pathologic, and molecular aspects. Int J Gynecol Pathol. 2011;30:553–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4130217</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21979592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng Q, Ding ZM, Lv XL, Yang DX, Song YZ, Wang FF, Ye YH, Qu F. Chinese medicinal plants for advanced endometriosis after conservative surgery: a prospective, multi-center and controlled trial. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2015;8:11307–11311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4565323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26379940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickiewicz D, Chrobak A, Gmyrek GB, Halbersztadt A, Gabrys MS, Goluda M, Chelmonska-Soyta A. Diagnostic accuracy of interleukin-6 levels in peritoneal fluid for detection of endometriosis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2013;288:805–814.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23553197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiegand KC, Lee AF, Al-Agha OM, Chow C, Kalloger SE, Scott DW, Steidl C, Wiseman SM, Gascoyne RD, Gilks B, Huntsman DG. Loss of BAF250a (ARID1A) is frequent in high-grade endometrial carcinomas. J Pathol. 2011;224:328–333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21590771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiegand KC, Shah SP, Al-Agha OM, Zhao Y, Tse K, Zeng T, Senz J, McConechy MK, Anglesio MS, Kalloger SE, Yang W, Heravi-Moussavi A, Giuliany R, Chow C, Fee J, Zayed A, Prentice L, Melnyk N, Turashvili G, Delaney AD, Madore J, Yip S, McPherson AW, Ha G, Bell L, Fereday S, Tam A, Galletta L, Tonin PN, Provencher D, Miller D, Jones SJ, Moore RA, Morin GB, Oloumi A, Boyd N, Aparicio SA, Shih Ie M, Mes-Masson AM, Bowtell DD, Hirst M, Gilks B, Marra MA, Huntsman DG. ARID1A mutations in endometriosis-associated ovarian carcinomas. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:1532–1543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2976679</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20942669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Worley MJ, Jr, Liu S, Hua Y, Kwok JS, Samuel A, Hou L, Shoni M, Lu S, Sandberg EM, Keryan A, Wu D, Ng SK, Kuo WP, Parra-Herran CE, Tsui SK, Welch W, Crum C, Berkowitz RS, Ng SW. Molecular changes in endometriosis-associated ovarian clear cell carcinoma. Eur J Cancer. 2015;51:1831–1842.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4532605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26059197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu MH, Lu CW, Chang FM, Tsai SJ. Estrogen receptor expression affected by hypoxia inducible factor-1alpha in stromal cells from patients with endometriosis. Taiwan J Obstet Gynecol. 2012;51:50–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22482968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu H, Becker CM, Lui WT, Chu CY, Davis TN, Kung AL, Birsner AE, D'Amato RJ, Wai Man GC, Wang CC. Green tea epigallocatechin-3-gallate inhibits angiogenesis and suppresses vascular endothelial growth factor C/vascular endothelial growth factor receptor 2 expression and signaling in experimental endometriosis in vivo. Fertil Steril. 2011;96:1021–1028.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21821246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu H, Zhang T, Man GC, May KE, Becker CM, Davis TN, Kung AL, Birsner AE, D'Amato RJ, Wong AW, Wang CC. Vascular endothelial growth factor C is increased in endometrium and promotes endothelial functions, vascular permeability and angiogenesis and growth of endometriosis. Angiogenesis. 2013;16:541–551.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23334337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Y, Zhang X, Zhou C, Huang X, Lin J, Xu H. Elevated immunoreactivity of RANTES and CCR1 correlate with the severity of stages and dysmenorrhea in women with deep infiltrating endometriosis. Acta Histochem. 2013;115:434–439.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23219091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeo SG, Won YS, Lee HY, Kim YI, Lee JW, Park DC. Increased expression of pattern recognition receptors and nitric oxide synthase in patients with endometriosis. Int J Med Sci. 2013;10:1199–1208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3739019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23935397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young VJ, Brown JK, Maybin J, Saunders PT, Duncan WC, Horne AW. Transforming growth factor-beta induced Warburg-like metabolic reprogramming may underpin the development of peritoneal endometriosis. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014a;99:3450–3459.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4207934</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24796928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young VJ, Brown JK, Saunders PT, Duncan WC, Horne AW. The peritoneum is both a source and target of TGF-beta in women with endometriosis. PLoS One. 2014b;9:e106773.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4160207</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25207642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamah N, Dodson M, Stephens L, Buttram V, Besch P, Kaufman R. Transplantation of normal and ectopic human endometrial tissue into athymic nude mice. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1984;149:591–597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6742039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zanetta GM, Webb MJ, Li H, Keeney GL. Hyperestrogenism: a relevant risk factor for the development of cancer from endometriosis. Gynecol Oncol. 2000;79:18–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11006024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Gong P, Chen Y, Nwachukwu JC, Srinivasan S, Ko C, Bagchi MK, Taylor RN, Korach KS, Nettles KW, Katzenellenbogen JA, Katzenellenbogen BS. Dual suppression of estrogenic and inflammatory activities for targeting of endometriosis. Sci Transl Med. 2015;7:271ra279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4790140</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25609169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zito G, Luppi S, Giolo E, Martinelli M, Venturin I, Di Lorenzo G, Ricci G. Medical treatments for endometriosis-associated pelvic pain. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:191967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4140197</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25165691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zondervan K, Weeks D, Colman R, Cardon L, Hadfield R, Schleffler J, Goudy Trainor A, Coe C, Kemnitz J, Kennedy S. Familial aggregation of endometriosis in a large pedigree of rhesus macaques. Hum Reprod. 2004;19:448–455.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zorbas KA, Economopoulos KP, Vlahos NF. Continuous versus cyclic oral contraceptives for the treatment of endometriosis: a systematic review. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2015;292:37–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25644508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
