<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">27336130</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK368476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>University of Washington, Seattle</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Seattle (WA)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="gene">GeneReviews<sup>®</sup></BookTitle><PubDate><Year>1993</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>1993</Year></BeginningDate><EndingDate><Year>2022</Year></EndingDate><AuthorList Type="editors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adam</LastName><ForeName>Margaret P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ardinger</LastName><ForeName>Holly H</ForeName><Initials>HH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagon</LastName><ForeName>Roberta A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bean</LastName><ForeName>Lora JH</ForeName><Initials>LJH</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirzaa</LastName><ForeName>Ghayda M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amemiya</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="gene" part="lms"><i>NOTCH3</i>-Related Lateral Meningocele Syndrome</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ejaz</LastName><ForeName>Resham</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Genetics Department of Pediatrics McMaster Children’s Hospital Hamilton, Ontario, Canada</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Carter</LastName><ForeName>Melissa</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Children’s Hospital of Eastern Ontario Ottawa, Canada</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gripp</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Alfred I DuPont Hospital for Children Wilmington, Delaware</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CHARACTERISTICS"><i>NOTCH3</i>-related lateral meningocele syndrome (LMS) is characterized by multiple lateral spinal meningoceles (protrusions of the arachnoid and dura through spinal foramina), distinctive facial features, joint hyperextensibility, hypotonia, and skeletal, cardiac, and urogenital anomalies. Neurologic sequelæ of the meningoceles depend on size and location and can include neurogenic bladder, paresthesia, back pain, and/or paraparesis. Other neurologic findings can include Chiari I malformation, syringomyelia, and rarely, hydrocephalus. Additional findings of LMS include developmental delay, mixed or conductive hearing loss, and cleft palate. Skeletal abnormalities may include scoliosis, vertebral fusion, scalloping of vertebrae, and wormian bones. Infants may demonstrate feeding difficulties with poor weight gain.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSIS/TESTING">The diagnosis of <i>NOTCH3</i>-related LMS syndrome is established in a proband with consistent clinical findings and a heterozygous pathogenic variant in <i>NOTCH3.</i></AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MANAGEMENT"><i>Treatment of manifestations:</i> Surgical intervention of lateral spinal meningoceles is generally avoided, but may be necessary due to neurologic manifestations secondary to meningocele size and location. Symptomatic treatment of neurologic sequelae of lateral meningoceles (neurogenic bladder, paresthesias, back pain, and/or paraparesis) provided as needed. As needed: timely supportive interventions to optimize development; management by specialists in chronic pain management or rehabilitation medicine; physiotherapy to reduce the risk for joint subluxation and dislocation. Routine management of: cleft palate, cardiovascular issues, genitourinary abnormalities, ophthalmologic issues, hearing loss, feeding difficulties. <i>Surveillance:</i> Close clinical and radiographic monitoring for progressive neurologic symptoms and increase in meningocele size; an initial yearly scan to monitor for stability and subsequent spacing to every two years if meningoceles are small in size. Ongoing monitoring by the appropriate subspecialists for developmental, musculoskeletal, cardiovascular, genitourinary, gastrointestinal, ophthalmologic, and/or hearing issues.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="GENETIC COUNSELING">All probands reported to date with <i>NOTCH3</i>-related LMS whose parents have undergone molecular genetic testing have the disorder as the result of a <i>de novo</i> <i>NOTCH3</i> pathogenic variant. Each child of an individual with <i>NOTCH3</i>-related LMS has a 50% chance of inheriting the pathogenic variant. Once the <i>NOTCH3</i> pathogenic variant has been identified in an affected family member, prenatal testing for a pregnancy at increased risk and preimplantation genetic testing for <i>NOTCH3</i>-related LMS are possible.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 1993-2022, University of Washington, Seattle. GeneReviews is a registered trademark of the University of Washington, Seattle. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Summary">Summary</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Diagnosis">Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Clinical_Characteristics">Clinical Characteristics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Genetically_Related_Allelic_Disorder">Genetically Related (Allelic) Disorders</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Differential_Diagnosis">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Management">Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Genetic_Counseling">Genetic Counseling</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Resources">Resources</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Molecular_Genetics">Molecular Genetics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.Chapter_Notes">Chapter Notes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="gene" part="lms" sec="lms.References">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lehman Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lehman Syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurogenic locus notch homolog protein 3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NOTCH3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NOTCH3-Related Lateral Meningocele Syndrome</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2016</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></ContributionDate><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></DateRevised><ItemList ListType="Synonyms"><Item>Lehman Syndrome</Item></ItemList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Avela K, Valanne L, Helenius I, Mäkitie O. Hajdu-Cheney syndrome with severe dural ectasia. Am J Med Genet A. 2011;155A:595–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21337686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biesecker L, Adam MP, Alkuraya FS, Amemiya AR, Bamshad MJ, Beck AE, Bennett JT, Bird LM, Carey JC, Chung B, Clark RD, Cox TC, Curry C, Dinulos MBP, Dobyns WB, Giampietro PF, Girisha KM, Glass IA, Graham JM, Jr, Gripp KW, Haldeman-Englert CR, Hall BD, Innes AM, Kalish JM, Keppler-Noreuil KM, Kosaki K, Kozel BA, Mirzaa GM, Mulvihill JJ, Nowaczyk MJM, Pagon RA, Retterer K, Rope AF, Sanchez-Lara PA, Seaver LH, Shieh JT, Slavotinek AM, Sobering AK, Stevens CA, Stevenson DA, Tan TY, Tan WH, Tsai AC, Weaver DD, Williams MS, Zackai E, Zarate YA. A dyadic approach to the delineation of diagnostic entities in clinical genomics. Am J Hum Genet. 2021;108:8–15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7820621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown EC, Gupta K, Cantab M, Sayama C. Neurosurgical management in lateral meningocele syndrome: case report. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2017;19:232–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27911244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canalis E. The skeleton of lateral meningocele syndrome. Front Genet. 2021;11:620334. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7841456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cappuccio G, Apuzzo D, Alagia M, Torella A, Pinelli M, Franco B, Corrado B, Del Giudice E, D'Amico A, Nigro V, Brunetti-Pierri N, et al.  Expansion of the phenotype of lateral meningocele syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2020;182:1259–62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32141180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuoco JA, Klein BJ, Busch CM, Gosnell HL, Kar A, Marvin EA, Apfel LS. Neurosurgical management of lateral meningocele syndrome: a clinical update for the pediatric neurosurgeon. Pediatr Neurosurg. 2020;55:2–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31838470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ejaz R, Qin W, Huang L, Blaser S, Tetreault M, Hartley T, Boycott KM, Carter MT, et al.  Lateral meningocele (Lehman) syndrome: A child with a novel NOTCH3 mutation. Am J Med Genet A. 2016;170A:1070–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26754023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gripp KW. Lateral meningocele syndrome and Hajdu-Cheney syndrome: different disorders with overlapping phenotypes. Am J Med Genet. 2011;155A:1773–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21671395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gripp KW, Robbins KM, Sobreira NL, Witmer PD, Bird LM, Avela K, Makitie O, Alves D, Hogue JS, Zackai EH, Doheny KF, Stabley DL, Sol-Church K. Truncating mutations in the last exon of NOTCH3 cause lateral meningocele syndrome. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2015;167A:271–81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5589071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25394726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Chen M, Wang H. Management of lateral meningocele syndrome in a child without neurological symptoms and literature review. Childs Nerv Syst. 2022 Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35128567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehman RA, Stears JC, Wesenberg RL, Nusbaum ED. Familial osteosclerosis with abnormalities of the nervous system and meninges. J Pediatr. 1977;90:49–54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">830893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philip N, Andrac L, Moncla A, Sigaudy S, Zanon N, Lena G, Choux M. Multiple lateral meningoceles, distinctive facies and skeletal anomalies: a new case of Lehman syndrome. Clin Dysmorphol. 1995;4:347–51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8574426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahbari R, Wuster A, Lindsay SJ, Hardwick RJ, Alexandrov LB, Turki SA, Dominiczak A, Morris A, Porteous D, Smith B, Stratton MR, Hurles ME, et al.  Timing, rates and spectra of human germline mutation. Nat Genet. 2016;48:126–33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26656846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda K, Honda O, Satoh Y, Kawai M, Gyobu T, Kanazawa T, Hidaka S, Yanagawa M, Sumikawa H, Tomiyama N. Computed tomography (CT) findings in 88 neurofibromatosis 1 (NF1) patients: Prevalence rates and correlations of thoracic findings. Eur J Radiol. 2015;84:1191–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25802206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Zhang Q, Li D, Ching K, Zhang C, Zheng X, Ozeck M, Shi S, Li X, Wang H, Reito P, Christensen J, Olson P. PEST domain mutations in Notch receptors comprise an oncogenic driver segment in triple-negative breast cancer sensitive to γ-secretase inhibitor. Clin Cancer Res. 2015;21:1487–96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25564152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada M, Arimitsu T, Suzuki H, Miwa T, Kosaki K. Early diagnosis of lateral meningocele syndrome in an infant without neurological symptoms based on genomic analysis. Childs Nerv Syst. 2022;38:659–63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27336130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
