<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27445678</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1662-4548</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2016</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Frontiers in neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Pediatric Autoimmune Disorders Associated with Streptococcal Infections and Tourette's Syndrome in Preclinical Studies.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>310</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>310</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">310</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fnins.2016.00310</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Accumulating evidence suggests that Tourette's Syndrome (TS) - a multifactorial pediatric disorder characterized by the recurrent exhibition of motor tics and/or vocal utterances - can partly depend on immune dysregulation provoked by early repeated streptococcal infections. The natural and adaptive antibody-mediated reaction to streptococcus has been proposed to potentially turn into a pathological autoimmune response in vulnerable individuals. Specifically, in conditions of increased permeability of the blood brain barrier (BBB), streptococcus-induced antibodies have been proposed to: (i) reach neuronal targets located in brain areas responsible for motion control; and (ii) contribute to the exhibition of symptoms. This theoretical framework is supported by indirect evidence indicating that a subset of TS patients exhibit elevated streptococcal antibody titers upon tic relapses. A systematic evaluation of this hypothesis entails preclinical studies providing a proof of concept of the aforementioned pathological sequelae. These studies shall rest upon individuals characterized by a vulnerable immune system, repeatedly exposed to streptococcus, and carefully screened for phenotypes isomorphic to the pathological signs of TS observed in patients. Preclinical animal models may thus constitute an informative, useful tool upon which conducting targeted, hypothesis-driven experiments. In the present review we discuss the available evidence in preclinical models in support of the link between TS and pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcus infections (PANDAS), and the existing gaps that future research shall bridge. Specifically, we report recent preclinical evidence indicating that the immune responses to repeated streptococcal immunizations relate to the occurrence of behavioral and neurological phenotypes reminiscent of TS. By the same token, we discuss the limitations of these studies: limited evidence of behavioral phenotypes isomorphic to tics and scarce knowledge about the immunological phenomena favoring the transition from natural adaptive immunity to pathological outcomes.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spinello</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chiara</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Behavioural Neuroscience, Department of Cell Biology and Neuroscience, Istituto Superiore di Sanità Roma, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Laviola</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giovanni</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Behavioural Neuroscience, Department of Cell Biology and Neuroscience, Istituto Superiore di Sanità Roma, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Macrì</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simone</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Behavioural Neuroscience, Department of Cell Biology and Neuroscience, Istituto Superiore di Sanità Roma, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Front Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101478481</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1662-453X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PANDAS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tourette's Syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">animal models</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmunity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">group A–beta hemolytic streptococcus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445678</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4928151</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2016.00310</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abelson J. F., Kwan K. Y., O'Roak B. J., Baek D. Y., Stillman A. A., Morgan T. M., et al. . (2005). Sequence variants in SLITRK1 are associated with Tourette's syndrome. Science
310, 317–320. 10.1126/science.1116502</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1116502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16224024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acharjee S., Nayani N., Tsutsui M., Hill M. N., Ousman S. S., Pittman Q. J. (2013). Altered cognitive-emotional behavior in early experimental autoimmune encephalitis–cytokine and hormonal correlates. Brain Behav. Immun.
33, 164–172. 10.1016/j.bbi.2013.07.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2013.07.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23886782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adriani W., Koot S., Columba-Cabezas S., Romano E., Travaglini D., van den Bos R., et al. . (2012). Immunization with DAT fragments is associated with long-term striatal impairment, hyperactivity and reduced cognitive flexibility in mice. Behav. Brain Funct.
8:54. 10.1186/1744-9081-8-54</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1744-9081-8-54</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3537576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmari S. E., Risbrough V. B., Geyer M. A., Simpson H. B. (2012). Impaired sensorimotor gating in unmedicated adults with obsessive-compulsive disorder. Neuropsychopharmacology
37, 1216–1223. 10.1038/npp.2011.308</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2011.308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3306882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22218093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almutairi M. M., Gong C., Xu Y. G., Chang Y., Shi H. (2016). Factors controlling permeability of the blood-brain barrier. Cell. Mol. Life Sci.
73, 57–77. 10.1007/s00018-015-2050-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-015-2050-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26403789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amor S., Baker D., Groome N., Turk J. L. (1993). Identification of a major encephalitogenic epitope of proteolipid protein (residues 56–70) for the induction of experimental allergic encephalomyelitis in Biozzi AB/H and nonobese diabetic mice. J. Immunol.
150, 5666–5672. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7685799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amor S., Groome N., Linington C., Morris M. M., Dornmair K., Gardinier M. V., et al. . (1994). Identification of epitopes of myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein for the induction of experimental allergic encephalomyelitis in SJL and Biozzi AB/H mice. J. Immunol.
153, 4349–4356. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7525700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amor S., O'Neill J. K., Morris M. M., Smith R. M., Wraith D. C., Groome N., et al. . (1996). Encephalitogenic epitopes of myelin basic protein, proteolipid protein, myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein for experimental allergic encephalomyelitis induction in Biozzi ABH (H-2Ag7) mice share an amino acid motif. J. Immunol.
156, 3000–3008. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8609422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>APA  (2013). Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders. Arlington, VA: American Psychiatric Association.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aruga J., Mikoshiba K. (2003). Identification and characterization of Slitrk, a novel neuronal transmembrane protein family controlling neurite outgrowth. Mol. Cell. Neurosci.
24, 117–129. 10.1016/S1044-7431(03)00129-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1044-7431(03)00129-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14550773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asano N. M., Coriolano M., Asano B. J., Lins O. G. (2013). Psychiatric comorbidities in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a systematic review of the last 10 years. Rev. Bras. Reumatol.
53, 431–437. 10.1016/S2255-5021(13)70114-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2255-5021(13)70114-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24316900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakker J. M., Kavelaars A., Kamphuis P. J., Cobelens P. M., van Vugt H. H., van Bel F., et al. . (2000). Neonatal dexamethasone treatment increases susceptibility to experimental autoimmune disease in adult rats. J. Immunol.
165, 5932–5937. 10.4049/jimmunol.165.10.5932</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.165.10.5932</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11067955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baldan Ramsey L. C., Xu M., Wood N., Pittenger C. (2011). Lesions of the dorsomedial striatum disrupt prepulse inhibition. Neuroscience
180, 222–228. 10.1016/j.neuroscience.2011.01.041</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2011.01.041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3070827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21315809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beck L. H., Jr., Bonegio R. G., Lambeau G., Beck D. M., Powell D. W., Cummins T. D., et al. . (2009). M-type phospholipase A2 receptor as target antigen in idiopathic membranous nephropathy. N. Engl. J. Med.
361, 11–21. 10.1056/NEJMoa0810457</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0810457</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19571279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benedek G., Zhang J., Bodhankar S., Nguyen H., Kent G., Jordan K., et al. . (2016). Estrogen induces multiple regulatory B cell subtypes and promotes M2 microglia and neuroprotection during experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. J. Neuroimmunol.
293, 45–53. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2016.02.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2016.02.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4824954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27049561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Pazi H., Sadan O., Offen D. (2012). Striatal microinjection of Sydenham chorea antibodies: using a rat model to examine the dopamine hypothesis. J. Mol. Neurosci.
46, 162–166. 10.1007/s12031-011-9559-6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12031-011-9559-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berardelli A., Currà A., Fabbrini G., Gilio F., Manfredi M. (2003). Pathophysiology of tics and Tourette syndrome. J. Neurol.
250, 781–787. 10.1007/s00415-003-1102-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-003-1102-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12883917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bizzaro N., Tonutti E., Visentini D., Alessio M. G., Platzgummer S., Morozzi G., et al. . (2007). Antibodies to the lens and cornea in anti-DFS70-positive subjects. Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci.
1107, 174–183. 10.1196/annals.1381.019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1196/annals.1381.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17804545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boghosian-Sell L., Comings D. E., Overhauser J. (1996). Tourette syndrome in a pedigree with a 7;18 translocation: identification of a YAC spanning the translocation breakpoint at 18q22.3. Am. J. Hum. Genet.
59, 999–1005. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1914824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8900226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borchers A. T., Aoki C. A., Naguwa S. M., Keen C. L., Shoenfeld Y., Gershwin M. E. (2005). Neuropsychiatric features of systemic lupus erythematosus. Autoimmun. Rev.
4, 329–344. 10.1016/j.autrev.2005.01.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2005.01.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bornstein R. A., Stefl M. E., Hammond L. (1990). A survey of Tourette syndrome patients and their families: the 1987 Ohio Tourette Survey. J. Neuropsychiatry Clin. Neurosci.
2, 275–281. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2136086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bos-Veneman N. G., Olieman R., Tobiasova Z., Hoekstra P. J., Katsovich L., Bothwell A. L., et al. . (2011). Altered immunoglobulin profiles in children with Tourette syndrome. Brain Behav. Immun.
25, 532–538. 10.1016/j.bbi.2010.12.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2010.12.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21156204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brilot F., Merheb V., Ding A., Murphy T., Dale R. C. (2011). Antibody binding to neuronal surface in Sydenham chorea, but not in PANDAS or Tourette syndrome. Neurology
76, 1508–1513. 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182181090</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182181090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3087465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21411742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brimberg L., Benhar I., Mascaro-Blanco A., Alvarez K., Lotan D., Winter C., et al. . (2012). Behavioral, pharmacological, and immunological abnormalities after streptococcal exposure: a novel rat model of Sydenham chorea and related neuropsychiatric disorders. Neuropsychopharmacology
37, 2076–2087. 10.1038/npp.2012.56</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2012.56</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3398718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22534626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronson S. L., Bale T. L. (2016). The Placenta as a mediator of stress effects on neurodevelopmental reprogramming. Neuropsychopharmacology
41, 207–218. 10.1038/npp.2015.231</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2015.231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4677129</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26250599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cagnin A., Kassiou M., Meikle S. R., Banati R. B. (2007). Positron emission tomography imaging of neuroinflammation. Neurotherapeutics
4, 443–452. 10.1016/j.nurt.2007.04.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nurt.2007.04.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7479716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17599710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Capone F., Adriani W., Shumilina M., Izykenova G., Granstrem O., Dambinova S., et al. . (2008). Autoantibodies against opioid or glutamate receptors are associated with changes in morphine reward and physical dependence in mice. Psychopharmacology
197, 535–548. 10.1007/s00213-007-1062-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-007-1062-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18265961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona F., Orefici G. (2001). Group A streptococcal infections and tic disorders in an Italian pediatric population. J. Pediatr.
138, 71–75. 10.1067/mpd.2001.110325</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mpd.2001.110325</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso F., Vargas A. P., Oliveira L. D., Guerra A. A., Amaral S. V. (1999). Persistent Sydenham's chorea. Mov. Disord.
14, 805–807. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10495042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castellan Baldan L., Williams K. A., Gallezot J. D., Pogorelov V., Rapanelli M., Crowley M., et al. . (2014). Histidine decarboxylase deficiency causes tourette syndrome: parallel findings in humans and mice. Neuron
81, 77–90. 10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.052</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2013.10.052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894588</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24411733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castellanos F. X., Fine E. J., Kaysen D., Marsh W. L., Rapoport J. L., Hallett M. (1996). Sensorimotor gating in boys with Tourette's syndrome and ADHD: preliminary results. Biol. Psychiatry
39, 33–41. 10.1016/0006-3223(95)00101-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-3223(95)00101-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8719124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cieza A., Anczewska M., Ayuso-Mateos J. L., Baker M., Bickenbach J., Chatterji S., et al. . (2015). Understanding the impact of brain disorders: towards a ‘horizontal epidemiology’ of psychosocial difficulties and their determinants. PLoS ONE
10:e0136271. 10.1371/journal.pone.0136271</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0136271</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564202</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26352911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coenen M., Cabello M., Umlauf S., Ayuso-Mateos J. L., Anczewska M., Tourunen J., et al. . (2016). Psychosocial difficulties from the perspective of persons with neuropsychiatric disorders. Disabil. Rehabil. 38, 1134–1145. 10.3109/09638288.2015.1074729</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09638288.2015.1074729</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26289372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Comabella M., Montalban X. (2014). Body fluid biomarkers in multiple sclerosis. Lancet Neurol.
13, 113–126. 10.1016/S1474-4422(13)70233-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(13)70233-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24331797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Correale J. (2014). The role of microglial activation in disease progression. Mult. Scler.
20, 1288–1295. 10.1177/1352458514533230</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458514533230</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24812046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cutforth T., DeMille M. M., Agalliu I., Agalliu D. (2016). CNS autoimmune disease after infections: animal models, cellular mechanisms and genetic factors. Future Neurol.
11, 63–76. 10.2217/fnl.16.4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fnl.16.4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27110222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale R. C., Church A. J., Candler P. M., Chapman M., Martino D., Giovannoni G. (2006). Serum autoantibodies do not differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. Neurology
66:1612. 10.1212/01.wnl.0000226832.36908.4c</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000226832.36908.4c</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalsgaard S., Waltoft B. L., Leckman J. F., Mortensen P. B. (2015). Maternal history of autoimmune disease and later development of tourette syndrome in offspring. J. Am. Acad. Child Adolesc. Psychiatry
54, 495–501.e1. 10.1016/j.jaac.2015.03.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2015.03.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26004665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Damoiseaux J., Andrade L. E., Fritzler M. J., Shoenfeld Y. (2015). Autoantibodies 2015: from diagnostic biomarkers toward prediction, prognosis and prevention. Autoimmun. Rev.
14, 555–563. 10.1016/j.autrev.2015.01.017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2015.01.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25661979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davison K. (2012). Autoimmunity in psychiatry. Br. J. Psychiatry
200, 353–355. 10.1192/bjp.bp.111.104471</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.111.104471</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22550326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deacon R. M., Rawlins J. N. (2006). T-maze alternation in the rodent. Nat. Protoc.
1, 7–12. 10.1038/nprot.2006.2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nprot.2006.2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17406205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng H., Gao K., Jankovic J. (2012). The genetics of Tourette syndrome. Nat. Rev. Neurol.
8, 203–213. 10.1038/nrneurol.2012.26</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2012.26</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22410579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dileepan T., Linehan J. L., Moon J. J., Pepper M., Jenkins M. K., Cleary P. P. (2011). Robust antigen specific th17 T cell response to group A Streptococcus is dependent on IL-6 and intranasal route of infection. PLoS Pathog.
7:e1002252. 10.1371/journal.ppat.1002252</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1002252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3178561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21966268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dileepan T., Smith E. D., Knowland D., Hsu M., Platt M., Bittner-Eddy P., et al. . (2016). Group A Streptococcus intranasal infection promotes CNS infiltration by streptococcal-specific Th17 cells. J. Clin. Invest.
126, 303–317. 10.1172/JCI80792</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI80792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4701547</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26657857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebrahimi A., Pochet R., Roger M. (1992). Topographical organization of the projections from physiologically identified areas of the motor cortex to the striatum in the rat. Neurosci. Res.
14, 39–60. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1380687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ercan-Sencicek A. G., Stillman A. A., Ghosh A. K., Bilguvar K., O'Roak B. J., Mason C. E., et al. . (2010). L-histidine decarboxylase and Tourette's syndrome. N. Engl. J. Med.
362, 1901–1908. 10.1056/NEJMoa0907006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0907006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2894694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20445167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fanouriakis A., Boumpas D. T., Bertsias G. K. (2013). Pathogenesis and treatment of CNS lupus. Curr. Opin. Rheumatol.
25, 577–583. 10.1097/BOR.0b013e328363eaf1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0b013e328363eaf1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23836074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez T. V., Sanders S. J., Yurkiewicz I. R., Ercan-Sencicek A. G., Kim Y. S., Fishman D. O., et al. . (2012). Rare copy number variants in tourette syndrome disrupt genes in histaminergic pathways and overlap with autism. Biol. Psychiatry
71, 392–402. 10.1016/j.biopsych.2011.09.034</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2011.09.034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3282144</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22169095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganor Y., Freilinger M., Dulac O., Levite M. (2005a). Monozygotic twins discordant for epilepsy differ in the levels of potentially pathogenic autoantibodies and cytokines. Autoimmunity
38, 139–150. 10.1080/08916930500100825</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08916930500100825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16040334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganor Y., Goldberg-Stern H., Amrom D., Lerman-Sagie T., Teichberg V. I., Pelled D., et al. . (2004). Autoimmune epilepsy: some epilepsy patients harbor autoantibodies to glutamate receptors and dsDNA on both sides of the blood-brain barrier, which may kill neurons and decrease in brain fluids after hemispherotomy. Clin. Dev. Immunol.
11, 241–252. 10.1080/17402520400001736</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17402520400001736</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2486323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15559370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganor Y., Goldberg-Stern H., Blank M., Shoenfeld Y., Dobrynina L. A., Kalashnikova L., et al. . (2005c). Antibodies to glutamate receptor subtype 3 (GluR3) are found in some patients suffering from epilepsy as the main disease, but not in patients whose epilepsy accompanies antiphospholipid syndrome or Sneddon's syndrome. Autoimmunity
38, 417–424. 10.1080/08916930500246339</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08916930500246339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16278146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganor Y., Goldberg-Stern H., Cohen R., Teichberg V., Levite M. (2014). Glutamate receptor antibodies directed against AMPA receptors subunit 3 peptide B (GluR3B) can be produced in DBA/2J mice, lower seizure threshold and induce abnormal behavior. Psychoneuroendocrinology
42, 106–117. 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.01.005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2014.01.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24636507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganor Y., Goldberg-Stern H., Lerman-Sagie T., Teichberg V. I., Levite M. (2005b). Autoimmune epilepsy: distinct subpopulations of epilepsy patients harbor serum autoantibodies to either glutamate/AMPA receptor GluR3, glutamate/NMDA receptor subunit NR2A or double-stranded DNA. Epilepsy Res.
65, 11–22. 10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2005.03.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2005.03.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15978777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giana G., Romano E., Porfirio M. C., D'Ambrosio R., Giovinazzo S., Troianiello M., et al. . (2015). Detection of auto-antibodies to DAT in the serum: interactions with DAT genotype and psycho-stimulant therapy for ADHD. J. Neuroimmunol.
278, 212–222. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2014.11.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2014.11.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25468771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldberg-Stern H., Ganor Y., Cohen R., Pollak L., Teichberg V., Levite M. (2014). Glutamate receptor antibodies directed against AMPA receptors subunit 3 peptide B (GluR3B) associate with some cognitive/psychiatric/behavioral abnormalities in epilepsy patients. Psychoneuroendocrinology
40, 221–231. 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2013.11.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2013.11.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haas H. L., Sergeeva O. A., Selbach O. (2008). Histamine in the nervous system. Physiol. Rev.
88, 1183–1241. 10.1152/physrev.00043.2007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00043.2007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18626069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hachiya Y., Miyata R., Tanuma N., Hongou K., Tanaka K., Shimoda K., et al. . (2013). Autoimmune neurological disorders associated with group-A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection. Brain Dev.
35, 670–674. 10.1016/j.braindev.2012.10.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.braindev.2012.10.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23142103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallett J. J., Harling-Berg C. J., Knopf P. M., Stopa E. G., Kiessling L. S. (2000). Anti-striatal antibodies in Tourette syndrome cause neuronal dysfunction. J. Neuroimmunol.
111, 195–202. 10.1016/S0165-5728(00)00320-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0165-5728(00)00320-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11063838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harel M., Shoenfeld Y. (2006). Predicting and preventing autoimmunity, myth or reality?
Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci.
1069, 322–345. 10.1196/annals.1351.031</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1196/annals.1351.031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartley S., McArthur M., Coenen M., Cabello M., Covelli V., Roszczynska-Michta J., et al. . (2014). Narratives reflecting the lived experiences of people with brain disorders: common psychosocial difficulties and determinants. PLoS ONE
9:e96890. 10.1371/journal.pone.0096890</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0096890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4013080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24805128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heim C., Newport D. J., Mletzko T., Miller A. H., Nemeroff C. B. (2008). The link between childhood trauma and depression: insights from HPA axis studies in humans. Psychoneuroendocrinology
33, 693–710. 10.1016/j.psyneuen.2008.03.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psyneuen.2008.03.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18602762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heim C., Plotsky P. M., Nemeroff C. B. (2004). Importance of studying the contributions of early adverse experience to neurobiological findings in depression. Neuropsychopharmacology
29, 641–648. 10.1038/sj.npp.1300397</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.npp.1300397</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra P. J., Dietrich A., Edwards M. J., Elamin I., Martino D. (2013). Environmental factors in Tourette syndrome. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.
37, 1040–1049. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.10.010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.10.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23092654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoenig K., Hochrein A., Quednow B. B., Maier W., Wagner M. (2005). Impaired prepulse inhibition of acoustic startle in obsessive-compulsive disorder. Biol. Psychiatry
57, 1153–1158. 10.1016/j.biopsych.2005.01.040</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2005.01.040</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15866555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman K. L., Hornig M., Yaddanapudi K., Jabado O., Lipkin W. I. (2004). A murine model for neuropsychiatric disorders associated with group A beta-hemolytic streptococcal infection. J. Neurosci.
24, 1780–1791. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0887-03.2004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0887-03.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6730451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14973249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Höftberger R. (2015). Neuroimmunology: an expanding frontier in autoimmunity. Front. Immunol.
6:206. 10.3389/fimmu.2015.00206</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2015.00206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4413830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25972873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hornig M. (2013). The role of microbes and autoimmunity in the pathogenesis of neuropsychiatric illness. Curr. Opin. Rheumatol.
25, 488–795. 10.1097/BOR.0b013e32836208de</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0b013e32836208de</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23656715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hornig M., Lipkin W. I. (2013). Immune-mediated animal models of Tourette syndrome. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.
37, 1120–1138. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2013.01.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2013.01.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4054816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23313649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huerta P. T., Kowal C., DeGiorgio L. A., Volpe B. T., Diamond B. (2006). Immunity and behavior: antibodies alter emotion. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A.
103, 678–683. 10.1073/pnas.0510055103</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0510055103</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1334673</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16407105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huppert J., Closhen D., Croxford A., White R., Kulig P., Pietrowski E., et al. . (2010). Cellular mechanisms of IL-17-induced blood-brain barrier disruption. FASEB J.
24, 1023–1034. 10.1096/fj.09-141978</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.09-141978</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19940258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyman S. E. (2008). A glimmer of light for neuropsychiatric disorders. Nature
455, 890–893. 10.1038/nature07454</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature07454</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18923510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irani S. R., Gelfand J. M., Al-Diwani A., Vincent A. (2014). Cell-surface central nervous system autoantibodies: clinical relevance and emerging paradigms. Ann. Neurol.
76, 168–184. 10.1002/ana.24200</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24930434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irwin J., Tombaugh T. N., Zacharko R. M., Anisman H. (1983). Alteration of exploration and the response to food associated cues after treatment with pimozide. Pharmacol. Biochem. Behav.
18, 235–246. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6835981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs J. F., van der Molen R. G., Bossuyt X., Damoiseaux J. (2015). Antigen excess in modern immunoassays: to anticipate on the unexpected. Autoimmun. Rev.
14, 160–167. 10.1016/j.autrev.2014.10.018</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2014.10.018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaffard R., Mocaer E., Poignant J. C., Micheau J., Marighetto A., Meunier M., et al. . (1991). Effects of tianeptine on spontaneous alternation, simple and concurrent spatial discrimination learning and on alcohol-induced alternation deficits in mice. Behav. Pharmacol.
2, 37–46. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11224046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>John C. C., Carabin H., Montano S. M., Bangirana P., Zunt J. R., Peterson P. K. (2015). Global research priorities for infections that affect the nervous system. Nature
527, S178–S186. 10.1038/nature16033</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature16033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4697933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kajiwara Y., Buxbaum J. D., Grice D. E. (2009). SLITRK1 binds 14-3-3 and regulates neurite outgrowth in a phosphorylation-dependent manner. Biol. Psychiatry
66, 918–925. 10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.05.033</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2009.05.033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19640509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaltwasser M. T. (1990). Acoustic signaling in the black rat (Rattus rattus). J. Comp. Psychol.
104, 227–232. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2225759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalueff A. V., Stewart A. M., Song C., Berridge K. C., Graybiel A. M., Fentress J. C. (2016). Neurobiology of rodent self-grooming and its value for translational neuroscience. Nat. Rev. Neurosci.
17, 45–59. 10.1038/nrn.2015.8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn.2015.8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4840777</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katayama K., Yamada K., Ornthanalai V. G., Inoue T., Ota M., Murphy N. P., et al. . (2010). Slitrk1-deficient mice display elevated anxiety-like behavior and noradrenergic abnormalities. Mol. Psychiatry
15, 177–184. 10.1038/mp.2008.97</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2008.97</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18794888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawikova I., Leckman J. F., Kronig H., Katsovich L., Bessen D. E., Ghebremichael M., et al. . (2007). Decreased numbers of regulatory T cells suggest impaired immune tolerance in children with tourette syndrome: a preliminary study. Biol. Psychiatry
61, 273–278. 10.1016/j.biopsych.2006.06.012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2006.06.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kebir H., Kreymborg K., Ifergan I., Dodelet-Devillers A., Cayrol R., Bernard M., et al. . (2007). Human TH17 lymphocytes promote blood-brain barrier disruption and central nervous system inflammation. Nat. Med.
13, 1173–1175. 10.1038/nm1651</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5114125</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17828272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kipp M., van der Star B., Vogel D. Y., Puentes F., van der Valk P., Baker D., et al. . (2012). Experimental in vivo and in vitro models of multiple sclerosis: EAE and beyond. Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord.
1, 15–28. 10.1016/j.msard.2011.09.002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2011.09.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25876447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korngold R., Feldman A., Rorke L. B., Lublin F. D., Doherty P. C. (1986). Acute experimental allergic encephalomyelitis in radiation bone marrow chimeras between high and low susceptible strains of mice. Immunogenetics
24, 309–315. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3781573</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kowal C., Diamond B. (2012). Aspects of CNS lupus: mouse models of anti-NMDA receptor antibody mediated reactivity. Methods Mol. Biol.
900, 181–206. 10.1007/978-1-60761-720-4_9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-60761-720-4_9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22933070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kowal C., DeGiorgio L. A., Nakaoka T., Hetherington H., Huerta P. T., Diamond B., et al. . (2004). Cognition and immunity; antibody impairs memory. Immunity
21, 179–188. 10.1016/j.immuni.2004.07.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2004.07.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15308099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreutzberg G. W. (1996). Microglia: a sensor for pathological events in the CNS. Trends Neurosci.
19, 312–318. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8843599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A., Williams M. T., Chugani H. T. (2015). Evaluation of basal ganglia and thalamic inflammation in children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection and tourette syndrome: a positron emission tomographic (PET) study using 11C-[R]-PK11195. J. Child Neurol.
30, 749–756. 10.1177/0883073814543303</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073814543303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25117419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laban O., Dimitrijevic M., von Hoersten S., Markovic B. M., Jankovic B. D. (1995). Experimental allergic encephalomyelitis in adult DA rats subjected to neonatal handling or gentling. Brain Res.
676, 133–140. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7540932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lalonde R. (2002). The neurobiological basis of spontaneous alternation. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.
26, 91–104. 10.1016/S0149-7634(01)00041-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0149-7634(01)00041-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11835987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landau Y. E., Steinberg T., Richmand B., Leckman J. F., Apter A. (2012). Involvement of immunologic and biochemical mechanisms in the pathogenesis of Tourette's syndrome. J. Neural Transm.
119, 621–626. 10.1007/s00702-011-0739-x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-011-0739-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3936959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22139323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman J. F., Peterson B. S. (1993). The pathogenesis of Tourette's syndrome: epigenetic factors active in early CNS development. Biol. Psychiatry
34, 425–427. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8268326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman J. F., Bloch M. H., Smith M. E., Larabi D., Hampson M. (2010). Neurobiological substrates of Tourette's disorder. J. Child Adolesc. Psychopharmacol.
20, 237–247. 10.1089/cap.2009.0118</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2009.0118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2958453</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman J. F., Dolnansky E. S., Hardin M. T., Clubb M., Walkup J. T., Stevenson J., et al. . (1990). Perinatal factors in the expression of Tourette's syndrome: an exploratory study. J. Am. Acad. Child Adolesc. Psychiatry
29, 220–226. 10.1097/00004583-199003000-00010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004583-199003000-00010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1969861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman J. F., Katsovich L., Kawikova I., Lin H., Zhang H., Krönig H., et al. . (2005). Increased serum levels of interleukin-12 and tumor necrosis factor-alpha in Tourette's syndrome. Biol. Psychiatry
57, 667–673. 10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15780855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman J. F., Price R. A., Walkup J. T., Ort S., Pauls D. L., Cohen D. J. (1987). Nongenetic factors in Gilles de la Tourette's syndrome. Arch. Gen. Psychiatry
44:100. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3467660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lécuyer M. A., Kebir H., Prat A. (2016). Glial influences on BBB functions and molecular players in immune cell trafficking. Biochim. Biophys. Acta
1862, 472–482. 10.1016/j.bbadis.2015.10.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2015.10.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26454208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levine S., Saltzman A. (1987). Nonspecific stress prevents relapses of experimental allergic encephalomyelitis in rats. Brain Behav. Immun.
1, 336–341. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3502584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levine S., Strebel R., Wenk E. J., Harman P. J. (1962a). Suppression of experimental allergic encephalomyelitis by stress. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med.
109, 294–298. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14464656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levine S., Wenk E. J., Muldoon T. N., Cohen S. G. (1962b). Enhancement of experimental allergic encephalomyelitis by adrenalectomy. Proc. Soc. Exp. Biol. Med.
111, 383–385. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13930175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levite M. (2014). Glutamate receptor antibodies in neurological diseases: anti-AMPA-GluR3 antibodies, anti-NMDA-NR1 antibodies, anti-NMDA-NR2A/B antibodies, anti-mGluR1 antibodies or anti-mGluR5 antibodies are present in subpopulations of patients with either: epilepsy, encephalitis, cerebellar ataxia, systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) and neuropsychiatric SLE, Sjogren's syndrome, schizophrenia, mania or stroke. These autoimmune anti-glutamate receptor antibodies can bind neurons in few brain regions, activate glutamate receptors, decrease glutamate receptor's expression, impair glutamate-induced signaling and function, activate blood brain barrier endothelial cells, kill neurons, damage the brain, induce behavioral/psychiatric/cognitive abnormalities and ataxia in animal models, and can be removed or silenced in some patients by immunotherapy. J. Neural Transm.
121, 1029–1075. 10.1007/s00702-014-1193-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-014-1193-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25081016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levite M., Hermelin A. (1999). Autoimmunity to the glutamate receptor in mice–a model for Rasmussen's encephalitis?
J. Autoimmun.
13, 73–82. 10.1006/jaut.1999.0297</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jaut.1999.0297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10441170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levite M., Fleidervish I. A., Schwarz A., Pelled D., Futerman A. H. (1999). Autoantibodies to the glutamate receptor kill neurons via activation of the receptor ion channel. J. Autoimmun.
13, 61–72. 10.1006/jaut.1999.0301</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jaut.1999.0301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10441169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loiselle C. R., Lee O., Moran T. H., Singer H. S. (2004). Striatal microinfusion of Tourette syndrome and PANDAS sera: failure to induce behavioral changes. Mov. Disord.
19, 390–396. 10.1002/mds.10522</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.10522</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lombroso P. J., Scahill L. (2008). Tourette syndrome and obsessive-compulsive disorder. Brain Dev.
30, 231–237. 10.1016/j.braindev.2007.09.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.braindev.2007.09.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2291145</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17937978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lotan D., Benhar I., Alvarez K., Mascaro-Blanco A., Brimberg L., Frenkel D., et al. . (2014). Behavioral and neural effects of intra-striatal infusion of anti-streptococcal antibodies in rats. Brain Behav. Immun.
38, 249–262. 10.1016/j.bbi.2014.02.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2014.02.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000697</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyons D. M., Macrì S. (2011). Resilience and adaptive aspects of stress in neurobehavioral development. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.
35:1451. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2010.09.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2010.09.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20851144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Y., Mehta S. L., Lu B., Li P. A. (2011). Deficiency in the inner mitochondrial membrane peptidase 2-like (Immp21) gene increases ischemic brain damage and impairs mitochondrial function. Neurobiol. Dis.
44, 270–276. 10.1016/j.nbd.2011.06.019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2011.06.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3185146</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21824519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macrì S., Ceci C., Onori M. P., Invernizzi R. W., Bartolini E., Altabella L., et al. . (2015). Mice repeatedly exposed to Group-A beta-Haemolytic Streptococcus show perseverative behaviors, impaired sensorimotor gating, and immune activation in rostral diencephalon. Sci. Rep.
5:13257. 10.1038/srep13257</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep13257</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4548234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26304458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macrì S., Proietti Onori M., Laviola G. (2013). Theoretical and practical considerations behind the use of laboratory animals for the study of Tourette syndrome. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.
37, 1085–1100. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2013.03.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2013.03.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mandolesi G., Grasselli G., Musumeci G., Centonze D. (2010). Cognitive deficits in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis: neuroinflammation and synaptic degeneration. Neurol. Sci.
31(Suppl. 2), S255–S259. 10.1007/s10072-010-0369-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-010-0369-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20635112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mansbach R. S., Geyer M. A., Braff D. L. (1988). Dopaminergic stimulation disrupts sensorimotor gating in the rat. Psychopharmacology
94, 507–514. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3131796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margari F., Petruzzelli M. G., Mianulli R., Toto M., Pastore A., Bizzaro N., et al. . (2013). Anti-brain autoantibodies in the serum of schizophrenic patients: a case-control study. Psychiatry Res.
210, 800–805. 10.1016/j.psychres.2013.09.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2013.09.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24103908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marques-Dias M. J., Mercadante M. T., Tucker D., Lombroso P. (1997). Sydenham's chorea. Psychiatr. Clin. North Am.
20, 809–820. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9443351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D., Chiarotti F., Buttiglione M., Cardona F., Creti R., Nardocci N., et al. . (2011). The relationship between group A streptococcal infections and Tourette syndrome: a study on a large service-based cohort. Dev. Med. Child Neurol.
53, 951–957. 10.1111/j.1469-8749.2011.04018.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.2011.04018.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21679362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D., Dale R. C., Gilbert D. L., Giovannoni G., Leckman J. F. (2009). Immunopathogenic mechanisms in tourette syndrome: a critical review. Mov. Disord.
24, 1267–1279. 10.1002/mds.22504</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.22504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3972005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19353683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D., Zis P., Buttiglione M. (2015). The role of immune mechanisms in Tourette syndrome. Brain Res.
1617, 126–143. 10.1016/j.brainres.2014.04.027</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2014.04.027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meagher M. W., Sieve A. N., Johnson R. R., Satterlee D., Belyavskyi M., Mi W., et al. . (2010). Neonatal maternal separation alters immune, endocrine, and behavioral responses to acute Theiler's virus infection in adult mice. Behav. Genet.
40, 233–249. 10.1007/s10519-010-9333-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10519-010-9333-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20135342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meldrum B. S. (2000). Glutamate as a neurotransmitter in the brain: review of physiology and pathology. J. Nutr.
130(4S Suppl), 1007S–1015S. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10736372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris C. M., Pardo-Villamizar C., Gause C. D., Singer H. S. (2009). Serum autoantibodies measured by immunofluorescence confirm a failure to differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. J. Neurol. Sci.
276, 45–48. 10.1016/j.jns.2008.08.032</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2008.08.032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18823914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy T. K., Kurlan R., Leckman J. (2010). The immunobiology of Tourette's disorder, pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with Streptococcus, and related disorders: a way forward. J. Child Adolesc. Psychopharmacol.
20, 317–331. 10.1089/cap.2010.0043</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2010.0043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4003464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20807070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nordstrom E. J., Burton F. H. (2002). A transgenic model of comorbid Tourette's syndrome and obsessive-compulsive disorder circuitry. Mol. Psychiatry
7, 617–625, 524. 10.1038/sj.mp.4001144</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.mp.4001144</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12140785</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olechowski C. J., Tenorio G., Sauve Y., Kerr B. J. (2013). Changes in nociceptive sensitivity and object recognition in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE). Exp. Neurol.
241, 113–121. 10.1016/j.expneurol.2012.12.012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2012.12.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23291347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park H. S., Francis K. P., Yu J., Cleary P. P. (2003). Membranous cells in nasal-associated lymphoid tissue: a portal of entry for the respiratory mucosal pathogen group A streptococcus. J. Immunol.
171, 2532–2537. 10.4049/jimmunol.171.5.2532</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.171.5.2532</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12928403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petek E., Windpassinger C., Vincent J. B., Cheung J., Boright A. P., Scherer S. W., et al. . (2001). Disruption of a novel gene (IMMP2L) by a breakpoint in 7q31 associated with Tourette syndrome. Am. J. Hum. Genet.
68, 848–858. 10.1086/319523</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/319523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1275638</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11254443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Platt S. R. (2007). The role of glutamate in central nervous system health and disease–a review. Vet. J.
173, 278–286. 10.1016/j.tvjl.2005.11.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tvjl.2005.11.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16376594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Podolska M. J., Biermann M. H., Maueröder C., Hahn J., Herrmann M. (2015). Inflammatory etiopathogenesis of systemic lupus erythematosus: an update. J. Inflamm. Res.
8, 161–171. 10.2147/JIR.S70325</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JIR.S70325</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4548750</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poliak S., Gollan L., Martinez R., Custer A., Einheber S., Salzer J. L., et al. . (1999). Caspr2, a new member of the neurexin superfamily, is localized at the juxtaparanodes of myelinated axons and associates with K+ channels. Neuron
24, 1037–1047. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10624965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proenca C. C., Gao K. P., Shmelkov S. V., Rafii S., Lee F. S. (2011). Slitrks as emerging candidate genes involved in neuropsychiatric disorders. Trends Neurosci.
34, 143–153. 10.1016/j.tins.2011.01.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2011.01.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3051006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21315458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabchevsky A. G., Degos J. D., Dreyfus P. A. (1999). Peripheral injections of Freund's adjuvant in mice provoke leakage of serum proteins through the blood-brain barrier without inducing reactive gliosis. Brain Res.
832, 84–96. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10375654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rickard M. D. (2004). The use of animals for research on animal diseases: its impact on the harm-benefit analysis. Altern. Lab. Anim.
32(Suppl. 1A), 225–227. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23577464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzo R., Gulisano M., Pavone P., Fogliani F., Robertson M. M. (2006). Increased antistreptococcal antibody titers and anti-basal ganglia antibodies in patients with Tourette syndrome: controlled cross-sectional study. J. Child Neurol.
21, 747–753. 10.1177/08830738060210091001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738060210091001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16970879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roque S., Mesquita A. R., Palha J. A., Sousa N., Correia-Neves M. (2014). The behavioral and immunological impact of maternal separation: a matter of timing. Front. Behav. Neurosci.
8:192. 10.3389/fnbeh.2014.00192</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2014.00192</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4033212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24904343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russig H., Spooren W., Durkin S., Feldon J., Yee B. K. (2004). Apomorphine-induced disruption of prepulse inhibition that can be normalised by systemic haloperidol is insensitive to clozapine pretreatment. Psychopharmacology
175, 143–147. 10.1007/s00213-004-1810-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-004-1810-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14985922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scahill L., Erenberg G., Berlin C. M., Jr., Budman C., Coffey B. J., Jankovic J., et al. . (2006). Contemporary assessment and pharmacotherapy of Tourette syndrome. NeuroRx
3, 192–206. 10.1016/j.nurx.2006.01.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nurx.2006.01.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3593444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16554257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlumberger W., Hornig N., Lange S., Probst C., Komorowski L., Fechner K., et al. . (2014). Differential diagnosis of membranous nephropathy with autoantibodies to phospholipase A2 receptor 1. Autoimmun. Rev.
13, 108–113. 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.09.005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2013.09.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24075959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scoriels L., Salek R. M., Goodby E., Grainger D., Dean A. M., West J. A., et al. . (2015). Behavioural and molecular endophenotypes in psychotic disorders reveal heritable abnormalities in glutamatergic neurotransmission. Transl. Psychiatry
5:e540. 10.1038/tp.2015.26</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/tp.2015.26</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4429170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25826115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sengupta A., Winters B., Bagley E. E., McNally G. P. (2016). Disrupted prediction error links excessive amygdala activation to excessive fear. J. Neurosci.
36, 385–395. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3670-15.2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3670-15.2016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A., Jung S. (2015). Differential roles of resident microglia and infiltrating monocytes in murine CNS autoimmunity. Semin. Immunopathol.
37, 613–623. 10.1007/s00281-015-0519-z</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00281-015-0519-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26240063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shepshelovich D., Shoenfeld Y. (2006). Prediction and prevention of autoimmune diseases: additional aspects of the mosaic of autoimmunity. Lupus
15, 183–190. 10.1191/0961203306lu2274rr</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/0961203306lu2274rr</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16634374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shprecher D., Kurlan R. (2009). The management of tics. Mov. Disord.
24, 15–24. 10.1002/mds.22378</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.22378</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701289</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19170198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silberberg D., Anand N. P., Michels K., Kalaria R. N. (2015). Brain and other nervous system disorders across the lifespan - global challenges and opportunities. Nature
527, S151–S154. 10.1038/nature16028</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature16028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer H. S., Hong J. J., Yoon D. Y., Williams P. N. (2005a). Serum autoantibodies do not differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. Neurology
65, 1701–1707. 10.1212/01.wnl.0000183223.69946.f1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000183223.69946.f1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16207842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer H. S., Mink J. W., Loiselle C. R., Burke K. A., Ruchkina I., Morshed S., et al. . (2005b). Microinfusion of antineuronal antibodies into rodent striatum: failure to differentiate between elevated and low titers. J. Neuroimmunol.
163, 8–14. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2005.02.018</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2005.02.018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15885303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanwood G. D., Lucki I., McGonigle P. (2000). Differential regulation of dopamine D2 and D3 receptors by chronic drug treatments. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther.
295, 1232–1240. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11082460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>State M. W. (2011). The genetics of Tourette disorder. Curr. Opin. Genet. Dev.
21, 302–309. 10.1016/j.gde.2011.01.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gde.2011.01.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21277193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stillman A. A., Krsnik Z., Sun J., Rasin M. R., State M. W., Sestan N., et al. . (2009). Developmentally regulated and evolutionarily conserved expression of SLITRK1 in brain circuits implicated in Tourette syndrome. J. Comp. Neurol.
513, 21–37. 10.1002/cne.21919</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.21919</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19105198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swanborg R. H. (2001). Experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis in the rat: lessons in T-cell immunology and autoreactivity. Immunol. Rev.
184, 129–135. 10.1034/j.1600-065x.2001.1840112.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-065x.2001.1840112.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12086308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo S. E., Grant P. J. (2005). Annotation: PANDAS: a model for human autoimmune disease. J. Child Psychol. Psychiatry
46, 227–234. 10.1111/j.1469-7610.2004.00386.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7610.2004.00386.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15755299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo S. E., Leonard H. L., Garvey M., Mittleman B., Allen A. J., Perlmutter S., et al. . (1998). Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am. J. Psychiatry
155, 264–271. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo S. E., Leonard H. L., Schapiro M. B., Casey B. J., Mannheim G. B., Lenane M. C., et al. . (1993). Sydenham's chorea: physical and psychological symptoms of St Vitus dance. Pediatrics
91, 706–713. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8464654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo S. E., Rapoport J. L., Cheslow D. L., Leonard H. L., Ayoub E. M., Hosier D. M., et al. . (1989). High prevalence of obsessive-compulsive symptoms in patients with Sydenham's chorea. Am. J. Psychiatry
146, 246–249. 10.1176/ajp.146.2.246</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.146.2.246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2912267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R. (2013). Update: studies of prepulse inhibition of startle, with particular relevance to the pathophysiology or treatment of Tourette Syndrome. Neurosci. Biobehav. Rev.
37, 1150–1156. 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.09.002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.09.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3566359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23017868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R., Sutherland A. N. (2005). Using animal models to develop therapeutics for Tourette Syndrome. Pharmacol. Ther.
108, 281–293. 10.1016/j.pharmthera.2005.05.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2005.05.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15970330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R., Benbow C. H., Zisook S., Geyer M. A., Braff D. L. (1993). A preliminary assessment of sensorimotor gating in patients with obsessive compulsive disorder. Biol. Psychiatry
33, 298–301. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8471686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R., Geyer M. A., Braff D. L. (2001a). Neural circuit regulation of prepulse inhibition of startle in the rat: current knowledge and future challenges. Psychopharmacology
156, 194–215. 10.1007/s002130100799</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002130100799</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11549223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R., Karban B., Ploum Y., Sharp R., Geyer M. A., Eastvold A. (2001b). Tactile prepuff inhibition of startle in children with Tourette's syndrome: in search of an “fMRI-friendly” startle paradigm. Biol. Psychiatry
50, 578–585. 10.1016/S0006-3223(01)01164-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-3223(01)01164-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11690592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R., Light G. A., Cadenhead K. S., Sprock J., Hsieh M. H., Braff D. L. (2006). Startle gating deficits in a large cohort of patients with schizophrenia: relationship to medications, symptoms, neurocognition, and level of function. Arch. Gen. Psychiatry
63, 1325–1335. 10.1001/archpsyc.63.12.1325</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.63.12.1325</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17146007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow N. R., Paulsen J., Braff D. L., Butters N., Geyer M. A., Swenson M. R. (1995). Impaired prepulse inhibition of acoustic and tactile startle response in patients with Huntington's disease. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatr.
58, 192–200. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1073317</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7876851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor J. R., Morshed S. A., Parveen S., Mercadante M. T., Scahill L., Peterson B. S., et al. . (2002). An animal model of Tourette's syndrome. Am. J. Psychiatry
159, 657–660. 10.1176/appi.ajp.159.4.657</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.159.4.657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11925307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valls-Sole J., Munoz J. E., Valldeoriola F. (2004). Abnormalities of prepulse inhibition do not depend on blink reflex excitability: a study in Parkinson's disease and Huntington's disease. Clin. Neurophysiol.
115, 1527–1536. 10.1016/j.clinph.2004.02.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinph.2004.02.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15203054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Staay F. J. (2006). Animal models of behavioral dysfunctions: basic concepts and classifications, and an evaluation strategy. Brain Res. Rev.
52, 131–159. 10.1016/j.brainresrev.2006.01.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresrev.2006.01.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Staay F. J., Arndt S. S., Nordquist R. E. (2009). Evaluation of animal models of neurobehavioral disorders. Behav. Brain Funct.
5:11. 10.1186/1744-9081-5-11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1744-9081-5-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669803</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19243583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkerk A. J., Mathews C. A., Joosse M., Eussen B. H., Heutink P., Oostra B. A., et al. . (2003). CNTNAP2 is disrupted in a family with Gilles de la Tourette syndrome and obsessive compulsive disorder. Genomics
82, 1–9. 10.1016/S0888-7543(03)00097-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0888-7543(03)00097-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12809671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verschuuren J. J., Huijbers M. G., Plomp J. J., Niks E. H., Molenaar P. C., Martinez-Martinez P., et al. . (2013). Pathophysiology of myasthenia gravis with antibodies to the acetylcholine receptor, muscle-specific kinase and low-density lipoprotein receptor-related protein 4. Autoimmun. Rev.
12, 918–923. 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.03.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2013.03.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wick G., Hu Y., Schwarz S., Kroemer G. (1993). Immunoendocrine communication via the hypothalamo-pituitary-adrenal axis in autoimmune diseases. Endocr. Rev.
14, 539–563. 10.1210/edrv-14-5-539</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/edrv-14-5-539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8262005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willner P. (1984). The validity of animal models of depression. Psychopharmacology
83, 1–16. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6429692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willner P., Mitchell P. J. (2002). The validity of animal models of predisposition to depression. Behav. Pharmacol.
13, 169–188. 10.1097/00008877-200205000-00001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00008877-200205000-00001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaddanapudi K., Hornig M., Serge R., De Miranda J., Baghban A., Villar G., et al. . (2010). Passive transfer of streptococcus-induced antibodies reproduces behavioral disturbances in a mouse model of pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection. Mol. Psychiatry
15, 712–726. 10.1038/mp.2009.77</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2009.77</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19668249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh C. B., Shui H. A., Chu T. H., Chen Y. A., Tsung H. C., Shyu J. F. (2012). Hyperpolarisation-activated cyclic nucleotide channel 4 (HCN4) involvement in Tourette's syndrome autoimmunity. J. Neuroimmunol.
250, 18–26. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2012.05.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2012.05.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22683190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zebardast N., Crowley M. J., Bloch M. H., Mayes L. C., Wyk B. V., Leckman J. F., et al. . (2013). Brain mechanisms for prepulse inhibition in adults with Tourette syndrome: initial findings. Psychiatry Res.
214, 33–41. 10.1016/j.pscychresns.2013.05.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pscychresns.2013.05.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3932431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23916249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
