<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27533272</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1518-8345</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>24</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2016</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Revista latino-americana de enfermagem</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Lat Am Enfermagem</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Infusion pumps and red blood cell damage in transfusion therapy: an integrative revision of the academic literature.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e2763</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e2763</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2763</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1590/1518-8345.1155.2763</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0104-11692016000100407</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">to obtain information from scientific literature concerning infusion pumps used in administering erythrocyte (red blood cells) and to evaluate the implications in the practical use of this equipment by nurses when conducting transfusions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">an integrative revision of the following scientific databases: Pubmed/Medline, Scopus, the Virtual Library for Health, SciELO, Web of Science and Cochrane. The following descriptors were used: "infusion pumps", "blood transfusion", "transfused erythrocyte" and "hemolyis". There were no restrictions on the scope of the initial data and it was finalized in December 2014. 17 articles were identified in accordance with the inclusion and exclusion criteria.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">all of the publications included in the studies were experimental in vitro and covered the use of infusion pumps in transfusion therapy. A summary of the data was presented in a synoptic chart and an analysis of it generated the following categories: cellular damage and the infusion mechanism.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">infusion pumps can be harmful to erythrocytes based on the infusion mechanism that is used, as the linear peristaltic pump is more likely to cause hemolysis. Cellular damage is related to the plasmatic liberation of markers that largely dominate free hemoglobin and potassium. We reiterate the need for further research and technological investments to guide the development of protocols that promote safe practices and that can contribute to future clinical studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJETIVOS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">identificar na literatura a produção científica acerca dos efeitos de bomba de infusão na administração de hemácias e avaliar as implicações do uso desses equipamentos na prática transfusional de enfermagem.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MÉTODO" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">revisão integrativa de literatura nas bases de dados Pubmed/Medline, Scopus, Biblioteca Virtual em Saúde, SciELO, Web of Science e Cochrane, utilizando os descritores "bombas de infusão", "transfusão de sangue", "transfusão de eritrócitos" e "hemólise". A data inicial não foi delimitada e a final foi dezembro de 2014. Foram identificados 17 artigos de acordo com os critérios de inclusão e exclusão.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTADOS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Todas as publicações incluídas eram estudos experimentais in vitro e abordavam o uso de bombas de infusão na terapêutica transfusional. A síntese dos dados foi apresentada em quadro sinóptico e a análise gerou duas categorias relevantes: lesão celular e mecanismo de infusão.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSÃO" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">bombas de infusão podem ser deletérias às hemácias de acordo o mecanismo de infusão, sendo que as peristálticas lineares foram mais predisponentes à hemólise. A lesão celular foi relacionada à liberação plasmática de marcadores, predominando a hemoglobina livre e potássio. Reitera-se a necessidade de pesquisas adicionais e investimentos tecnológicos para nortear o desenvolvimento de protocolos que promovam prática segura e que subsidiem futuros estudos clínicos.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJETIVOS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">identificar en la literatura la producción científica acerca de los efectos de la bomba de transfusión en la administración de glóbulos rojos y evaluar las implicaciones del uso de esos equipos en la práctica transfusional de enfermería.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MÉTODO" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">revisión integradora de literatura en las bases de datos Pubmed/Medline, Scopus, Biblioteca Virtual en Salud, SciELO, Web of Science y Cochrane, utilizando los descriptores "bombas de infusión", "transfusión de sangre", "transfusión de eritrocitos" y "hemolisis". La fecha inicial no fue delimitada y la final fue en diciembre de 2014. Fueron identificados 17 artículos de acuerdo con los criterios de inclusión y exclusión.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTADOS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">todas las publicaciones incluidas eran estudios experimentales in vitro y abordaban el uso de bombas de infusión en la terapéutica transfusional. La síntesis de los datos se presenta en un cuadro sinóptico y el análisis generó dos categorías relevantes: lesión celular y mecanismo de transfusión.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIÓN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">las bombas de infusión pueden ser perjudiciales para los glóbulos rojos de acuerdo el mecanismo de transfusión, siendo que las peristálticas lineares fueron más predisponentes para la hemolisis. La lesión celular fue relacionada a la liberación plasmática de marcadores, predominando la hemoglobina libre y el potasio. Se reitera la necesidad de realizar investigaciones adicionales e inversiones tecnológicas que puedan orientar el desarrollo de protocolos que promuevan la práctica segura y que ayuden a futuros estudios clínicos.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wilson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ana Maria Miranda Martins</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MSc, RN, Escola de Enfermagem, Universidade de São Paulo, São Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peterlini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria Angélica Sorgini</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PhD, Associate Professor, Escola Paulista de Enfermagem, Universidade Federal de São Paulo, São Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pedreira</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mavilde da Luz Gonçalves</ForeName>
            <Initials>Mda L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PhD, Associate Professor, Escola Paulista de Enfermagem, Universidade Federal de São Paulo, São Paulo, SP, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <Language>por</Language>
        <Language>spa</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Rev Lat Am Enfermagem</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9420934</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0104-1169</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017707" MajorTopicYN="N">Erythrocyte Transfusion</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="Y">instrumentation</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004912" MajorTopicYN="N">Erythrocytes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006461" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hemolysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007260" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusion Pumps</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2015</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27533272</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4996091</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1518-8345.1155.2763</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0104-11692016000100407</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carson JL, Grossman BJ, Kleinman S, Tinmouth AT, Marques MB, Fung MK. Red blood cell transfusion a clinical practice guideline from the
AABB. Ann Intern Med. 2012;157:49–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22751760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministério da Saúde  . Secretaria de Atenção à Saúde. Coordenação Geral de Sangue e Hemoderivados.
Caderno de informação: sangue e hemoderivados: produção hemoterápica. ed: Brasília; 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministério da Saúde (BR). Secretaria de Atenção à Saúde, Coordenação Geral
de Sangue e Hemoderivados.   Caderno de informação: sangue e hemoderivados: produção hemoterápica. 4ª . Brasília: 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Philips LD.  Manual of IV Therapeutics: evidence-based practice to infusion
therapy. 5th . Philadelfia: F. A. Davis; 2010. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conselho Federal de Enfermagem (BR)   Resolução COFEN nº 306/2006. Normatiza a atuação do Enfermeiro em
Hemoterapia. Rio de Janeiro: 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harada MJCS, Pedreira MLG.  Terapia Intravenosa e Infusões. São Caetano do Sul: Yendis; 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Associação Brasileira de Normas Técnicas (ABNT)   Prescrições particulares para a segurança de bombas e controladores de
infusão. Rio de Janeiro: 1999. 84 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emergency Care Research Institute  General purpose infusion 193 pumps. Health devices. 1998;27(4-5):123–170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nightingale MJ, Norfolk DR, Pinchon DJ. Current uses of transfusion administration sets a cause for
concern? Transfus Med. 2010;20(5):291–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20553428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heaton A. Red blood cell hemolysis an old standard in changing
times. Transfusion. 2009;49(12):2551–2554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20163688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beyea S, Nicoll LH. Writing an integrative review. AORN J. 1998;67(4):877–880.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9616108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendes KDS, Silveira RCCP, Galvão CM. Revisão integrativa método de pesquisa para a incorporação de
evidências na saúde e na enfermagem. Texto Contexto Enferm. 2008;17(4):758–764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whittemore R, Knal K. The integrative review updated methodology. J Adv Nurs. 2005;52(5):546–553.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16268861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilcox GJ, Barnes A, Modanlou H. Does transfusion using a syringe infusion pump and small-gauge needle
cause hemolysis. Transfusion. 1981;21(6):750–751.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7314226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herrera AJ, Corless J. Blood transfusions effect of speed of infusion and of needle gauge on
hemolysis. J Pediatr. 1981;99(5):757–758.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7299556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson JS, Leff RD, Roberts RJ. Effects of intravenous delivery systems on infused red blood
cells. Am J Hosp Pharm. 1984;41(3):468–472.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6702849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veerman MW, Leff RD, Roberts RJ. Influence of two piston-type infusion pumps on hemolysis of infused
red blood cells. Am J Hosp Pharm. 1985;42(3):626–628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3985030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson HW, Lasky LC, Polesky HF. Evaluation of a volumetric intravenous infusion pump for transfusion
of blood components containing red cells. Transfusion. 1986;26(3):290–292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3705149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angel JL, O'Brien WF, Knuppel RA, Warren MB, Leparc GF. Infusion of packed erythrocytes an in vitro study of
hemolysis. Obstet Gynecol. 1987;69(6):948–950.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3574827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gurdak RG, Anderson G, Mintz PD. Evaluation of IVAC Variable Pressure Volumetric Pump Model 560 for the
delivery of red blood cells, adenine-saline added. Am J Clin Pathol. 1988;91(2):199–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2916463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denison MUP, Bell R, Schuldreich R, Chaudhri MA. Effect of different pump mechanisms on transfusion of
blood. Australas Phys Eng Sci Med. 1991;14(1):39–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2029240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strayer AH, Henry DW, Erenberg A, Leff RD. Administration of whole blood, packed red blood cells, and platelets
using a multipurpose infusion pump. Am J Hosp Pharm. 1991;48(9):1970–1972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1928143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burch KJ, Phelps SJ, Constance TD. Effect of an infusion device on the integrity of whole blood and
packed red blood cells. Am J Hosp Pharm. 1991;48(1):92–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2000884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Criss VR, DePalma L, Luban NL. Analysis of a linear peristaltic infusion device for the transfusion
of red cells to pediatric patients. Transfusion. 1993;33(10):842–844.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8236427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansen TG, Sprogoe-Jakobsen U, Pedersen CM, Olsen KS, Kristensen SR. Haemolysis following rapid experimental red blood cell transfusion an
evaluation of two infusion pumps. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 1998;42(1):57–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9527746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojas JT, Heras FB, García MRS, López EP, Vilchez MCM, Rodríguez JD. Volumetric pumps for blood transfusions: viability in pediatrics. 2001;24(11):8–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12149991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frey B, Eber S, Weiss M. Changes in red blood cell integrity related to infusion pumps a
comparison of three different pump mechanisms. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2003;4(4):465–470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14525644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho EB, Borges EL, Carlos LMB, Silva MAM, Magalhães SMM, Gomes FVBAF. Efeito da bomba de infusão de soluções sobre o grau de hemólise em
concentrado de hemácias. Rev Bras Hematol Hemoter. 2007;29(2):149–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parfitt HS, Davies SV, Tighe P, Ewings P. Red cell damage after pumping by two infusion control devices (Arcomed
VP 7000 and IVAC 572) Transfus Med. 2007;17(4):290–295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17680955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lieshout-Krikke RW, Van der Meer PF, Koopman MMW, Korte DDE. Effect on the quality of blood components after simulated blood
transfusions using volumetric infusion pumps. Transfusion. 2011;51(8):1835–1839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21303369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook DJ, Guyatt GH, Laupacis A, Sackett DL, Goldberg RJ. Clinical recommendations using levels of evidence for antithrombotic
agents. Chest. 1995;108(4 Suppl):227S–2230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7555178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langhi DM, Jr, Pereira JPM, Pereira CM. Bordin JO, Langhi DM, Jr, Covas DT.  Hemoterapia: fundamentos e prática. São Paulo: Atheneu; 2007. Reações Transfusionais Hemolíticas; pp. 437–444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raza S, Baig Ma, Chang C, Dabas R, Akhtar M, Khan A. A Prospective Study on Red Blood Cell Transfusion Related Hyperkalemia
in Critically Ill Patients. J Clin Med Res. 2015;7(6):417–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4394913</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25883703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vraets A, Lin Y, Callum J. Transfusion-Associated Hyperkalemia. Transfusion Med Rev. 2011;25(3):184–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21498041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith HM, Farrow SJ, Ackerman JD, Stubbs JR, Sprung J. Cardiac Arrests Associated with Hyperkalemia During Red Blood Cell
Transfusion A Case Series. Anesth Analg. 2008;106(4):1062–1069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18349174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McClelland B.  Guidelines for the Blood Transfusion Services in the United Kingdom. 7. London: The Stationery Office; 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministério da Saúde (BR). Agência Nacional de Vigilância Sanitária
(ANVISA)   RDC nº 34, de 11 de junho de 2004. Dispõe sobre as boas práticas no ciclo do
sangue. Brasília: 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC)   International Organization for Standardization (ISO) nº 1135-4:2012:
Transfusion equipment for medical use - Part 4: Transfusion sets for single
use. 2012. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janatpour KA, Paglieroni TG, Crocker VL, Holland PV. Visual assessment of hemolysis in red blood cell units and segments
can be deceptive. Transfusion. 2004;44(7):984–989.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15225237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedreira MLG, Peterlini MAS, Harada MJCS. Tecnologia da informação e prevenção de erros de medicação em
pediatria prescrição informatizada, código de barras e bombas de infusão
inteligentes. Rev Soc Bras Enferm Ped. 2005;5(1):55–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
