<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27606347</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2016</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2328-9503</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>3</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2016</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of clinical and translational neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Clin Transl Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with anti-Yo antibodies - a review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>655</StartPage>
          <EndPage>663</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>655-63</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/acn3.328</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The ataxic syndrome associated with Anti-Yo antibody, or Purkinje cell cytoplasmic antibody type 1 (PCA1), is the most common variant of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration (PCD). The typical presentation involves the subacute development of pancerebellar deficits with a clinical plateau within 6 months. The vast majority of cases have been reported in women with pelvic or breast tumors. Magnetic resonance imaging of the brain is often normal in the early stages, with cerebellar atrophy seen later. The underlying mechanism is believed to be an immunological reaction to cerebellar degeneration-related protein 2 (CDR2), a protein usually found in the cerebellum that is ectopically produced by tumor cells. Although both B- and T-cell abnormalities are seen, there is debate about the relative importance of the autoantibodies and cytotoxic T lymphocytes in the neuronal loss. Cerebrospinal fluid abnormalities, primarily elevated protein, lymphocytic pleocytosis, and oligoclonal bands, are common in the early stages. The low prevalence of this condition has not allowed for large-scale randomized controlled trials. Immunotherapies, such as steroids, intravenous immune globulins, and plasma exchange, have been extensively used in managing this condition, with limited success. Although some reports indicate benefit from antitumor therapies like surgery and chemotherapy, this has not been consistently observed. The prognosis for anti-Yo PCD is almost uniformly poor, with most patients left bedridden. Further studies are required to clarify the pathophysiology and provide evidence-based treatment options.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Venkatraman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anand</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology University of Alabama at Birmingham Birmingham Alabama.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Opal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Puneet</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Davee department of Neurology Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine Chicago Illinois; Department of Cell and Molecular Biology Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine Chicago Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Clin Transl Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101623278</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2328-9503</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Anti‐Yo</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">ataxia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">autoimmune</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cerebellar degeneration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">paraneoplastic syndromes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27606347</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999597</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.328</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">ACN3328</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jarius S, Wildemann B. ‘Medusa‐head ataxia’: the expanding spectrum of Purkinje cell antibodies in autoimmune cerebellar ataxia. Part 1: Anti‐mGluR1, anti‐Homer‐3, anti‐Sj/ITPR1 and anti‐CARP VIII. J Neuroinflammation
2015;12:166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4574226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26377085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vedeler CA, Antoine JC, Giometto B, et al. Management of paraneoplastic neurological syndromes: report of an EFNS task force. Eur J Neurol
2006;13:682–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16834698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
O'Brien TJ, Pasaliaris B, D'Apice A, Byrne E. Anti‐Yo positive paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: a report of three cases and review of the literature. J Clin Neurosci
1995;2:316–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18638835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Graus F, Delattre JY, Antoine JC, et al. Recommended diagnostic criteria for paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
2004;75:1135–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15258215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sadeghian H, Vernino S. Progress in the management of paraneoplastic neurological disorders. Ther Adv Neurol Disord.
2010;3:43–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3002612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21180635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hasadsri L, Lee J, Wang BH, et al. Anti‐yo associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a man with large cell cancer of the lung. Case Rep Neurol Med.
2013;2013:725936.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24167748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Meglic B, Graus F, Grad A. Anti‐Yo‐associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a man with gastric adenocarcinoma. J Neurol Sci
2001;185:135–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11311295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sutton IJ, Fursdon Davis CJ, Esiri MM, et al. Anti‐Yo antibodies and cerebellar degeneration in a man with adenocarcinoma of the esophagus. Ann Neurol
2001;49:253–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11220746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brouwer B. Beitrag zur. Kenntnis der chronischen diffusen Kleinhirnerkrankungen. Neurol Centralbl
1919;38:674–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Parker HLK, Kernohan JW. Parenchymatous cortical cerebellar atrophy (chronic atrophy of Purkinje cells). Brain
1933;56:191–212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Monstad SE, Storstein A, Dorum A, et al. Yo antibodies in ovarian and breast cancer patients detected by a sensitive immunoprecipitation technique. Clin Exp Immunol
2006;144:53–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1809634</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16542365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Drlicek M, Bianchi G, Bogliun G, et al. Antibodies of the anti‐Yo and anti‐Ri type in the absence of paraneoplastic neurological syndromes: a long‐term survey of ovarian cancer patients. J Neurol
1997;244:85–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9120501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Goldstein BH, Birk CL, Van Houten M, et al. Ovarian cancer and late onset paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Arch Gynecol Obstet
2009;280:99–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18987868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Power DG, McVey GP, Delaney DW, et al. Papillary serous carcinomas of the uterine cervix and paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: a report of two cases. Acta Oncol
2008;47:1590–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18941954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rojas I, Graus F, Keime‐Guibert F, et al. Long‐term clinical outcome of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and anti‐Yo antibodies. Neurology
2000;55:713–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10980743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Peterson K, Rosenblum MK, Kotanides H, Posner JB. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. I. A clinical analysis of 55 anti‐Yo antibody‐positive patients. Neurology
1992;42:1931–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1407575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shams'ili S, Grefkens J, De Leeuw B, et al. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with antineuronal antibodies: analysis of 50 patients. Brain. 2003;126(Pt 6):1409–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12764061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Key RG, Root JC. Anti‐Yo mediated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in the context of breast cancer: a case report and literature review. Psychooncology
2013;22:2152–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23585287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gilmore CP, Elliott I, Auer D, Maddison P. Diffuse cerebellar MR imaging changes in anti‐Yo positive paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol
2010;257:490–1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19943166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Giometto B, Marchiori GC, Nicolao P, et al. Sub‐acute cerebellar degeneration with anti‐Yo autoantibodies: immunohistochemical analysis of the immune reaction in the central nervous system. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol
1997;23:468–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9460712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
McHugh JC, Tubridy N, Collins CD, Hutchinson M. Unusual MRI abnormalities in anti‐Yo positive “pure” paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol
2008;255:138–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17994310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kannoth S. Paraneoplastic neurologic syndrome: a practical approach. Ann Indian Acad Neurol.
2012;15:6–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299076</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22412264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Paraneoplastic Neurological Syndromes. National Guideline Clearinghouse: Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. Avaliable at: https://www.guideline.gov/content.aspx?id=34906 (accessed May 14 2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dalmau JO, Posner JB. Paraneoplastic syndromes. Arch Neurol
1999;56:405–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10199327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stefansson K, Marton LS, Dieperink ME, et al. Circulating autoantibodies to the 200,000‐dalton protein of neurofilaments in the serum of healthy individuals. Science
1985;228:1117–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4039466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greenlee JE, Brashear HR. Antibodies to cerebellar Purkinje cells in patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and ovarian carcinoma. Ann Neurol
1983;14:609–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6360029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Darnell RBP, Posner JB. Paraneoplastic syndromes. USA:Oxford University Press, 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sakai K, Mitchell DJ, Tsukamoto T, Steinman L. Isolation of a complementary DNA clone encoding an autoantigen recognized by an anti‐neuronal cell antibody from a patient with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Ann Neurol
1990;28:692–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2260856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fathallah‐Shaykh H, Wolf S, Wong E, et al. Cloning of a leucine‐zipper protein recognized by the sera of patients with antibody‐associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA
1991;15:3451–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC51465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2014264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Amyes E, Curnow J, Stark Z, et al. Restricted IgG1 subclass of anti‐Yo antibodies in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neuroimmunol
2001;114(1–2):259–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11240040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Furneaux HF, Reich L, Posner JB. Autoantibody synthesis in the central nervous system of patients with paraneoplastic syndromes. Neurology
1990;40:1085–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2356009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aboul‐Enein F, Hoftberger R, Buxhofer‐Ausch V, et al. Neocortical neurones may be targeted by immune attack in anti‐Yo paraneoplastic syndrome. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol
2008;34:248–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17995920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Altermatt HJ, Rodriguez M, Scheithauer BW, Lennon VA. Paraneoplastic anti‐Purkinje and type I anti‐neuronal nuclear autoantibodies bind selectively to central, peripheral, and autonomic nervous system cells. Lab Invest
1991;65:412–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1921331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rodriguez M, Truh LI, O'Neill BP, Lennon VA. Autoimmune paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: ultrastructural localization of antibody‐binding sites in Purkinje cells. Neurology
1988;38:1380–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3045692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hida C, Tsukamoto T, Awano H, Yamamoto T. Ultrastructural localization of anti‐Purkinje cell antibody‐binding sites in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Arch Neurol
1994;51:555–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8198465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Darnell RB, Posner JB. Paraneoplastic syndromes involving the nervous system. N Engl J Med
2003;349:1543–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14561798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jarius S, Wildemann B. ‘Medusa head ataxia’: the expanding spectrum of Purkinje cell antibodies in autoimmune cerebellar ataxia. Part 3: Anti‐Yo/CDR2, anti‐Nb/AP3B2, PCA‐2, anti‐Tr/DNER, other antibodies, diagnostic pitfalls, summary and outlook. J Neuroinflammation
2015;12:168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4573944</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26377319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dropcho EJ, Chen YT, Posner JB, Old LJ. Cloning of a brain protein identified by autoantibodies from a patient with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA
1987;84:4552–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC305128</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3474619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schubert M, Panja D, Haugen M, et al. Paraneoplastic CDR2 and CDR2L antibodies affect Purkinje cell calcium homeostasis. Acta Neuropathol
2014;128:835–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4231287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25341622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Corradi JP, Yang C, Darnell JC, et al. A post‐transcriptional regulatory mechanism restricts expression of the paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration antigen cdr2 to immune privileged tissues. J Neurosci
1997;17:1406–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793730</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9006982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Darnell RB, Albert ML. cdr2‐specific CTLs are detected in the blood of all patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration analyzed. Ann Neurol
2000;48:270–1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10939585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Okano HJ, Park WY, Corradi JP, Darnell RB. The cytoplasmic Purkinje onconeural antigen cdr2 down‐regulates c‐Myc function: implications for neuronal and tumor cell survival. Genes Dev
1999;15:2087–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC316965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10465786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sakai K, Kitagawa Y, Li Y, et al. Suppression of the transcriptional activity and DNA binding of nuclear factor‐kappa B by a paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration‐associated antigen. J Neuroimmunol
2001;119:10–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11525795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sakai K, Shirakawa T, Li Y, et al. Interaction of a paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration‐associated neuronal protein with the nuclear helix‐loop‐helix leucine zipper protein MRG X. Mol Cell Neurosci
2002;19:477–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11988016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Storstein A, Krossnes BK, Vedeler CA. Morphological and immunohistochemical characterization of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with Yo antibodies. Acta Neurol Scand
2009;120:64–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brain WR, Daniel PM, Greenfield JG. Subacute cortical cerebellar degeneration and its relation to carcinoma. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
1951;14:59–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC499576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14850992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brock S, Ellison D, Frankel J, et al. Anti‐Yo antibody‐positive cerebellar degeneration associated with endometrial carcinoma: case report and review of the literature. Clin Oncol (R Coll Radiol)
2001;13:476–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11824891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Verschuuren J, Chuang L, Rosenblum MK, et al. Inflammatory infiltrates and complete absence of Purkinje cells in anti‐Yo‐associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Acta Neuropathol
1996;91:519–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8740233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greenlee JE, Clawson SA, Hill KE, et al. Purkinje cell death after uptake of anti‐Yo antibodies in cerebellar slice cultures. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol
2010;69:997–1007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2959164</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20838245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanaka K, Tanaka M, Onodera O, et al. Passive transfer and active immunization with the recombinant leucine‐zipper (Yo) protein as an attempt to establish an animal model of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol Sci
1994;127:153–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7707074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanaka K, Tanaka M, Igarashi S, et al. Trial to establish an animal model of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with anti‐Yo antibody. 2. Passive transfer of murine mononuclear cells activated with recombinant Yo protein to paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration lymphocytes in severe combined immunodeficiency mice. Clin Neurol Neurosurg
1995;97:101–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7788964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanaka M, Tanaka K, Onodera O, Tsuji S. Trial to establish an animal model of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with anti‐Yo antibody. 1. Mouse strains bearing different MHC molecules produce antibodies on immunization with recombinant Yo protein, but do not cause Purkinje cell loss. Clin Neurol Neurosurg
1995;97:95–100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7788981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Albert ML, Darnell JC, Bender A, et al. Tumor‐specific killer cells in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Nat Med
1998;4:1321–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9809559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Albert ML, Austin LM, Darnell RB. Detection and treatment of activated T cells in the cerebrospinal fluid of patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Ann Neurol
2000;47:9–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10632096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Carpenter EL, Vance BA, Klein RS, et al. Functional analysis of CD8+ T cell responses to the onconeural self protein cdr2 in patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neuroimmunol
2008;193(1–2):173–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sutton IJ, Steele J, Savage CO, et al. An interferon‐gamma ELISPOT and immunohistochemical investigation of cytotoxic T lymphocyte‐mediated tumour immunity in patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and anti‐Yo antibodies. J Neuroimmunol
2004;150(1–2):98–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15081253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greenlee JE, Clawson SA, Hill KE, et al. Anti‐Yo antibody uptake and interaction with its intracellular target antigen causes Purkinje cell death in rat cerebellar slice cultures: a possible mechanism for paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in humans with gynecological or breast cancers. PLoS ONE
2015;10:e0123446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4401511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25885452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Psimaras D, Carpentier AF, Rossi C, Euronetwork PNS. Cerebrospinal fluid study in paraneoplastic syndromes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
2010;81:42–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vernino S, O'Neill BP, Marks RS, et al. Immunomodulatory treatment trial for paraneoplastic neurological disorders. Neuro Oncol.
2004;6:55–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1871966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schessl J, Schuberth M, Reilich P, et al. Long‐term efficiency of intravenously administered immunoglobulin in anti‐Yo syndrome with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol
2011;258:946–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21174114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Phuphanich S, Brock C. Neurologic improvement after high‐dose intravenous immunoglobulin therapy in patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with anti‐Purkinje cell antibody. J Neurooncol
2007;81:67–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16773214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Meloni C, Iani C, Dominijanni S, et al. A case report of plasma exchange therapy in non‐paraneoplastic cerebellar ataxia associated with anti‐Yo antibody. Ther Apher Dial
2004;8:500–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Landtblom AM, Lindvall B, Ledin T, Berlin G. A case report of plasmapheresis treatment in a patient with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and high anti‐yo antibody titers. Ther Apher Dial
2008;12:82–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18257818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lin JT, Lachmann E, Nagler W. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration as the first manifestation of cancer. J Womens Health Gend Based Med
2001;10:495–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Thone J, Hohaus A, Lamprecht S, et al. Effective immunosuppressant therapy with cyclophosphamide and corticosteroids in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol Sci. 2008. 
272; (1‐2):171–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18632117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shams'ili S, deBeukelaar
J
, Gratama JW, et al. An uncontrolled trial of rituximab for antibody associated paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. J Neurol
2006;253:16–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16444604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cao Y, Abbas J, Wu X, et al. Anti‐Yo positive paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with ovarian carcinoma: case report and review of the literature. Gynecol Oncol
1999;75:178–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10502450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Geomini PM, Dellemijn PL, Bremer GL. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: neurological symptoms pointing to occult ovarian cancer. Gynecol Obstet Invest
2001;52:145–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11586046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanriverdi O, Meydan N, Barutca S, et al. Anti‐Yo antibody‐mediated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a female patient with pleural malignant mesothelioma. Jpn J Clin Oncol
2013;43:563–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23475537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Candler PM, Hart PE, Barnett M, et al. A follow up study of patients with paraneoplastic neurological disease in the United Kingdom. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
2004;75:1411–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1738729</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15377687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bradley WH, Dottino PR, Rahaman J. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in ovarian carcinoma: case report with review of immune modulation. Int J Gynecol Cancer
2008;18:1364–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bhargava A, Bhushan B, Kasundra GM, et al. Response to abdominal hysterectomy with bilateral salpingo‐oophorectomy in postmenopausal woman with anti‐yo antibody mediated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Ann Indian Acad Neurol.
2014;17:355–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4162030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25221413</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Scheid R, Voltz R, Briest S, et al. Clinical insights into paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
2006;77:529–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077487</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16543537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sancho MI, Lopez MR, Martinez LC, et al. Subacute cerebellar degeneration as paraneoplastic syndrome: initial symptom of breast cancer with HER2 overexpression. Clin Breast Cancer
2006;7:79–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16764747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Blaes F, Strittmatter M, Merkelbach S, et al. Intravenous immunoglobulins in the therapy of paraneoplastic neurological disorders. J Neurol
1999;246:299–303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10367699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanaka K, Tanaka M, Igarashi S, et al. Long term course of change in anti‐Yo antibody content in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
1995;58:256–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1073337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7876871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hammack JE, Kimmel DW, O'Neill BP, Lennon VA. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: a clinical comparison of patients with and without Purkinje cell cytoplasmic antibodies. Mayo Clin Proc
1990;65:1423–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2232897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
de Beukelaar JW, Sillevis Smitt PA. Managing paraneoplastic neurological disorders. Oncologist
2006;11:292–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16549814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Widdess‐Walsh P, Tavee JO, Schuele S, Stevens GH. Response to intravenous immunoglobulin in anti‐Yo associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: case report and review of the literature. J Neurooncol
2003;63:187–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12825823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stark E, Wurster U, Patzold U, et al. Immunological and clinical response to immunosuppressive treatment in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Arch Neurol
1995;52:814–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7639633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
