<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27614806</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-3840</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Canadian journal of diabetes</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Can J Diabetes</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Insulin Signalling: The Inside Story.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>108</StartPage>
          <EndPage>113</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>108-113</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jcjd.2016.07.002</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1499-2671(16)30191-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Insulin signalling begins with binding to its cell surface insulin receptor (IR), which is a tyrosine kinase. The insulin receptor kinase (IRK) is subsequently autophosphorylated and activated to tyrosine phosphorylate key cellular substrates that are essential for entraining the insulin response. Although IRK activation begins at the cell surface, it is maintained and augmented following internalization into the endosomal system (ENS). The peroxovanadium compounds (pVs) were discovered to activate the IRK in the absence of insulin and lead to a full insulin response. Thus, IRK activation is both necessary and sufficient for insulin signalling. Furthermore, this could be shown to occur with activation of only the endosomal IRK. The mechanism of pV action was shown to be the inhibition of IRK-associated phosphotyrosine phosphatases (PTPs). Our studies showed that the duration and intensity of insulin signalling are modulated within ENS by the recruitment of cellular substrates to ENS; intra-endosomal acidification, which promotes dissociation of insulin from the IRK; an endosomal acidic insulinase, which degrades intra-endosomal insulin; and IRK-associated PTPs, which dephosphorylate and, hence, deactivate the IRK. Therefore, the internalization of IRKs is central to insulin signalling and its regulation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2016 Canadian Diabetes Association. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Posner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Barry I</ForeName>
            <Initials>BI</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, McGill University Hospital Research Institute, Montreal, Quebec, Canada. Electronic address: barry.posner@mcgill.ca.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 DK019573</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Can J Diabetes</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101148810</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1499-2671</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011972">Receptor, Insulin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003920" MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes Mellitus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004730" MajorTopicYN="N">Endothelium, Vascular</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011972" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptor, Insulin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">
        <AbstractText>La signalisation de l’insuline commence par la liaison de l’insuline à son récepteur (IR) situé à la surface des cellules, soit la tyrosine kinase. La kinase du récepteur de l’insuline (KRI) s’est subséquemment autophosphorylée et activée vers les principaux substrats cellulaires de la tyrosine phosphorylée qui sont essentiels au déclenchement de la réponse à l’insuline. Bien que l’activation de la KRI commence à la surface des cellules, elle est maintenue et augmentée à la suite de l’internalisation du système endosomal (SEN). Il a été découvert que les composés de peroxovanadium (pV) activent la KRI en l’absence d’insuline et mènent à une réponse insulinique complète. Par conséquent, l’activation de la KRI est nécessaire et suffisante à la signalisation de l’insuline. De plus, il pourrait être démontré qu’elle apparaît avec l’activation de la KRI endosomale seulement. Il a été démontré que le mécanisme de l’activité du pV est l’inhibition des phosphotyrosines phosphatases (PTP) associées à la KRI. Nos études ont montré que la durée et l’intensité de la signalisation de l’insuline sont modulées au sein du SEN par le recrutement de substrats cellulaires du SEN; l’acidification intra-endosomale, qui favorise la dissociation de l’insuline de la KRI; une insulinase endosomique acide, qui dégrade l’insuline dans les endosomes; les PTP associées à la KRI, qui déphosphorylent et, donc, désactivent la KRI. Par conséquent, l’internalisation des KRI est essentielle au déclenchement de la signalisation de l’insuline et à sa régulation.</AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2016 Canadian Diabetes Association. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endosomal acidic insulinase</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endosomes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin receptor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulinase endosomique acide</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phosphorylation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phosphotyrosine phosphatase</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">récepteur de l'insuline</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tyrosine kinase</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27614806</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS815473</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5272803</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcjd.2016.07.002</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1499-2671(16)30191-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freychet P, Roth J, Neville DM., Jr Insulin receptors in the liver: Specific binding of (125 I) insulin to the plasma membrane and its relation to insulin bioactivity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1971;68:1833–1837.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC389303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4331561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Posner BI, Kelly PA, Shiu RP, Friesen HG. Studies of insulin, growth hormone and prolactin binding: Tissue distribution, species variation and characterization. Endocrinology. 1974;95:521–531.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4369225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergeron JJ, Levine G, Sikstrom R, et al.  Polypeptide hormone binding sites in vivo: Initial localization of 125I-labeled insulin to hepatocyte plasmalemma as visualized by electron microscope radioautography. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1977;74:5051–5055.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC432096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">270739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Houten M, Posner BI. Insulin binds to brain blood vessels in vivo. Nature. 1979;282:623–625.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">399330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Houten M, Posner BI, Kopriwa BM, Brawer JR. Insulin binding sites localized to nerve terminals in rat median eminence and arcuate nucleus. Science. 1980;207:1081–1083.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6986652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Houten M, Posner BI, Kopriwa BM, Brawer JR. Insulin-binding sites in the rat brain: In vivo localization to the circumventricular organs by quantitative radioautography. Endocrinology. 1979;105:666–673.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">223829</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Houten M, Posner BI. Circumventricular organs: Receptors and mediators of direct peptide hormone action on brain. Adv Metab Disord. 1983;10:269–289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6320604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergeron JJ, Posner BI, Josefsberg Z, Sikstrom R. Intracellular polypeptide hormone receptors: The demonstration of specific binding sites for insulin and human growth hormone in Golgi fractions isolated from the liver of female rats. J Biol Chem. 1978;253:4058–4066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">206561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Posner BI, Patel B, Verma AK, Bergeron JJ. Uptake of insulin by plasmalemma and Golgi subcellular fractions of rat liver. J Biol Chem. 1980;255:735–741.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7356641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kay DG, Khan MN, Posner BI, Bergeron JJ. In vivo uptake of insulin into hepatic Golgi fractions: Application of the diaminobenzidine-shift protocol. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1984;123:1144–1148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6435623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebina Y, Araki E, Taira M, et al.  Replacement of lysine residue 1030 in the putative ATP-binding region of the insulin receptor abolishes insulin- and antibody-stimulated glucose uptake and receptor kinase activity. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1987;84:704–708.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC304284</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3101064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Posner BI, Faure R, Burgess JW, et al.  Peroxovanadium compounds: A new class of potent phosphotyrosine phosphatase inhibitors which are insulin mimetics. J Biol Chem. 1994;269:4596–4604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8308031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan MN, Baquiran G, Brule C, et al.  Internalization and activation of the rat liver insulin receptor kinase in vivo. J Biol Chem. 1989;264:12931–12940.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2546941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Authier F, Bergeron JJ, Ou WJ, et al.  Degradation of the cleaved leader peptide of thiolase by a peroxisomal proteinase. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1995;92:3859–3863.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC42061</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7731996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamel FG, Posner BI, Bergeron JJ, et al.  Isolation of insulin degradation products from endosomes derived from intact rat liver. J Biol Chem. 1988;263:6703–6708.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3283131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doherty JJ, 2nd, Kay DG, Lai WH, et al.  Selective degradation of insulin within rat liver endosomes. J Cell Biol. 1990;110:35–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2115978</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2404022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Authier F, Metioui M, Fabrega S, et al.  Endosomal proteolysis of internalized insulin at the C-terminal region of the B chain by cathepsin D. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:9437–9446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11779865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kadota S, Fantus IG, Deragon G, et al.  Stimulation of insulin-like growth factor II receptor binding and insulin receptor kinase activity in rat adipocytes: Effects of vanadate and H2O2. J Biol Chem. 1987;262:8252–8256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3036804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kadota S, Fantus IG, Deragon G, et al.  Peroxide(s) of vanadium: A novel and potent insulin-mimetic agent which activates the insulin receptor kinase. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1987;147:259–266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3632668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fantus IG, Kadota S, Deragon G, et al.  Pervanadate (peroxide(s) of vanadate) mimics insulin action in rat adipocytes via activation of the insulin receptor tyrosine kinase. Biochemistry. 1989;28:8864–8871.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2690951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faure R, Baquiran G, Bergeron JJ, Posner BI. The dephosphorylation of insulin and epidermal growth factor receptors: Role of endosome-associated phosphotyrosine phosphatase(s) J Biol Chem. 1992;267:11215–11221.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1375938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bevan AP, Burgess JW, Drake PG, et al.  Selective activation of the rat hepatic endosomal insulin receptor kinase: Role for the endosome in insulin signaling. J Biol Chem. 1995;270:10784–10791.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7537739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Pennock S, Chen X, Wang Z. Internalization of inactive EGF receptor into endosomes and the subsequent activation of endosome-associated EGF receptors: Epidermal growth factor. Sci STKE. 2002;2002:l17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12464704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergeron JJ, Di Guglielmo GM, Dahan S, et al.  Spatial and temporal regulation of receptor tyrosine kinase activation and intracellular signal transduction. Annu Rev Biochem. 2016;85:573–597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27023845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
