<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27725331</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2017</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0004-0614</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>69</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2016</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Archivos espanoles de urologia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Arch Esp Urol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Biodegradable catheters and urinary stents. When?].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>553</StartPage>
          <EndPage>564</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>553-564</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>One of the main wishes in the field of urinary catheters and stents is to arm them with biodegradable characteristics because we consider a failure of these devices the need for retrieval, the forgotten catheter syndrome as well as the adverse effects permanent devices cause after fulfilling their aim. The efforts focused in new designs, coatings and biomaterials aim to increase the biocompatibility of theses internal devices. Lately, there have been correct advances to answer the main challenges regarding biodegradable ureteral devices. Thus, modulation of the rate of degradation has been achieved thanks to new biomaterials and the use of copolymers that enable to choose the time of permanence as it is programmed with conventional double J catheters. Biocompatibility has improved with the use of new polymers that adapt better to the urine. Finally, one of the main problems is elimination of degraded fragments and experimentally it has be demonstrated that new designs elicit controlled degradation, from distal to proximal; using stranding and combination of copolymers degradation may be caused by dilution, reducing fragmentation to the last stages of life of the prosthesis. Moreover, it has been demonstrated that biodegradable catheters potentially may cause less urinary tract infection, less encrustation and predictably they will diminish catheter morbidity, since their degradation process reduces adverse effects. Regarding the development of biodegradable urethral stents, it is necessary to find biomaterials that enable maintaining their biomechanical properties in the long term, keeping open the urethral lumen both in patients with BPH and urethral stenosis. Modulation of the time of degradation of the prosthesis has been achieved, but the appearance of urothelial hyperplasia is still a constant in the initial phases after implantation. The development of drug eluting stents, anti-proliferative or anti-inflammatory, as well as biodegradable stents biocoated is a field from which it is expected the arrival of the solution of theses adverse effects. Therefore, many features need to be improved to obtain biodegradable stents, but over the last years some turning points have been accomplished thanks to the advances in Bioengineering, allowing to foresee safe and effective solutions in the nearest future.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Soria</LastName>
            <ForeName>F</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unidad de Endoscopia de la Fundación Centro de Cirugía de Mínima Invasión Jesús Usón. Cáceres. España.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morcillo</LastName>
            <ForeName>E</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unidad de Endoscopia de la Fundación Centro de Cirugía de Mínima Invasión Jesús Usón. Cáceres. España.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>López de Alda</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Servicio de Urología. Hospital Don Benito-Villanueva. Badajoz. España.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pastor</LastName>
            <ForeName>T</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Servicio de Urología. Hospital San Pedro de Alcántara. Cáceres. España.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sánchez-Margallo</LastName>
            <ForeName>F M</ForeName>
            <Initials>FM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unidad de Endoscopia de la Fundación Centro de Cirugía de Mínima Invasión Jesús Usón. Cáceres. España.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>spa</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Catéteres y stents urinarios biodegradables. ¿Para cuándo?</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Spain</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Arch Esp Urol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0064757</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0004-0614</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020341" MajorTopicYN="Y">Absorbable Implants</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004867" MajorTopicYN="N">Equipment Design</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015607" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stents</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062885" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Catheters</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27725331</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
