<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27789971</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-7074</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2016</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of general medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Gen Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Morgellons disease: a filamentous borrelial dermatitis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>349</StartPage>
          <EndPage>354</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>349-354</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Morgellons disease (MD) is a dermopathy characterized by multicolored filaments that lie under, are embedded in, or project from skin. Although MD was initially considered to be a delusional disorder, recent studies have demonstrated that the dermopathy is associated with tickborne infection, that the filaments are composed of keratin and collagen, and that they result from proliferation of keratinocytes and fibroblasts in epithelial tissue. Culture, histopathological and molecular evidence of spirochetal infection associated with MD has been presented in several published studies using a variety of techniques. Spirochetes genetically identified as <i>Borrelia burgdorferi</i> sensu stricto predominate as the infective agent in most of the Morgellons skin specimens studied so far. Other species of <i>Borrelia</i> including <i>Borrelia garinii</i>, <i>Borrelia miyamotoi</i>, and <i>Borrelia hermsii</i> have also been detected in skin specimens taken from MD patients. The optimal treatment for MD remains to be determined.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Middelveen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marianne J</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Lyme and Associated Diseases Society, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stricker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Raphael B</ForeName>
            <Initials>RB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Lyme and Associated Diseases Society, Bethesda, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Gen Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101515487</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1178-7074</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Borrelia burgdorferi</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lyme disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Morgellons disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dermatitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spirochetes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27789971</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5072536</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJGM.S116608</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">ijgm-9-349</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kellett CE. Sir Thomas Browne and the disease called Morgellons. Ann Med Hist, n.s., VII. 1935;7:467–479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savely G, Leitao MM. Skin lesions and crawling sensation: disease or delusion? Adv Nurse Pract. 2005;13(5):16–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15898309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savely VR, Leitao MM, Stricker RB. The mystery of Morgellons disease: infection or delusion? Am J Clin Dermatol. 2006;7(1):1–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16489838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savely VR, Stricker RB. Morgellons disease: the mystery unfolds. Expert Rev Dermatol. 2007;2(5):585–591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savely VR, Stricker RB. Morgellons disease: analysis of a population with clinically confirmed microscopic subcutaneous fibers of unknown etiology. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2010;3:67–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3047951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21437061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middelveen MJ, Stricker RB. Filament formation associated with spirochetal infection: a comparative approach to Morgellons disease. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2011;4:167–177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3257881</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22253541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayne PJ. Clinical determinants of Lyme borreliosis, babesiosis, bartonellosis, anaplasmosis, and ehrlichiosis in an Australian cohort. Int J Gen Med. 2015;8:15–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4278782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25565883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berry SL, Read DH, Famula TR, Mongini A, Dopfer D. Long-term observations on the dynamics of bovine digital dermatitis lesions on a California dairy after topical treatment with lincomycin HCl. Vet J. 2012;193(3):654–658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22892182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez A, Cook NB, Bernardoni ND, et al.  An experimental infection model to induce digital dermatitis infection in cattle. J Dairy Sci. 2012;95(4):1821–1830.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22459830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middelveen MJ, Rasmussen EH, Kahn DG, Stricker RB. Morgellons disease: a chemical and light microscopic study. J Clin Exp Dermatol Res. 2012;3:140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middelveen MJ, Mayne PJ, Kahn DG, Stricker RB. Characterization and evolution of dermal filaments from patients with Morgellons disease. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2013;6:1–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3544355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23326202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middelveen MJ, Burugu D, Poruri A, et al.  Association of spirochetal infection with Morgellons disease. F1000Res. 2013;2:25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3954163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middelveen MJ, Bandoski C, Burke J, et al.  Exploring the association between Morgellons disease and Lyme disease: identification of Borrelia burgdorferi in Morgellons disease patients. BMC Dermatol. 2015;15:1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4328066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25879673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galván I, Jorge A, Ito K, Tabuchi K, Solano F, Wakamatsu K. Raman spectroscopy as a non-invasive technique for the quantification of melanins in feathers and hairs. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2013;26(6):917–923.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23890020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayne P, English JS, Kilbane EJ, Burke JM, Middelveen MJ, Stricker RB. Morgellons: a novel dermatological perspective as the multisystem infective disease borreliosis. F1000Res. 2013;2:118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah JS. Morgellons disease – chronic form of Borreliainfection?; Presented at: 9th Annual Medical-Scientific Conference on Morgellons Disease; April 30–May 1, 2016; Austin, TX.  [Accessed September 30, 2016].  Available from:  http://www.thecehf.org/jyotsna-s-shahphd.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen L, Saylor-Hefley C. Morgellons under investigation: identification of associated microorganisms by molecular analysis of epithelial samples; Presented at: 7th Annual Medical-Scientific Conference on Morgellons Disease; March 29–30, 2014; Austin, TX.  [Accessed September 30, 2016].  Available from:  http://www.thecehf.org/resources/OSU%20_2015%20_Research.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mursic VP, Wanner G, Reinhardt S, Wilske B, Busch U, Marget W. Formation and cultivation of Borrelia burgdorferi spheroplast L-form variants. Infection. 1996;24(3):218–226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8811359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brorson O, Brorson SH. An in vitro study of the susceptibility of mobile and cystic forms of Borrelia burgdorferi to tinidazole. Int Microbiol. 2004;7(2):139–142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15248163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandoski C. Evidence for the presence of human pathogens Borreliaand Helicobacterin Morgellons patients’ skin samples; Presented at: 7th Annual Medical-Scientific Conference on Morgellons Disease; March 29–30, 2014; Austin, TX.  [Accessed September 30, 2016].  Available from:  http://www.thecehf.org/cheryl-bandoski.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgilis K, Peacock M, Klempner MS. Fibroblasts protect the Lyme disease spirochete, Borrelia burgdorferi, from ceftriaxone in vitro. J Infect Dis. 1992;166(2):440–444.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1634816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klempner MS, Noring R, Rogers RA. Invasion of human skin fibroblasts by the Lyme disease spirochete Borrelia burgdorferi. J Infect Dis. 1993;167(5):1074–1081.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8486939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chmielewski T, Tylewska-Wierzbanowska S. Interactions between Borrelia burgdorferi and mouse fibroblasts. Pol J Microbiol. 2010;59(3):157–160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21033577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearson ML, Selby JV, Katz KA, et al. Unexplained Dermopathy Study Team  Clinical, epidemiologic, histopathologic and molecular features of an unexplained dermopathy. PLoS One. 2012;7(1):e29908.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3266263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22295070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Lyme disease: diagnosis, treatment and testing. 2016.  [Accessed September 30, 2016].  Available from:  http://www.cdc.gov/lyme/healthcare/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dattwyler RJ, Volkman DJ, Luft BJ, Halperin JJ, Thomas J, Golightly MG. Seronegative Lyme disease. N Engl J Med. 1988;319:1441–1446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3054554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stricker RB, Johnson L. Serologic tests for Lyme disease: more smoke and mirrors. Clin Infect Dis. 2008;47(8):1111–1112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18800935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girard YA, Federova N, Lane RS. Genetic diversity of Borrelia burgdorferi and detection of B. bissettii-like DNA in serum of north coastal California residents. J Clin Microbiol. 2011;49(3):945–954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3067736</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogden NH, Margos G, Aanensen DM, et al.  Investigation of genotypes of Borrelia burgdorferi in Ixodes scapularis ticks collected during surveillance in Canada. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2011;77(10):3244–3254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21421790</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Péter O, Bretz AG, Bee D. Occurrence of different genospecies of Borrelia burgdorferi sensu lato in Ixodid ticks of Valais, Switzerland. Eur J Epidemiol. 1995;11(4):463–467.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8549716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lange R, Seyyedi S. Evidence of a Lyme borreliosis infection from the viewpoint of laboratory medicine. Int J Med Microbiol. 2002;291(33):120–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12141736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt BL. PCR in laboratory diagnosis of human Borrelia burgdorferi infections. Clin Microbiol Rev. 1997;10(1):185–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC172948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8993863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steere AC, Malawista SE, Snydman DR, et al.  Lyme arthritis: an epidemic of oligoarticular arthritis in children and adults in three connecticut communities. Arthritis Rheum. 1977;20(1):7–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">836338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ekbom KA. Praeseniler Dermat-zooenwahn. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1938;13:227–259.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keller A, Graefen A, Ball M, et al.  New insights into the Tyrolean Iceman’s origin and phenotype as inferred by whole-genome sequencing. Nat Commun. 2012;3:698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22426219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fallon BA, Schwartzberg M, Bransfield R, et al.  Late-stage neuropsychiatric Lyme borreliosis. Differential diagnosis and treatment. Psychosomatics. 1995;36(3):295–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7638317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bransfield RC. The psychoimmunology of Lyme/tick-borne diseases and its association with neuropsychatric symptoms. Open Neurol J. 2012;6:88–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3474947</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23091569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao HM, Hong JS. Why neurodegenerative diseases are progressive: uncontrolled inflammation drives disease progression. Trends Immunol. 2008;29(8):357–365.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4794280</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18599350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattinley DW, Koda MM. Association between Lyme disease and schizoaffective disorder, bipolar type: is it inflammation mediated? Indian J Psychol Med. 2015;37(2):243–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4418265</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kristensson K. Microbes’ roadmap to neurons. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2011;12(6):345–357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21587289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fallon BA, Levi ES, Schweitzer PJ, Hardesty D. Inflammation and central nervous system Lyme disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2010;37(3):534–541.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19944760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harvey WT, Bransfield RC, Mercer DE, Wright AJ, Ricchi RM, Leitao MM. Morgellons disease, illuminating an undefined illness: a case series. J Med Case Rep. 2009;3:8243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2737752</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19830222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cameron DJ, Johnson LB, Maloney EL. Evidence assessments and guideline recommendations in Lyme disease: the clinical management of known tick bites, erythema migrans rashes and persistent disease. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2014;12(9):1103–1135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4196523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25077519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horowitz RI, Freeman PR. The use of dapsone as a novel “persister” drug in the treatment of chronic Lyme disease/post treatment Lyme disease syndrome. J Clin Exp Dermatol Res. 2016;7(3):345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
