<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">27821390</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1555-905X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical journal of the American Society of Nephrology : CJASN</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Update on Lupus Nephritis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>825</StartPage>
          <EndPage>835</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>825-835</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2215/CJN.05780616</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>SLE is a chronic inflammatory disease that affects the kidneys in about 50% of patients. Lupus nephritis is a major risk factor for overall morbidity and mortality in SLE, and despite potent anti-inflammatory and immunosuppressive therapies still ends in CKD or ESRD for too many patients. This review highlights recent updates in our understanding of disease epidemiology, genetics, pathogenesis, and treatment in an effort to establish a framework for lupus nephritis management that is patient-specific and oriented toward maintaining long-term kidney function in patients with lupus.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2017 by the American Society of Nephrology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Almaani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Salem</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, The Ohio State Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexa</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, The Ohio State Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rovin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brad H</ForeName>
            <Initials>BH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, The Ohio State Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio Rovin.1@osu.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>U01 DK096927</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101271570</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1555-9041</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007676" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Failure, Chronic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011237" MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive Value of Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Discoid</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology and outcomes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lupus Erythematosus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Renal Insufficiency</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glomerular disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glomerulonephritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">humans</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunosuppression</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kidney</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kidney failure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lupus nephritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nephritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27821390</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5477208</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.05780616</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">CJN.05780616</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartzman-Morris J, Putterman C: Gender differences in the pathogenesis and outcome of lupus and of lupus nephritis. Clin Dev Immunol
2012: 604892, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3368358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22690240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danchenko N, Satia JA, Anthony MS: Epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus: a comparison of worldwide disease burden. Lupus
15: 308–318, 2006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16761508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mina R, Brunner HI: Pediatric lupus--are there differences in presentation, genetics, response to therapy, and damage accrual compared with adult lupus?
Rheum Dis Clin North Am
36: 53–80, vii–viii, 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2837537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osio-Salido E, Manapat-Reyes H: Epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus in Asia. Lupus
19: 1365–1373, 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20947544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Symmons DPM: Frequency of lupus in people of African origin. Lupus
4: 176–178, 1995</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7655486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiffin N, Hodkinson B, Okpechi I: Lupus in Africa: can we dispel the myths and face the challenges?
Lupus
23: 102–111, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24174511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pons-Estel GJ, Alarcón GS, Scofield L, Reinlib L, Cooper GS: Understanding the epidemiology and progression of systemic lupus erythematosus. Semin Arthritis Rheum
39: 257–268, 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2813992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19136143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastian HM, Roseman JM, McGwin G Jr, Alarcón GS, Friedman AW, Fessler BJ, Baethge BA, Reveille JD; LUMINA Study Group. LUpus in MInority populations: NAture vs nurture: Systemic lupus erythematosus in three ethnic groups. XII. Risk factors for lupus nephritis after diagnosis. Lupus
11: 152–160, 2002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12004788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanly JG, O’Keeffe AG, Su L, Urowitz MB, Romero-Diaz J, Gordon C, Bae S-C, Bernatsky S, Clarke AE, Wallace DJ, Merrill JT, Isenberg DA, Rahman A, Ginzler EM, Fortin P, Gladman DD, Sanchez-Guerrero J, Petri M, Bruce IN, Dooley MA, Ramsey-Goldman R, Aranow C, Alarcón GS, Fessler BJ, Steinsson K, Nived O, Sturfelt GK, Manzi S, Khamashta MA, van Vollenhoven RF, Zoma AA, Ramos-Casals M, Ruiz-Irastorza G, Lim SS, Stoll T, Inanc M, Kalunian KC, Kamen DL, Maddison P, Peschken CA, Jacobsen S, Askanase A, Theriault C, Thompson K, Farewell V: The frequency and outcome of lupus nephritis: results from an international inception cohort study. Rheumatology (Oxford)
55: 252–262, 2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4939728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26342222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Contreras G, Lenz O, Pardo V, Borja E, Cely C, Iqbal K, Nahar N, de La Cuesta C, Hurtado A, Fornoni A, Beltran-Garcia L, Asif A, Young L, Diego J, Zachariah M, Smith-Norwood B: Outcomes in African Americans and Hispanics with lupus nephritis. Kidney Int
69: 1846–1851, 2006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16598205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Shaughnessy MM, Montez-Rath ME, Lafayette RA, Winkelmayer WC: Patient characteristics and outcomes by GN subtype in ESRD. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol
10: 1170–1178, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4491300</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopkinson ND, Jenkinson C, Muir KR, Doherty M, Powell RJ: Racial group: Racial group, socioeconomic status, and the development of persistent proteinuria in systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Rheum Dis
59: 116–119, 2000</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10666166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huong DL, Papo T, Beaufils H, Wechsler B, Blétry O, Baumelou A, Godeau P, Piette J-C: Renal involvement in systemic lupus erythematosus. A study of 180 patients from a single center. Medicine (Baltimore)
78: 148–166, 1999</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10352647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pons-Estel GJ, Catoggio LJ, Cardiel MH, Bonfa E, Caeiro F, Sato E, Massardo L, Molina-Restrepo JF, Toledano MG, Barile-Fabris LA, Amigo MC, Acevedo-Vásquez EM, Abadi I, Wojdyla D, Alarcón-Riquelme ME, Alarcón GS, Pons-Estel BA; GLADEL: Lupus in Latin-American patients: lessons from the GLADEL cohort. Lupus
24: 536–545, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25697768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman CH, Hiraki LT, Liu J, Fischer MA, Solomon DH, Alarcón GS, Winkelmayer WC, Costenbader KH: Epidemiology and sociodemographics of systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis among US adults with Medicaid coverage, 2000-2004. Arthritis Rheum
65: 753–763, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23203603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgos PI, McGwin G, Pons-Estel GJ, Reveille JD, Alarcón GS, Vilá LM: US patients of Hispanic and African ancestry develop lupus nephritis early in the disease course: Data from LUMINA, a multiethnic US cohort (LUMINA LXXIV). Ann Rheum Dis
70: 393–394, 2011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3764916</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20627945</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nee R, Martinez-Osorio J, Yuan CM, Little DJ, Watson MA, Agodoa L, Abbott KC: Survival Disparity of African American Versus Non-African American Patients With ESRD Due to SLE. Am J Kidney Dis
66: 630–637, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26002293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Austin HA 3rd, Boumpas DT, Vaughan EM, Balow JE: High-risk features of lupus nephritis: importance of race and clinical and histological factors in 166 patients. Nephrol Dial Transplant
10: 1620–1628, 1995</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8559480</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reveille JD, Moulds JM, Ahn C, Friedman AW, Baethge B, Roseman J, Straaton KV, Alarcón GS: Systemic lupus erythematosus in three ethnic groups: I. The effects of HLA class II, C4, and CR1 alleles, socioeconomic factors, and ethnicity at disease onset. LUMINA Study Group. Lupus in minority populations, nature versus nurture. Arthritis Rheum
41: 1161–1172, 1998</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9663471</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salmon JE, Millard S, Schachter LA, Arnett FC, Ginzler EM, Gourley MF, Ramsey-Goldman R, Peterson MG, Kimberly RP: Fc gamma RIIA alleles are heritable risk factors for lupus nephritis in African Americans. J Clin Invest
97: 1348–1354, 1996</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC507190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8636449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korbet SM, Schwartz MM, Evans J, Lewis EJ; Collaborative Study Group: Severe lupus nephritis: racial differences in presentation and outcome. J Am Soc Nephrol
18: 244–254, 2007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin CP, Adrianto I, Lessard CJ, Kelly JA, Kaufman KM, Guthridge JM, Freedman BI, Anaya JM, Alarcón-Riquelme ME, Pons-Estel BA, Martin J, Glenn S, Adler A, Bae SC, Park SY, Bang SY, Song YW, Boackle SA, Brown EE, Edberg JC, Alarcón GS, Petri MA, Criswell LA, Ramsey-Goldman R, Reveille JD, Vila LM, Gilkeson GS, Kamen DL, Ziegler J, Jacob CO, Rasmussen A, James JA, Kimberly RP, Merrill JT, Niewold TB, Scofield RH, Stevens AM, Tsao BP, Vyse TJ, Langefeld CD, Moser KL, Harley JB, Gaffney PM, Montgomery CG; BIOLUPUS and GENLES Networks: Role of MYH9 and APOL1 in African and non-African populations with lupus nephritis. Genes Immun
13: 232–238, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3330160</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22189356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freedman BI, Langefeld CD, Andringa KK, Croker JA, Williams AH, Garner NE, Birmingham DJ, Hebert LA, Hicks PJ, Segal MS, Edberg JC, Brown EE, Alarcón GS, Costenbader KH, Comeau ME, Criswell LA, Harley JB, James JA, Kamen DL, Lim SS, Merrill JT, Sivils KL, Niewold TB, Patel NM, Petri M, Ramsey-Goldman R, Reveille JD, Salmon JE, Tsao BP, Gibson KL, Byers JR, Vinnikova AK, Lea JP, Julian BA, Kimberly RP; Lupus Nephritis–End‐Stage Renal Disease Consortium: End-stage renal disease in African Americans with lupus nephritis is associated with APOL1. Arthritis Rheumatol
66: 390–396, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24504811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastian HM, Alarcón GS, Roseman JM, McGwin G Jr, Vilá LM, Fessler BJ, Reveille JD; LUMINA Study Group: Systemic lupus erythematosus in a multiethnic US cohort (LUMINA) XL II: factors predictive of new or worsening proteinuria. Rheumatology (Oxford)
46: 683–689, 2007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17132694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarty GA, Harley JB, Reichlin M: A distinctive autoantibody profile in black female patients with lupus nephritis. Arthritis Rheum
36: 1560–1565, 1993</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8240432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alarcón GS: Multiethnic lupus cohorts: what have they taught us?
Reumatol Clin
7: 3–6, 2011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21794772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tektonidou M, Dasgupta A, Ward M: Risk of end-stage renal disease in patients with lupus nephritis, 1970-2015: A systematic review and Bayesian meta-analysis. Arthritis Rheumatol
68:1432– 1441, 2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5071782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yap DYH, Tang CSO, Ma MKM, Lam MF, Chan TM: Survival analysis and causes of mortality in patients with lupus nephritis. Nephrol Dial Transplant
27: 3248–3254, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22523116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lerang K, Gilboe I-M, Steinar Thelle D, Gran JT: Mortality and years of potential life loss in systemic lupus erythematosus: a population-based cohort study. Lupus
23: 1546–1552, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25209070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernatsky S, Boivin JF, Joseph L, Manzi S, Ginzler E, Gladman DD, Urowitz M, Fortin PR, Petri M, Barr S, Gordon C, Bae SC, Isenberg D, Zoma A, Aranow C, Dooley MA, Nived O, Sturfelt G, Steinsson K, Alarcón G, Senécal JL, Zummer M, Hanly J, Ensworth S, Pope J, Edworthy S, Rahman A, Sibley J, El-Gabalawy H, McCarthy T, St Pierre Y, Clarke A, Ramsey-Goldman R: Mortality in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum
54: 2550–2557, 2006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faurschou M, Dreyer L, Kamper AL, Starklint H, Jacobsen S: Long-term mortality and renal outcome in a cohort of 100 patients with lupus nephritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)
62: 873–880, 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YE, Korbet SM, Katz RS, Schwartz MM, Lewis EJ; Collaborative Study Group: Value of a complete or partial remission in severe lupus nephritis. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol
3: 46–53, 2008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2390978</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18003764</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munroe ME, James JA: Genetics of Lupus Nephritis: Clinical Implications. Semin Nephrol
35: 396–409, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4653095</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu Z, Zhang P, Tong Y: Value of HLA-DR genotype in systemic lupus erythematosus and lupus nephritis: a meta-analysis. Int J Rheum Dis
18: 17–28, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25546242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyadera H, Ohashi J, Lernmark Å, Kitamura T, Tokunaga K: Cell-surface MHC density profiling reveals instability of autoimmunity-associated HLA. J Clin Invest
125: 275–291, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4382229</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25485681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyadera H, Tokunaga K: Associations of human leukocyte antigens with autoimmune diseases: challenges in identifying the mechanism. J Hum Genet
60: 697–702, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26290149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung SA, Brown EE, Williams AH, Ramos PS, Berthier CC, Bhangale T, Alarcon-Riquelme ME, Behrens TW, Criswell LA, Graham DC, Demirci FY, Edberg JC, Gaffney PM, Harley JB, Jacob CO, Kamboh MI, Kelly JA, Manzi S, Moser-Sivils KL, Russell LP, Petri M, Tsao BP, Vyse TJ, Zidovetzki R, Kretzler M, Kimberly RP, Freedman BI, Graham RR, Langefeld CD; International Consortium for Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Genetics: Lupus nephritis susceptibility loci in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Am Soc Nephrol
25: 2859–2870, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4243339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24925725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raffler J, Friedrich N, Arnold M, Kacprowski T, Rueedi R, Altmaier E, Bergmann S, Budde K, Gieger C, Homuth G, Pietzner M, Römisch-Margl W, Strauch K, Völzke H, Waldenberger M, Wallaschofski H, Nauck M, Völker U, Kastenmüller G, Suhre K: Genome-Wide Association Study with Targeted and Non-targeted NMR Metabolomics Identifies 15 Novel Loci of Urinary Human Metabolic Individuality. PLoS Genet
11: e1005487, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26352407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai LJ, Hsiao SH, Tsai LM, Lin CY, Tsai JJ, Liou DM, Lan JL: The sodium-dependent glucose cotransporter SLC5A11 as an autoimmune modifier gene in SLE. Tissue Antigens
71: 114–126, 2008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18069935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banchereau R, Hong S, Cantarel B, Baldwin N, Baisch J, Edens M, Cepika AM, Acs P, Turner J, Anguiano E, Vinod P, Kahn S, Obermoser G, Blankenship D, Wakeland E, Nassi L, Gotte A, Punaro M, Liu YJ, Banchereau J, Rossello-Urgell J, Wright T, Pascual V: Personalized Immunomonitoring Uncovers Molecular Networks that Stratify Lupus Patients. Cell
165: 551–565, 2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5426482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27040498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villanueva E, Yalavarthi S, Berthier CC, Hodgin JB, Khandpur R, Lin AM, Rubin CJ, Zhao W, Olsen SH, Klinker M, Shealy D, Denny MF, Plumas J, Chaperot L, Kretzler M, Bruce AT, Kaplan MJ: Netting neutrophils induce endothelial damage, infiltrate tissues, and expose immunostimulatory molecules in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol
187: 538–552, 2011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119769</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21613614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakkim A, Fürnrohr BG, Amann K, Laube B, Abed UA, Brinkmann V, Herrmann M, Voll RE, Zychlinsky A: Impairment of neutrophil extracellular trap degradation is associated with lupus nephritis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
107: 9813–9818, 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2906830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20439745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birmingham DJ, Bitter JE, Ndukwe EG, Dials S, Gullo TR, Conroy S, Nagaraja HN, Rovin BH, Hebert LA: Relationship of Circulating Anti-C3b and Anti-C1q IgG to Lupus Nephritis and Its Flare. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol
11: 47–53, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26700439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pang Y, Yang XW, Song Y, Yu F, Zhao MH: Anti-C1q autoantibodies from active lupus nephritis patients could inhibit the clearance of apoptotic cells and complement classical pathway activation mediated by C1q in vitro. Immunobiology
219: 980–989, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gargiulo ML, Gómez G, Khoury M, Collado MV, Suárez L, Álvarez C, Sarano J: Association between the presence of anti-C1q antibodies and active nephritis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Medicina (B Aires)
75: 23–28, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25637896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKinney EF, Lee JC, Jayne DR, Lyons PA, Smith KG: T-cell exhaustion, co-stimulation and clinical outcome in autoimmunity and infection. Nature
523: 612–616, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4623162</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26123020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christopher-Stine L, Siedner M, Lin J, Haas M, Parekh H, Petri M, Fine DM: Renal biopsy in lupus patients with low levels of proteinuria. J Rheumatol
34: 332–335, 2007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17183619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fiehn C, Hajjar Y, Mueller K, Waldherr R, Ho AD, Andrassy K: Improved clinical outcome of lupus nephritis during the past decade: importance of early diagnosis and treatment. Ann Rheum Dis
62: 435–439, 2003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1754523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12695156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rovin BH: Glomerular disease: Lupus nephritis treatment: are we beyond cyclophosphamide?
Nat Rev Nephrol
5: 492–494, 2009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19701224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song D, Wu LH, Wang FM, Yang XW, Zhu D, Chen M, Yu F, Liu G, Zhao MH: The spectrum of renal thrombotic microangiopathy in lupus nephritis. Arthritis Res Ther
15: R12, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3672792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23320601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu W, Chen Y, Wang S, Chen H, Liu Z, Zeng C, Zhang H, Liu Z: Clinical-Morphological Features and Outcomes of Lupus Podocytopathy. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol
11: 585–592, 2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4822663</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26983707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh AK, Ucci A, Madias NE: Predominant tubulointerstitial lupus nephritis. Am J Kidney Dis
27: 273–278, 1996</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8659506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weening JJ, D’Agati VD, Schwartz MM, Seshan SV, Alpers CE, Appel GB, Balow JE, Bruijn JA, Cook T, Ferrario F, Fogo AB, Ginzler EM, Hebert L, Hill G, Hill P, Jennette JC, Kong NC, Lesavre P, Lockshin M, Looi L-M, Makino H, Moura LA, Nagata M: The classification of glomerulonephritis in systemic lupus erythematosus revisited. J Am Soc Nephrol
15: 241–250, 2004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson KS, Huang JF, Zhu J, D’Agati V, Liu X, Miller N, Erlander MG, Jackson MR, Winchester RJ: Characterization of heterogeneity in the molecular pathogenesis of lupus nephritis from transcriptional profiles of laser-captured glomeruli. J Clin Invest
113: 1722–1733, 2004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC420500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15199407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bethunaickan R, Berthier CC, Zhang W, Kretzler M, Davidson A: Comparative transcriptional profiling of 3 murine models of SLE nephritis reveals both unique and shared regulatory networks. PLoS One
8: e77489, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3805607</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24167575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parikh SV, Malvar A, Song H, Alberton V, Lococo B, Vance J, Zhang J, Yu L, Rovin BH: Characterising the immune profile of the kidney biopsy at lupus nephritis flare differentiates early treatment responders from non-responders. Lupus Sci Med
2: e000112, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4654163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26629350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malvar A, Pirruccio P, Alberton V, Lococo B, Recalde C, Fazini B, Nagaraja H, Indrakanti D, Rovin BH: Histologic versus clinical remission in proliferative lupus nephritis [published online ahead of print August 6, 2015]. Nephrol Dial Transplant
doi:10.1093/ndt/gfv296, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26250434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zickert A, Sundelin B, Svenungsson E, Gunnarsson I: Role of early repeated renal biopsies in lupus nephritis. Lupus Sci Med
1: e000018, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4213828</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25379188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvarado AS, Malvar A, Lococo B, Alberton V, Toniolo F, Nagaraja HN, Rovin BH: The value of repeat kidney biopsy in quiescent Argentinian lupus nephritis patients. Lupus
23: 840–847, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24401872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kidney Disease Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) Glomerulonephritis Work Group: Kidney Int Suppl
2: 139–274, 2012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parikh SV, Alvarado A, Malvar A, Rovin BH: The Kidney Biopsy in Lupus Nephritis: Past, Present, and Future. Semin Nephrol
35: 465–477, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill GS, Delahousse M, Nochy D, Rémy P, Mignon F, Méry JP, Bariéty J: Predictive power of the second renal biopsy in lupus nephritis: significance of macrophages. Kidney Int
59: 304–316, 2001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11135084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill GS, Delahousse M, Nochy D, Tomkiewicz E, Rémy P, Mignon F, Méry JP: A new morphologic index for the evaluation of renal biopsies in lupus nephritis. Kidney Int
58: 1160–1173, 2000</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10972679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Austin HA 3rd, Muenz LR, Joyce KM, Antonovych TA, Kullick ME, Klippel JH, Decker JL, Balow JE: Prognostic factors in lupus nephritis. Contribution of renal histologic data. Am J Med
75: 382–391, 1983</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6351607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alsuwaida A, Husain S, Alghonaim M, AlOudah N, Alwakeel J, ullah A, Kfoury H: Strategy for second kidney biopsy in patients with lupus nephritis. Nephrol Dial Transplant
27: 1472–1478, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21931127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bajaj S, Albert L, Gladman DD, Urowitz MB, Hallett DC, Ritchie S: Serial renal biopsy in systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol
27: 2822–2826, 2000</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11128670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daleboudt GM, Bajema IM, Goemaere NN, van Laar JM, Bruijn JA, Berger SP: The clinical relevance of a repeat biopsy in lupus nephritis flares. Nephrol Dial Transplant
24: 3712–3717, 2009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greloni G, Scolnik M, Marin J, Lancioni E, Quiroz C, Zacariaz J, De la Iglesia Niveyro P, Christiansen S, Pierangelo MA, Varela CF, Rosa-Diez GJ, Catoggio LJ, Soriano ER: Value of repeat biopsy in lupus nephritis flares. Lupus Sci Med
1: e000004, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4225737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25396056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moroni G, Pasquali S, Quaglini S, Banfi G, Casanova S, Maccario M, Zucchelli P, Ponticelli C: Clinical and prognostic value of serial renal biopsies in lupus nephritis. Am J Kidney Dis
34: 530–539, 1999</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10469865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pagni F, Galimberti S, Goffredo P, Basciu M, Malachina S, Pilla D, Galbiati E, Ferrario F: The value of repeat biopsy in the management of lupus nephritis: an international multicentre study in a large cohort of patients. Nephrol Dial Transplant
28: 3014–3023, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23975838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginzler EM, Bollet AJ, Friedman EA: The natural history and response to therapy of lupus nephritis. Annu Rev Med
31: 463–487, 1980</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6994624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costenbader KH, Desai A, Alarcón GS, Hiraki LT, Shaykevich T, Brookhart MA, Massarotti E, Lu B, Solomon DH, Winkelmayer WC: Trends in the incidence, demographics, and outcomes of end-stage renal disease due to lupus nephritis in the US from 1995 to 2006. Arthritis Rheum
63: 1681–1688, 2011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3106117</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21445962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appel GB, Contreras G, Dooley MA, Ginzler EM, Isenberg D, Jayne D, Li L-S, Mysler E, Sánchez-Guerrero J, Solomons N, Wofsy D; Aspreva Lupus Management Study Group: Mycophenolate mofetil versus cyclophosphamide for induction treatment of lupus nephritis. J Am Soc Nephrol
20: 1103–1112, 2009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houssiau FA, Vasconcelos C, D’Cruz D, Sebastiani GD, Garrido Ed ER, Danieli MG, Abramovicz D, Blockmans D, Mathieu A, Direskeneli H, Galeazzi M, Gül A, Levy Y, Petera P, Popovic R, Petrovic R, Sinico RA, Cattaneo R, Font J, Depresseux G, Cosyns JP, Cervera R: Immunosuppressive therapy in lupus nephritis: the Euro-Lupus Nephritis Trial, a randomized trial of low-dose versus high-dose intravenous cyclophosphamide. Arthritis Rheum
46: 2121–2131, 2002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12209517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rovin BH, Furie R, Latinis K, Looney RJ, Fervenza FC, Sanchez-Guerrero J, Maciuca R, Zhang D, Garg JP, Brunetta P, Appel G; LUNAR Investigator Group: Efficacy and safety of rituximab in patients with active proliferative lupus nephritis: the Lupus Nephritis Assessment with Rituximab study. Arthritis Rheum
64: 1215–1226, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22231479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parikh SV, Nagaraja HN, Hebert L, Rovin BH: Renal flare as a predictor of incident and progressive CKD in patients with lupus nephritis. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol
9: 279–284, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913239</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24262502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dooley MA, Jayne D, Ginzler EM, Isenberg D, Olsen NJ, Wofsy D, Eitner F, Appel GB, Contreras G, Lisk L, Solomons N; ALMS Group: Mycophenolate versus azathioprine as maintenance therapy for lupus nephritis. N Engl J Med
365: 1886–1895, 2011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22087680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houssiau FA, Vasconcelos C, D’Cruz D, Sebastiani GD, de Ramon Garrido E, Danieli MG, Abramovicz D, Blockmans D, Cauli A, Direskeneli H, Galeazzi M, Gül A, Levy Y, Petera P, Popovic R, Petrovic R, Sinico RA, Cattaneo R, Font J, Depresseux G, Cosyns J-P, Cervera R: The 10-year follow-up data of the Euro-Lupus Nephritis Trial comparing low-dose and high-dose intravenous cyclophosphamide. Ann Rheum Dis
69: 61–64, 2010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19155235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation> Parikh SV, Rovin BH: Current and Emerging Therapies for Lupus Nephritis [published online ahead of print June 9, 2016]. J Am Soc Nephrol doi:10.1681/ASN.2016040415, 2016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5042683</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27283496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dall’Era M, Levesque V, Solomons N, Truman M, Wofsy D: Identification of clinical and serological factors during induction treatment of lupus nephritis that are associated with renal outcome. Lupus Sci Med
2: e000089, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26023331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Austin HAI 3rd, Klippel JH, Balow JE, le Riche NGH, Steinberg AD, Plotz PH, Decker JL: Therapy of lupus nephritis. Controlled trial of prednisone and cytotoxic drugs. N Engl J Med
314: 614–619, 1986</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3511372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ACCESS Trial Group: Treatment of lupus nephritis with abatacept: the Abatacept and Cyclophosphamide Combination Efficacy and Safety Study. Arthritis Rheumatol
66: 3096–3104, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528976</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25403681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galbraith L, Manns B, Hemmelgarn B, Walsh M: The Steroids In the Maintenance of remission of Proliferative Lupus nephritis (SIMPL) pilot trial. Can J Kidney Health Dis
1: 30, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4349625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25780619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naik A, Sharma S, Quigg RJ: Complement regulation in renal disease models. Semin Nephrol
33: 575–585, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24161042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao H, Dairaghi DJ, Powers JP, Ertl LS, Baumgart T, Wang Y, Seitz LC, Penfold ME, Gan L, Hu P, Lu B, Gerard NP, Gerard C, Schall TJ, Jaen JC, Falk RJ, Jennette JC: C5a receptor (CD88) blockade protects against MPO-ANCA GN. J Am Soc Nephrol
25: 225–231, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904560</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24179165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enia G, Catalano C, Misefari V, Salnitro F, Mundo N, Tetta C, Maggiore Q: Complement activated leucopenia during hemodialysis: effect of pulse methyl-prednisolone. Int J Artif Organs
13: 98–102, 1990</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2347663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vollmer TL, Sorensen PS, Selmaj K, Zipp F, Havrdova E, Cohen JA, Sasson N, Gilgun-Sherki Y, Arnold DL; BRAVO Study Group: A randomized placebo-controlled phase III trial of oral laquinimod for multiple sclerosis. J Neurol
261: 773–783, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24535134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourenço EV, Wong M, Hahn BH, Palma-Diaz MF, Skaggs BJ: Laquinimod delays and suppresses nephritis in lupus-prone mice and affects both myeloid and lymphoid immune cells. Arthritis Rheumatol
66: 674–685, 2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24574228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayne D, Appel G, Chan TM, Mimrod D, Spiegelstein O, Barkay H, Weiss R, Wofsy D: The pharmacokinetics of laquinimod and mycophenolate mofetil during treatment of active lupus nephritis. Presented at the 2013 American Society of Nephrology Annual Meeting, Atlanta, GA, November 5–10, 2013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng J, Lai P, Lv M, Lin S, Ling W, Geng S, Luo C, Liu X, Du X: Bortezomib modulates regulatory T cell subpopulations in the process of acute graft-versus-host disease. Clin Lab
59: 51–58, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23505906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dooley MA, Houssiau F, Aranow C, D’Cruz DP, Askanase A, Roth DA, Zhong ZJ, Cooper S, Freimuth WW, Ginzler EM; BLISS-52 and -76 Study Groups: Effect of belimumab treatment on renal outcomes: results from the phase 3 belimumab clinical trials in patients with SLE. Lupus
22: 63–72, 2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23263865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rovin BH, Dooley MA, Radhakrishnan J, Ginzler EM, Forrester TD, Anderson PW: The impact of tabalumab on the kidney in systemic lupus erythematosus: results from two phase 3 randomized, clinical trials [published online ahead of print, may 24, 2016]. Lupus
doi:10.1177/0961203316650734, 2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27220348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher KM, Lauder S, Rees IW, Gallimore AM, Godkin AJ: Type I interferon (IFN alpha) acts directly on human memory CD4+ T cells altering their response to antigen. J Immunol
183: 2915–2920, 2009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19667099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jego G, Palucka AK, Blanck JP, Chalouni C, Pascual V, Banchereau J: Plasmacytoid dendritic cells induce plasma cell differentiation through type I interferon and interleukin 6. Immunity
19: 225–234, 2003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12932356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rönnblom L, Alm GV, Eloranta ML: The type I interferon system in the development of lupus. Semin Immunol
23: 113–121, 2011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsuda K, Yamanaka K, Kitagawa H, Akeda T, Naka M, Niwa K, Nakanishi T, Kakeda M, Gabazza EC, Mizutani H: Calcineurin inhibitors suppress cytokine production from memory T cells and differentiation of naïve T cells into cytokine-producing mature T cells. PLoS One
7: e31465, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3281079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22359594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Zhang H, Liu Z, Xing C, Fu P, Ni Z, Chen J, Lin H, Liu F, He Y, He Y, Miao L, Chen N, Li Y, Gu Y, Shi W, Hu W, Liu Z, Bao H, Zeng C, Zhou M: Multitarget Therapy for Induction Treatment of Lupus Nephritis: A Randomized Trial. Ann Intern Med
162: 18–26, 2015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok CC, Ying KY, Yim CW, Siu YP, Tong KH, To CH, Ng WL: Tacrolimus versus mycophenolate mofetil for induction therapy of lupus nephritis: a randomised controlled trial and long-term follow-up. Ann Rheum Dis
75: 30–36, 2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25550339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jakes RW, Bae S-C, Louthrenoo W, Mok C-C, Navarra SV, Kwon N: Systematic review of the epidemiology of systemic lupus erythematosus in the Asia-Pacific region: prevalence, incidence, clinical features, and mortality. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)
64: 159–168, 2012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22052624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
