<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">28169413</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1576-6578</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>64</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Revista de neurologia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Efficacy of the application of kinesio tape in patients with stroke].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>175</StartPage>
          <EndPage>179</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>175-179</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To review the effects achieved by the kinesio tape in patients with stroke in scientific studies published on date and to discuss these findings may be of interest to neurology.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DEVELOPMENT" NlmCategory="METHODS">An exhaustive search in the main scientific databases using keywords such as kinesio tape, kinesiotaping, musculoskeletal tape, taping medical concept was carried out. Citations of selected articles and scientific papers published on the website of the Spanish Association of Neuromuscular Bandage were analyzed. Experimental, quasi-experimental, clinical trials and case studies published were used, without limit date, with therapeutical treatment purpose provide important results. Eight articles have met the inclusion criteria. There are eight studies that examine the effect on kinesio tape on lower limb, gait and balance in this kind of therapy, even upper limb and swallowing problems that these patients could present.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The kinesio tape in neurological patients can be a complementary technique that empirically provides benefits. However, better methodological quality studies demonstrating the effects attributed to him are still needed.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ortiz-Ramirez</LastName>
            <ForeName>J</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidad de Almeria, 04120 Almeria, Espana.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Perez-De la Cruz</LastName>
            <ForeName>S</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidad de Almeria, 04120 Almeria, Espana.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>spa</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Eficacia de la aplicacion del vendaje neuromuscular en accidentes cerebrovasculares.</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Spain</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Rev Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7706841</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0210-0010</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009043" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Activity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009468" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromuscular Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020127" MajorTopicYN="N">Recovery of Function</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
        <AbstractText Label="TITLE" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Eficacia de la aplicacion del vendaje neuromuscular en accidentes cerebrovasculares.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">Objetivos. Revisar la efectividad del vendaje neuromuscular (kinesio tape) en pacientes con accidente cerebrovascular en los estudios cientificos publicados hasta la fecha y discutir estos hallazgos a la luz de lo que pueda ser de interes para la neurologia. Desarrollo. Busqueda exhaustiva en las principales bases de datos cientificas utilizando palabras clave como kinesio tape, kinesiotaping y vendaje neuromuscular, asi como analisis de las citas bibliograficas de los articulos seleccionados y los estudios publicados en la pagina oficial de la Asociacion Española de Vendaje Neuromuscular. Se han admitido estudios cuantitativos experimentales, cuasiexperimentales y estudios de casos, sin limite de fecha, con finalidad terapeutica del vendaje neuromuscular, y que han aportado resultados importantes. Ocho articulos han cumplido los criterios de inclusion. Existen estudios que muestran el tratamiento de los miembros inferiores, la marcha y el equilibrio con este tipo de terapia, asi como de los miembros superiores, y los problemas de deglucion que estos pacientes pueden presentar. Conclusion. El vendaje neuromuscular en patologia neurologica en adultos puede ser una tecnica complementaria que, empiricamente, aporta beneficios, pero aun se precisan estudios de mejor calidad metodologica que evidencien los efectos que se le atribuyen.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28169413</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">rn2016459</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
