<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">28265897</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1995-8218</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuroscience bulletin</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurosci Bull</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Wilson's Disease in China.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>323</StartPage>
          <EndPage>330</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>323-330</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12264-017-0107-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Wilson's disease (WD) is an autosomal recessive disorder of copper metabolism. Its incidence is higher in China than in western countries. ATP7B is the causative gene and encodes a P-type ATPase, which participates in the synthesis of holoceruloplasmin and copper excretion. Disease-causing variants of ATP7B disrupt the normal structure or function of the enzyme and cause copper deposition in multiple organs, leading to diverse clinical manifestations. Given the variety of presentations, misdiagnosis is not rare. Genetic diagnosis plays an important role and has gradually become a routine test in China. The first Chinese spectrum of disease-causing mutations of ATP7B has been established. As a remediable hereditary disorder, most WD patients have a good prognosis with an early diagnosis and chelation treatment. However, clinical trials are relatively few in China, and most treatments are based on the experience of experts and evidences from other countries. It is necessary to study and develop appropriate regimens specific for Chinese WD patients.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan-Juan</ForeName>
            <Initials>JJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Research Center of Neurology in the Second Affiliated Hospital, and the Collaborative Innovation Center for Brain Science, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhi-Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Research Center of Neurology in the Second Affiliated Hospital, and the Collaborative Innovation Center for Brain Science, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, 310009, China. zhiyingwu@zju.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neurosci Bull</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101256850</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1995-8218</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N">China</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006527" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatolenticular Degeneration</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Copper</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Management</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pathogenesis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wilson’s Disease</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2016</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28265897</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567514</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12264-017-0107-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12264-017-0107-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng YL. Hepatolenticular degeneration (pseudosclerosis, progressive lenticular degeneration and torsion spasm) review of literature and report of two cases. Chin Med J. 1932;46:347–364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu WB, Han YZ, Xue BC, Cheng N, Sun DY, Ye DQ, et al.  Epidemiological investigation of Wilson disease in Hanshan county. Anhui Province. Chin Med J. 2010;91:894–897.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Y, Ni W, Chen WJ, Wan B, Zhao GX, Shi ZQ, et al.  Spectrum and classification of ATP7B variants in a large cohort of Chinese patients with Wilson’s disease guides genetic diagnosis. Theranostics. 2016;6:638–649. doi: 10.7150/thno.14596.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/thno.14596</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4805659</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27022412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang XL, Yang RM, Wu ZY, Wang N, Li XH, Wang X. Diagnosis and treatment guidelines of Wilson disease. Chin J Neurol. 2008;41:566–569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang YD, Yang RM. Therapeutic assessment of dimercaptosuccinic acid capsule in the treatment of hepatolenticular degeneration. New Drugs Clin Rem. 1990;9:73–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Lin MT, Murong SX, Wang N. Molecular diagnosis and prophylactic therapy for presymptomatic Chinese patients with Wilson disease. Arch Neurol. 2003;60:737–741. doi: 10.1001/archneur.60.5.737.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.60.5.737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12756138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ni W, Dong QY, Zhang Y, Wu ZY. Zinc monotherapy and a low-copper diet are beneficial in patients with Wilson disease after liver transplantation. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2013;19:905–907. doi: 10.1111/cns.12167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cns.12167</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6493497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24119323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang YC. Research of hepatolenticular degeneration in the past 10 years. Zhonghua Shen Jing Jing Shen Ke Za Zhi. 1959;5:326–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13809170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferenci P, Czlonkowska A, Stremmel W, Houwen R, Rosenberg W, Schilsky M, et al.  EASL clinical practice guidelines: Wilson’s disease. J Hepatol. 2012;56:671–685. doi: 10.1016/j.jhep.2011.11.007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2011.11.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abuduxikuer K, Li LT, Qiu YL, Wang NL, Wang JS. Wilson disease with hepatic presentation in an eight-month-old boy. World J Gastroenterol. 2015;21:8981–8984. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v21.i29.8981.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v21.i29.8981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26269689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hui J, Yuen YP, Chow CM, Chong J, Chiang G, Cheung CK, et al.  Isolated persistent elevation of alanine transaminase for early diagnosis of pre-symptomatic Wilson’s disease in Chinese children. World J Pediatr. 2013;9:361–364. doi: 10.1007/s12519-013-0436-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12519-013-0436-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24146181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin LJ, Wang DX, Ding NN, Lin Y, Jin Y, Zheng CQ. Comprehensive analysis on clinical features of Wilson’s disease: an experience over 28 years with 133 cases. Neurol Res. 2014;36:157–163. doi: 10.1179/1743132813Y.0000000262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/1743132813Y.0000000262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24107488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Zhang Y, Sun YM.  Metabolic Disorder of Neurogenetic Disease. Shanghai: Science and Technology Press of Shanghai; 2014. pp. 799–830.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Murong SX, Chen SR. Wilson disease starting with psychiatric disorder. Chin J Birth Health Heredity. 1997;5:97–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huo LJ, Liao RR, Chen XM. Ophthalmic manifestations of Wilson’s disease. Chin J Ophthalmol. 2008;44:128–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18683696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li XH, Lu Y, Ling Y, Fu QC, Xu J, Zang GQ, et al.  Clinical and molecular characterization of Wilson’s disease in China: identification of 14 novel mutations. BMC Med Genet. 2011;12:6. doi: 10.1186/1471-2350-12-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2350-12-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3025937</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21219664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts EA, Schilsky ML. Diagnosis and treatment of Wilson disease: an update. Hepatology. 2008;47:2089–2111. doi: 10.1002/hep.22261.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.22261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18506894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang L, Li XH, Liang XL. Correlation between the findings by MRI in brain of Wilson disease and clinical manifestations. J Apoplexy Nerv Dis. 2011;28:216–219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang YB, Lu Q, Huang JJ, Yuan NP. MRI diagnosis of brain with hepatolenticular degeneration. J Clin Radiol. 2008;27:1454–1456.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu XE, Yang RM. 132 cases brain MR imaging of hepatolenticular degeneration. J Apoplexy Nerv Dis. 2007;24:30–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ZB, Liu B, Liu HQ, Li DL, Wang XD. MRI features of brain with hepatolenticular degeneration in adults. Chin J CT MRI. 2014;12:37–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang JJ, Li XH, Yang RM, Yu XE, Yu CL, Qian YF, et al.  Susceptibility-Weighted Imaging manifestations in the brain of Wilson’s disease patients. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0125100. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0125100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0125100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4411130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25915414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang YC, Qin ZJ, Zou HW. Observation of 25 patients with hepatolenticular degeneration. Zhonghua Shen Jing Jing Shen Ke Za Zhi. 1957;1:45–59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly M, Daly L, Hutchinson M. An epidemiological study of Wilson’s disease in the Republic of Ireland. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1993;56:298–300. doi: 10.1136/jnnp.56.3.298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.56.3.298</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1014866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8459248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coffey AJ, Durkie M, Hague S, McLay K, Emmerson J, Lo C, et al.  A genetic study of Wilson’s disease in the United Kingdom. Brain. 2013;136:1476–1487. doi: 10.1093/brain/awt035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awt035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3634195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23518715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gialluisi A, Incollu S, Pippucci T, Lepori MB, Zappu A, Loudianos G, et al.  The homozygosity index (HI) approach reveals high allele frequency for Wilson disease in the Sardinian population. Eur J Hum Genet. 2013;21:1308–1311. doi: 10.1038/ejhg.2013.43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejhg.2013.43</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3798848</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu WB, Han YZ, Yang RM, Cheng N, Xue BC, Sun DY, et al.  Epidemiological investigation on hepatolenticular degeneration of Han population in Jinzhai county and Lixin county, Anhui province: report of a family pedigree. Anhui Med J. 2012;33:734–737.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park HD, Ki CS, Lee SY, Kim JW. Carrier frequency of the R778L, A874V, and N1270S mutations in the ATP7B gene in a Korean population. Clin Genet. 2009;75:405–407. doi: 10.1111/j.1399-0004.2008.01132.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-0004.2008.01132.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19419418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mak CM, Lam CW, Tam S, Lai CL, Chan LY, Fan ST, et al.  Mutational analysis of 65 Wilson disease patients in Hong Kong Chinese: identification of 17 novel mutations and its genetic heterogeneity. J Hum Genet. 2008;53:55–63. doi: 10.1007/s10038-007-0218-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10038-007-0218-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18034201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Wang N, Lin MT, Fang L, Murong SX. Detection and analysis of mutations in Chinese patients with Wilson disease. Chin J Neurol. 2001;34:152–156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Wang N, Lin MT, Fang L, Murong SX. Genotype-phenotype correlation of patients with Wilson disease in Chinese population. Chin Med J. 2003;83:309–311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12812649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu XQ, Zhang YF, Liu TT, Hsiao KJ, Zhang JM, Gu XF, et al.  Correlation of ATP7B genotype with phenotype in Chinese patients with Wilson disease. World J Gastroenterol. 2004;10:590–593. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v10.i4.590.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v10.i4.590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716986</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14966923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu M, Dong Y, Ni W, Wu ZY. Defective roles of ATP7B missense mutations in cellular copper tolerance and copper excretion. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2015;67:31–36. doi: 10.1016/j.mcn.2015.05.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcn.2015.05.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26032686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu M, Ni W, Dong Y, Wu ZY. EGFP tags affect cellular localization of ATP7B mutants. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2013;19:346–351. doi: 10.1111/cns.12091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cns.12091</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6493502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23607698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang F, Liang XL, Wang Y, Xu PY, Yang CS, Yan ZW. Study on correlation between gene Arg778Leu mutation and clinical manifestation in Wilson’ s disease. Chin J Neurol. 2000;33:290–291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu Y, Wang JS, Yu H, Wang XH. Correlation of clinical features of Wilson’s disease with ATP7B gene mutation in Children. Chin J Evid Based Pediatr. 2013;8:346–351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van De Sluis B, Rothuizen J, Pearson PL, van Oost BA, Wijmenga C. Identification of a new copper metabolism gene by positional cloning in a purebred dog population. Hum Mol Genet. 2002;11:165–173. doi: 10.1093/hmg/11.2.165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/hmg/11.2.165</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Materia S, Cater MA, Klomp LW, Mercer JF, La Fontaine S. Clusterin and COMMD1 independently regulate degradation of the mammalian copper ATPases ATP7A and ATP7B. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:2485–2499. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M111.302216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M111.302216</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3268409</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stuehler B, Reichert J, Stremmel W, Schaefer M. Analysis of the human homologue of the canine copper toxicosis gene MURR1 in Wilson disease patients. J Mol Med (Berl) 2004;82:629–634. doi: 10.1007/s00109-004-0557-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00109-004-0557-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15205742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Zhao GX, Chen WJ, Wang N, Wan B, Lin MT, et al.  Mutation analysis of 218 Chinese patients with Wilson disease revealed no correlation between the canine copper toxicosis gene MURR1 and Wilson disease. J Mol Med. 2006;84:438–442. doi: 10.1007/s00109-005-0036-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00109-005-0036-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16649058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hung IH, Suzuki M, Yamaguchi Y, Yuan DS, Klausner RD, Gitlin JD. Biochemical characterization of the Wilson disease protein and functional expression in the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae. J Biol Chem. 1997;272:21461–21466. doi: 10.1074/jbc.272.34.21461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.272.34.21461</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9261163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen C, Shen B, Xiao JJ, Wu R, Duff Canning SJ, Wang XP. Currently clinical views on genetics of Wilson’s disease. Chin Med J (Engl) 2015;128:1826–1830. doi: 10.4103/0366-6999.159361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0366-6999.159361</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4733722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Wang N, Murong SX. Construction of site-directed mutant variants of ATP7B in vitro and their expression. Chin J Neurol. 2003;36:339–342.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang CS, Liang XL, Li JY, Yan ZW, Huang F. Effect of the mutation of promoter region in Wilson disease ATP7B gene on the expression of reporter gene. Chin J Med Genet. 2005;22:566–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16215951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diao SP, Hong MF, Huang YQ, Wei ZS, Su QX, Peng ZX, et al.  Identification and characterization of a novel splice-site mutation in the Wilson disease gene. J Neurol Sci. 2014;345:154–158. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2014.07.031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2014.07.031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25086856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wan L, Tsai CH, Hsu CM, Huang CC, Yang CC, Liao CC, et al.  Mutation analysis and characterization of alternative splice variants of the Wilson disease gene ATP7B. Hepatology. 2010;52:1662–1670. doi: 10.1002/hep.23865.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.23865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20931554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng N, Wang X, Yu X, Zhou Z, Gao M, Rao R, et al.  Clinical and genetic study of Wilson’s disease in affected twins and siblings. Chin J Med Genet. 2013;30:261–265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23744310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huster D. Wilson disease. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2010;24:531–539. doi: 10.1016/j.bpg.2010.07.014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpg.2010.07.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20955957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koopman WJ, Nijtmans LG, Dieteren CE, Roestenberg P, Valsecchi F, Smeitink JA, et al.  Mammalian mitochondrial complex I: biogenesis, regulation, and reactive oxygen species generation. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2010;12:1431–1470. doi: 10.1089/ars.2009.2743.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ars.2009.2743</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19803744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zischka H, Lichtmannegger J, Schmitt S, Jägemann N, Schulz S, Wartini D, et al.  Liver mitochondrial membrane crosslinking and destruction in a rat model of Wilson disease. J Clin Invest. 2011;121:1508–1518. doi: 10.1172/JCI45401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI45401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3068979</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21364284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Y, Shi SS, Chen S, Ni W, Zhu M, Wu ZY. The discrepancy between the absence of copper deposition and the presence of neuronal damage in the brain of Atp7b(-/-) mice. Metallomics. 2015;7:283–288. doi: 10.1039/C4MT00242C.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C4MT00242C</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25594375</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang JW, Liu JX, Hou HM, Chen DB, Feng L, Wu C, et al.  Effects of tetrathiomolybdate and penicillamine on brain hydroxyl radical and free copper levels: a microdialysis study in vivo. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2015;458:82–85. doi: 10.1016/j.bbrc.2015.01.071.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2015.01.071</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25634697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts EA, Schilsky ML. A practice guideline on Wilson disease. Hepatology. 2003;37:1475–1492. doi: 10.1053/jhep.2003.50252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/jhep.2003.50252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12774027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu SQ, Li XF, Zhu HY, Liu Y, Fang F, Chen L. Clinical efficacy and safety of chelation treatment with typical penicillamine in cross combination with DMPS repeatedly for Wilson’s disease. J Huazhong Univ Sci Technolog Med Sci. 2013;33:743–747. doi: 10.1007/s11596-013-1190-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11596-013-1190-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24142730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang RM, Cheng N. Observation on short-term effect and follow-up of integrative medicine in treating 198 patients with hepatolenticular degeneration. Chin J Integr Trad West Med. 2002;22:657–659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu JY, Yang RM, Han YZ, Hong MF, Wang X, Li K, et al.  The clinical study of six antidotes against heavy metal poisoning in Wilson’ s disease. Anhui Med J. 2004;25:361–365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li WJ, Wang JF, Wang XP. Wilson’s disease: Update on integrated chinese and western medicine. Chin J Integr Med. 2013;19:233–240. doi: 10.1007/s11655-012-1089-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11655-012-1089-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22610954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang QQ, Yang RM, Han YZ, Ren MS, Hong MF, Wang XP. Effect of gandou decoction on copper metabolism of skin fibroblast of hepatolenticular degeneration model. Chin J Integr Trad West Med. 2000;20:37–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11783335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue BC, Yang RM, Hu JY, Han YZ, Wang JH. Effect of Gandou Decoction IV combined with short-term decoppering therapy with sodium dimercapto-sulphonate on serum indexes of hepatic fibrosis in patients with Wilson’ s disease. Chin J Integr Trad West Med. 2007;27:785–788.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17969887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Xie CL, Fu DL, Lu L, Lin Y, Dong QQ, et al.  Clinical efficacy and safety of Chinese herbal medicine for Wilson’s disease: a systematic review of 9 randomized controlled trials. Complement Ther Med. 2012;20:143–154. doi: 10.1016/j.ctim.2011.12.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctim.2011.12.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22500664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang F, Yu ZG, Liang XL. Therapeusis for Wilson’s disease accomplicated with splenosis-16 cases with splenectomization analysis. Chin J Nervous Mental Dis. 2000;26:6–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng Q, He SQ, Gao D, Lei B, Long X, Liang HF, et al.  Early application of auxiliary partial orthotopic liver transplantation in murine model of Wilson disease. Transplantation. 2015;99:2317–2324. doi: 10.1097/TP.0000000000000787.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TP.0000000000000787</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26018347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
