<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">28527919</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-016X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>179</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pharmacology &amp; therapeutics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pharmacol Ther</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Mechanisms of the amplifying pathway of insulin secretion in the β cell.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>17</StartPage>
          <EndPage>30</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>17-30</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2017.05.003</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0163-7258(17)30122-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pancreatic islet β cells secrete insulin in response to nutrient secretagogues, like glucose, dependent on calcium influx and nutrient metabolism. One of the most intriguing qualities of β cells is their ability to use metabolism to amplify the amount of secreted insulin independent of further alterations in intracellular calcium. Many years studying this amplifying process have shaped our current understanding of β cell stimulus-secretion coupling; yet, the exact mechanisms of amplification have been elusive. Recent studies utilizing metabolomics, computational modeling, and animal models have progressed our understanding of the metabolic amplifying pathway of insulin secretion from the β cell. New approaches will be discussed which offer in-roads to a more complete model of β cell function. The development of β cell therapeutics may be aided by such a model, facilitating the targeting of aspects of the metabolic amplifying pathway which are unique to the β cell.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2017 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kalwat</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, United States. Electronic address: Michael.Kalwat@utsouthwestern.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cobb</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melanie H</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, TX, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>F32 DK100113</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 DK034128</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 DK055310</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R37 DK034128</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Pharmacol Ther</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7905840</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0163-7258</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>IY9XDZ35W2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005947">Glucose</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005947" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000078790" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin Secretion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D050417" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin-Secreting Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055432" MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolomics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Amplifying pathway</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biphasic insulin secretion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell signaling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose sensing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Metabolomics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pancreatic islet beta cells</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Statement</b>: The authors declare that there are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527919</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS878035</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7269041</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2017.05.003</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0163-7258(17)30122-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdulreda MH, Rodriguez-Diaz R, Caicedo A, Berggren PO. Liraglutide Compromises Pancreatic beta Cell Function in a Humanized Mouse Model. Cell Metab. 2016;23:541–546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26876561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adriaenssens AE, Svendsen B, Lam BY, Yeo GS, Holst JJ, Reimann F, Gribble FM. Transcriptomic profiling of pancreatic alpha, beta and delta cell populations identifies delta cells as a principal target for ghrelin in mouse islets. Diabetologia. 2016;59:2156–2165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5016554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27390011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar-Bryan L, Bryan J. Molecular biology of adenosine triphosphate-sensitive potassium channels. Endocr Rev. 1999;20:101–135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10204114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alfa RW, Park S, Skelly KR, Poffenberger G, Jain N, Gu X, Kockel L, Wang J, Liu Y, Powers AC, Kim SK. Suppression of insulin production and secretion by a decretin hormone. Cell Metab. 2015;21:323–333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4349554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25651184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves TC, Pongratz RL, Zhao X, Yarborough O, Sereda S, Shirihai O, Cline GW, Mason G, Kibbey RG. Integrated, Step-Wise, Mass-Isotopomeric Flux Analysis of the TCA Cycle. Cell Metab. 2015;22:936–947.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635072</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26411341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson LE, Nicholas LM, Filipsson K, Sun J, Medina A, Al-Majdoub M, Fex M, Mulder H, Spegel P. Glycogen metabolism in the glucose-sensing and supply-driven beta-cell. FEBS Lett. 2016;590:4242–4251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27943300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anello M, Ucciardello V, Piro S, Patané G, Frittitta L, Calabrese V, Giuffrida Stella AM, Vigneri R, Purrello F, Rabuazzo AM. Chronic exposure to high leucine impairs glucose-induced insulin release by lowering the ATP-to-ADP ratio. AJP: Endocrinology and Metabolism. 2001;281:E1082–E1087.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11595666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asahara S, Shibutani Y, Teruyama K, Inoue HY, Kawada Y, Etoh H, Matsuda T, Kimura-Koyanagi M, Hashimoto N, Sakahara M, Fujimoto W, Takahashi H, Ueda S, Hosooka T, Satoh T, Inoue H, Matsumoto M, Aiba A, Kasuga M, Kido Y. Ras-related C3 botulinum toxin substrate 1 (RAC1) regulates glucose-stimulated insulin secretion via modulation of F-actin. Diabetologia. 2013;56:1088–1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3622740</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23412604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashcroft FM, Rorsman P. Diabetes mellitus and the beta cell: the last ten years. Cell. 2012;148:1160–1171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5890906</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22424227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bailey CJ.  Future Drug Treatments for Type 2 Diabetes. In: Holt R, Cockram C, Flyvbjerg A, Goldstein B, editors. Textbook of Diabetes. 5th. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; 2017. pp. 1000–1011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barg S, Huang P, Eliasson L, Nelson DJ, Obermüller S, Rorsman P, Thévenod F, Renström E. Priming of insulin granules for exocytosis by granular Cl−uptake and acidification. J Cell Sci. 2001;114:2145–2154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11493650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berdan CA, Erion KA, Burritt NE, Corkey BE, Deeney JT. Inhibition of Monoacylglycerol Lipase Activity Decreases Glucose-Stimulated Insulin Secretion in INS-1 (832/13) Cells and Rat Islets. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0149008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4750965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertrand G, Ishiyama N, Nenquin M, Ravier MA, Henquin JC. The elevation of glutamate content and the amplification of insulin secretion in glucose-stimulated pancreatic islets are not causally related. J Biol Chem. 2002;277:32883–32891.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12087106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhatnagar S, Oler AT, Rabaglia ME, Stapleton DS, Schueler KL, Truchan NA, Worzella SL, Stoehr JP, Clee SM, Yandell BS, Keller MP, Thurmond DC, Attie AD. Positional cloning of a type 2 diabetes quantitative trait locus; tomosyn-2, a negative regulator of insulin secretion. PLoS Genet. 2011;7:e1002323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3188574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21998599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun M, Ramracheya R, Amisten S, Bengtsson M, Moritoh Y, Zhang Q, Johnson PR, Rorsman P. Somatostatin release, electrical activity, membrane currents and exocytosis in human pancreatic delta cells. Diabetologia. 2009;52:1566–1578.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19440689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brereton MF, Rohm M, Shimomura K, Holland C, Tornovsky-Babeay S, Dadon D, Iberl M, Chibalina MV, Lee S, Glaser B, Dor Y, Rorsman P, Clark A, Ashcroft FM. Hyperglycaemia induces metabolic dysfunction and glycogen accumulation in pancreatic beta-cells. Nat Commun. 2016;7:13496.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5123088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brines M, Cerami A. Discovering erythropoietin’s extra-hematopoietic functions: biology and clinical promise. Kidney Int. 2006;70:246–250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16738535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brines M, Dunne AN, van Velzen M, Proto PL, Ostenson CG, Kirk RI, Petropoulos IN, Javed S, Malik RA, Cerami A, Dahan A. ARA 290, a nonerythropoietic peptide engineered from erythropoietin, improves metabolic control and neuropathic symptoms in patients with type 2 diabetes. Mol Med. 2015;20:658–666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4365069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25387363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brines M, Patel NS, Villa P, Brines C, Mennini T, De Paola M, Erbayraktar Z, Erbayraktar S, Sepodes B, Thiemermann C, Ghezzi P, Yamin M, Hand CC, Xie QW, Coleman T, Cerami A. Nonerythropoietic, tissue-protective peptides derived from the tertiary structure of erythropoietin. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105:10925–10930.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2504825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown LJ, Longacre MJ, Hasan NM, Kendrick MA, Stoker SW, Macdonald MJ. Chronic reduction of the cytosolic or mitochondrial NAD(P)-malic enzyme does not affect insulin secretion in a rat insulinoma cell line. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:35359–35367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2790965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19858194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brun T, Li N, Jourdain AA, Gaudet P, Duhamel D, Meyer J, Bosco D, Maechler P. Diabetogenic milieus induce specific changes in mitochondrial transcriptome and differentiation of human pancreatic islets. Hum Mol Genet. 2015;24:5270–5284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26123492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cameron WD, Bui CV, Hutchinson A, Loppnau P, Graslund S, Rocheleau JV. Apollo-NADP(+): a spectrally tunable family of genetically encoded sensors for NADP(+) Nat Methods. 2016;13:352–358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26878383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell JE, Drucker DJ. Pharmacology, physiology, and mechanisms of incretin hormone action. Cell Metab. 2013;17:819–837.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23684623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao Z, Li X, Li J, Kang B, Chen J, Luo W, Huang C. SUMOylation of RhoGDIalpha is required for its repression of cyclin D1 expression and anchorage-independent growth of cancer cells. Mol Oncol. 2014;8:285–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24342356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carobbio S, Frigerio F, Rubi B, Vetterli L, Bloksgaard M, Gjinovci A, Pournourmohammadi S, Herrera PL, Reith W, Mandrup S, Maechler P. Deletion of glutamate dehydrogenase in beta-cells abolishes part of the insulin secretory response not required for glucose homeostasis. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:921–929.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19015267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carpenter L, Mitchell CJ, Xu ZZ, Poronnik P, Both GW, Biden TJ. PKC Is Activated But Not Required During Glucose-Induced Insulin Secretion From Rat Pancreatic Islets. Diabetes. 2003;53:53–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14693697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen C, Chmelova H, Cohrs CM, Chouinard JA, Jahn SR, Stertmann J, Uphues I, Speier S. Alterations in beta-Cell Calcium Dynamics and Efficacy Outweigh Islet Mass Adaptation in Compensation of Insulin Resistance and Prediabetes Onset. Diabetes. 2016;65:2676–2685.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YD, Wang S, Sherman A. Identifying the targets of the amplifying pathway for insulin secretion in pancreatic beta-cells by kinetic modeling of granule exocytosis. Biophys J. 2008;95:2226–2241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2517041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18515381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi D, Schroer SA, Lu SY, Wang L, Wu X, Liu Y, Zhang Y, Gaisano HY, Wagner KU, Wu H, Retnakaran R, Woo M. Erythropoietin protects against diabetes through direct effects on pancreatic beta cells. J Exp Med. 2010;207:2831–2842.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3005231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21149549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chuang JC, Sakata I, Kohno D, Perello M, Osborne-Lawrence S, Repa JJ, Zigman JM. Ghrelin directly stimulates glucagon secretion from pancreatic alpha-cells. Mol Endocrinol. 2011;25:1600–1611.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3165914</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21719535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Civelek VN, Deeney JT, Kubik K, Schultz V, Tornheim K, Corkey BE. Temporal sequence of metabolic and ionic events in glucose-stimulated clonal pancreaticβ-cells (HIT) Biochemical Journal. 1996;315:1015–1019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1217255</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8645138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clayton PT, Eaton S, Aynsley-Green A, Edginton M, Hussain K, Krywawych S, Datta V, Malingre HE, Berger R, van den Berg IE. Hyperinsulinism in short-chain L-3-hydroxyacyl-CoA dehydrogenase deficiency reveals the importance of beta-oxidation in insulin secretion. J Clin Invest. 2001;108:457–465.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC209352</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11489939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook DL, Ikeuchi M, Fujimoto WY. Lowering of pHi inhibits Ca2+-activated K+ channels in pancreatic B-cells. Nature. 1984;311:269–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6090929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai XQ, Plummer G, Casimir M, Kang Y, Hajmrle C, Gaisano HY, Manning Fox JE, MacDonald PE. SUMOylation regulates insulin exocytosis downstream of secretory granule docking in rodents and humans. Diabetes. 2011;60:838–847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046844</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniel S, Noda M, Straub SG, Sharp GW. Identification of the docked granule pool responsible for the first phase of glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. Diabetes. 1999;48:1686–1690.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10480595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deeney JT. Acute Stimulation with Long Chain Acyl-CoA Enhances Exocytosis in Insulin-secreting Cells (HIT T-15 and NMRI beta -Cells) Journal of Biological Chemistry. 2000;275:9363–9368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10734079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Detimary P, Van den Berghe G, Henquin JC. Concentration Dependence and Time Course of the Effects of Glucose on Adenine and Guanine Nucleotides in Mouse Pancreatic Islets. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 1996;271:20559–20565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8702800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DiGruccio MR, Mawla AM, Donaldson CJ, Noguchi GM, Vaughan J, Cowing-Zitron C, van der Meulen T, Huising MO. Comprehensive alpha, beta and delta cell transcriptomes reveal that ghrelin selectively activates delta cells and promotes somatostatin release from pancreatic islets. Mol Metab. 2016;5:449–458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4921781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27408771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doliba NM, Wehrli SL, Vatamaniuk MZ, Qin W, Buettger CW, Collins HW, Matschinsky FM. Metabolic and ionic coupling factors in amino acid-stimulated insulin release in pancreatic beta-HC9 cells. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2007;292:E1507–1519.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17264232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyachok O, Idevall-Hagren O, Sagetorp J, Tian G, Wuttke A, Arrieumerlou C, Akusjarvi G, Gylfe E, Tengholm A. Glucose-induced cyclic AMP oscillations regulate pulsatile insulin secretion. Cell Metab. 2008;8:26–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18590690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edfalk S, Steneberg P, Edlund H. Gpr40 is expressed in enteroendocrine cells and mediates free fatty acid stimulation of incretin secretion. Diabetes. 2008;57:2280–2287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2518478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Azzouny M, Evans CR, Treutelaar MK, Kennedy RT, Burant CF. Increased glucose metabolism and glycerolipid formation by fatty acids and GPR40 receptor signaling underlies the fatty acid potentiation of insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:13575–13588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24675078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El Azzouny M, Longacre MJ, Ansari IU, Kennedy RT, Burant CF, MacDonald MJ. Knockdown of ATP citrate lyase in pancreatic beta cells does not inhibit insulin secretion or glucose flux and implicates the acetoacetate pathway in insulin secretion. Mol Metab. 2016;5:980–987.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5034614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27689010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ElAzzouny MA, Evans CR, Burant CF, Kennedy RT. Metabolomics Analysis Reveals that AICAR Affects Glycerolipid, Ceramide and Nucleotide Synthesis Pathways in INS-1 Cells. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0129029.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4480354</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26107620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliasson L, Renström E, Ding W-G, Proks P, Rorsman P. Rapid ATP-Dependent Priming of Secretory Granules Precedes Ca2+-Induced Exocytosis in Mouse Pancreatic B-Cells. The Journal of Physiology. 1997;503:399–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1159871</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9306281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eto K. NADH Shuttle System Regulates KATP Channel-dependent Pathway and Steps Distal to Cytosolic Ca2+ Concentration Elevation in Glucose-induced Insulin Secretion. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 1999;274:25386–25392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10464266</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahien LA, Macdonald MJ. The complex mechanism of glutamate dehydrogenase in insulin secretion. Diabetes. 2011;60:2450–2454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3178282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21948999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan J, Ye J, Kamphorst JJ, Shlomi T, Thompson CB, Rabinowitz JD. Quantitative flux analysis reveals folate-dependent NADPH production. Nature. 2014;510:298–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24805240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferdaoussi M, Bergeron V, Zarrouki B, Kolic J, Cantley J, Fielitz J, Olson EN, Prentki M, Biden T, MacDonald PE, Poitout V. G protein-coupled receptor (GPR)40-dependent potentiation of insulin secretion in mouse islets is mediated by protein kinase D1. Diabetologia. 2012;55:2682–2692.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22820510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferdaoussi M, Dai X, Jensen MV, Wang R, Peterson BS, Huang C, Ilkayeva O, Smith N, Miller N, Hajmrle C, Spigelman AF, Wright RC, Plummer G, Suzuki K, Mackay JP, van de Bunt M, Gloyn AL, Ryan TE, Norquay LD, Brosnan MJ, Trimmer JK, Rolph TP, Kibbey RG, Manning Fox JE, Colmers WF, Shirihai OS, Neufer PD, Yeh ET, Newgard CB, MacDonald PE. Isocitrate-to-SENP1 signaling amplifies insulin secretion and rescues dysfunctional beta cells. J Clin Invest. 2015;125:3847–3860.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4607115</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26389676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferdaoussi M, Fu J, Dai X, Manning Fox JE, Suzuki K, Smith N, Plummer G, MacDonald PE. SUMOylation and calcium control syntaxin-1A and secretagogin sequestration by tomosyn to regulate insulin exocytosis in human ss cells. Sci Rep. 2017;7:248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5428262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28325894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferdaoussi M, MacDonald PE. Toward Connecting Metabolism to the Exocytotic Site. Trends Cell Biol. 2017;27:163–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27932063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finan B, Clemmensen C, Zhu Z, Stemmer K, Gauthier K, Muller L, De Angelis M, Moreth K, Neff F, Perez-Tilve D, Fischer K, Lutter D, Sanchez-Garrido MA, Liu P, Tuckermann J, Malehmir M, Healy ME, Weber A, Heikenwalder M, Jastroch M, Kleinert M, Jall S, Brandt S, Flamant F, Schramm KW, Biebermann H, Doring Y, Weber C, Habegger KM, Keuper M, Gelfanov V, Liu F, Kohrle J, Rozman J, Fuchs H, Gailus-Durner V, Hrabe de Angelis M, Hofmann SM, Yang B, Tschop MH, DiMarchi R, Muller TD. Chemical Hybridization of Glucagon and Thyroid Hormone Optimizes Therapeutic Impact for Metabolic Disease. Cell. 2016;167:843–857 e814.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27720451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finan B, Yang B, Ottaway N, Stemmer K, Muller TD, Yi CX, Habegger K, Schriever SC, Garcia-Caceres C, Kabra DG, Hembree J, Holland J, Raver C, Seeley RJ, Hans W, Irmler M, Beckers J, de Angelis MH, Tiano JP, Mauvais-Jarvis F, Perez-Tilve D, Pfluger P, Zhang L, Gelfanov V, DiMarchi RD, Tschop MH. Targeted estrogen delivery reverses the metabolic syndrome. Nat Med. 2012;18:1847–1856.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3757949</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23142820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fridlyand LE, Philipson LH. Coupling of metabolic, second messenger pathways and insulin granule dynamics in pancreatic beta-cells: a computational analysis. Prog Biophys Mol Biol. 2011;107:293–303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4439405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21920379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fridlyand LE, Philipson LH. Pancreatic Beta Cell G-Protein Coupled Receptors and Second Messenger Interactions: A Systems Biology Computational Analysis. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0152869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4854486</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27138453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gan WJ, Zavortink M, Ludick C, Templin R, Webb R, Webb R, Ma W, Poronnik P, Parton RG, Gaisano HY, Shewan AM, Thorn P. Cell polarity defines three distinct domains in pancreatic beta-cells. J Cell Sci. 2017;130:143–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394774</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26919978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Barrado MJ, Ravier MA, Rolland JF, Gilon P, Nenquin M, Henquin JC. Inhibition of protein synthesis sequentially impairs distinct steps of stimulus-secretion coupling in pancreatic beta cells. Endocrinology. 2001;142:299–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11145593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gembal M, Detimary P, Gilon P, Gao ZY, Henquin JC. Mechanisms by which glucose can control insulin release independently from its action on adenosine triphosphate-sensitive K+ channels in mouse B cells. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 1993;91:871–880.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC288039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8383702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gembal M, Gilon P, Henquin JC. Evidence that glucose can control insulin release independently from its action on ATP-sensitive K+ channels in mouse B cells. J Clin Invest. 1992;89:1288–1295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC442990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1556189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>George RE, Joseph S. A review of newer treatment approaches for type-2 diabetes: Focusing safety and efficacy of incretin based therapy. Saudi Pharm J. 2014;22:403–410.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4246366</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25473328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerencser AA. Bioenergetic Analysis of Single Pancreatic beta-Cells Indicates an Impaired Metabolic Signature in Type 2 Diabetic Subjects. Endocrinology. 2015;156:3496–3503.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26204464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gheni G, Ogura M, Iwasaki M, Yokoi N, Minami K, Nakayama Y, Harada K, Hastoy B, Wu X, Takahashi H, Kimura K, Matsubara T, Hoshikawa R, Hatano N, Sugawara K, Shibasaki T, Inagaki N, Bamba T, Mizoguchi A, Fukusaki E, Rorsman P, Seino S. Glutamate acts as a key signal linking glucose metabolism to incretin/cAMP action to amplify insulin secretion. Cell Rep. 2014;9:661–673.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4536302</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25373904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh AB, Ronner P, Cheong E, Khalid P, Matschinsky FM. The Role of ATP and free ADP in Metabolic Coupling during Fuel-stimulated Insulin Release from Islet beta Cells in the Isolated Perfused Rat Pancreas. J Biol Chem. 1991;266:22887–22892.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1744082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilon P, Henquin JC. Mechanisms and physiological significance of the cholinergic control of pancreatic beta-cell function. Endocr Rev. 2001;22:565–604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11588141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glynn E, Thompson B, Vadrevu S, Lu S, Kennedy RT, Ha J, Sherman A, Satin LS. Chronic Glucose Exposure Systematically Shifts the Oscillatory Threshold of Mouse Islets: Experimental Evidence for an Early Intrinsic Mechanism of Compensation for Hyperglycemia. Endocrinology. 2016;157:611–623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4733117</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26697721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goehring I, Sauter NS, Catchpole G, Assmann A, Shu L, Zien KS, Moehlig M, Pfeiffer AF, Oberholzer J, Willmitzer L, Spranger J, Maedler K. Identification of an intracellular metabolic signature impairing beta cell function in the rat beta cell line INS-1E and human islets. Diabetologia. 2011;54:2584–2594.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21796486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gooding JR, Jensen MV, Dai X, Wenner BR, Lu D, Arumugam R, Ferdaoussi M, MacDonald PE, Newgard CB. Adenylosuccinate Is an Insulin Secretagogue Derived from Glucose-Induced Purine Metabolism. Cell Rep. 2015;13:157–167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4598307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26411681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gooding JR, Jensen MV, Newgard CB. Metabolomics applied to the pancreatic islet. Arch Biochem Biophys. 2016;589:120–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4863644</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26116790</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gray JP, Alavian KN, Jonas EA, Heart EA. NAD kinase regulates the size of the NADPH pool and insulin secretion in pancreatic beta-cells. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;303:E191–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3431206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22550069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guay C, Joly E, Pepin E, Barbeau A, Hentsch L, Pineda M, Madiraju SR, Brunengraber H, Prentki M. A role for cytosolic isocitrate dehydrogenase as a negative regulator of glucose signaling for insulin secretion in pancreatic ss-cells. PLoS One. 2013;8:e77097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3795013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24130841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerra ML, Kalwat MA, McGlynn K, Cobb MH. Sucralose activates an ERK1/2-ribosomal protein S6 signaling axis. FEBS Open Bio. 2017;7:174–186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292669</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28174684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ha J, Satin LS, Sherman AS. A Mathematical Model of the Pathogenesis, Prevention, and Reversal of Type 2 Diabetes. Endocrinology. 2016;157:624–635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4733125</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26709417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallakou-Bozec S, Bolze S, Kergoat M, Roden M, Lebovitz H. Imeglimin Increases Insulin Secretion in Response to Glucose by a Unique Mechanism of Action Depending on NAD Synthesis. Diabetes. 2016;65:A282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasan NM, Longacre MJ, Stoker SW, Kendrick MA, MacDonald MJ. Mitochondrial malic enzyme 3 is important for insulin secretion in pancreatic beta-cells. Mol Endocrinol. 2015;29:396–410.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4347290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25594249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heart E, Cline GW, Collis LP, Pongratz RL, Gray JP, Smith PJ. Role for malic enzyme, pyruvate carboxylation, and mitochondrial malate import in glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2009;296:E1354–1362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692397</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19293334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henquin JC. Triggering and amplifying pathways of regulation of insulin secretion by glucose. Diabetes. 2000;49:1751–1760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henquin JC. Regulation of insulin secretion: a matter of phase control and amplitude modulation. Diabetologia. 2009;52:739–751.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19288076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henquin JC. The dual control of insulin secretion by glucose involves triggering and amplifying pathways in β-cells. Diabetes Research and Clinical Practice. 2011;93:S27–S31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21864748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henquin JC, Dufrane D, Gmyr V, Kerr-Conte J, Nenquin M. Pharmacological approach to understanding the control of insulin secretion in human islets. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2017;19:1061–1070.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28116849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henquin JC, Dufrane D, Kerr-Conte J, Nenquin M. Dynamics of glucose-induced insulin secretion in normal human islets. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2015 ajpendo 00251 02015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26264556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodson DJ, Tarasov AI, Gimeno Brias S, Mitchell RK, Johnston NR, Haghollahi S, Cane MC, Bugliani M, Marchetti P, Bosco D, Johnson PR, Hughes SJ, Rutter GA. Incretin-modulated beta cell energetics in intact islets of Langerhans. Mol Endocrinol. 2014;28:860–871.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4042069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24766140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang M, Joseph JW. Assessment of the metabolic pathways associated with glucose-stimulated biphasic insulin secretion. Endocrinology. 2014;155:1653–1666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24564396</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ivarsson R, Quintens R, Dejonghe S, Tsukamoto K, in‘t Veld P, Renstrom E, Schuit FC. Redox control of exocytosis: regulatory role of NADPH, thioredoxin, and glutaredoxin. Diabetes. 2005;54:2132–2142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15983215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayaram B, Syed I, Kyathanahalli CN, Rhodes CJ, Kowluru A. Arf nucleotide binding site opener [ARNO] promotes sequential activation of Arf6, Cdc42 and Rac1 and insulin secretion in INS 832/13 beta-cells and rat islets. Biochem Pharmacol. 2011;81:1016–1027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3073812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21276423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen MV, Joseph JW, Ronnebaum SM, Burgess SC, Sherry AD, Newgard CB. Metabolic cycling in control of glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2008;295:E1287–1297.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2603555</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18728221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joseph JW, Odegaard ML, Ronnebaum SM, Burgess SC, Muehlbauer J, Sherry AD, Newgard CB. Normal flux through ATP-citrate lyase or fatty acid synthase is not required for glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:31592–31600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung SR, Kuok IT, Couron D, Rizzo N, Margineantu DH, Hockenbery DM, Kim F, Sweet IR. Reduced cytochrome C is an essential regulator of sustained insulin secretion by pancreatic islets. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:17422–17434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3093816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21393241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kailey B, van de Bunt M, Cheley S, Johnson PR, MacDonald PE, Gloyn AL, Rorsman P, Braun M. SSTR2 is the functionally dominant somatostatin receptor in human pancreatic beta- and alpha-cells. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;303:E1107–1116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3492856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22932785</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalwat MA, Thurmond DC. Signaling mechanisms of glucose-induced F-actin remodeling in pancreatic islet beta cells. Exp Mol Med. 2013;45:e37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23969997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalwat MA, Wichaidit C, Nava Garcia AY, McCoy MK, McGlynn K, Hwang IH, MacMillan JB, Posner BA, Cobb MH. Insulin promoter-driven Gaussia luciferase-based insulin secretion biosensor assay for discovery of beta-cell glucose-sensing pathways. ACS Sens. 2016;1:1208–1212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5089812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27819058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalwat MA, Yoder SM, Wang Z, Thurmond DC. A p21-activated kinase (PAK1) signaling cascade coordinately regulates F-actin remodeling and insulin granule exocytosis in pancreatic beta cells. Biochem Pharmacol. 2013;85:808–816.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3578113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23246867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keane K, Newsholme P. Metabolic regulation of insulin secretion. Vitam Horm. 2014;95:1–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24559912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kepner EM, Yoder SM, Oh E, Kalwat MA, Wang Z, Quilliam LA, Thurmond DC. Cool-1/betaPIX functions as a guanine nucleotide exchange factor in the cycling of Cdc42 to regulate insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2011;301:E1072–1080.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3233779</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21828338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kojima I, Nakagawa Y, Ohtsu Y, Hamano K, Medina J, Nagasawa M. Return of the glucoreceptor: Glucose activates the glucose-sensing receptor T1R3 and facilitates metabolism in pancreatic beta-cells. J Diabetes Investig. 2015;6:256–263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4420555</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komatsu M, McDermott AM, Gillison SL, Sharp GW. Mastoparan stimulates exocytosis at a Ca(2+)-independent late site in stimulus-secretion coupling. Studies with the RINm5F beta-cell line. J Biol Chem. 1993;268:23297–23306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8226853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komatsu M, Noda M, Sharp GWG. Nutrient Augmentation of Ca 2+ -Dependent and Ca 2+ -Independent Pathways in Stimulus-Coupling to Insulin Secretion Can Be Distinguished by Their Guanosine Triphosphate Requirements: Studies on Rat Pancreatic Islets 1. Endocrinology. 1998;139:1172–1183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9492052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komatsu M, Takei M, Ishii H, Sato Y. Glucose-stimulated insulin secretion: A newer perspective. J Diabetes Investig. 2013;4:511–516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4020243</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24843702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kowluru A. Small G proteins in islet beta-cell function. Endocr Rev. 2010;31:52–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2852207</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19890090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lantz KA, Vatamaniuk MZ, Brestelli JE, Friedman JR, Matschinsky FM, Kaestner KH. Foxa2 regulates multiple pathways of insulin secretion. Journal of Clinical Investigation. 2004;114:512–520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC503770</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15314688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebovitz HE. Insulin: potential negative consequences of early routine use in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2011;34(Suppl 2):S225–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3632184</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21525460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JW, Choi AH, Ham M, Kim JW, Choe SS, Park J, Lee GY, Yoon KH, Kim JB. G6PD up-regulation promotes pancreatic beta-cell dysfunction. Endocrinology. 2011;152:793–803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21248143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leite NC, de Paula F, Borck PC, Vettorazzi JF, Branco RC, Lubaczeuski C, Boschero AC, Zoppi CC, Carneiro EM. Protein malnutrition potentiates the amplifying pathway of insulin secretion in adult obese mice. Sci Rep. 2016;6:33464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5025848</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis CA, Parker SJ, Fiske BP, McCloskey D, Gui DY, Green CR, Vokes NI, Feist AM, Vander Heiden MG, Metallo CM. Tracing compartmentalized NADPH metabolism in the cytosol and mitochondria of mammalian cells. Mol Cell. 2014;55:253–263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4106038</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24882210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li N, Wu JX, Ding D, Cheng J, Gao N, Chen L. Structure of a Pancreatic ATP-Sensitive Potassium Channel. Cell. 2017;168:101–110e110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28086082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang Y, Matschinsky FM. Content of CoA-Esters in Perifused Rat Islets Stimulated by Glucose and Other Fuels. Diabetes. 1991;40:327–333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1999274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, Han S, Yang Y, Kang J, Wu J. Glucose-induced glutathione reduction in mitochondria is involved in the first phase of pancreatic beta-cell insulin secretion. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2015;464:730–736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26164230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lorenz MA, El Azzouny MA, Kennedy RT, Burant CF. Metabolome response to glucose in the beta-cell line INS-1 832/13. J Biol Chem. 2013;288:10923–10935.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624472</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23426361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu D, Mulder H, Zhao P, Burgess SC, Jensen MV, Kamzolova S, Newgard CB, Sherry AD. 13C NMR isotopomer analysis reveals a connection between pyruvate cycling and glucose-stimulated insulin secretion (GSIS) Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99:2708–2713.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC122412</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11880625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luni C, Marth JD, Doyle FJ., 3rd Computational modeling of glucose transport in pancreatic beta-cells identifies metabolic thresholds and therapeutic targets in diabetes. PLoS One. 2012;7:e53130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3531366</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23300881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald MJ, Fahien LA. Glutamate is not a messenger in insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2000;275:34025–34027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10967090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald MJ, Fahien LA, Brown LJ, Hasan NM, Buss JD, Kendrick MA. Perspective: emerging evidence for signaling roles of mitochondrial anaplerotic products in insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288:E1–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15585595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macdonald MJ, Hasan NM, Longacre MJ. Studies with leucine, beta-hydroxybutyrate and ATP citrate lyase-deficient beta cells support the acetoacetate pathway of insulin secretion. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2008;1780:966–972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18439432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald MJ, Marshall LK. Survey of mouse strain lacking malic enzyme and GPD. Molecular and Cellular Biochemistry. 2001;220:117–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11451371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald MJ, Smith AD, 3rd, Hasan NM, Sabat G, Fahien LA. Feasibility of pathways for transfer of acyl groups from mitochondria to the cytosol to form short chain acyl-CoAs in the pancreatic beta cell. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:30596–30606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17724028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maechler P, Wollheim CB. Mitochondrial glutamate acts as a messenger in glucose-induced insulin exocytosis. Nature. 1999;402:685–689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10604477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmoud AN, Saad M, Mansoor H, Elgendy AY, Barakat AF, Abuzaid A, Mentias A, Elgendy IY. Cardiovascular safety of incretin-based therapy for type 2 diabetes: A meta-analysis of randomized trials. Int J Cardiol. 2017;230:324–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28043676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mancini AD, Poitout V. The fatty acid receptor FFA1/GPR40 a decade later: how much do we know? Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2013;24:398–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23631851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mari A, Gastaldelli A, Natali A, Ostergard T, Schmitz O, Ferrannini E. Characterization of beta-cell function impairment in first-degree relatives of type 2 diabetic subjects: modeling analysis of 24-h triple-meal tests. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2005;288:E541–546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15522997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin GM, Yoshioka C, Rex EA, Fay JF, Xie Q, Whorton MR, Chen JZ, Shyng SL. Cryo-EM structure of the ATP-sensitive potassium channel illuminates mechanisms of assembly and gating. Elife. 2017;6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5344670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28092267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKenna JP, Ha J, Merrins MJ, Satin LS, Sherman A, Bertram R. Ca2+ Effects on ATP Production and Consumption Have Regulatory Roles on Oscillatory Islet Activity. Biophys J. 2016;110:733–742.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744176</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26840737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meier JJ, Nauck MA. Incretin-based therapies: where will we be 50 years from now? Diabetologia. 2015;58:1745–1750.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25994073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merrins MJ, Fendler B, Zhang M, Sherman A, Bertram R, Satin LS. Metabolic oscillations in pancreatic islets depend on the intracellular Ca2+ level but not Ca2+ oscillations. Biophys J. 2010;99:76–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20655835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merrins MJ, Poudel C, McKenna JP, Ha J, Sherman A, Bertram R, Satin LS. Phase Analysis of Metabolic Oscillations and Membrane Potential in Pancreatic Islet beta-Cells. Biophys J. 2016;110:691–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26840733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miki T, Nagashima K, Tashiro F, Kotake K, Yoshitomi H, Tamamoto A, Gonoi T, Iwanaga T, Miyazaki J-i, Seino S. Defective insulin secretion and enhanced insulin action in KATP channel-deficient mice. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 1998;95:10402–10406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27906</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9724715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mourad NI, Nenquin M, Henquin JC. Metabolic amplifying pathway increases both phases of insulin secretion independently of beta-cell actin microfilaments. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2010;299:C389–398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20484655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mourad NI, Nenquin M, Henquin JC. Metabolic amplification of insulin secretion by glucose is independent of beta-cell microtubules. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2011;300:C697–706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21178111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mugabo Y, Zhao S, Lamontagne J, Al-Mass A, Peyot ML, Corkey BE, Joly E, Madiraju SRM, Prentki M. Metabolic fate of glucose and candidate signaling and excess-fuel detoxification pathways in pancreatic beta-cells. J Biol Chem. 2017;292:7407–7422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5418042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller C, Yassin K, Li LS, Palmblad M, Efendic S, Berggren PO, Cerami A, Brines M, Ostenson CG. ARA290 improves insulin release and glucose tolerance in type 2 diabetic GK rats. Mol Med. 2015;21:969–978.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4818260</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26736179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller TD, Nogueiras R, Andermann ML, Andrews ZB, Anker SD, Argente J, Batterham RL, Benoit SC, Bowers CY, Broglio F, Casanueva FF, D’Alessio D, Depoortere I, Geliebter A, Ghigo E, Cole PA, Cowley M, Cummings DE, Dagher A, Diano S, Dickson SL, Dieguez C, Granata R, Grill HJ, Grove K, Habegger KM, Heppner K, Heiman ML, Holsen L, Holst B, Inui A, Jansson JO, Kirchner H, Korbonits M, Laferrere B, LeRoux CW, Lopez M, Morin S, Nakazato M, Nass R, Perez-Tilve D, Pfluger PT, Schwartz TW, Seeley RJ, Sleeman M, Sun Y, Sussel L, Tong J, Thorner MO, van der Lely AJ, van der Ploeg LH, Zigman JM, Kojima M, Kangawa K, Smith RG, Horvath T, Tschop MH. Ghrelin. Mol Metab. 2015;4:437–460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4443295</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26042199</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagamatsu S, Ohara-Imaizumi M, Nakamichi Y, Kikuta T, Nishiwaki C. Imaging docking and fusion of insulin granules induced by antidiabetes agents: sulfonylurea and glinide drugs preferentially mediate the fusion of newcomer, but not previously docked, insulin granules. Diabetes. 2006;55:2819–2825.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakagawa Y, Ohtsu Y, Nagasawa M, Shibata H, Kojima I. Glucose promotes its own metabolism by acting on the cell-surface glucose-sensing receptor T1R3. Endocr J. 2014;61:119–131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24200979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nenquin M, Szollosi A, Aguilar-Bryan L, Bryan J, Henquin JC. Both triggering and amplifying pathways contribute to fuel-induced insulin secretion in the absence of sulfonylurea receptor-1 in pancreatic beta-cells. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:32316–32324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15175349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nesher R, Cerasi E. Modeling Phasic Insulin Release: Immediate and Time-Dependent Effects of Glucose. Diabetes. 2002;51:S53–S59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11815459</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nevins AK, Thurmond DC. Glucose regulates the cortical actin network through modulation of Cdc42 cycling to stimulate insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2003;285:C698–710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12760905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nevins AK, Thurmond DC. Caveolin-1 functions as a novel Cdc42 guanine nucleotide dissociation inhibitor in pancreatic beta-cells. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:18961–18972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16714282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newsholme P, Cruzat V, Arfuso F, Keane K. Nutrient regulation of insulin secretion and action. J Endocrinol. 2014;221:R105–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24667247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholls DG. The Pancreatic beta-Cell: A Bioenergetic Perspective. Physiol Rev. 2016;96:1385–1447.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27582250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nie J, Lilley BN, Pan YA, Faruque O, Liu X, Zhang W, Sanes JR, Han X, Shi Y. SAD-A potentiates glucose-stimulated insulin secretion as a mediator of glucagon-like peptide 1 response in pancreatic beta cells. Mol Cell Biol. 2013;33:2527–2534.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700116</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23629625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunez DJ, Bush MA, Collins DA, McMullen SL, Gillmor D, Apseloff G, Atiee G, Corsino L, Morrow L, Feldman PL. Gut hormone pharmacology of a novel GPR119 agonist (GSK1292263), metformin, and sitagliptin in type 2 diabetes mellitus: results from two randomized studies. PLoS One. 2014;9:e92494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3974707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24699248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohara-Imaizumi M, Fujiwara T, Nakamichi Y, Okamura T, Akimoto Y, Kawai J, Matsushima S, Kawakami H, Watanabe T, Akagawa K, Nagamatsu S. Imaging analysis reveals mechanistic differences between first- and second-phase insulin exocytosis. J Cell Biol. 2007;177:695–705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2064214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17502420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohishi T, Yoshida S. The therapeutic potential of GPR119 agonists for type 2 diabetes. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2012;21:321–328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22292451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oya M, Kitaguchi T, Harada K, Numano R, Sato T, Kojima M, Tsuboi T. Low glucose-induced ghrelin secretion is mediated by an ATP-sensitive potassium channel. J Endocrinol. 2015;226:25–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26099355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacini G, Mari A, Fouqueray P, Bolze S, Roden M. Imeglimin increases glucose-dependent insulin secretion and improves beta-cell function in patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2015;17:541–545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panten U, Fruh E, Reckers K, Rustenbeck I. Acute metabolic amplification of insulin secretion in mouse islets: Role of cytosolic acetyl-CoA. Metabolism. 2016;65:1225–1229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panten U, Rustenbeck I. Fuel-induced amplification of insulin secretion in mouse pancreatic islets exposed to a high sulfonylurea concentration: role of the NADPH/NADP+ ratio. Diabetologia. 2008;51:101–109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17960358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parker HE, Adriaenssens A, Rogers G, Richards P, Koepsell H, Reimann F, Gribble FM. Predominant role of active versus facilitative glucose transport for glucagon-like peptide-1 secretion. Diabetologia. 2012;55:2445–2455.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3411305</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22638549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patterson JN, Cousteils K, Lou JW, Manning Fox JE, MacDonald PE, Joseph JW. Mitochondrial metabolism of pyruvate is essential for regulating glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:13335–13346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24675076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perry RJ, Cardone RL, Petersen MC, Zhang D, Fouqueray P, Hallakou-Bozec S, Bolze S, Shulman GI, Petersen KF, Kibbey RG. Imeglimin lowers glucose primarily by amplifying glucose-stimulated insulin secretion in high-fat-fed rodents. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2016;311:E461–470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5005968</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27406738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pirags V, Lebovitz H, Fouqueray P. Imeglimin, a novel glimin oral antidiabetic, exhibits a good efficacy and safety profile in type 2 diabetic patients. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2012;14:852–858.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22519919</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pizarro-Delgado J, Deeney JT, Martin-del-Rio R, Corkey BE, Tamarit-Rodriguez J. KCl -Permeabilized Pancreatic Islets: An Experimental Model to Explore the Messenger Role of ATP in the Mechanism of Insulin Secretion. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0140096.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4596849</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26444014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pollak N, Dolle C, Ziegler M. The power to reduce: pyridine nucleotides–small molecules with a multitude of functions. Biochem J. 2007;402:205–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1798440</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17295611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prentki M, Matschinsky FM, Madiraju SR. Metabolic signaling in fuel-induced insulin secretion. Cell Metab. 2013;18:162–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23791483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prentki M, Vischer S, Glennon MC, Regazzi R, Deeney JT, Corkey BE. Malonyl-CoA and long chain acyl-CoA esters as metabolic coupling factors in nutrient-induced insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 1992;267:5802–5810.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1556096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravier MA, Nenquin M, Miki T, Seino S, Henquin JC. Glucose controls cytosolic Ca2+ and insulin secretion in mouse islets lacking adenosine triphosphate-sensitive K+ channels owing to a knockout of the pore-forming subunit Kir6.2. Endocrinology. 2009;150:33–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18787024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts A, Renwick AG, Sims J, Snodin DJ. Sucralose metabolism and pharmacokinetics in man. Food Chem Toxicol. 2000;38(Suppl 2):S31–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10882816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ronnebaum SM, Ilkayeva O, Burgess SC, Joseph JW, Lu D, Stevens RD, Becker TC, Sherry AD, Newgard CB, Jensen MV. A pyruvate cycling pathway involving cytosolic NADP-dependent isocitrate dehydrogenase regulates glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:30593–30602.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16912049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ronnebaum SM, Jensen MV, Hohmeier HE, Burgess SC, Zhou YP, Qian S, MacNeil D, Howard A, Thornberry N, Ilkayeva O, Lu D, Sherry AD, Newgard CB. Silencing of cytosolic or mitochondrial isoforms of malic enzyme has no effect on glucose-stimulated insulin secretion from rodent islets. J Biol Chem. 2008;283:28909–28917.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2570884</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18755687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rorsman P, Ashcroft FM, Trube G. Single Ca channel currents in mouse pancreatic B-cells. Pflugers Arch. 1988;412:597–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2463514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rorsman P, Renstrom E. Insulin granule dynamics in pancreatic beta cells. Diabetologia. 2003;46:1029–1045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12879249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roscioni SS, Migliorini A, Gegg M, Lickert H. Impact of islet architecture on beta-cell heterogeneity, plasticity and function. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2016;12:695–709.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27585958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rountree AM, Neal AS, Lisowski M, Rizzo N, Radtke J, White S, Luciani DS, Kim F, Hampe CS, Sweet IR. Control of insulin secretion by cytochrome C and calcium signaling in islets with impaired metabolism. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:19110–19119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4081948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24841202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rutter GA, Pullen TJ, Hodson DJ, Martinez-Sanchez A. Pancreatic beta-cell identity, glucose sensing and the control of insulin secretion. Biochem J. 2015;466:203–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25697093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamaki J, Fu A, Reeks C, Baird S, Depatie C, Al Azzabi M, Bardeesy N, Gingras AC, Yee SP, Screaton RA. Role of the SIK2-p35-PJA2 complex in pancreatic beta-cell functional compensation. Nat Cell Biol. 2014;16:234–244.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4107453</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakata I, Park WM, Walker AK, Piper PK, Chuang JC, Osborne-Lawrence S, Zigman JM. Glucose-mediated control of ghrelin release from primary cultures of gastric mucosal cells. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2012;302:E1300–1310.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361986</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22414807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakuma K, Yabuki C, Maruyama M, Abiru A, Komatsu H, Negoro N, Tsujihata Y, Takeuchi K, Habata Y, Mori M. Fasiglifam (TAK-875) has dual potentiating mechanisms via Galphaq-GPR40/FFAR1 signaling branches on glucose-dependent insulin secretion. Pharmacol Res Perspect. 2016;4:e00237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876146</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27433346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santana MS, Monteiro WM, Costa MR, Sampaio VS, Brito MA, Lacerda MV, Alecrim MG. High frequency of diabetes and impaired fasting glucose in patients with glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency in the Western brazilian Amazon. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2014;91:74–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4080572</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24865682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satin LS, Cook DL. Voltage-gated Ca2+ current in pancreatic B-cells. Pflugers Arch. 1985;404:385–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2414720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato Y, Aizawa T, Komatsu M, Okada N, Yamada T. Dual Functional Role of Membrane Depolarization/Ca2+ Influx in Rat Pancreatic B-Cell. Diabetes. 1992;41:438–443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1318855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato Y, Nenquin M, Henquin JC. Relative contribution of Ca2+-dependent and Ca2+-independent mechanisms to the regulation of insulin secretion by glucose. FEBS Letters. 1998;421:115–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9468290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scheen AJ. Investigational insulin secretagogues for type 2 diabetes. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2016:1–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26881467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuit F, De Vos A, Farfari S, Moens K, Pipeleers D, Brun T, Prentki M. Metabolic Fate of Glucose in Purified Islet Cells: GLUCOSE-REGULATED ANAPLEROSIS IN CELLS. Journal of Biological Chemistry. 1997;272:18572–18579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9228023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott JW, Galic S, Graham KL, Foitzik R, Ling NX, Dite TA, Issa SM, Langendorf CG, Weng QP, Thomas HE, Kay TW, Birnberg NC, Steinberg GR, Kemp BE, Oakhill JS. Inhibition of AMP-Activated Protein Kinase at the Allosteric Drug-Binding Site Promotes Islet Insulin Release. Chem Biol. 2015;22:705–711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26091167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shigeto M, Ramracheya R, Tarasov AI, Cha CY, Chibalina MV, Hastoy B, Philippaert K, Reinbothe T, Rorsman N, Salehi A, Sones WR, Vergari E, Weston C, Gorelik J, Katsura M, Nikolaev VO, Vennekens R, Zaccolo M, Galione A, Johnson PR, Kaku K, Ladds G, Rorsman P. GLP-1 stimulates insulin secretion by PKC-dependent TRPM4 and TRPM5 activation. J Clin Invest. 2015;125:4714–4728.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4665783</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26571400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shyng S, Ferrigni T, Nichols CG. Regulation of KATP channel activity by diazoxide and MgADP. Distinct functions of the two nucleotide binding folds of the sulfonylurea receptor. J Gen Physiol. 1997;110:643–654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2229399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9382893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith HQ, Smith TJ. Identification of a Novel Activator of Mammalian Glutamate Dehydrogenase. Biochemistry. 2016;55:6568–6576.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27808506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spegel P, Sharoyko VV, Goehring I, Danielsson AP, Malmgren S, Nagorny CL, Andersson LE, Koeck T, Sharp GW, Straub SG, Wollheim CB, Mulder H. Time-resolved metabolomics analysis of beta-cells implicates the pentose phosphate pathway in the control of insulin release. Biochem J. 2013;450:595–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23282133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stamenkovic JA, Andersson LE, Adriaenssens AE, Bagge A, Sharoyko VV, Gribble F, Reimann F, Wollheim CB, Mulder H, Spegel P. Inhibition of the malate-aspartate shuttle in mouse pancreatic islets abolishes glucagon secretion without affecting insulin secretion. Biochem J. 2015;468:49–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7234840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25731850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanley CA. Two genetic forms of hyperinsulinemic hypoglycemia caused by dysregulation of glutamate dehydrogenase. Neurochem Int. 2011;59:465–472.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081417</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21130127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stiernet P, Guiot Y, Gilon P, Henquin JC. Glucose acutely decreases pH of secretory granules in mouse pancreatic islets. Mechanisms and influence on insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2006;281:22142–22151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16760469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Straub SG, Sharp GW. Evolving insights regarding mechanisms for the inhibition of insulin release by norepinephrine and heterotrimeric G proteins. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2012;302:C1687–1698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3378079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22492651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swisa A, Granot Z, Tamarina N, Sayers S, Bardeesy N, Philipson L, Hodson DJ, Wikstrom JD, Rutter GA, Leibowitz G, Glaser B, Dor Y. Loss of Liver Kinase B1 (LKB1) in Beta Cells Enhances Glucose-stimulated Insulin Secretion Despite Profound Mitochondrial Defects. J Biol Chem. 2015;290:20934–20946.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4543653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26139601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tagliavini A, Pedersen MG. Spatiotemporal Modeling of Triggering and Amplifying Pathways in GLP-1 Secreting Intestinal L Cells. Biophys J. 2017;112:162–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5232896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28076808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi HK, Santos LR, Roma LP, Duprez J, Broca C, Wojtusciszyn A, Jonas JC. Acute nutrient regulation of the mitochondrial glutathione redox state in pancreatic beta-cells. Biochem J. 2014;460:411–423.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24678915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi N, Kadowaki T, Yazaki Y, Ellis-Davies GC, Miyashita Y, Kasai H. Post-priming actions of ATP on Ca2+-dependent exocytosis in pancreatic beta cells. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1999;96:760–765.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC15210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9892707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorens B. Neural regulation of pancreatic islet cell mass and function. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2014;16(Suppl 1):87–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25200301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thurmond DC, Gonelle-Gispert C, Furukawa M, Halban PA, Pessin JE. Glucose-stimulated insulin secretion is coupled to the interaction of actin with the t-SNARE (target membrane soluble N-ethylmaleimide-sensitive factor attachment protein receptor protein) complex. Mol Endocrinol. 2003;17:732–742.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12554769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian G, Sagetorp J, Xu Y, Shuai H, Degerman E, Tengholm A. Role of phosphodiesterases in the shaping of sub-plasma-membrane cAMP oscillations and pulsatile insulin secretion. J Cell Sci. 2012;125:5084–5095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22946044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian G, Sandler S, Gylfe E, Tengholm A. Glucose- and hormone-induced cAMP oscillations in alpha- and beta-cells within intact pancreatic islets. Diabetes. 2011;60:1535–1543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3292328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21444924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unger RH, Roth MG. A new biology of diabetes revealed by leptin. Cell Metab. 2015;21:15–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urban KA, Panten U. Selective loss of glucose-induced amplification of insulin secretion in mouse pancreatic islets pretreated with sulfonylurea in the absence of fuels. Diabetologia. 2005;48:2563–2566.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16283243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veprik A, Laufer D, Weiss S, Rubins N, Walker MD. GPR41 modulates insulin secretion and gene expression in pancreatic beta-cells and modifies metabolic homeostasis in fed and fasting states. FASEB J. 2016;30:3860–3869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vetterli L, Carobbio S, Pournourmohammadi S, Martin-del-Rio R, Skytt DM, Waagepetersen HS, Tamarit-Rodriguez J, Maechler P. Delineation of glutamate pathways and secretory responses in pancreatic islets with -cell-specific abrogation of the glutamate dehydrogenase. Mol Biol Cell. 2012;23:3851–3862.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459861</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22875990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vetterli L, Carobbio S, Frigerio F, Karaca M, Maechler P. The Amplifying Pathway of the beta-Cell Contributes to Diet-induced Obesity. J Biol Chem. 2016;291:13063–13075.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4933223</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27137930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vial G, Chauvin MA, Bendridi N, Durand A, Meugnier E, Madec AM, Bernoud-Hubac N, Pais de Barros JP, Fontaine E, Acquaviva C, Hallakou-Bozec S, Bolze S, Vidal H, Rieusset J. Imeglimin normalizes glucose tolerance and insulin sensitivity and improves mitochondrial function in liver of a high-fat, high-sucrose diet mice model. Diabetes. 2015;64:2254–2264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25552598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang SY, Chi MM, Li L, Moley KH, Wice BM. Studies with GIP/Ins cells indicate secretion by gut K cells is KATP channel independent. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2003;284:E988–1000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12676650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Z, Thurmond DC. Mechanisms of biphasic insulin-granule exocytosis - roles of the cytoskeleton, small GTPases and SNARE proteins. J Cell Sci. 2009;122:893–903.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2720925</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19295123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Z, Thurmond DC. Differential phosphorylation of RhoGDI mediates the distinct cycling of Cdc42 and Rac1 to regulate second-phase insulin secretion. J Biol Chem. 2010;285:6186–6197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2825414</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20028975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watts M, Fendler B, Merrins MJ, Satin LS, Bertram R, Sherman A. Calcium and Metabolic Oscillations in Pancreatic Islets: Who’s Driving the Bus?*. SIAM J Appl Dyn Syst. 2014;13:683–703.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4331037</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25698909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wauson EM, Zaganjor E, Lee AY, Guerra ML, Ghosh AB, Bookout AL, Chambers CP, Jivan A, McGlynn K, Hutchison MR, Deberardinis RJ, Cobb MH. The G proteincoupled taste receptor T1R1/T1R3 regulates mTORC1 and autophagy. Mol Cell. 2012;47:851–862.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3749915</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22959271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wauson EM, Guerra ML, Dyachok J, McGlynn K, Giles J, Ross EM, Cobb MH. Differential Regulation of ERK1/2 and mTORC1 Through T1R1/T1R3 in MIN6 Cells. Mol Endocrinol. 2015;29:1114–1122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4517997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26168033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie L, Zhu D, Gaisano HY. Role of mammalian homologue of Caenorhabditis elegans unc-13-1 (Munc13-1) in the recruitment of newcomer insulin granules in both first and second phases of glucose-stimulated insulin secretion in mouse islets. Diabetologia. 2012;55:2693–2702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada H, Yoshida M, Ito K, Dezaki K, Yada T, Ishikawa SE, Kakei M. Potentiation of Glucose-stimulated Insulin Secretion by the GPR40-PLC-TRPC Pathway in Pancreatic beta-Cells. Sci Rep. 2016;6:25912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4867641</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27180622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoder SM, Dineen SL, Wang Z, Thurmond DC. YES, a Src family kinase, is a proximal glucose-specific activator of cell division cycle control protein 42 (Cdc42) in pancreatic islet beta cells. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:11476–11487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24610809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Q, Bengtsson M, Partridge C, Salehi A, Braun M, Cox R, Eliasson L, Johnson PR, Renstrom E, Schneider T, Berggren PO, Gopel S, Ashcroft FM, Rorsman P. R-type Ca(2+)-channel-evoked CICR regulates glucose-induced somatostatin secretion. Nat Cell Biol. 2007;9:453–460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17369816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W, Lilja L, Mandic SA, Gromada J, Smidt K, Janson J, Takai Y, Bark C, Berggren PO, Meister B. Tomosyn Is Expressed in -Cells and Negatively Regulates Insulin Exocytosis. 2006. Diabetes. 55:574–581.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16505218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Z, Liew CW, Handy DE, Zhang Y, Leopold JA, Hu J, Guo L, Kulkarni RN, Loscalzo J, Stanton RC. High glucose inhibits glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase, leading to increased oxidative stress and beta-cell apoptosis. FASEB J. 2010;24:1497–1505.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2879949</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20032314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao S, Mugabo Y, Iglesias J, Xie L, Delghingaro-Augusto V, Lussier R, Peyot ML, Joly E, Taib B, Davis MA, Brown JM, Abousalham A, Gaisano H, Madiraju SR, Prentki M. alpha/beta-Hydrolase domain-6-accessible monoacylglycerol controls glucose-stimulated insulin secretion. Cell Metab. 2014;19:993–1007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24814481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
