<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">28613730</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK431076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822">Arnold Chiari Malformation</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hidalgo</LastName><ForeName>Joaquin A.</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Mississippi</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tork</LastName><ForeName>Craig A.</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>San Antonio Military Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varacallo</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Penn Highlands Healthcare System</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Arnold-Chiari, or simply Chiari malformation, is the name given to a group of deformities of the posterior fossa and hindbrain (cerebellum, pons, and medulla oblongata). Issues range from cerebellar tonsillar herniation through the foramen magnum to the absence of the cerebellum with or without other associated intracranial or extracranial defects such as hydrocephalus, syrinx, encephalocele, or spinal dysraphism. <b>Classification</b> Chiari malformations are classified based on their morphology and severity of anatomic defects, typically through imaging (or autopsy). Chiari I is the least severe and often found incidentally. It is characterized by one or both pointed (not rounded) cerebellar tonsils that project 5 mm below the foramen magnum, measured by a line drawn from the basion to the opisthion (McRae Line). Chiari II consists of brainstem herniation and a towering cerebellum in addition to the herniated cerebellar tonsils and vermis due to an open distal spinal dysraphism/myelomeningocele. Chiari III involves herniation of the hindbrain (cerebellum with or without the brainstem) into a low occipital or high cervical meningoencephalocele. Chiari IV is now considered obsolete. Prior to becoming an obsolete diagnosis, it was already a more controversial and rare variant that demonstrated severe cerebellar hypoplasia, similar to primary cerebellar agenesis. Previously some stated that myelomeningocele could be present, while others argued that the presence of myelomeningocele should then be classified as a Chiari II with a vanishing cerebellum. There are other controversial reported classifications, including Chiari 0, Chiari 1.5, and Chiari V. Chiari 0 is characterized by syringomyelia without hindbrain herniation while Chiari 1.5 is felt to be the progression of Chiari I with increased cerebellar tonsillar descent and some involvement of the brainstem. Chiari V, the most severe variant, represents cerebellar agenesis with occipital lobe descent and herniation through the foramen magnum.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s10">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s11">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s12">Postoperative and Rehabilitation Care</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s13">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s14">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s15">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s16">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17822" sec="article-17822.s18">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>de Arruda JA, Figueiredo E, Monteiro JL, Barbosa LM, Rodrigues C, Vasconcelos B. Orofacial clinical features in Arnold Chiari type I malformation: A case series. J Clin Exp Dent. 2018 Apr;10(4):e378-e382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5937955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29750100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhimani AD, Esfahani DR, Denyer S, Chiu RG, Rosenberg D, Barks AL, Arnone GD, Mehta AI. Adult Chiari I Malformations: An Analysis of Surgical Risk Factors and Complications Using an International Database. World Neurosurg. 2018 Jul;115:e490-e500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29684513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kandeger A, Guler HA, Egilmez U, Guler O. Major depressive disorder comorbid severe hydrocephalus caused by Arnold-Chiari malformation. Indian J Psychiatry. 2017 Oct-Dec;59(4):520-521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29497204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora R. Imaging spectrum of cerebellar pathologies: a pictorial essay. Pol J Radiol. 2015;80:142-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4364256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25806100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cama A, Tortori-Donati P, Piatelli GL, Fondelli MP, Andreussi L. Chiari complex in children--neuroradiological diagnosis, neurosurgical treatment and proposal of a new classification (312 cases). Eur J Pediatr Surg. 1995 Dec;5 Suppl 1:35-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8770577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hadley DM. The Chiari malformations. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2002 Jun;72 Suppl 2:ii38-ii40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1765588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12122202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iskandar BJ, Hedlund GL, Grabb PA, Oakes WJ. The resolution of syringohydromyelia without hindbrain herniation after posterior fossa decompression. J Neurosurg. 1998 Aug;89(2):212-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9688115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IK, Wang KC, Kim IO, Cho BK. Chiari 1.5 malformation : an advanced form of Chiari I malformation. J Korean Neurosurg Soc. 2010 Oct;48(4):375-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2982921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21113370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tubbs RS, Muhleman M, Loukas M, Oakes WJ. A new form of herniation: the Chiari V malformation. Childs Nerv Syst. 2012 Feb;28(2):305-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22038152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giammattei L, Borsotti F, Parker F, Messerer M. Chiari I malformation: surgical technique, indications and limits. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2018 Jan;160(1):213-217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29130121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markunas CA, Enterline DS, Dunlap K, Soldano K, Cope H, Stajich J, Grant G, Fuchs H, Gregory SG, Ashley-Koch AE. Genetic evaluation and application of posterior cranial fossa traits as endophenotypes for Chiari type I malformation. Ann Hum Genet. 2014 Jan;78(1):1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4041368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24359474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLone DG, Knepper PA. The cause of Chiari II malformation: a unified theory. Pediatr Neurosci. 1989;15(1):1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2699756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnautovic A, Splavski B, Boop FA, Arnautovic KI. Pediatric and adult Chiari malformation Type I surgical series 1965-2013: a review of demographics, operative treatment, and outcomes. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2015 Feb;15(2):161-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25479580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langridge B, Phillips E, Choi D. Chiari Malformation Type 1: A Systematic Review of Natural History and Conservative Management. World Neurosurg. 2017 Aug;104:213-219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28435116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlouhy BJ, Dawson JD, Menezes AH. Intradural pathology and pathophysiology associated with Chiari I malformation in children and adults with and without syringomyelia. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2017 Dec;20(6):526-541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29027876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Melikian R, Papavassiliou E. Chiari I Malformation Presenting as Shoulder Pain, Weakness, and Muscle Atrophy in a Collegiate Athlete. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2016 Jan-Feb;15(1):10-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26745162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers JM, Savage G, Stoodley MA. A Systematic Review of Cognition in Chiari I Malformation. Neuropsychol Rev. 2018 Jun;28(2):176-187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29468516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayamanne C, Fernando L, Mettananda S. Chiari malformation type 1 presenting as unilateral progressive foot drop: a case report and review of literature. BMC Pediatr. 2018 Feb 07;18(1):34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5804004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29415676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klekamp J. How Should Syringomyelia be Defined and Diagnosed? World Neurosurg. 2018 Mar;111:e729-e745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29317358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M. The lemon sign. Radiology. 2003 Jul;228(1):206-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12832584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicolaides KH, Campbell S, Gabbe SG, Guidetti R. Ultrasound screening for spina bifida: cranial and cerebellar signs. Lancet. 1986 Jul 12;2(8498):72-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2425202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin W, Duan G, Xie J, Shao J, Wang Z, Jiao B. Comparison of Results Between Posterior Fossa Decompression with and without Duraplasty for the Surgical Treatment of Chiari Malformation Type I: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. World Neurosurg. 2018 Feb;110:460-474.e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocque BG, Oakes WJ. Surgical Treatment of Chiari I Malformation. Neurosurg Clin N Am. 2015 Oct;26(4):527-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26408062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabba MF, Renor BS, Ghizoni E, Tedeschi H, Joaquim AF. Posterior fossa decompression with duraplasty in Chiari surgery: A technical note. Rev Assoc Med Bras (1992) 2017 Nov;63(11):946-949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J, Li Y, Wang T, Gao J, Xu J, Lai R, Tan D. Comparison of posterior fossa decompression with and without duraplasty for the surgical treatment of Chiari malformation type I in adult patients: A retrospective analysis of 103 patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017 Jan;96(4):e5945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5287962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28121938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grasso G, Torregrossa F. Minimally Invasive Surgery for Decompression in Chiari I Malformation. World Neurosurg. 2019 Aug;128:333-335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31121366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotil K, Ozdogan S, Kayaci S, Duzkalir HG. Long-Term Outcomes of a New Minimally Invasive Approach in Chiari Type 1 and 1.5 Malformations: Technical Note and Preliminary Results. World Neurosurg. 2018 Jul;115:407-413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29698796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakzaban P. Technique for Mini-open Decompression of Chiari Type I Malformation in Adults. Oper Neurosurg (Hagerstown) 2017 Aug 01;13(4):465-470.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28838117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quillo-Olvera J, Navarro-Ramírez R, Quillo-Olvera D, Quillo-Reséndiz J, Kim JS. Minimally Invasive Craniocervical Decompression for Chiari 1 Malformation: An Operative Technique. J Neurol Surg A Cent Eur Neurosurg. 2019 Jul;80(4):312-317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31018228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagzoog N, Reddy KK. Use of Minimally Invasive Tubular Retractors for Foramen Magnum Decompression of Chiari Malformation: A Technical Note and Case Series. World Neurosurg. 2019 Aug;128:248-253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31048052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Y, Liu J, Chen H, Jiang S, Li Q, Fang Y, Gong S, Wang Y, Huang S. A minimally invasive technique for decompression of Chiari malformation type I (DECMI study): study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2015 Apr 29;5(4):e007869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4420982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adzick NS, Thom EA, Spong CY, Brock JW, Burrows PK, Johnson MP, Howell LJ, Farrell JA, Dabrowiak ME, Sutton LN, Gupta N, Tulipan NB, D'Alton ME, Farmer DL, MOMS Investigators  A randomized trial of prenatal versus postnatal repair of myelomeningocele. N Engl J Med. 2011 Mar 17;364(11):993-1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3770179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21306277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messing-Jünger M, Röhrig A. Primary and secondary management of the Chiari II malformation in children with myelomeningocele. Childs Nerv Syst. 2013 Sep;29(9):1553-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24013325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Işik N, Elmaci I, Silav G, Celik M, Kalelioğlu M. Chiari malformation type III and results of surgery: a clinical study: report of eight surgically treated cases and review of the literature. Pediatr Neurosurg. 2009;45(1):19-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19221459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A, Gore S, Shah A, Dharurkar P, Vutha R, Patil A. Atlantoaxial Fixation for Chiari 1 Formation in Pediatric Age-Group Patients: Report of Treatment in 33 Patients. World Neurosurg. 2018 Mar;111:e668-e677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29294396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez-Sabater A, Ballestar-Tarin ML, Vazquez-Seoane M, Mari-Avargues L, Saus-Ortega C, Del Carmen Casal-Angulo M. Quality of Life in Individuals Affected by Arnold Chiari Malformation: Comparison and Validation of a Measurement Instrument. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. 2018;18(4):388-396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliaga L, Hekman KE, Yassari R, Straus D, Luther G, Chen J, Sampat A, Frim D. A novel scoring system for assessing Chiari malformation type I treatment outcomes. Neurosurgery. 2012 Mar;70(3):656-64; discussion 664-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6718293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21849925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yarbrough CK, Greenberg JK, Smyth MD, Leonard JR, Park TS, Limbrick DD. External validation of the Chicago Chiari Outcome Scale. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2014 Jun;13(6):679-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4327771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24724715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmer HS, Xi M, Young SH. Surgical Decompression for Chiari Malformation Type I: An Age-Based Outcomes Study Based on the Chicago Chiari Outcome Scale. World Neurosurg. 2017 Nov;107:285-290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28804039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strahle J, Geh N, Selzer BJ, Bower R, Himedan M, Strahle M, Wetjen NM, Muraszko KM, Garton HJ, Maher CO. Sports participation with Chiari I malformation. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2016 Apr;17(4):403-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26636249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meehan WP, Jordaan M, Prabhu SP, Carew L, Mannix RC, Proctor MR. Risk of athletes with Chiari malformations suffering catastrophic injuries during sports participation is low. Clin J Sport Med. 2015 Mar;25(2):133-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4257888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24905537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lei ZW, Wu SQ, Zhang Z, Han Y, Wang JW, Li F, Shu K. Clinical Characteristics, Imaging Findings and Surgical Outcomes of Chiari Malformation Type I in Pediatric and Adult Patients. Curr Med Sci. 2018 Apr;38(2):289-295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30074187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
