<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">28613624</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK430874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151">Bartonellosis</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mada</LastName><ForeName>Pradeep Kumar</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Louisiana State University Shreveport</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zulfiqar</LastName><ForeName>Hassam</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rawalpindi Medical University &amp; Allied Hospitals</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joel Chandranesan</LastName><ForeName>Andrew Stevenson</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Louisiana State University - Shreveport</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText><i>Bartonella</i> is a gram-negative intracellular facultative bacterium that is commonly implicated in causing zoonotic infections globally. Almost 20 different species of Bartonella have been isolated thus far among in which <i>Bartonella henselae</i>, <i>Bartonella quintana</i>, and <i>Bartonella bacilliformis</i> are frequently associated with infections in humans.  Trench fever also known as the five-day fever was first reported in Europe in soldiers. Trench fever is transmitted by body louse and is known to exclusively occur in humans. Oroya fever was first reported in 1870 when a railway line was being built from Lima to Oroya in Peru. An outbreak of fever killed several thousand workmen and was named Oroya fever after the place it was first reported. Some workers who survived the outbreak developed verruga peruana which are nodular ulcerating skin lesions. It is commonly reported in mountainous parts of Peru, Columbia, and Ecuador in South America. In 1885, a Peruvian medical student Daniel Carrion inoculated himself with material from verruga which resulted in his death from Oroya fever. Oroya fever is also known as Carrion disease for this reason.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s10">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s11">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s12">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s13">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18151" sec="article-18151.s14">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maurin M, Birtles R, Raoult D. Current knowledge of Bartonella species. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 1997 Jul;16(7):487-506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9272384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson CA, Moore AR, Perea AE, Mead PS. Cat scratch disease: U.S. clinicians' experience and knowledge. Zoonoses Public Health. 2018 Feb;65(1):67-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28707827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouqui P, Stein A, Dupont HT, Gallian P, Badiaga S, Rolain JM, Mege JL, La Scola B, Berbis P, Raoult D. Ectoparasitism and vector-borne diseases in 930 homeless people from Marseilles. Medicine (Baltimore) 2005 Jan;84(1):61-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15643300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez Clemente N, Ugarte-Gil CA, Solórzano N, Maguiña C, Pachas P, Blazes D, Bailey R, Mabey D, Moore D. Bartonella bacilliformis: a systematic review of the literature to guide the research agenda for elimination. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2012;6(10):e1819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3493376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23145188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chomel BB, Kasten RW, Floyd-Hawkins K, Chi B, Yamamoto K, Roberts-Wilson J, Gurfield AN, Abbott RC, Pedersen NC, Koehler JE. Experimental transmission of Bartonella henselae by the cat flea. J Clin Microbiol. 1996 Aug;34(8):1952-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC229161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8818889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosbacher ME, Klotz S, Klotz J, Pinnas JL. Bartonella henselae and the potential for arthropod vector-borne transmission. Vector Borne Zoonotic Dis. 2011 May;11(5):471-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20973657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foucault C, Brouqui P, Raoult D. Bartonella quintana characteristics and clinical management. Emerg Infect Dis. 2006 Feb;12(2):217-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3373112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16494745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arisoy ES, Correa AG, Wagner ML, Kaplan SL. Hepatosplenic cat-scratch disease in children: selected clinical features and treatment. Clin Infect Dis. 1999 Apr;28(4):778-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10825038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridder GJ, Boedeker CC, Technau-Ihling K, Sander A. Cat-scratch disease: Otolaryngologic manifestations and management. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2005 Mar;132(3):353-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marra CM. Neurologic complications of Bartonella henselae infection. Curr Opin Neurol. 1995 Jun;8(3):164-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7551113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raoult D, Fournier PE, Drancourt M, Marrie TJ, Etienne J, Cosserat J, Cacoub P, Poinsignon Y, Leclercq P, Sefton AM. Diagnosis of 22 new cases of Bartonella endocarditis. Ann Intern Med. 1996 Oct 15;125(8):646-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8849149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koehler JE, Sanchez MA, Garrido CS, Whitfeld MJ, Chen FM, Berger TG, Rodriguez-Barradas MC, LeBoit PE, Tappero JW. Molecular epidemiology of bartonella infections in patients with bacillary angiomatosis-peliosis. N Engl J Med. 1997 Dec 25;337(26):1876-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9407154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinson JW, Varela G, Molina-Pasquel C. Trench fever. 3. Induction of clinical disease in volunteers inoculated with Rickettsia quintana propagated on blood agar. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1969 Sep;18(5):713-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5810799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass JW, Vincent JM, Person DA. The expanding spectrum of Bartonella infections: II. Cat-scratch disease. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1997 Feb;16(2):163-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9041596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sander A, Posselt M, Oberle K, Bredt W. Seroprevalence of antibodies to Bartonella henselae in patients with cat scratch disease and in healthy controls: evaluation and comparison of two commercial serological tests. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 1998 Jul;5(4):486-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9665953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arias-Stella J, Lieberman PH, Erlandson RA, Arias-Stella J. Histology, immunohistochemistry, and ultrastructure of the verruga in Carrion's disease. Am J Surg Pathol. 1986 Sep;10(9):595-610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2428261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass JW, Freitas BC, Freitas AD, Sisler CL, Chan DS, Vincent JM, Person DA, Claybaugh JR, Wittler RR, Weisse ME, Regnery RL, Slater LN. Prospective randomized double blind placebo-controlled evaluation of azithromycin for treatment of cat-scratch disease. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1998 Jun;17(6):447-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9655532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foucault C, Raoult D, Brouqui P. Randomized open trial of gentamicin and doxycycline for eradication of Bartonella quintana from blood in patients with chronic bacteremia. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2003 Jul;47(7):2204-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC161867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tunkel AR, Glaser CA, Bloch KC, Sejvar JJ, Marra CM, Roos KL, Hartman BJ, Kaplan SL, Scheld WM, Whitley RJ, Infectious Diseases Society of America  The management of encephalitis: clinical practice guidelines by the Infectious Diseases Society of America. Clin Infect Dis. 2008 Aug 01;47(3):303-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18582201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
