<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">28613625</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK430875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112">Systemic Sclerosis</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adigun</LastName><ForeName>Rotimi</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Health Sciences, Antigua</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goyal</LastName><ForeName>Amandeep</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hariz</LastName><ForeName>Anis</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Charles Nicolle Hospital, Un. of Tunis El Manar</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>In 1753, Carlo Curzio first described a case of scleroderma, which was later thought to be scleroedema. The word "Scleroderma" was first used in 1836 to describe skin changes in an adult by Fantonetti, a Milanese physician. The triphasic vasospastic changes were first described by Maurice Raynaud in 1862. The systemic nature of the disease with increased pulmonary and/or renal involvement and mortality was described in 1894 in the textbook <i>The principles and practice of medicine</i> by Osler. <i>Thibierge-Weissenbach syndrome </i>was described in 1910, which was later described as CRST syndrome in 1964 by Winterbauer.  Although there has been significant progress in understanding the pathophysiology of Scleroderma over the past several years, the disease still poses significant morbidity and mortality in patients. Scleroderma is a rare connective tissue disorder with unknown and complex pathogenesis. Scleroderma can be divided into two forms, localized Scleroderma (morphea, linear scleroderma, and scleroderma en coup de sabre), or Systemic sclerosis, which can further be classified as either limited systemic sclerosis (formerly known as the CREST syndrome comprising of calcinosis, Raynaud phenomenon, esophageal dysmotility, sclerodactyly, and telangiectasia) or diffuse systemic sclerosis based on clinical and serological criteria. Localized scleroderma is a disease of the skin and subcutaneous tissue, leading to patches of thickened skin which on biopsy reveals dermal fibrosis similar to the histopathological changes seen in the thickened skin in Systemic Sclerosis. However, Localized Scleroderma is not associated with Raynaud phenomenon, digital ischemic events, or internal organ involvement. Antinuclear antibodies (ANA) may be present in up to 50% of cases of localized scleroderma; however, the more specific autoantibodies such as anti-centromere, anti-SCL70, and anti-RNA polymerase III are absent. Localized scleroderma is not associated with increased mortality. On the other hand, systemic sclerosis is associated with several systemic manifestations and internal organ involvement and is associated with increased mortality. The classification of systemic sclerosis is based on skin involvement.  Limited cutaneous systemic sclerosis (LcSSc), formerly known as the CREST syndrome, is associated with skin thickening distal to the elbows, distal to the knees, and/or face without trunk involvement. Diffuse cutaneous systemic sclerosis (DcSSc) is associated with skin thickening that may involve skin proximal to the elbows, proximal to the knees, face, and/or trunk. Both LcSSc and DcSSc are associated with several systemic manifestations and autoantibody positivity. Antinuclear antibodies (ANA) may be present in more than 90% of cases of systemic sclerosis, and at least one of the more specific autoantibodies (anti-centromere, anti-SCL70, and anti-RNA polymerase III) is present in up to 70% of the cases. The organs most frequently affected by scleroderma are the skin, gastrointestinal tract, lungs, kidneys, skeletal muscle, and pericardium.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s13">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s14">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s15">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-20112" sec="article-20112.s17">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>RODNAN GP, BENEDEK TG. An historical account of the study of progressive systemic sclerosis (diffuse scleroderma). Ann Intern Med. 1962 Aug;57:305-19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14493141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WINTERBAUER RH. MULTIPLE TELANGIECTASIA, RAYNAUD'S PHENOMENON, SCLERODACTYLY, AND SUBCUTANIOUS CALCINOSIS: A SYNDROME MIMICKING HEREDITARY HEMORRHAGIC TELANGIECTASIA. Bull Johns Hopkins Hosp. 1964 Jun;114:361-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14171636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arkachaisri T, Fertig N, Pino S, Medsger TA. Serum autoantibodies and their clinical associations in patients with childhood- and adult-onset linear scleroderma. A single-center study. J Rheumatol. 2008 Dec;35(12):2439-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19004036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zulian F. New developments in localized scleroderma. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2008 Sep;20(5):601-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18698185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeRoy EC, Medsger TA. Criteria for the classification of early systemic sclerosis. J Rheumatol. 2001 Jul;28(7):1573-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11469464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coentro JQ, Pugliese E, Hanley G, Raghunath M, Zeugolis DI. Current and upcoming therapies to modulate skin scarring and fibrosis. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2019 Jun;146:37-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30172924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politikou O, Giesen T, Reissner L, Calcagni M. Hand and wrist joint procedures in patients with scleroderma: a systematic review. J Hand Surg Eur Vol. 2019 May;44(4):402-407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30176750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunzelmann N. [Current treatment of systemic scleroderma]. Hautarzt. 2018 Nov;69(11):901-907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30143809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett FC, Cho M, Chatterjee S, Aguilar MB, Reveille JD, Mayes MD. Familial occurrence frequencies and relative risks for systemic sclerosis (scleroderma) in three United States cohorts. Arthritis Rheum. 2001 Jun;44(6):1359-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11407695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assassi S, Arnett FC, Reveille JD, Gourh P, Mayes MD. Clinical, immunologic, and genetic features of familial systemic sclerosis. Arthritis Rheum. 2007 Jun;56(6):2031-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17530643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora-Singh RK, Assassi S, del Junco DJ, Arnett FC, Perry M, Irfan U, Sharif R, Mattar T, Mayes MD. Autoimmune diseases and autoantibodies in the first degree relatives of patients with systemic sclerosis. J Autoimmun. 2010 Aug;35(1):52-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2878866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20223638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett FC, Gourh P, Shete S, Ahn CW, Honey RE, Agarwal SK, Tan FK, McNearney T, Fischbach M, Fritzler MJ, Mayes MD, Reveille JD. Major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class II alleles, haplotypes and epitopes which confer susceptibility or protection in systemic sclerosis: analyses in 1300 Caucasian, African-American and Hispanic cases and 1000 controls. Ann Rheum Dis. 2010 May;69(5):822-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2916702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19596691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormic ZD, Khuder SS, Aryal BK, Ames AL, Khuder SA. Occupational silica exposure as a risk factor for scleroderma: a meta-analysis. Int Arch Occup Environ Health. 2010 Oct;83(7):763-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20047060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabuenca JM. Toxic-allergic syndrome caused by ingestion of rapeseed oil denatured with aniline. Lancet. 1981 Sep 12;2(8246):567-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6116011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertzman PA, Blevins WL, Mayer J, Greenfield B, Ting M, Gleich GJ. Association of the eosinophilia-myalgia syndrome with the ingestion of tryptophan. N Engl J Med. 1990 Mar 29;322(13):869-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2314421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori Y, Kahari VM, Varga J. Scleroderma-like cutaneous syndromes. Curr Rheumatol Rep. 2002 Apr;4(2):113-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11890876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayes MD, Lacey JV, Beebe-Dimmer J, Gillespie BW, Cooper B, Laing TJ, Schottenfeld D. Prevalence, incidence, survival, and disease characteristics of systemic sclerosis in a large US population. Arthritis Rheum. 2003 Aug;48(8):2246-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12905479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernatsky S, Joseph L, Pineau CA, Belisle P, Hudson M, Clarke AE. Scleroderma prevalence: demographic variations in a population-based sample. Arthritis Rheum. 2009 Mar 15;61(3):400-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19248123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Englert H, Small-McMahon J, Davis K, O'Connor H, Chambers P, Brooks P. Systemic sclerosis prevalence and mortality in Sydney 1974-88. Aust N Z J Med. 1999 Feb;29(1):42-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10200812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri C, Valentini G, Cozzi F, Sebastiani M, Michelassi C, La Montagna G, Bullo A, Cazzato M, Tirri E, Storino F, Giuggioli D, Cuomo G, Rosada M, Bombardieri S, Todesco S, Tirri G, Systemic Sclerosis Study Group of the Italian Society of Rheumatology (SIR-GSSSc)  Systemic sclerosis: demographic, clinical, and serologic features and survival in 1,012 Italian patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 2002 Mar;81(2):139-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11889413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamaki T, Mori S, Takehara K. Epidemiological study of patients with systemic sclerosis in Tokyo. Arch Dermatol Res. 1991;283(6):366-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1796818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo CF, See LC, Yu KH, Chou IJ, Tseng WY, Chang HC, Shen YM, Luo SF. Epidemiology and mortality of systemic sclerosis: a nationwide population study in Taiwan. Scand J Rheumatol. 2011;40(5):373-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21388247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnett FC, Howard RF, Tan F, Moulds JM, Bias WB, Durban E, Cameron HD, Paxton G, Hodge TJ, Weathers PE, Reveille JD. Increased prevalence of systemic sclerosis in a Native American tribe in Oklahoma. Association with an Amerindian HLA haplotype. Arthritis Rheum. 1996 Aug;39(8):1362-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8702445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chifflot H, Fautrel B, Sordet C, Chatelus E, Sibilia J. Incidence and prevalence of systemic sclerosis: a systematic literature review. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2008 Feb;37(4):223-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17692364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silman AJ. Epidemiology of scleroderma. Ann Rheum Dis. 1991 Nov;50 Suppl 4:846-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1033319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1750796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laing TJ, Gillespie BW, Toth MB, Mayes MD, Gallavan RH, Burns CJ, Johanns JR, Cooper BC, Keroack BJ, Wasko MC, Lacey JV, Schottenfeld D. Racial differences in scleroderma among women in Michigan. Arthritis Rheum. 1997 Apr;40(4):734-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9125258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szücs G, Szekanecz Z, Zilahi E, Kapitány A, Baráth S, Szamosi S, Végvári A, Szabó Z, Szántó S, Czirják L, György Kiss C. Systemic sclerosis-rheumatoid arthritis overlap syndrome: a unique combination of features suggests a distinct genetic, serological and clinical entity. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2007 Jun;46(6):989-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17384178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinnin M, Ihn H, Yamane K, Asano Y, Yazawa N, Tamaki K. Clinical features of patients with systemic sclerosis accompanied by rheumatoid arthritis. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2003 Jan-Feb;21(1):91-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12673896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akimoto S, Ishikawa O, Muro Y, Takagi H, Tamura T, Miyachi Y. Clinical and immunological characterization of patients with systemic sclerosis overlapping primary biliary cirrhosis: a comparison with patients with systemic sclerosis alone. J Dermatol. 1999 Jan;26(1):18-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10063207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Angelo WA, Fries JF, Masi AT, Shulman LE. Pathologic observations in systemic sclerosis (scleroderma). A study of fifty-eight autopsy cases and fifty-eight matched controls. Am J Med. 1969 Mar;46(3):428-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5780367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Hoogen F, Khanna D, Fransen J, Johnson SR, Baron M, Tyndall A, Matucci-Cerinic M, Naden RP, Medsger TA, Carreira PE, Riemekasten G, Clements PJ, Denton CP, Distler O, Allanore Y, Furst DE, Gabrielli A, Mayes MD, van Laar JM, Seibold JR, Czirjak L, Steen VD, Inanc M, Kowal-Bielecka O, Müller-Ladner U, Valentini G, Veale DJ, Vonk MC, Walker UA, Chung L, Collier DH, Csuka ME, Fessler BJ, Guiducci S, Herrick A, Hsu VM, Jimenez S, Kahaleh B, Merkel PA, Sierakowski S, Silver RM, Simms RW, Varga J, Pope JE. 2013 classification criteria for systemic sclerosis: an American College of Rheumatology/European League against Rheumatism collaborative initiative. Arthritis Rheum. 2013 Nov;65(11):2737-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3930146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24122180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes M, Pauling JD. Exploring the patient experience of digital ulcers in systemic sclerosis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2019 Apr;48(5):888-894.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30205981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hruskova Z, Pippias M, Stel VS, Abad-Díez JM, Benítez Sánchez M, Caskey FJ, Collart F, De Meester J, Finne P, Heaf JG, Magaz A, Palsson R, Reisæter AV, Salama AD, Segelmark M, Traynor JP, Massy ZA, Jager KJ, Tesar V. Characteristics and Outcomes of Patients With Systemic Sclerosis (Scleroderma) Requiring Renal Replacement Therapy in Europe: Results From the ERA-EDTA Registry. Am J Kidney Dis. 2019 Feb;73(2):184-193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30122544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam GK, Hummers LK, Woods A, Wigley FM. Efficacy and safety of etanercept in the treatment of scleroderma-associated joint disease. J Rheumatol. 2007 Jul;34(7):1636-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17611970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nannini C, West CP, Erwin PJ, Matteson EL. Effects of cyclophosphamide on pulmonary function in patients with scleroderma and interstitial lung disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials and observational prospective cohort studies. Arthritis Res Ther. 2008;10(5):R124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2592814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18937831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira L, Mouthon L, Mahr A, Berezné A, Agard C, Mehrenberger M, Noël LH, Trolliet P, Frances C, Cabane J, Guillevin L, Group Français de Recherche sur le Sclérodermie (GFRS)  Mortality and risk factors of scleroderma renal crisis: a French retrospective study of 50 patients. Ann Rheum Dis. 2008 Jan;67(1):110-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17557890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penn H, Howie AJ, Kingdon EJ, Bunn CC, Stratton RJ, Black CM, Burns A, Denton CP. Scleroderma renal crisis: patient characteristics and long-term outcomes. QJM. 2007 Aug;100(8):485-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17601770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steen VD, Medsger TA. Changes in causes of death in systemic sclerosis, 1972-2002. Ann Rheum Dis. 2007 Jul;66(7):940-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1955114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17329309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guler SA, Winstone TA, Murphy D, Hague C, Soon J, Sulaiman N, Li KH, Dunne J, Wilcox PG, Ryerson CJ. Does Systemic Sclerosis-associated Interstitial Lung Disease Burn Out? Specific Phenotypes of Disease Progression. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2018 Dec;15(12):1427-1433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30188737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrisroe K, Hudson M, Baron M, de Vries-Bouwstra J, Carreira PE, Wuttge DM, Wang M, Frech TM, Stevens W, Proudman SM, Nikpour M, International Systemic Sclerosis Inception Cohort (INSYNC) collaboration  Determinants of health-related quality of life in a multinational systemic sclerosis inception cohort. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2018 Jul-Aug;36 Suppl 113(4):53-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30183603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
