<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">28723019</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK441990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370">Wilson Disease</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chaudhry</LastName><ForeName>Hammad S.</ForeName><Initials>HS</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anilkumar</LastName><ForeName>Arayamparambil C.</ForeName><Initials>AC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>SUNY Upstate Medical University</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Wilson disease or hepatolenticular degeneration is an autosomal recessive disease which results in an excess copper build up in the body. It primarily affects the liver and basal ganglia of the brain, but it can affect other organ systems too. Symptoms usually are related to the brain and liver. Liver-related symptoms include vomiting, weakness, ascites, swelling of the legs, yellowish skin, and itchiness. Brain or neurological symptoms include tremors, muscle stiffness, trouble speaking, personality changes, anxiety, and auditory or visual hallucinations. Wilson disease is an autosomal recessive condition caused by a mutation in the Wilson disease protein (<i>ATP7B</i>) gene. For a person to be affected,  a copy of the gene from each parent need to be inherited. Diagnosis is difficult and involves blood tests, urine tests, and a liver biopsy along with the clinical evaluation. Genetic testing may be used to screen the family members of those affected. The genetic defect is localized to long arm of chromosome 13 (13q), which has been shown to alter the copper transporting ATP gene in the liver. The majority of patients with Wilson disease present within the first decade of life with liver dysfunction. The neuropsychiatric features are seen in the third/fourth decade of life. Wilson disease is rare but if not recognized and treated, it is fatal.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s11">Staging</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s12">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s13">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s14">Postoperative and Rehabilitation Care</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s15">Consultations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s16">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s17">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s18">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31370" sec="article-31370.s21">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hedera P. Wilson's disease: A master of disguise. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2019 Feb;59:140-145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30797706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagral A, Sarma MS, Matthai J, Kukkle PL, Devarbhavi H, Sinha S, Alam S, Bavdekar A, Dhiman RK, Eapen CE, Goyal V, Mohan N, Kandadai RM, Sathiyasekaran M, Poddar U, Sibal A, Sankaranarayanan S, Srivastava A, Thapa BR, Wadia PM, Yachha SK, Dhawan A. Wilson's Disease: Clinical Practice Guidelines of the Indian National Association for Study of the Liver, the Indian Society of Pediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology and Nutrition, and the Movement Disorders Society of India. J Clin Exp Hepatol. 2019 Jan-Feb;9(1):74-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6363961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30765941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffenberger J, Lohse CM, Gotthardt D, Rupp C, Weiler M, Teufel U, Weiss KH, Gauss A. Long-term evaluation of urinary copper excretion and non-caeruloplasmin associated copper in Wilson disease patients under medical treatment. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2019 Mar;42(2):371-380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30746719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerosa C, Fanni D, Congiu T, Piras M, Cau F, Moi M, Faa G. Liver pathology in Wilson's disease: From copper overload to cirrhosis. J Inorg Biochem. 2019 Apr;193:106-111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30703747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takkar B, Temkar S, Venkatesh P. Wilson disease: Copper in the eye. Natl Med J India. 2018 Mar-Apr;31(2):122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30829235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou L, Song Y, Zhou X, Chu J, Tang X. Regional morphometric abnormalities and clinical relevance in Wilson's disease. Mov Disord. 2019 Apr;34(4):545-554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capone K, Azzam RK. Wilson's Disease: A Review for the General Pediatrician. Pediatr Ann. 2018 Nov 01;47(11):e440-e444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30423186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn N, Møller LB, Nurchi VM, Aaseth J. Chelating principles in Menkes and Wilson diseases: Choosing the right compounds in the right combinations at the right time. J Inorg Biochem. 2019 Jan;190:98-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30384011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan A, Yacoubian C, Beetham R, Catchpole A, Bullock D. The role of calculated non-caeruloplasmin-bound copper in Wilson's disease. Ann Clin Biochem. 2017 Nov;54(6):649-654.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27742851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stezin A, Kamble N, Jhunjhunwala K, Prasad S, Pal PK. Clinical Utility of Longitudinal Measurement of Motor Threshold in Wilson's Disease. Can J Neurol Sci. 2019 Mar;46(2):251-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30665472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poujois A, Sobesky R, Meissner WG, Brunet AS, Broussolle E, Laurencin C, Lion-François L, Guillaud O, Lachaux A, Maillot F, Belin J, Salamé E, Vanlemmens C, Heyd B, Bellesme C, Habes D, Bureau C, Ory-Magne F, Chaine P, Trocello JM, Cherqui D, Samuel D, de Ledinghen V, Duclos-Vallée JC, Woimant F. Liver transplantation as a rescue therapy for severe neurologic forms of Wilson disease. Neurology. 2020 May 26;94(21):e2189-e2202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazer H, Ede RJ, Mowat AP, Williams R. Wilson's disease: clinical presentation and use of prognostic index. Gut. 1986 Nov;27(11):1377-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1434058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3792921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillaud O, Dumortier J, Sobesky R, Debray D, Wolf P, Vanlemmens C, Durand F, Calmus Y, Duvoux C, Dharancy S, Kamar N, Boudjema K, Bernard PH, Pageaux GP, Salamé E, Gugenheim J, Lachaux A, Habes D, Radenne S, Hardwigsen J, Chazouillères O, Trocello JM, Woimant F, Ichai P, Branchereau S, Soubrane O, Castaing D, Jacquemin E, Samuel D, Duclos-Vallée JC. Long term results of liver transplantation for Wilson's disease: experience in France. J Hepatol. 2014 Mar;60(3):579-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24211743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qu W, Wei L, Zhu ZJ, Sun LY, Liu Y, Zeng ZG. Considerations for Use of Domino Cross-auxiliary Liver Transplantation in Metabolic Liver Diseases: A Review of Case Studies. Transplantation. 2019 Sep;103(9):1916-1920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30801517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhary NS, Saigal S, Saraf N, Rastogi A, Goja S, Bhangui P, Thiagrajan S, Gautam D, Govil D, Vohra V, Soin AS. Outcome of Living Donor Liver Transplantation for Wilson's Disease in Adults: A Single Center Experience. J Clin Exp Hepatol. 2018 Jun;8(2):132-135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5992308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29892175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belkhribchia MR, Belabbes S, Loukili M, El Hasni I, El Makkaoui M. An unusual and devastating presentation of neurologic Wilson's disease with extensive brain MRI lesions. Presse Med. 2018 Jun;47(6):588-591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29776795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28723019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
