<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">28722879</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK441849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327">Deadly Single Dose Agents</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Euwema</LastName><ForeName>Michael S.</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orange Park Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swanson</LastName><ForeName>Terrell J.</ForeName><Initials>TJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orange Park Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Although the basics of evaluating and treating most unknown ingestants are well known, many overdoses require very specific treatment if the patient is to have any chance of survival. Countless studies have been published supporting Dr. Gideon Koren's 1993 landmark article "Medications Which Can Kill a Toddler with One Tablet or Teaspoonful" in the Journal of Toxicology. while each has its own merits, most focus solely on pediatric overdoses, and relatively few of them provide an exhaustive list or act as a "quick-reference" when dealing with real-time ingestions.  Despite widespread public education, childproof containers, and other safety measures, accidental overdoses continue to occur.  In the United States, poison control centers receive over 2.2 million calls each year, 47% of which concern children less than six years of age.  Most pediatric accidental ingestions involve cosmetics and personal care products, followed by cleaning products, and then analgesics and prescription medications.  Adult overdoses usually are due to the intentional ingestion of analgesics and sedative-hypnotics.  Following are the list of toxic drugs (in decreasing severity/difficulty of treatment) included in this summary: : 1. Alpha-2 adrenergic agonists - clonidine, naphazoline, oxymetazoline, tetrahydrozoline. 2. Sulfonylureas - chlorpropamide, glyburide, glipizide, glimepiride. 3. Calcium channel blockers - nifedipine, verapamil, diltiazem, amlodipine, nicardipine. 4. Beta-blockers - metoprolol, labetalol. 5. Tricyclic antidepressants - imipramine, desipramine, amitriptyline, nortriptyline. 6. Opioids - codeine, hydrocodone, methadone, morphine, heroin. 7. Anti-diarrheals - diphenoxylate + atropine, loperamide. 8. Salicylates/Methyl salicylates - wintergreen oil, bismuth subsalicylate, mentholated balms. 9. Antipsychotics - loxapine, thioridazine, chlorpromazine. 10. Antimalarials - chloroquine, hydroxychloroquine, quinine. 11. Antiarrhythmics - quinidine, disopyramide, procainamide, flecainide. 12. Terpenoid (camphor) - analgesic, anti-itch, and cooling gels, ointments, and balms. 13. Non-alkaloid toxic lignan - podophyllin, podofilox. 14. Plant toxin/secondary metabolite - colchicine. 15. Oral acetylcholinesterase inhibitors - rivastigmine, donepezil, galantamine. 16. Methylxanthine - theophylline: 1,3-dimethylxanthine. 17. Partial opioid agonist/synthetics - buprenorphine/fentanyl. 18. Toxic alcohols - methanol, ethylene glycol. 19. Caustics /household products - acidic or alkaline household products, hydrofluoric acid, selenious acid, ammonia fluoride, methacrylic acid (cosmetic glue), naphthalene (mothballs).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s3">Function</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s4">Issues of Concern</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s5">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s6">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s7">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30327" sec="article-30327.s8">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Erickson TB, Thompson TM, Lu JJ. The approach to the patient with an unknown overdose. Emerg Med Clin North Am. 2007 May;25(2):249-81; abstract vii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17482020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koren G. Medications which can kill a toddler with one tablet or teaspoonful. J Toxicol Clin Toxicol. 1993;31(3):407-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8355317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bar-Oz B, Levichek Z, Koren G. Medications that can be fatal for a toddler with one tablet or teaspoonful: a 2004 update. Paediatr Drugs. 2004;6(2):123-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15035652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braitberg G, Oakley E. Small dose... big poison. Aust Fam Physician. 2010 Nov;39(11):826-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21301654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael JB, Sztajnkrycer MD. Deadly pediatric poisons: nine common agents that kill at low doses. Emerg Med Clin North Am. 2004 Nov;22(4):1019-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15474780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutter ME, Gerona RR, Davis MT, Roche BM, Colby DK, Chenoweth JA, Adams AJ, Owen KP, Ford JB, Black HB, Albertson TE. Fatal Fentanyl: One Pill Can Kill. Acad Emerg Med. 2017 Jan;24(1):106-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27322591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine M, Boyer EW, Pozner CN, Geib AJ, Thomsen T, Mick N, Thomas SH. Assessment of hyperglycemia after calcium channel blocker overdoses involving diltiazem or verapamil. Crit Care Med. 2007 Sep;35(9):2071-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marraffa JM, Holland MG, Sullivan RW, Morgan BW, Oakes JA, Wiegand TJ, Hodgman MJ. Cardiac conduction disturbance after loperamide abuse. Clin Toxicol (Phila) 2014 Nov;52(9):952-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25345436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein Y, Aks SE, Hutson JR, Juurlink DN, Nguyen P, Dubnov-Raz G, Pollak U, Koren G, Bentur Y. Colchicine poisoning: the dark side of an ancient drug. Clin Toxicol (Phila) 2010 Jun;48(5):407-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20586571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geib AJ, Babu K, Ewald MB, Boyer EW. Adverse effects in children after unintentional buprenorphine exposure. Pediatrics. 2006 Oct;118(4):1746-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17015570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M, Dubé PA, Gosselin S, Guimont C, Godwin J, Archambault PM, Chauny JM, Frenette AJ, Darveau M, Le Sage N, Poitras J, Provencher J, Juurlink DN, Blais R. Treatment for calcium channel blocker poisoning: a systematic review. Clin Toxicol (Phila) 2014 Nov;52(9):926-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4245158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25283255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao D, Heard K, Foran M, Koyfman A. Intravenous lipid emulsion in the emergency department: a systematic review of recent literature. J Emerg Med. 2015 Mar;48(3):387-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25534900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lange DW, Sikma MA, Meulenbelt J. Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation in the treatment of poisoned patients. Clin Toxicol (Phila) 2013 Jun;51(5):385-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23697460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang DH, Nelson LS, Hoffman RS. Methylene blue in the treatment of refractory shock from an amlodipine overdose. Ann Emerg Med. 2011 Dec;58(6):565-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21546119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey CN, Mycyk MB, Wahl MS. Can a poison center overdose guideline safely reduce pediatric emergency department visits for unintentional β-blocker ingestions? Am J Ther. 2012 Sep;19(5):346-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21192245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
