<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">29083706</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK459145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152">Quetiapine</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maan</LastName><ForeName>Jasdave S.</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>American University of Antigua</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ershadi</LastName><ForeName>Mona</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mazandaran University of Medical Sciences</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Israr</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bolan Medical College, Quetta, Pakistan</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saadabadi</LastName><ForeName>Abdolreza</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Western University/ Kaweah Delta</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Quetiapine is FDA approved for schizophrenia, acute manic episodes, and adjunctive treatment for major depressive disorder. Quetiapine is also used for several non-FDA-approved indications, such as generalized anxiety disorder. Quetiapine is available both as extended-release (once-daily dosing) or immediate-release (twice-daily dosing) tablets. This activity outlines the indications, mechanism of action, methods of administration, significant adverse effects, contraindications, monitoring, and toxicity of quetiapine, so providers can direct patient therapy successfully in instances where quetiapine provides a benefit to patient care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s2">Indications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s3">Mechanism of Action</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s4">Administration</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s5">Adverse Effects</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s6">Contraindications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s7">Monitoring</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s8">Toxicity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s9">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s10">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28152" sec="article-28152.s11">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Garriga M, Solé E, González-Pinto A, Selva-Vera G, Arranz B, Amann BL, Saiz-Ruiz J, Pérez-Blanco J, Vieta E. Efficacy of quetiapine XR vs. placebo as concomitant treatment to mood stabilizers in the control of subthreshold symptoms of bipolar disorder: Results from a pilot, randomized controlled trial. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2017 Oct;27(10):959-969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28882405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suttajit S, Srisurapanont M, Maneeton N, Maneeton B. Quetiapine for acute bipolar depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2014;8:827-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4077390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25028535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindström L, Lindström E, Nilsson M, Höistad M. Maintenance therapy with second generation antipsychotics for bipolar disorder - A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2017 Apr 15;213:138-150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28222360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maneeton N, Maneeton B, Woottiluk P, Likhitsathian S, Suttajit S, Boonyanaruthee V, Srisurapanont M. Quetiapine monotherapy in acute treatment of generalized anxiety disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2016;10:259-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villarreal G, Hamner MB, Cañive JM, Robert S, Calais LA, Durklaski V, Zhai Y, Qualls C. Efficacy of Quetiapine Monotherapy in Posttraumatic Stress Disorder: A Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial. Am J Psychiatry. 2016 Dec 01;173(12):1205-1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27418378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan M, Sperry L, Malhado-Chang N, Duffy A, Wheelock V, Farias S, O'Connor K, Olichney J, Shahlaie K, Zhang L. Atypical antipsychotic therapy in Parkinson's disease psychosis: A retrospective study. Brain Behav. 2017 Jun;7(6):e00639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5474696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28638698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagata T, Nakajima S, Shinagawa S, Plitman E, Nakayama K, Graff-Guerrero A, Mimura M. Baseline Predictors of Antipsychotic Treatment Continuation and Response at Week 8 in Patients with Alzheimer's Disease with Psychosis or Aggressive Symptoms: An Analysis of the CATIE-AD Study. J Alzheimers Dis. 2017;60(1):263-272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riedel M, Schmitz M, Østergaard PK, Ferrannini L, Franco MA, Alfano V, Vansvik ED. Comparison of the effects of quetiapine extended-release and quetiapine immediate-release on cognitive performance, sedation and patient satisfaction in patients with schizophrenia: a randomised, double-blind, crossover study (eXtRa). Schizophr Res. 2015 Mar;162(1-3):162-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25592805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber SR, Wehr AM, Duchemin AM. Prevalence of antipsychotic prescriptions among patients with anxiety disorders treated in inpatient and outpatient psychiatric settings. J Affect Disord. 2016 Feb;191:292-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26688499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saller CF, Salama AI. Seroquel: biochemical profile of a potential atypical antipsychotic. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1993;112(2-3):285-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7871032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cross AJ, Widzowski D, Maciag C, Zacco A, Hudzik T, Liu J, Nyberg S, Wood MW. Quetiapine and its metabolite norquetiapine: translation from in vitro pharmacology to in vivo efficacy in rodent models. Br J Pharmacol. 2016 Jan;173(1):155-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4813385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26436896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen NH, Rodriguiz RM, Caron MG, Wetsel WC, Rothman RB, Roth BL. N-desalkylquetiapine, a potent norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor and partial 5-HT1A agonist, as a putative mediator of quetiapine's antidepressant activity. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2008 Sep;33(10):2303-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18059438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Figueroa C, Brecher M, Hamer-Maansson JE, Winter H. Pharmacokinetic profiles of extended release quetiapine fumarate compared with quetiapine immediate release. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2009 Mar 17;33(2):199-204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18948162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz M, Iwersen-Bergmann S, Andresen H, Schmoldt A. Therapeutic and toxic blood concentrations of nearly 1,000 drugs and other xenobiotics. Crit Care. 2012 Jul 26;16(4):R136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3580721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22835221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeVane CL, Nemeroff CB. Clinical pharmacokinetics of quetiapine: an atypical antipsychotic. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2001;40(7):509-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11510628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergman H, Walker DM, Nikolakopoulou A, Soares-Weiser K, Adams CE. Systematic review of interventions for treating or preventing antipsychotic-induced tardive dyskinesia. Health Technol Assess. 2017 Aug;21(43):1-218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5572117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28812541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmi M, Murru A, Pacchiarotti I, Undurraga J, Veronese N, Fornaro M, Stubbs B, Monaco F, Vieta E, Seeman MV, Correll CU, Carvalho AF. Safety, tolerability, and risks associated with first- and second-generation antipsychotics: a state-of-the-art clinical review. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2017;13:757-777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5499790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28721057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aronow WS, Shamliyan TA. Effects of atypical antipsychotic drugs on QT interval in patients with mental disorders. Ann Transl Med. 2018 Apr;6(8):147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5952011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29862236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain V, Patel RK, Kapadia Z, Galiveeti S, Banerji M, Hope L. Drugs and hyperglycemia: A practical guide. Maturitas. 2017 Oct;104:80-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28923179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine M, Ruha AM. Overdose of atypical antipsychotics: clinical presentation, mechanisms of toxicity and management. CNS Drugs. 2012 Jul 01;26(7):601-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22668123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minns AB, Clark RF. Toxicology and overdose of atypical antipsychotics. J Emerg Med. 2012 Nov;43(5):906-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22555052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arslan ED, Demir A, Yilmaz F, Kavalci C, Karakilic E, Çelikel E. Treatment of quetiapine overdose with intravenous lipid emulsion. Keio J Med. 2013;62(2):53-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23708294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartos M, Knudsen K. Use of intravenous lipid emulsion in the resuscitation of a patient with cardiovascular collapse after a severe overdose of quetiapine. Clin Toxicol (Phila) 2013 Jul;51(6):501-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23768031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole JB, Stellpflug SJ, Ellsworth H, Harris CR. Reversal of quetiapine-induced altered mental status with physostigmine: a case series. Am J Emerg Med. 2012 Jul;30(6):950-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21802878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29083706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
