<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">29138588</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-704X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2017</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The application of clinical genetics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Appl Clin Genet</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle><i>RAI1</i> gene mutations: mechanisms of Smith-Magenis syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>85</StartPage>
          <EndPage>94</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>85-94</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/TACG.S128455</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Smith-Magenis syndrome (SMS; OMIM #182290) is a complex genetic disorder characterized by distinctive physical features, developmental delay, cognitive impairment, and a typical behavioral phenotype. SMS is caused by interstitial 17p11.2 deletions, encompassing multiple genes and including the retinoic acid-induced 1 gene (<i>RAI1</i>), or by mutations in <i>RAI1</i> itself. About 10% of all the SMS patients, in fact, carry an <i>RAI1</i> mutation responsible for the phenotype. <i>RAI1</i> (OMIM *607642) is a dosage-sensitive gene expressed in many tissues and highly conserved among species. Over the years, several studies have demonstrated that <i>RAI1</i> (or its homologs in animal models) acts as a transcriptional factor implicated in embryonic neurodevelopment, neuronal differentiation, cell growth and cell cycle regulation, bone and skeletal development, lipid and glucose metabolisms, behavioral functions, and circadian activity. Patients with <i>RAI1</i> pathogenic variants show some phenotypic differences when compared to those carrying the typical deletion. They usually have lower incidence of hypotonia and less cognitive impairment than those with 17p11.2 deletions but more frequently show the behavioral characteristics of the syndrome and overeating issues. These differences reflect the primary pathogenetic role of <i>RAI1</i> without the pathogenetic contribution of the other genes included in the typical 17p11.2 deletion. The better comprehension of physiological roles of <i>RAI1</i>, its molecular co-workers and interactors, and its contribution in determining the typical SMS phenotype will certainly open a new path for therapeutic interventions.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Falco</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mariateresa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and Medical Biotechnology, University of Naples "Federico II", Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Amabile</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sonia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and Medical Biotechnology, University of Naples "Federico II", Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Acquaviva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fabio</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Translational Medical Sciences (DISMET), Section of Pediatric Clinical Genetics, University of Naples "Federico II", Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Appl Clin Genet</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101579789</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1178-704X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">17p11.2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">craniofacial abnormalities</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurogenesis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep disorders</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">syndromic obesity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Disclosure The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29138588</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5680963</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/TACG.S128455</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">tacg-10-085</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith ACM. Deletion of the 17 short arm in 2 patients with facial clefts and congenital heart-disease. Am J Hum Genet. 1982;32(6):A146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AC, Magenis RE, Elsea SH. Overview of Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Assoc Genet Technol. 2005;31(4):163–167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16354942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenberg F, Guzzetta V, Montes de Oca-Luna R, et al.  Molecular analysis of the Smith-Magenis syndrome: a possible contiguous-gene syndrome associated with del(17)(p11.2) Am J Hum Genet. 1991;49(6):1207–1218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1686451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1746552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elsea SH, Girirajan S. Smith–Magenis syndrome. Eur J Hum Genet. 2008;16(4):412–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18231123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AC, McGavran L, Robinson J, et al.  Interstitial deletion of (17) (p11.2p11.2) in nine patients. Am J Med Genet. 1986;24(3):393–414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2425619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slager RE, Newton TL, Vlangos CN, Finucane B, Elsea SH. Mutations in RAI1 associated with Smith–Magenis syndrome. Nat Genet. 2003;33(4):466–468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12652298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zori RT, Lupski JR, Heju Z, et al.  Clinical, cytogenetic, and molecular evidence for an infant with Smith-Magenis syndrome born from a mother having a mosaic 17p11.2p12 deletion. Am J Med Genet. 1993;47(4):504–511.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8256814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell IM, Yuan B, Robberecht C, et al.  Parental somatic mosaicism is underrecognized and influences recurrence risk of genomic disorders. Am J Hum Genet. 2014;95(2):173–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4129404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25087610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acquaviva F, Sana ME, Della Monica M, et al.  First evidence of Smith-Magenis syndrome in mother and daughter due to a novel RAI mutation. Am J Med Genet A. 2017;173(1):231–238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juyal RC, Figuera LE, Hauge X, et al.  Molecular analyses of 17p11.2 deletions in 62 Smith-Magenis syndrome patients. Am J Hum Genet. 1996;58(5):998–1007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1914618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8651284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen KS, Manian P, Koeuth T, et al.  Homologous recombination of a flanking repeat gene cluster is a mechanism for a common contiguous gene deletion syndrome. Nat Genet. 1997;17(2):154–163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9326934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bi W, Saifi GM, Shaw CJ, et al.  Mutations of RAI1, a PHD-containing protein, in nondeletion patients with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Hum Genet. 2004;115(6):515–524.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15565467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girirajan S, Elsas LJ, Devriendt K, Elsea SH. RAI1 variations in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients without 17p11.2 deletions. J Med Genet. 2005;42(11):820–828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735950</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edelman EA, Girirajan S, Finucane B, et al.  Gender, genotype, and phenotype differences in Smith-Magenis syndrome: a meta-analysis of 105 cases. Clin Genet. 2007;71(6):540–550.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17539903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girirajan S, Vlangos CN, Szomju BB, et al.  Genotype-phenotype correlation in Smith-Magenis syndrome: evidence that multiple genes in 17p11.2 contribute to the clinical spectrum. Genet Med. 2006;8(7):417–427.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricard G, Molina J, Chrast J, et al.  Phenotypic consequences of copy number variation: insights from Smith-Magenis and Potocki-Lupski syndrome mouse models. PLoS Biol. 2010;8(11):e1000543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2990707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21124890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan J, Bi W, Lupski JR. Penetrance of craniofacial anomalies in mouse models of Smith-Magenis syndrome is modified by genomic sequence surrounding Rai1: not all null alleles are alike. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;80(3):518–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1821110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17273973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenberg F, Lewis RA, Potocki L, et al.  Multi-disciplinary clinical study of Smith-Magenis syndrome (deletion 17p11.2) Am J Med Genet. 1996;62(3):247–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8882782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dykens EMM, Smith ACC. Distinctiveness and correlates of maladaptive behaviour in children and adolescents with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 1998;42(Pt 6):481–489.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10030444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AC, Dykens E, Greenberg F. Behavioral phenotype of Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2) Am J Med Genet. 1998;81(2):179–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9613859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AC, Gropman AL, Bailey-Wilson JE, et al.  Hypercholesterolemia in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome: del (17) (p11.2p11.2) Genet Med. 2002;4(3):118–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12180145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubourg C, Bonnet-Brilhault F, Toutain A, et al.  Identification of nine new RAI1-truncating mutations in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients without 17p11.2 deletions. Mol Syndromol. 2014;5(2):57–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3977224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24715852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finucane BM, Konar D, Haas-Givler B, Kurtz MB, Scott CI., Jr The spasmodic upper-body squeeze: a characteristic behavior in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Dev Med Child Neurol. 1994;36(1):78–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8132119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Truong HT, Dudding T, Blanchard CL, Elsea SH. Frameshift mutation hotspot identified in Smith-Magenis syndrome: case report and review of literature. BMC Med Genet. 2010;11(1):142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2964533</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20932317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith ACM, Gropman A.  Smith-Magenis syndrome. In: Cassidy SB, Allanson JE, editors. Management of Genetic Syndromes. 3rd ed. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc; 2010. pp. 739–768.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allanson JE, Greenberg F, Smith AC. The face of Smith-Magenis syndrome: a subjective and objective study. J Med Genet. 1999;36(5):394–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734375</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10353786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomona N, Smith AC, Guadagnini JP, Hart TC. Craniofacial and dental phenotype of Smith–Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet A. 2006;140A(23):2556–2561.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17001665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarimski K. Communicative competence and behavioural phenotype in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Genet Couns. 2004;15(3):347–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15517828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gropman AL, Duncan WC, Smith AC. Neurologic and developmental features of the Smith-Magenis syndrome (del 17p11.2) Pediatr Neurol. 2006;34(5):337–350.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16647992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolters PL, Gropman AL, Martin SC, et al.  Neurodevelopment of children under 3 years of age with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Pediatr Neurol. 2009;41(4):250–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2785222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19748044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hildenbrand HL, Smith AC. Analysis of the sensory profile in children with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. 2012;32(1):48–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21599572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laje G, Morse R, Richter W, Ball J, Pao M, Smith AC. Autism spectrum features in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2010;154(4):456–462.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20981775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arron K, Oliver C, Moss J, Berg K, Burbidge C. The prevalence and phenomenology of self-injurious and aggressive behaviour in genetic syndromes. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2011;55(2):109–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20977515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sloneem J, Oliver C, Udwin O, Woodcock KA. Prevalence, phenomenology, aetiology and predictors of challenging behaviour in Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Intellect Disabil Res. 2011;55(2):138–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21199049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finucane B, Dirrigl KH, Simon EW. Characterization of self-injurious behaviors in children and adults with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Ment Retard. 2001;106(1):52–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11246713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alaimo JT, Barton LV, Mullegama SV, Wills RD, Foster RH, Elsea SH. Individuals with Smith-Magenis syndrome display profound neurodevelopmental behavioral deficiencies and exhibit food-related behaviors equivalent to Prader-Willi syndrome. Res Dev Disabil. 2015;47:27–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26323055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burns B, Schmidt K, Williams SR, Kim S, Girirajan S, Elsea SH. Rai1 haploinsufficiency causes reduced Bdnf expression resulting in hyperphagia, obesity and altered fat distribution in mice and humans with no evidence of metabolic syndrome. Hum Mol Genet. 2010;19(20):4026–4042.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7714048</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster RH, Kozachek S, Stern M, Elsea SH. Caring for the caregivers: an investigation of factors related to well-being among parents caring for a child with Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Genet Couns. 2010;19(2):187–198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20151318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potocki L, Glaze D, Tan DX, et al.  Circadian rhythm abnormalities of melatonin in Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Med Genet. 2000;37(6):428–433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1734604</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10851253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Leersnyder H, De Blois MC, Claustrat B, et al.  Inversion of the circadian rhythm of melatonin in the Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Pediatr. 2001;139(1):111–116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11445803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boone PM, Reiter RJ, Glaze DG, Tan DX, Lupski JR, Potocki L. Abnormal circadian rhythm of melatonin in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients with RAI1 point mutations. Am J Med Genet A. 2011;155(8):2024–2027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21739587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boudreau EA, Johnson KP, Jackman AR, et al.  Review of disrupted sleep patterns in Smith-Magenis syndrome and normal melatonin secretion in a patient with an atypical interstitial 17p11.2 deletion. Am J Med Genet A. 2009;149(7):1382–1391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2760428</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19530184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoumans J, Staaf J, Jönsson G, et al.  Detection and delineation of an unusual 17p11.2 deletion by array-CGH and refinement of the Smith-Magenis syndrome minimum deletion to approximately 650 kb. Eur J Med Genet. 2005;48(3):290–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16179224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlangos CN, Yim DK, Elsea SH. Refinement of the Smith-Magenis syndrome critical region to approximately 950kb and assessment of 17p11.2 deletions. Are all deletions created equally? Mol Genet Metab. 2003;79(2):134–141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12809645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlangos CN, Wilson M, Blancato J, Smith AC, Elsea SH. Diagnostic FISH probes for del(17)(p11.2p11.2) associated with Smith-Magenis syndrome should contain the RAI1 gene. Am J Med Genet A. 2005;132A(3):278–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15690371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liburd N, Ghosh M, Riazuddin S, et al.  Novel mutations of MYO15A associated with profound deafness in consanguineous families and moderately severe hearing loss in a patient with Smith-Magenis syndrome. Hum Genet. 2001;109(5):535–541.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang A, Liang Y, Fridell RA, et al.  Association of unconventional myosin MYO15 mutations with human nonsyndromic deafness DFNB3. Science. 1998;280(5368):1447–1451.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9603736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castigli E, Wilson SA, Garibyan L, et al.  TACI is mutant in common variable immunodeficiency and IgA deficiency. Nat Genet. 2005;37(8):829–834.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16007086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nickerson ML, Warren MB, Toro JR, et al.  Mutations in a novel gene lead to kidney tumors, lung wall defects, and benign tumors of the hair follicle in patients with the Birt-Hogg-Dubé syndrome. Cancer Cell. 2002;2(2):157–164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12204536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dardour L, Verleyen P, Lesage K, Holvoet M, Devriendt K. Bilateral renal tumors in an adult man with Smith-Magenis syndrome: the role of the FLCN gene. Eur J Med Genet. 2016;59(10):499–501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27633572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carney G, Wei S, Rizzo WB. Sjögren-Larsson syndrome: seven novel mutations in the fatty aldehyde dehydrogenase gene ALDH3A2. Hum Mutat. 2004;24(2):186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15241804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imai Y, Suzuki Y, Matsui T, Tohyama M, Wanaka A, Takagi T. Cloning of a retinoic acid-induced gene, GT1, in the embryonal carcinoma cell line P19: neuron-specific expression in the mouse brain. Brain Res Mol Brain Res. 1995;31(1–2):1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7476016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walz K, Caratini-Rivera S, Bi W, et al.  Modeling del(17)(p11.2p11.2) and dup(17)(p11.2p11.2) contiguous gene syndromes by chromosome engineering in mice: phenotypic consequences of gene dosage imbalance. Mol Cell Biol. 2003;23(10):3646–3655.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC154242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12724422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bi W, Yan J, Shi X, et al.  Rai1 deficiency in mice causes learning impairment and motor dysfunction, whereas Rai1 heterozygous mice display minimal behavioral phenotypes. Hum Mol Genet. 2007;16(15):1802–1813.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17517686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toulouse A, Rochefort D, Roussel J, Joober R, Rouleau GA. Molecular cloning and characterization of human RAI1, a gene associated with schizophrenia. Genomics. 2003;82(2):162–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12837267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fragoso YD, Stoney PN, Shearer KD, et al.  Expression in the human brain of retinoic acid induced 1, a protein associated with neurobehav-ioural disorders. Brain Struct Funct. 2015;220(2):1195–1203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4341004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24519454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seranski P, Hoff C, Radelof U, et al.  RAI1 is a novel polyglutamine encoding gene that is deleted in Smith-Magenis syndrome patients. Gene. 2001;270(1–2):69–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11404004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vulto-van Silfhout AT, Rajamanickam S, Jensik PJ, et al.  Mutations affecting the SAND domain of DEAF1 cause intellectual disability with severe speech impairment and behavioral problems. Am J Hum Genet. 2014;94(5):649–661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4067565</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24726472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faqeih EA, Al-Owain M, Colak D, et al.  Novel homozygous DEAF1 variant suspected in causing white matter disease, intellectual disability, and microcephaly. Am J Med Genet A. 2014;164A(6):1565–1570.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo T, Wagner E, Crandall JE, Dräger UC. A retinoic-acid critical period in the early postnatal mouse brain. Biol Psychiatry. 2004;56(12):971–980.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15601608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen L, Tao Y, Song F, Yuan X, Wang J, Saffen D. Evidence for genetic regulation of mRNA expression of the dosage-sensitive gene retinoic acid induced-1 (RAI1) in human brain. Sci Rep. 2016;6:19010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger SI, Ciccone C, Simon KL, et al.  Exome analysis of Smith-Magenis-like syndrome cohort identifies de novo likely pathogenic variants. Hum Genet. 2017;136(4):409–420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848494</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28213671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmona-Mora P, Encina CA, Canales CP, et al.  Functional and cellular characterization of human Retinoic Acid Induced 1 (RAI1) mutations associated with Smith-Magenis Syndrome. BMC Mol Biol. 2010;11(1):63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20738874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang WH, Guenthner CJ, Xu J, et al.  Molecular and neural functions of RAI1, the causal gene for Smith-Magenis syndrome. Neuron. 2016;92(2):392–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5098476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27693255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girirajan S, Truong HT, Blanchard CL, Elsea SH. A functional network module for Smith-Magenis syndrome. Clin Genet. 2009;75(4):364–374.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19236431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams SR, Zies D, Mullegama SV, Grotewiel MS, Elsea SH. Smithmagenis syndrome results in disruption of CLOCK gene transcription and reveals an integral role for RAI1 in the maintenance of circadian rhythmicity. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;90(6):941–949.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3370274</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22578325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darvekar S, Johnsen SS, Eriksen AB, Johansen T, Sjøttem E. Identification of two independent nucleosome-binding domains in the transcriptional co-activator SPBP. Biochem J. 2012;442(1):65–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22081970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yun M, Wu J, Workman JL, Li B. Readers of histone modifications. Cell Res. 2011;21(4):564–578.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3131977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21423274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atanesyan L, Günther V, Dichtl B, Georgiev O, Schaffner W. Polyglutamine tracts as modulators of transcriptional activation from yeast to mammals. Biol Chem. 2012;393(1–2):63–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22628299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilboux T, Ciccone C, Blancato JK, et al.  Molecular analysis of the Retinoic Acid Induced 1 gene (RAI1) in patients with suspected smith-magenis syndrome without the 17p11.2 deletion. PLoS One. 2011;6(8)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152558</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21857958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bi W, Ohyama T, Nakamura H, et al.  Inactivation of Rai1 in mice recapitulates phenotypes observed in chromosome engineered mouse models for Smith-Magenis syndrome. Hum Mol Genet. 2005;14(8):983–995.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15746153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alaimo JT, Hahn NC, Mullegama SV, Elsea SH. Dietary regimens modify early onset of obesity in mice haploinsufficient for Rai1. PLoS One. 2014;9(8):e105077.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25127133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahir R, Kennedy A, Elsea SH, Dickinson AJ. Retinoic acid induced-1 (Rai1) regulates craniofacial and brain development in Xenopus. Mech Dev. 2014;133:91–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen L, Mullegama SV, Alaimo JT, Elsea SH. Smith-Magenis syndrome and its circadian influence on development, behavior, and obesity – own experience. Dev Period Med. 2015;19(2):149–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26384114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carneiro BT, Araujo JF. The food-entrainable oscillator: a network of interconnected brain structures entrained by humoral signals? Chronobiol Int. 2009;26(7):1273–1289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noble EE, Billington CJ, Kotz CM, Wang C. The lighter side of BDNF. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol. 2011;300(5):R1053–R1069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3293512</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21346243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gray J, Yeo GS, Cox JJ, et al.  Hyperphagia, severe obesity, impaired cognitive function, and hyperactivity associated with functional loss of one copy of the brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) gene. Diabetes. 2006;55(12):3366–3371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2413291</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17130481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joober R, Benkelfat C, Toulouse A, et al.  Analysis of 14 CAG repeat-containing genes in schizophrenia. Am J Med Genet. 1999;88(6):694–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10581491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayes S, Turecki G, Brisebois K, et al.  CAG repeat length in RAI1 is associated with age at onset variability in spinocerebellar ataxia type 2 (SCA2) Hum Mol Genet. 2000;9(12):1753–1758.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10915763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potocki L, Bi W, Treadwell-Deering D, et al.  Characterization of Potocki-Lupski syndrome (dup(17)(p11.2p11.2)) and delineation of a dosage-sensitive critical interval that can convey an autism phenotype. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;80(4):633–649.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852712</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17357070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Zwaag B, Franke L, Poot M, et al.  Gene-network analysis identifies susceptibility genes related to glycobiology in autism. PLoS One. 2009;4(5):e5324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2683930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19492091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmona-Mora P, Walz K. Retinoic acid induced 1, RAI1: a dosage sensitive gene related to neurobehavioral alterations including autistic behavior. Curr Genomics. 2010;11(8):607–617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3078685</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21629438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redin C, Gérard B, Lauer J, et al.  Efficient strategy for the molecular diagnosis of intellectual disability using targeted high-throughput sequencing. J Med Genet. 2014;51(11):724–736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4215287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25167861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thaker VV, Esteves KM, Towne MC, et al.  Whole exome sequencing identifies RAI1 mutation in a morbidly obese child diagnosed with ROHHAD syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2015;100(5):1723–1730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422892</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25781356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Churbanov AY, Karafet TM, Morozov IV, et al.  Whole exome sequencing reveals homozygous mutations in RAI1, OTOF, and SLC26A4 genes associated with nonsyndromic hearing loss in Altaian families (South Siberia) PLoS One. 2016;11(4):e0153841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27082237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnett C, Yazgan O, Kuo HC, et al.  Williams syndrome transcription factor is critical for neural crest cell function in Xenopus laevis. Mech Dev. 2012;129(9–12):324–338.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3459152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22691402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hittner HM, King RA, Riccardi VM, et al.  Oculocutaneous albinoidism as a manifestation of reduced neural crest derivatives in the Prader-Willi syndrome. Am J Ophthalmol. 1982;94(3):328–337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6812426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kochilas L, Merscher-Gomez S, Lu MM, et al.  The role of neural crest during cardiac development in a mouse model of DiGeorge syndrome. Dev Biol. 2002;251(1):157–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12413905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim JH, Luo T, Sargent TD, Fallon JR. Developmental expression of Xenopus fragile X mental retardation-1 gene. Int J Dev Biol. 2005;49(8):981–984.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16281176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roper RJ, VanHorn JF, Cain CC, Reeves RH. A neural crest deficit in Down syndrome mice is associated with deficient mitotic response to Sonic hedgehog. Mech Dev. 2009;126(3–4):212–219.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19056491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wurdak H, Ittner LM, Lang KS, et al.  Inactivation of TGFbeta signaling in neural crest stem cells leads to multiple defects reminiscent of DiGeorge syndrome. Genes Dev. 2005;19(5):530–535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC551573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laje G, Bernert R, Morse R, Pao M, Smith AC. Pharmacological treatment of disruptive behavior in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2010;154C(4):463–468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3022344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20981776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poisson A, Nicolas A, Cochat P, et al.  Behavioral disturbance and treatment strategies in Smith-Magenis syndrome. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2015;10(1):111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4559928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26336863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Leersnyder H, Bresson JL, de Blois MC, et al.  Beta 1-adrenergic antagonists and melatonin reset the clock and restore sleep in a circadian disorder, Smith-Magenis syndrome. J Med Genet. 2003;40(1):74–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735264</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loviglio MN, Beck CR, White JJ, et al.  Identification of a RAI1-associated disease network through integration of exome sequencing, transcriptomics, and 3D genomics. Genome Med. 2016;8(1):105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5088687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27799067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
