<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">29251963</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1939-0599</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2018</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Developmental psychology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dev Psychol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Identifying differences in early literacy skills across subgroups of language-minority children: A latent profile analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>631</StartPage>
          <EndPage>647</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>631-647</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1037/dev0000477</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Despite acknowledgment that language-minority children come from a wide variety of home language backgrounds and have a wide range of proficiency in their first (L1) and second (L2) languages, it is unknown whether differences across language-minority children in relative and absolute levels of proficiency in L1 and L2 predict subsequent development of literacy-related skills. The purpose of this study was to identify subgroups of language-minority children and evaluate whether differences in level and rate of growth of early literacy skills differed across subgroups. Five-hundred and twenty-six children completed measures of Spanish and English language and early literacy skills at the beginning, middle, and end of the preschool year. Latent growth models indicated that children's early literacy skills were increasing over the course of the preschool year. Latent profile analysis indicated that language-minority children could be classified into nine distinct groups, each with unique patterns of absolute and relative levels of proficiency in L1 and L2. Results of three-step mixture models indicated that profiles were closely associated with level of early literacy skills at the beginning of the preschool year. Initial level of early literacy skills was positively associated with growth in code-related skills (i.e., print knowledge, phonological awareness) and inversely associated with growth in language skills. These findings suggest that language-minority children are a diverse group with regard to their L1 and L2 proficiencies and that growth in early literacy skills is most associated with level of proficiency in the same language. (PsycINFO Database Record</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>(c) 2018 APA, all rights reserved).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lonigan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName>
            <Initials>CJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Florida State University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Goodrich</LastName>
            <ForeName>J Marc</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Florida Center for Reading Research, Florida State University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Farver</LastName>
            <ForeName>JoAnn M</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Southern California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>U01 HD060292</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HD</Acronym>
            <Agency>NICHD NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <Agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <Agency>National Science Foundation</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Dev Psychol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0260564</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0012-1649</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002663" MajorTopicYN="Y">Child Language</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D032882" MajorTopicYN="N">Comprehension</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007807" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016013" MajorTopicYN="N">Likelihood Functions</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000067010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Literacy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008913" MajorTopicYN="N">Minority Groups</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019303" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multilingualism</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010700" MajorTopicYN="N">Phonetics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011932" MajorTopicYN="N">Reading</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013067" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Perception</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29251963</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS918374</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5886800</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/dev0000477</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">2017-56309-001</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Artiles AJ, Rueda R, Salazar JJ, Higareda I. Within-group diversity in minority disproportionate representation: English language learners in urban school districts. Exceptional Children. 2005;71:283–300.  https://doi.org/10.1177/001440290507100305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/001440290507100305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asparouhov T, Muthén B. Auxiliary variables in mixture modeling: Three-step approaches using Mplus. Structural Equation Modeling: A Multidisciplinary Journal. 2014;21:329–341.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10705511.2014.915181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705511.2014.915181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>August D, Shanahan T.  Report of the National Literacy Panel on Language-Minority Children and Youth. Mahwah, NJ: Erlbaum; 2006. Executive summary: Developing literacy in second-language learners.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the false discovery rate: A practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. 1995;57:289–300.  http://www.jstor.org/stable/2346101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bialystok E. Reshaping the mind: The benefits of bilingualism. Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology. 2011;65:229–235.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0025406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0025406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4341987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21910523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins LM, Lanza ST.  Latent Class and Latent Transition Analysis. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley; 2010. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cummins J. Linguistic interdependence and the educational development of bilingual children. Review of Educational Research. 1979;49:222–251.  https://doi.org/10.3102/00346543049002222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/00346543049002222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cummins J.  Teaching for transfer: Challenging the two solitudes assumption in bilingual education. In: Cummins J, Hornberger NH, editors. Encyclopedia of language and education: Vol. 5. Bilingual education. 2. New York, NY: Spring Science + Business Media; 2008. pp. 65–75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durgunoglu AY, Nagy WE, Hancin-Bhatt BJ. Cross-language transfer of phonological awareness. Journal of Educational Psychology. 1993;85:453–465.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.85.3.453.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.85.3.453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farver JM, Lonigan CJ, Eppe S. Effective early literacy skill development for young Spanish-speaking English language learners: An experimental study of two methods. Child development. 2009;80:703–719.  https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8624.2009.01292.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-8624.2009.01292.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19489898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fletcher JM, Shaywitz SE, Shankweiler DP, Katz L, Liberman IY, Suebing KK, … Shaywitz BA. Cognitive profiles of reading disability: Comparisons of discrepancy and low achievement definitions. Journal of Educational Psychology. 1994;86:6–23.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.86.1.6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.86.1.6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ford KL, Cabell SQ, Konold TR, Invernizzi M, Gartland LB. Diversity among Spanish-speaking English language learners: Profiles of early literacy skills in kindergarten. Reading and Writing: An Interdisciplinary Journal. 2013;26:889–912.  https://doi.org/10.1007/s11145-012-9397-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11145-012-9397-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Genesee F, Lindholm-Leary K, Saunders WM, Christian D, editors. Educating English language learners: A synthesis of research evidence. New York, NY: Cambridge University Press; 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldenberg C. Teaching English language learners: What the research does--and does not--say. American Educator. 2008;32(2):8–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez J, Pollard-Durodola S, Saenz L, Soares D, Davis H, Resendez N, Zhu L. Spanish and English early literacy profiles of preschool Latino English language learner children. Early Education and Development. 2016;27:513–531.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2015.1077038.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10409289.2015.1077038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodrich JM, Lonigan CJ, Farver JM. Do early literacy skills in children’s first language promote development of skills in their second language? An experimental evaluation of transfer. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2013;105:414–426.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0031780.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0031780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3764594</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24019555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodrich JM, Lonigan CJ, Kleuver CG, Farver JM. Development and transfer of vocabulary knowledge in Spanish-speaking language minority preschool children. Journal of Child Language. 2016;43:969–992.  https://doi.org/10.1017/S030500091500032X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S030500091500032X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26235695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gottardo A, Mueller J. Are first- and second-language factors related in predicting second-language reading comprehension? A study of Spanish-speaking children acquiring English as a second language from first to second grade. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2009;101:330–344.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0014320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0014320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer CS, Lawrence FR, Miccio AW. Exposure to English before and after entry into Head Start: Bilingual children’s receptive language growth in Spanish and English. International Journal of Bilingual Education and Bilingualism. 2008;11:30–56.  http://dx.doi.org/10.2167/beb376.0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2167/beb376.0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4586052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26430382</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart SA, Logan JAR, Thompson L, Kovas Y, McLoughlin G, Petrill SA. A latent profile analysis of math achievement, numerosity, and math anxiety in twins. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2016;108:181–193.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/edu0000045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/edu0000045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4779361</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26957650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemphill FC, Vanneman A, Rahman T. Achievement gaps: How Hispanic and White students in public schools perform in mathematics and reading on the National Assessment of Educational Progress [Statistical Analysis Report] National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP) 2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamil ML, Borman GD, Dole J, Kral CC, Salinger T, Torgesen J.  Improving adolescent literacy: Effective classroom and intervention practices: A practice guide. Washington, DC: National Center for Education, Evaluation, and Regional Assistance, Institute of Education Sciences, U.S. Department of Education; 2008.  (NCEE #2008-4027)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapantzoglou M, Restrepo MA, Gray S, Thompson MS. Language ability groups in bilingual children: A latent profile analysis. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research. 2015;58:1549–1562.  https://doi.org/10.1044/2015_JSLHR-L-14-0290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1044/2015_JSLHR-L-14-0290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26200211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kass RE, Raftery AE. Bayes Factors. Journal of the American Statistical Association. 1995;90:773–795.  http://www.jstor.org/stable/2291091.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kieffer MJ. Catching up or falling behind? Initial English proficiency, concentrated poverty, and the reading growth of language minority learners in the United States. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2008;100:851–868.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.100.4.851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.100.4.851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kieffer MJ. Converging trajectories: Reading growth in language minority learners and their classmates, kindergarten to grade 8. American Educational Research Journal. 2011;48:1187–1225.  https://doi.org/10.3102/0002831211419490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3102/0002831211419490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindsey KA, Manis FR, Bailey CE. Prediction of first-grade reading in Spanish-speaking English-language learners. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2003;95:482–494.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.95.3.482.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-0663.95.3.482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lonigan CJ, Farver JM, Eppe S.  Preschool comprehensive test of phonological and Print Processing: Spanish version (P-CTOPPP-S) Tallahassee, FL: Author; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lonigan CJ, Farver JM, Nakamoto J, Eppe S. Developmental trajectories of preschool early literacy skills: A comparison of language-minority and monolingual-English children. Developmental Psychology. 2013;49:1943–1957.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0031408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0031408</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23316767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lonigan CJ, Schatschneider C, Westberg L.  Developing early literacy: Report of the National Early Literacy Panel. Washington, DC: National Institute for Literacy; 2008. Identification of children’s skills and abilities linked to later outcomes in reading, writing, and spelling; pp. 55–106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lonigan CJ, Wagner RK, Torgesen JK, Rashotte CA.  Preschool Comprehensive Test of Phonological and Print Processing. Tallahassee, FL: Author; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manis FR, Lindsey KA, Bailey CE. Development of reading in grades K-2 in Spanish-speaking English-language learners. Learning Disabilities Research &amp; Practice. 2004;19:214–224.  https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1540-5826.2004.00107.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1540-5826.2004.00107.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muthén LK, Muthén BO.  Mplus User’s Guide. 7. Los Angeles, CA: Muthén &amp; Muthén; 1998–2015. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanovich KE. Matthew effects in reading: Some consequences of individual differences in the acquisition of literacy. Reading Research Quarterly. 1986;21:360–407.  http://www.jstor.org/stable/747612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storch SA, Whitehurst GJ. Oral language and code-related precursors to reading: Evidence from a longitudinal structural model. Developmental Psychology. 2002;38:934–947.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0012-1649.38.6.934.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0012-1649.38.6.934</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12428705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tein JY, Coxe S, Cham H. Statistical power to detect the correct number of classes in latent profile analysis. Structural Equation Modeling: A Multidisciplinary Journal. 2013;20:640–657.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10705511.2013.824781.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705511.2013.824781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904803</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24489457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas WP, Collier VP.  A national study of school effectiveness for language minority students’ long-term academic achievement. Santa Cruz, CA: University of California at Santa Cruz, Center for Research on Education, Diversity, and Excellence; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorndike RL, Hagen EP, Sattler JM.  The Stanford-Binet Intelligence Scale. 4. Chicago, IL: Riverside; 1986. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Census Bureau. Language use in the United States: 2011. 2013 Retrieved from  http://census.gov/library/publications/2013/acs/acs-22.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Census Bureau. Millennials outnumber baby boomers and are far more diverse, census bureau reports. 2015 Retrieved from  http://www.census.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2015/cb15-113.html?intcmp=sldr2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Department of Education, U.S. Department of Justice. Dear colleague letter: English learner students and limited English proficient parents. 2015 Retrieved from  http://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/oela/index.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vermunt JK. Latent class modeling with covariates: Two improved three-step approaches. Political Analysis. 2010;18:450–469.  http://www.jstor.org/stable/25792024.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner RK, Torgesen JK, Rashotte CA. Development of reading-related phonological processing abilities: New evidence of bidirectional causality from a latent variable longitudinal study. Developmental Psychology. 1994;30:73–87.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0012-1649.30.1.73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0012-1649.30.1.73</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner RK, Torgesen JK, Rashotte CA, Hecht SA. Changing relations between phonological processing abilities and word-level reading as children develop from beginning to skilled readers: A 5-year longitudinal study. Developmental Psychology. 1997;33:468–479.  http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/0012-1649.33.3.468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0012-1649.33.3.468</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9149925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitehurst GJ, Lonigan CJ. Child development and emergent literacy. Child Development. 1998;69:848–872.  https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8624.1998.tb06247.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-8624.1998.tb06247.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9680688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmerman IL, Steiner VG, Pond RE.  Preschool Language Scale, fourth edition, (PLS-4) San Antonio, TX: Psychological Corporation; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmerman IL, Steiner VG, Pond RE.  Preschool Language Scale, fourth edition, Spanish edition, (PLS-4 Spanish) San Antonio, TX: Psychological Corporation; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
