<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">29749357</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2018</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0971-5916</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>147</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2018</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Indian journal of medical research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Med Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle><i>Mycoplasma pneumoniae</i>: A significant but underrated pathogen in paediatric community-acquired lower respiratory tract infections.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>23</StartPage>
          <EndPage>31</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>23-31</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_1582_16</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Lower respiratory tract infections are considered a common cause responsible for morbidity and mortality among children, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae is identified to be responsible for up to 40 per cent of community-acquired pneumonia in children greater than five years of age. Extrapulmonary manifestations have been reported either due to spread of infection or autoimmune mechanisms. Infection by M. pneumoniae has high incidence and clinical importance but is still an underrated disease. Most widely used serologic methods are enzyme immunoassays for detection of immunoglobulin M (IgM), IgG and IgA antibodies to M. pneumoniae, though other methods such as particle agglutination assays and immunofluorescence methods are also used. Detection of M. pneumoniae by nucleic acid amplification techniques provides fast, sensitive and specific results. Utilization of polymerase chain reaction (PCR) has improved the diagnosis of M. pneumoniae infections. Besides PCR, other alternative amplification techniques include (i) nucleic acid sequence-based amplification, (ii) Qβ replicase amplification, (iii) strand displacement amplification, (iv) transcription-mediated amplification, and (v) ligase chain reaction. Macrolides are used as the first-line treatment in childhood for M. pneumoniae infections; however, emergence of macrolide-resistant M. pneumoniae is a cause of concern. Development of a safe vaccine is important that gives protective immunity and would be a major step in reducing M. pneumoniae infections.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kumar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Surinder</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Maulana Azad Medical College, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Indian J Med Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0374701</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0971-5916</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007075">Immunoglobulin M</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017714" MajorTopicYN="N">Community-Acquired Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007075" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin M</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009177" MajorTopicYN="N">Mycoplasma pneumoniae</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012141" MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory Tract Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-acquired pneumonia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycoplasma pneumoniae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lower respiratory tract infections</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macrolides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymerase chain reaction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serology</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29749357</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5967212</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_1582_16</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">IndianJMedRes_2018_147_1_23_232005</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Saigal SR, Sethi GR. Detection of IgM and IgG antibodies to Chlamydophila pneumoniae in pediatric community-acquired lower respiratory tract infections. Indian J Pathol Microbiol. 2011;54:782–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22234110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkinson TP, Waites KB. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections in childhood. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2014;33:92–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24346598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadsby NJ, Reynolds AJ, McMenamin J, Gunson RN, McDonagh S, Molyneaux PJ, et al.  Increased reports of Mycoplasma pneumoniae from laboratories in Scotland in 2010 and 2011-impact of the epidemic in infants. Euro Surveill. 2012;17 pii: 20110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22433597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Saigal SR, Sethi GR. Rapid diagnosis of Mycoplasma pneumoniae by polymerase chain reaction in community-acquired lower respiratory tract infections. Trop Doct. 2011;41:160–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21596845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammerschlag MR. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2001;14:181–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11979130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korppi M. Community-acquired pneumonia in children: Issues in optimizing antibacterial treatment. Paediatr Drugs. 2003;5:821–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14658923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nocard E, Roux ER. The microbe of peripneumonie. Ann Inst Pasteur (Paris) 1898;12:240–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dienes L, Edstall G. Observations on the L-organisms of Klieneberger. Proc Soc Exp Biol. 1937;36:740–74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Talkington DF. Mycoplasma pneumoniae and its role as a human pathogen. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2004;17:697–728.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC523564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15489344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Domingues D, Nogueira F, Tavira L, Exposto F. Mycoplasmas: What is the role in human infections? Acta Med Port. 2005;18:377–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16611542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eaton MD, Meiklejohn G, van Herick W. Studies on the etiology of primary atypical pneumonia: A filterable agent transmissible to cotton rats, hamsters, and chick embryos. J Exp Med. 1944;79:649–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2135382</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19871393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chanok RM, Dienes L, Eaton MD, Edward DGA, Freundt EA, Hayflick L, et al.  Mycoplamsa pneumoniae: Proposed nomenclature for atypical pneumonia organisms (Eaton agent) Science. 1963;140:662.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14020096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matas Andreu L, Molinos Abós S, Fernández Rivas G, González Soler V, Ausina Ruiz V. Serologic diagnosis of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin. 2006;24(Suppl 1):19–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17125664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Crabb DM, Bing X, Duffy LB. In vitro susceptibilities to and bactericidal activities of garenoxacin (BMS-284756) and other antimicrobial agents against human mycoplasmas and ureaplasmas. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2003;47:161–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12499185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB. New concepts of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections in children. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2003;36:267–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12950038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kannan TR, Baseman JB. ADP-ribosylating and vacuolating cytotoxin of Mycoplasma pneumoniae represents unique virulence determinant among bacterial pathogens. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:6724–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1458948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16617115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Balish MF, Atkinson TP. New insights into the pathogenesis and detection of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections. Future Microbiol. 2008;3:635–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2633477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19072181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maheshwari M, Kumar S, Sethi GR, Bhalla P. Detection of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in children with lower respiratory tract infections. Trop Doct. 2011;41:40–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21123487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Maria A, Saigal SR, Maheshwari M. Mycoplasma pneumoniae as a cause of non-resolving pneumonia in a neonate. J Med Microbiol. 2010;59:731–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20185548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ursi D, Ursi JP, Ieven M, Docx M, Van Reempts P, Pattyn SR, et al.  Congenital pneumonia due to Mycoplasma pneumoniae. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 1995;72:F118–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2528398</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7712269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters J, Singh H, Brooks EG, Diaz J, Kannan TR, Coalson JJ, et al.  Persistence of community-acquired respiratory distress syndrome toxin-producing Mycoplasma pneumoniae in refractory asthma. Chest. 2011;140:401–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3148797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21622549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood PR, Hill VL, Burks ML, Peters JI, Singh H, Kannan TR, et al.  Mycoplasma pneumoniae in children with acute and refractory asthma. Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2013;110:328–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3703852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23622002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>British Thoracic Society Standards of Care Committee. British thoracic society guidelines for the management of community acquired pneumonia in childhood. Thorax. 2002;57(Suppl 1):i1–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1765993</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorthi SP, Kapoor L, Chaudhry R, Sharma N, Perez-Perez GI, Panigrahi P, et al.  Guillain-Barré syndrome: Association with Campylobacter jejuni and Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections in India. Natl Med J India. 2006;19:137–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16836263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kashyap B, Kumar S, Sethi GR, Das BC, Saigal SR. Comparison of PCR, culture &amp; serological tests for the diagnosis of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in community-acquired lower respiratory tract infections in children. Indian J Med Res. 2008;128:134–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shenoy VD, Upadhyaya SA, Rao SP, Shobha KL. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children with acute respiratory infection. J Trop Pediatr. 2005;51:232–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15980029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaudhry R, Sharma S, Javed S, Passi K, Dey AB, Malhotra P, et al.  Molecular detection of Mycoplasma pneumoniae by quantitative real-time PCR in patients with community acquired pneumonia. Indian J Med Res. 2013;138:244–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3788211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24056602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nadagir SD, Kaleem Bahadur A, Anantappa Shepur T. Prevalence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae among HIV infected children. Indian J Pediatr. 2011;78:430–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21161445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shankar EM, Kumarasamy N, Balakrishnan P, Solomon S, Lejith R, Vengatesan A, et al.  Serosurveillance of acute Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection among HIV infected patients with pulmonary complaints in Chennai, Southern India. J Infect. 2006;53:325–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16442630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shankar EM, Rajasekaran S, Rao UA, Paramesh P, Krishnakumar R, Rajan R, et al.  Colonization of mycoplasma in the upper respiratory tract of AIDS patients with pulmonary symptoms in Chennai, India. Indian J Med Res. 2005;122:506–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16518001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Taylor-Robinson D. Mycoplasma and ureaplasma.  In: Manual of clinical microbiology. 10th ed. Versalovic J, Carroll KC, Funke G, Jorgensen JH, Landry ML, Warnock DW, editors. Washington, D.C: ASM Press; 2011. pp. 970–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rock RT, Vital AC, Silva COS, Pereira CAC, Tani JN. Community-acquired pneumonia in outpatients: Epidemiological, clinical and radiological findings of atypical pneumonia and not atypical. J Pneumol. 2000;26:5–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen M, Sahn SA. Resolution of pleural effusions. Chest. 2001;119:1547–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11348966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Rikihisa Y, Taylor-Robinson D. Mycoplasma and ureaplasma.  In: Manual of clinical microbiology. 8th ed. Murray PR, Baron EJ, Jorgensen JH, Pfaller MA, Yolken YH, editors. Washington, DC: American Society for Microbiology; 2003. pp. 972–90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Bébéar CM, Robertson JA, Talkington DF, Kenny GE.  Washington, DC: American Society for Microbiology; 2001. Cumitech 34, laboratory diagnosis of mycoplasmal infections.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waites KB, Bébéar CM, Talkington DF.  Mycoplasmas. Manual of commercial methods in clinical microbiology. In: Truant A, editor. Washington, DC: American Society for Microbiology; 2002. pp. 201–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daxboeck F, Krause R, Wenisch C. Laboratory diagnosis of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2003;9:263–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12667235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loens K, Beck T, Ursi D, Overdijk M, Sillekens P, Goossens H, et al.  Development of real-time multiplex nucleic acid sequence-based amplification for detection of Mycoplasma pneumoniae, Chlamydophila pneumoniae, and Legionella spp. in respiratory specimens. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46:185–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2224298</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar S, Wang L, Fan J, Kraft A, Bose ME, Tiwari S, et al.  Detection of 11 common viral and bacterial pathogens causing community-acquired pneumonia or sepsis in asymptomatic patients by using a multiplex reverse transcription-PCR assay with manual (enzyme hybridization) or automated (electronic microarray) detection. J Clin Microbiol. 2008;46:3063–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2546717</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Zong ZY, Liu YB, Ye H, Lv XJ. PCR versus serology for diagnosing Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection: A systematic review &amp; meta-analysis. Indian J Med Res. 2011;134:270–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3193707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21985809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitcher D, Chalker VJ, Sheppard C, George RC, Harrison TG. Real-time detection of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in respiratory samples with an internal processing control. J Med Microbiol. 2006;55:149–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16434706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loens K, Ieven M. Mycoplasma pneumoniae: Current knowledge on nucleic acid amplification techniques and serological diagnostics. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4814781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27064893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li W, Liu Y, Zhao Y, Tao R, Li Y, Shang S. Rapid diagnosis of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in children with pneumonia by an immunochromatographic antigen assay. Sci Rep. 2015;5:15539.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4614389</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26486047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-González R, Costa-García A, Fernández-Abedul MT. Enzymatic amplification-free nucleic acid hybridisation sensing on nanostructured thick-film electrodes by using covalently attached methylene blue. Talanta. 2015;142:11–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26003686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henderson KC, Benitez AJ, Ratliff AE, Crabb DM, Sheppard ES, Winchell JM, et al.  Specificity and strain-typing capabilities of nanorod array-surface enhanced Raman spectroscopy for Mycoplasma pneumoniae detection. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0131831.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4487258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao B, Zhao CJ, Yin YD, Zhao F, Song SF, Bai L, et al.  High prevalence of macrolide resistance in Mycoplasma pneumoniae isolates from adult and adolescent patients with respiratory tract infection in China. Clin Infect Dis. 2010;51:189–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20540621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okada T, Morozumi M, Tajima T, Hasegawa M, Sakata H, Ohnari S, et al.  Rapid effectiveness of minocycline or doxycycline against macrolide-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in a 2011 outbreak among Japanese children. Clin Infect Dis. 2012;55:1642–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22972867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dumke R, von Baum H, Lück PC, Jacobs E. Occurrence of macrolide-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae strains in Germany. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2010;16:613–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19765022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peuchant O, Ménard A, Renaudin H, Morozumi M, Ubukata K, Bébéar CM, et al.  Increased macrolide resistance of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in France directly detected in clinical specimens by real-time PCR and melting curve analysis. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2009;64:52–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19429926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada M, Buller R, Bledsoe S, Storch GA. Rising rates of macrolide-resistant Mycoplasma pneumoniae in the central United States. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31:409–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22209916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schurwanz N, Jacobs E, Dumke R. Strategy to create chimeric proteins derived from functional adhesin regions of Mycoplasma pneumoniae for vaccine development. Infect Immun. 2009;77:5007–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19667041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hausner M, Schamberger A, Naumann W, Jacobs E, Dumke R. Development of protective anti-Mycoplasma pneumoniae antibodies after immunization of guinea pigs with the combination of a P1-P30 chimeric recombinant protein and chitosan. Microb Pathog. 2013;64:23–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23948467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
