<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">29791036</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>50</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neuroplasticity in cholinergic neurons of the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus contributes to the development of cocaine addiction.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2239</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2246</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2239-2246</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.13962</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The laterodorsal tegmental nucleus (LDT) is a brainstem nucleus that sends cholinergic, glutamatergic, and gamma-aminobutyric acid (GABA)-ergic projections to the ventral tegmental area (VTA), a key brain region associated with reward information processing and reinforcement learning, and thus, with addiction induced by drugs of abuse, including cocaine. Recent studies have revealed that the LDT, in addition to the VTA, plays important roles in the development and expression of cocaine-induced addiction and stress-induced enhancement of addictive behaviors. Additionally, neuroplasticity induced in LDT cholinergic neurons by repeated cocaine administration critically contributes to these behaviors. Elucidation of the underlying mechanisms of cocaine-induced neuroplasticity in the LDT that influences reward circuit activity may lead to the development of therapeutic strategies to treat cocaine addiction and stress-induced reinstatement of cocaine use. This review summarizes recent progress in the study of the LDT, specifically neuroplasticity in LDT cholinergic neurons induced by cocaine and its functional roles in the development and modulation of addictive behaviors associated with cocaine.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2018 Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaneda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katsuyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7046-9275</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Molecular Pharmacology, Institute of Medical, Pharmaceutical and Health Sciences, Kanazawa University, Kanazawa, 920-1192, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>26120702</GrantID>
            <Agency>Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science, and Technology (MEXT) of Japan</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>15K06765</GrantID>
            <Agency>Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS)</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <Agency>Hoansha Foundation</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <Agency>Astellas Foundation for Research on Metabolic Disorders</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <Agency>The Natio Foundation</Agency>
            <Country>International</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>France</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059329" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019970" MajorTopicYN="N">Cocaine-Related Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009473" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuronal Plasticity</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013681" MajorTopicYN="N">Tegmentum Mesencephali</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">acetylcholine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">stress</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">synaptic plasticity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">ventral tegmental area</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29791036</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.13962</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abercrombie, E.D. &amp; Jacobs, B.L. (1987) Single-unit response of noradrenergic neurons in the locus coeruleus of freely moving cats. II. Adaptation to chronically presented stressful stimuli. J. Neurosci., 7, 2844-2848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arencibia-Albite, F., Vázquez, R., Velásquez-Martinez, M.C. &amp; Jiménez-Rivera, C.A. (2012) Cocaine sensitization inhibits the hyperpolarization-activated cation current Ih and reduces cell size in dopamine neurons of the ventral tegmental area. J. Neurophysiol., 107, 2271-2282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balcita-Pedicino, J.J., Omelchenko, N., Bell, R. &amp; Sesack, S.R. (2011) The inhibitory influence of the lateral habenula on midbrain dopamine cells: ultrastructural evidence for indirect mediation via the rostromedial mesopontine tegmental nucleus. J. Comp. Neurol., 519, 1143-1164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellone, C. &amp; Lüscher, C. (2006) Cocaine triggered AMPA receptor redistribution is reversed in vivo by mGluR-dependent long-term depression. Nat. Neurosci., 9, 636-641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolam, J.P., Francis, C.M. &amp; Henderson, Z. (1991) Cholinergic input to dopaminergic neurons in the substantia nigra: a double immunocytochemical study. Neuroscience, 41, 483-494.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Capriles, N., Rodaros, D., Sorge, R.E. &amp; Stewart, J. (2003) A role for the prefrontal cortex in stress- and cocaine-induced reinstatement of cocaine seeking in rats. Psychopharmacology, 168, 66-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cecchi, M., Khoshbouei, H., Javors, M. &amp; Morilak, D.A. (2002) Modulatory effects of norepinephrine in the lateral bed nucleus of the stria terminalis on behavioral and neuroendocrine responses to acute stress. Neuroscience, 112, 13-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cenci, M.A., Kalén, P., Mandel, R.J. &amp; Björklund, A. (1992) Regional differences in the regulation of dopamine and noradrenaline release in medial frontal cortex, nucleus accumbens and caudate-putamen: a microdialysis study in the rat. Brain Res., 581, 217-228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, B.T., Bowers, M.S., Martin, M., Hopf, F.W., Guillory, A.M., Carelli, R.M., Chou, J.K. &amp; Bonci, A. (2008) Cocaine but not natural reward self-administration nor passive cocaine infusion produces persistent LTP in the VTA. Neuron, 59, 288-297.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chowdhury, G.M., Fujioka, T. &amp; Nakamura, S. (2000) Induction and adaptation of Fos expression in the rat brain by two types of acute restraint stress. Brain Res. Bull., 52, 171-182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarke, P.B., Hommer, D.W., Pert, A. &amp; Skirboll, L.R. (1987) Innervation of substantia nigra neurons by cholinergic afferents from pedunculopontine nucleus in the rat: neuroanatomical and electrophysiological evidence. Neuroscience, 23, 1011-1019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conrad, K.L., McCutcheon, J.E., Cotterly, L.M., Ford, K.A., Beales, M. &amp; Marinelli, M. (2010) Persistent increases in cocaine-seeking behavior after acute exposure to cold swim stress. Biol. Psychiat., 68, 303-305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cornwall, J., Cooper, J.D. &amp; Phillipson, O.T. (1990) Afferent and efferent connections of the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus in the rat. Brain Res. Bull., 25, 271-284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Creed, M., Pascoli, V.J. &amp; Lüscher, C. (2015) Addiction therapy. Refining deep brain stimulation to emulate optogenetic treatment of synaptic pathology. Science, 347, 659-664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Creed, M., Kaufling, J., Fois, G.R., Jalabert, M., Yuan, T., Lüscher, C., Georges, F. &amp; Bellone, C. (2016) Cocaine exposure enhances the activity of ventral tegmental area dopamine neurons via calcium-impermeable NMDARs. J. Neurosci., 36, 10759-10768.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dautan, D., Huerta-Ocampo, I., Witten, I.B., Deisseroth, K., Bolam, J.P., Gerdjikov, T. &amp; Mena-Segovia, J. (2014) A major external source of cholinergic innervation of the striatum and nucleus accumbens originates in the brainstem. J. Neurosci., 34, 4509-4518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dautan, D., Hacioglu Bay, H., Bolam, J.P., Gerdjikov, T.V. &amp; Mena-Segovia, J. (2016a) Extrinsic sources of cholinergic innervation of the striatal complex: a whole-brain mapping analysis. Front. Neuroanat., 10, 1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dautan, D., Souza, A.S., Huerta-Ocampo, I., Valencia, M., Assous, M., Witten, I.B., Deisseroth, K., Tepper, J.M. et al. (2016b) Segregated cholinergic transmission modulates dopamine neurons integrated in distinct functional circuits. Nat. Neurosci., 19, 1025-1033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del Arco, A., Ronzoni, G. &amp; Mora, F. (2015) Hypofunction of prefrontal cortex NMDA receptors does not change stress-induced release of dopamine and noradrenaline in amygdala but disrupts aversive memory. Psychopharmacology, 232, 2577-2586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong, Y. &amp; White, F.J. (2003) Dopamine D1-class receptors selectively modulate a slowly inactivating potassium current in rat medial prefrontal cortex pyramidal neurons. J. Neurosci., 23, 2686-2695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong, Y., Nasif, F.J., Tsui, J.J., Ju, W.Y., Cooper, D.C., Hu, X.T., Malenka, R.C. &amp; White, F.J. (2005) Cocaine-induced plasticity of intrinsic membrane properties in prefrontal cortex pyramidal neurons: adaptations in potassium currents. J. Neurosci., 25, 936-940.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erb, S., Shaham, Y. &amp; Stewart, J. (1996) Stress reinstates cocaine-seeking behavior after prolonged extinction and a drug-free period. Psychopharmacology, 128, 408-412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erb, S., Funk, D. &amp; Lê, A.D. (2003) Prior, repeated exposure to cocaine potentiates locomotor responsivity to central injections of corticotropin-releasing factor (CRF) in rats. Psychopharmacology, 170, 383-389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fassini, A., Antero, L.S., Corrêa, F.M., Joca, S.R. &amp; Resstel, L.B. (2015) The prelimbic cortex muscarinic M3 receptor-nitric oxide-guanylyl cyclase pathway modulates cardiovascular responses in rats. J. Neurosci. Res., 93, 830-838.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forster, G.L. &amp; Blaha, C.D. (2000) Laterodorsal tegmental stimulation elicits dopamine efflux in the rat nucleus accumbens by activation of acetylcholine and glutamate receptors in the ventral tegmental area. Eur. J. Neurosci., 12, 3596-3604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forster, G.L., Yeomans, J.S., Takeuchi, J. &amp; Blaha, C.D. (2002) M5 muscarinic receptors are required for prolonged accumbal dopamine release after electrical stimulation of the pons in mice. J. Neurosci., 22, RC190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fort, P., Luppi, P.H. &amp; Jouvet, M. (1993) Glycine-immunoreactive neurones in the cat brain stem reticular formation. NeuroReport, 4, 1123-1126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goncalves, L., Sego, C. &amp; Metzger, M. (2012) Differential projections from the lateral habenula to the rostromedial tegmental nucleus and ventral tegmental area in the rat. J. Comp. Neurol., 520, 1278-1300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graziane, N.M., Polter, A.M., Briand, L.A., Pierce, R.C. &amp; Kauer, J.A. (2013) Kappa opioid receptors regulate stress-induced cocaine seeking and synaptic plasticity. Neuron, 77, 942-954.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grillner, P. &amp; Svensson, T.H. (2000) Nicotine-induced excitation of midbrain dopamine neurons in vitro involves ionotropic glutamate receptor activation. Synapse, 38, 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gronier, B. &amp; Rasmussen, K. (1998) Activation of midbrain presumed dopaminergic neurones by muscarinic cholinergic receptors: an in vivo electrophysiological study in the rat. Brit. J. Pharmacol., 124, 455-464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hahn, M.K. &amp; Bannon, M.J. (1999) Stress-induced c-fos expression in the rat locus coeruleus is dependent on neurokinin 1 receptor activation. Neuroscience, 94, 1183-1188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hahn, J., Hopf, F.W. &amp; Bonci, A. (2009) Chronic cocaine enhances corticotropin-releasing factor-dependent potentiation of excitatory transmission in ventral tegmental area dopamine neurons. J. Neurosci., 29, 6535-6544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmstrand, E.C. &amp; Sesack, S.R. (2011) Projections from the rat pedunculopontine and laterodorsal tegmental nuclei to the anterior thalamus and ventral tegmental area arise from largely separate populations of neurons. Brain Struct. Funct., 216, 331-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hou, Y.P., Manns, I.D. &amp; Jones, B.E. (2002) Immunostaining of cholinergic pontomesencephalic neurons for α1 versus α2 adrenergic receptors suggests different sleep-wake state activities and roles. Neuroscience, 114, 517-521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikemoto, S. &amp; Wise, R.A. (2002) Rewarding effects of the cholinergic agents carbachol and neostigmine in the posterior ventral tegmental area. J. Neurosci., 22, 9895-9904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishikawa, M., Mu, P., Moyer, J.T., Wolf, J.A., Quock, R.M., Davies, N.M., Hu, X.T., Schlüter, O.M. et al. (2009) Homeostatic synapse-driven membrane plasticity in nucleus accumbens neurons. J. Neurosci., 29, 5820-5831.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itzhak, Y., Martin, J.L., Black, M.D. &amp; Huang, P.L. (1998) The role of neuronal nitric oxide synthase in cocaine-induced conditioned place preference. NeuroReport, 9, 2485-2488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jhou, T.C., Fields, H.L., Baxter, M.G., Saper, C.B. &amp; Holland, P.C. (2009a) The rostromedial tegmental nucleus (RMTg), a GABAergic afferent to midbrain dopamine neurons, encodes aversive stimuli and inhibits motor responses. Neuron, 61, 786-800.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jhou, T.C., Geisler, S., Marinelli, M., Degarmo, B.A. &amp; Zahm, D.S. (2009b) The mesopontine rostromedial tegmental nucleus: a structure targeted by the lateral habenula that projects to the ventral tegmental area of Tsai and substantia nigra compacta. J. Comp. Neurol., 513, 566-596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson, S.W. &amp; North, R.A. (1992) Opioids excite dopamine neurons by hyperpolarization of local interneurons. J. Neurosci., 12, 483-488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones, B.E. (1991) Noradrenergic locus coeruleus neurons: their distant connections and their relationship to neighboring (including cholinergic and GABAergic) neurons of the central gray and reticular formation. Prog. Brain Res., 88, 15-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jordan, S., Kramer, G.L., Zukas, P.K. &amp; Petty, F. (1994) Previous stress increases in vivo biogenic amine response to swim stress. Neurochem. Res., 19, 1521-1525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalivas, P.W. (2009) The glutamate homeostasis hypothesis of addiction. Nat. Rev. Neurosci., 10, 561-572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalivas, P.W. &amp; Volkow, N.D. (2011) New medications for drug addiction hiding in glutamatergic neuroplasticity. Mol. Psychiatr., 16, 974-986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kallupi, M., Wee, S., Edwards, S., Whitfield Jr, T.W., Oleata, C.S., Luu, G., Schmeichel, B.E., Koob, G.F. et al. (2013) Kappa opioid receptor-mediated dysregulation of gamma-aminobutyric acidergic transmission in the central amygdala in cocaine addiction. Biol. Psychiat., 74, 520-528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamii, H., Kurosawa, R., Taoka, N., Shinohara, F., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2015) Intrinsic membrane plasticity via increased persistent sodium conductance of cholinergic neurons in the rat laterodorsal tegmental nucleus contributes to cocaine-induced addictive behavior. Eur. J. Neurosci., 41, 1126-1138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamii, H., Taoka, N., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2017) Nitric oxide in the medial prefrontal cortex contributes to the acquisition of cocaine place preference and synaptic plasticity in the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus. Neurosci. Lett., 660, 39-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kauer, J.A. &amp; Malenka, R.C. (2007) Synaptic plasticity and addiction. Nat. Rev. Neurosci., 8, 844-858.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klitenick, M.A., DeWitte, P. &amp; Kalivas, P.W. (1992) Regulation of somatodendritic dopamine release in the ventral tegmental area by opioids and GABA: an in vivo microdialysis study. J. Neurosci., 12, 2623-2632.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohlmeier, K.A., Ishibashi, M., Wess, J., Bickford, M.E. &amp; Leonard, C.S. (2012) Knockouts reveal overlapping functions of M(2) and M(4) muscarinic receptors and evidence for a local glutamatergic circuit within the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus. J. Neurophysiol., 108, 2751-2766.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kourrich, S. &amp; Thomas, M.J. (2009) Similar neurons, opposite adaptations: psychostimulant experience differentially alters firing properties in accumbens core versus shell. J. Neurosci., 29, 12275-12283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreibich, A.S. &amp; Blendy, J.A. (2004) cAMP response element-binding protein is required for stress but not cocaine-induced reinstatement. J. Neurosci., 24, 6686-6692.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreibich, A.S., Briand, L., Cleck, J.N., Ecke, L., Rice, K.C. &amp; Blendy, J.A. (2009) Stress-induced potentiation of cocaine reward: a role for CRF R1 and CREB. Neuropsychopharmacology, 34, 2609-2617.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurosawa, R., Taoka, N., Shinohara, F., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2013) Cocaine exposure enhances excitatory synaptic drive to cholinergic neurons in the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus. Eur. J. Neurosci., 38, 3027-3035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lammel, S., Ion, D.I., Roeper, J. &amp; Malenka, R.C. (2011) Projection-specific modulation of dopamine neuron synapses by aversive and rewarding stimuli. Neuron, 70, 855-862.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lammel, S., Lim, B.K., Ran, C., Huang, K.W., Betley, M.J., Tye, K.M., Deisseroth, K. &amp; Malenka, R.C. (2012) Input-specific control of reward and aversion in the ventral tegmental area. Nature, 491, 212-217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lammel, S., Lim, B.K. &amp; Malenka, R.C. (2014) Reward and aversion in a heterogeneous midbrain dopamine system. Neuropharmacology, 76(Pt B), 351-359.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonard, C.S. &amp; Llinás, R. (1994) Serotonergic and cholinergic inhibition of mesopontine cholinergic neurons controlling REM sleep: an in vitro electrophysiological study. Neuroscience, 59, 309-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lester, D.B., Miller, A.D. &amp; Blaha, C.D. (2010a) Muscarinic receptor blockade in the ventral tegmental area attenuates cocaine enhancement of laterodorsal tegmentum stimulation-evoked accumbens dopamine efflux in the mouse. Synapse, 64, 216-223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lester, D.B., Rogers, T.D. &amp; Blaha, C.D. (2010b) Acetylcholine-dopamine interactions in the pathophysiology and treatment of CNS disorders. CNS Neurosci. Ther., 16, 137-162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liddie, S., Balda, M.A. &amp; Itzhak, Y. (2013) Nitric oxide (NO) signaling as a potential therapeutic modality against psychostimulants. Curr. Pharm. Design., 19, 7092-7102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lodge, D.J. &amp; Grace, A.A. (2005) Acute and chronic corticotropin-releasing factor 1 receptor blockade inhibits cocaine-induced dopamine release: correlation with dopamine neuron activity. J. Pharmacol. Exp. Ther., 314, 201-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lodge, D.J. &amp; Grace, A.A. (2006) The laterodorsal tegmentum is essential for burst firing of ventral tegmental area dopamine neurons. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA, 103, 5167-5172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, L., Liu, D. &amp; Ceng, X. (2001) Corticotropin-releasing factor receptor type 1 mediates stress-induced relapse to cocaine-conditioned place preference in rats. Eur. J. Pharmacol., 415, 203-208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lüscher, C. (2016) The emergence of a circuit model for addiction. Annu. Rev. Neurosci., 39, 257-276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lüscher, C. &amp; Malenka, R.C. (2011) Drug-evoked synaptic plasticity in addiction: from molecular changes to circuit remodeling. Neuron, 69, 650-663.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma, S. &amp; Morilak, D.A. (2005) Norepinephrine release in medial amygdala facilitates activation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis in response to acute immobilisation stress. J. Neuroendocrinol., 17, 22-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mameli, M., Bellone, C., Brown, M.T. &amp; Lüscher, C. (2011) Cocaine inverts rules for synaptic plasticity of glutamate transmission in the ventral tegmental area. Nat. Neurosci., 14, 414-416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantsch, J.R., Weyer, A., Vranjkovic, O., Beyer, C.E., Baker, D.A. &amp; Caretta, H. (2010) Involvement of noradrenergic neurotransmission in the stress- but not cocaine-induced reinstatement of extinguished cocaine-induced conditioned place preference in mice: role for β-2 adrenergic receptors. Neuropsychopharmacology, 35, 2165-2178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantsch, J.R., Baker, D.A., Funk, D., Lê, A.D. &amp; Shaham, Y. (2016) Stress-induced reinstatement of drug seeking: 20 years of progress. Neuropsychopharmacology, 41, 335-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maskos, U. (2008) The cholinergic mesopontine tegmentum is a relatively neglected nicotinic master modulator of the dopaminergic system: relevance to drugs of abuse and pathology. Brit. J. Pharmacol., 153(Suppl. 1), S438-S445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCutcheon, J.E., Wang, X., Tseng, K.Y., Wolf, M.E. &amp; Marinelli, M. (2011) Calcium-permeable AMPA receptors are present in nucleus accumbens synapses after prolonged withdrawal from cocaine self-administration but not experimenter-administered cocaine. J. Neurosci., 31, 5737-5743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin, J.P., Marton-Popovici, M. &amp; Chavkin, C. (2003) Kappa opioid receptor antagonism and prodynorphin gene disruption block stress-induced behavioral responses. J. Neurosci., 23, 5674-5683.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McReynolds, J.R., Peña, D.F., Blacktop, J.M. &amp; Mantsch, J.R. (2014) Neurobiological mechanisms underlying relapse to cocaine use: contributions of CRF and noradrenergic systems and regulation by glucocorticoids. Stress, 17, 22-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mena-Segovia, J. &amp; Bolam, J.P. (2017) Rethinking the pedunculopontine nucleus: from cellular organization to function. Neuron, 94, 7-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mena-Segovia, J., Winn, P. &amp; Bolam, J.P. (2008) Cholinergic modulation of midbrain dopaminergic systems. Brain Res. Rev., 58, 265-271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montagud-Romero, S., Aguilar, M.A., Maldonado, C., Manzanedo, C., Miñarro, J. &amp; Rodríguez-Arias, M. (2015) Acute social defeat stress increases the conditioned rewarding effects of cocaine in adult but not in adolescent mice. Pharmacol. Biochem. Be., 135, 1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mu, P., Moyer, J.T., Ishikawa, M., Zhang, Y., Panksepp, J., Sorg, B.A., Schlüter, O.M. &amp; Dong, Y. (2010) Exposure to cocaine dynamically regulates the intrinsic membrane excitability of nucleus accumbens neurons. J. Neurosci., 30, 3689-3699.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakane, H., Shimizu, N. &amp; Hori, T. (1994) Stress-induced norepinephrine release in the rat prefrontal cortex measured by microdialysis. Am. J. Physiol., 267, R1559-R1566.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasif, F.J., Hu, X.T. &amp; White, F.J. (2005) Repeated cocaine administration increases voltage-sensitive calcium currents in response to membrane depolarization in medial prefrontal cortex pyramidal neurons. J. Neurosci., 25, 3674-3679.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasif, F.J., Hu, X.T., Ramirez, O.A. &amp; Perez, M.F. (2011) Inhibition of neuronal nitric oxide synthase prevents alterations in medial prefrontal cortex excitability induced by repeated cocaine administration. Psychopharmacology, 218, 323-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson, C.L., Wetter, J.B., Milovanovic, M. &amp; Wolf, M.E. (2007) The laterodorsal tegmentum contributes to behavioral sensitization to amphetamine. Neuroscience, 146, 41-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oakman, S.A., Faris, P.L., Kerr, P.E., Cozzari, C. &amp; Hartman, B.K. (1995) Distribution of pontomesencephalic cholinergic neurons projecting to substantia nigra differs significantly from those projecting to ventral tegmental area. J. Neurosci., 15, 5859-5869.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omelchenko, N. &amp; Sesack, S.R. (2005) Laterodorsal tegmental projections to identified cell populations in the rat ventral tegmental area. J. Comp. Neurol., 483, 217-235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omelchenko, N. &amp; Sesack, S.R. (2006) Cholinergic axons in the rat ventral tegmental area synapse preferentially onto mesoaccumbens dopamine neurons. J. Comp. Neurol., 494, 863-875.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omelchenko, N. &amp; Sesack, S.R. (2009) Ultrastructural analysis of local collaterals of rat ventral tegmental area neurons: GABA phenotype and synapses onto dopamine and GABA cells. Synapse, 63, 895-906.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otis, J.M. &amp; Mueller, D. (2017) Reversal of cocaine-associated synaptic plasticity in medial prefrontal cortex parallels elimination of memory retrieval. Neuropsychopharmacology, 42, 2000-2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pascoli, V., Turiault, M. &amp; Lüscher, C. (2011) Reversal of cocaine-evoked synaptic potentiation resets drug-induced adaptive behaviour. Nature, 481, 71-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Otano, I., Schulteis, C.T., Contractor, A., Lipton, S.A., Trimmer, J.S., Sucher, N.J. &amp; Heinemann, S.F. (2001) Assembly with the NR1 subunit is required for surface expression of NR3A-containing NMDA receptors. J. Neurosci., 21, 1228-1237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polter, A.M. &amp; Kauer, J.A. (2014) Stress and VTA synapses: implications for addiction and depression. Eur. J. Neurosci., 39, 1179-1188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polter, A.M., Barcomb, K., Chen, R.W., Dingess, P.M., Graziane, N.M., Brown, T.E. &amp; Kauer, J.A. (2017) Constitutive activation of kappa opioid receptors at ventral tegmental area inhibitory synapses following acute stress. Elife, 6, pii: e23785.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redgrave, P., Gurney, K. &amp; Reynolds, J. (2008) What is reinforced by phasic dopamine signals?. Brain Res. Rev., 58, 322-339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redila, V.A. &amp; Chavkin, C. (2008) Stress-induced reinstatement of cocaine seeking is mediated by the kappa opioid system. Psychopharmacology, 200, 59-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saito, K., Kanazawa, M. &amp; Fukudo, S. (2002) Colorectal distention induces hippocampal noradrenaline release in rats: an in vivo microdialysis study. Brain Res., 947, 146-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salchner, P., Lubec, G., Engelmann, M., Orlando, G.F., Wolf, G. &amp; Sartori, S.B. (2004) Genetic functional inactivation of neuronal nitric oxide synthase affects stress-related Fos expression in specific brain regions. Cell. Mol. Life Sci., 61, 1498-1506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sammut, S. &amp; West, A.R. (2008) Acute cocaine administration increases NO efflux in the rat prefrontal cortex via a neuronal NOS-dependent mechanism. Synapse, 62, 710-713.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanchez, C.J., Bailie, T.M., Wu, W.R., Li, N. &amp; Sorg, B.A. (2003) Manipulation of dopamine d1-like receptor activation in the rat medial prefrontal cortex alters stress- and cocaine-induced reinstatement of conditioned place preference behavior. Neuroscience, 119, 497-505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindler, A.G., Li, S. &amp; Chavkin, C. (2010) Behavioral stress may increase the rewarding valence of cocaine-associated cues through a dynorphin/kappa-opioid receptor-mediated mechanism without affecting associative learning or memory retrieval mechanisms. Neuropsychopharmacology, 35, 1932-1942.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindler, A.G., Messinger, D.I., Smith, J.S., Shankar, H., Gustin, R.M. &amp; Schattauer, S.S. (2012) Stress produces aversion and potentiates cocaine reward by releasing endogenous dynorphins in the ventral striatum to locally stimulate serotonin reuptake. J. Neurosci., 32, 17582-17596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, H.D. &amp; Pierce, R.C. (2010) Cocaine-induced neuroadaptations in glutamate transmission: potential therapeutic targets for craving and addiction. Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci., 1187, 35-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, H.D., Famous, K.R. &amp; Pierce, R.C. (2009) The limbic circuitry underlying cocaine seeking encompasses the PPTg/LDT. Eur. J. Neurosci., 30, 1358-1369.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schultz, W. (2016) Dopamine reward prediction-error signalling: a two-component response. Nat. Rev. Neurosci., 17, 183-195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semba, K. &amp; Fibiger, H.C. (1992) Afferent connections of the laterodorsal and the pedunculopontine tegmental nuclei in the rat: a retro- and antero-grade transport and immunohistochemical study. J. Comp. Neurol., 323, 387-410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sesack, S.R., Deutch, A.Y., Roth, R.H. &amp; Bunney, B.S. (1989) Topographical organization of the efferent projections of the medial prefrontal cortex in the rat: an anterograde tract-tracing study with Phaseolus vulgaris leucoagglutinin. J. Comp. Neurol., 290, 213-242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaham, Y. &amp; Hope, B.T. (2005) The role of neuroadaptations in relapse to drug seeking. Nat. Neurosci., 8, 1437-1439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinohara, F., Kihara, Y., Ide, S., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2014) Critical role of cholinergic transmission from the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus to the ventral tegmental area in cocaine-induced place preference. Neuropharmacology, 79, 573-579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinohara, F., Kamii, H., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2017) The role of dopaminergic signaling in the medial prefrontal cortex for the expression of cocaine-induced conditioned place preference in rats. Biol. Pharm. Bull., 40, 1983-1989.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinohara, F., Asaoka, Y., Kamii, H., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2019) Stress augments the rewarding memory of cocaine via the activation of brainstem-reward circuitry. Addict. Biol., 24, 509-521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, R.J. &amp; Aston-Jones, G. (2008) Noradrenergic transmission in the extended amygdala: role in increased drug-seeking and relapse during protracted drug abstinence. Brain Struct. Funct., 213, 43-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steidl, S., Miller, A.D., Blaha, C.D. &amp; Yeomans, J.S. (2011) M5 muscarinic receptors mediate striatal dopamine activation by ventral tegmental morphine and pedunculopontine stimulation in mice. PLoS ONE, 6, e27538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steidl, S., Cardiff, K.M. &amp; Wise, R.A. (2015) Increased latencies to initiate cocaine self-administration following laterodorsal tegmental nucleus lesions. Behav. Brain Res., 287, 82-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steidl, S., Wang, H., Ordonez, M., Zhang, S. &amp; Morales, M. (2017a) Optogenetic excitation in the ventral tegmental area of glutamatergic or cholinergic inputs from the laterodorsal tegmental area drives reward. Eur. J. Neurosci., 45, 559-571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steidl, S., O'Sullivan, S., Pilat, D., Bubula, N., Brown, J. &amp; Vezina, P. (2017b) Operant responding for optogenetic excitation of LDTg inputs to the VTA requires D1 and D2 dopamine receptor activation in the NAcc. Behav. Brain Res., 333, 161-170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stelly, C.E., Pomrenze, M.B., Cook, J.B. &amp; Morikawa, H. (2016) Repeated social defeat stress enhances glutamatergic synaptic plasticity in the VTA and cocaine place conditioning. Elife, 5, pii: e15448.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steriade, M., Datta, S., Paré, D., Oakson, G. &amp; Curró Dossi, R.C. (1990) Neuronal activities in brain-stem cholinergic nuclei related to tonic activation processes in thalamocortical systems. J. Neurosci., 10, 2541-2559.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takase, L.F., Nogueira, M.I., Bland, S.T., Baratta, M., Watkins, L.R. &amp; Maier, S.F. (2005) Effect of number of tailshocks on learned helplessness and activation of serotonergic and noradrenergic neurons in the rat. Behav. Brain Res., 162, 299-306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, K.R., Yvon, C., Turiault, M., Mirzabekov, J.J., Doehner, J., Labouèbe, G., Deisseroth, K., Tye, K.M. et al. (2012) GABA neurons of the VTA drive conditioned place aversion. Neuron, 73, 1173-1183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka, M. (1999) Emotional stress and characteristics of brain noradrenaline release in the rat. Ind. Health, 37, 143-156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taoka, N., Kamiizawa, R., Wada, S., Minami, M. &amp; Kaneda, K. (2016) Chronic cocaine exposure induces noradrenergic modulation of inhibitory synaptic transmission to cholinergic neurons of the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus. Eur. J. Neurosci., 44, 3035-3045.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ungless, M.A., Whistler, J.L., Malenka, R.C. &amp; Bonci, A. (2001) Single cocaine exposure in vivo induces long-term potentiation in dopamine neurons. Nature, 411, 583-587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ungless, M.A., Argilli, E. &amp; Bonci, A. (2010) Effects of stress and aversion on dopamine neurons: implications for addiction. Neurosci. Biobehav. R., 35, 151-156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbani, A. &amp; Belluzzi, O. (2000) Riluzole inhibits the persistent sodium current in mammalian CNS neurons. Eur. J. Neurosci., 12, 3567-3574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, H.L. &amp; Morales, M. (2009) Pedunculopontine and laterodorsal tegmental nuclei contain distinct populations of cholinergic, glutamatergic and GABAergic neurons in the rat. Eur. J. Neurosci., 29, 340-358.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, B., Shaham, Y., Zitzman, D., Azari, S., Wise, R.A. &amp; You, Z.B. (2005) Cocaine experience establishes control of midbrain glutamate and dopamine by corticotropin-releasing factor: a role in stress-induced relapse to drug seeking. J. Neurosci., 25, 5389-5396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wasserman, D.I., Tan, J.M., Kim, J.C. &amp; Yeomans, J.S. (2016) Muscarinic control of rostromedial tegmental nucleus GABA neurons and morphine-induced locomotion. Eur. J. Neurosci., 44, 1761-1770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wise, R.A. &amp; Morales, M. (2010) A ventral tegmental CRF-glutamate-dopamine interaction in addiction. Brain Res., 1314, 38-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf, M.E. (2016) Synaptic mechanisms underlying persistent cocaine craving. Nat. Rev. Neurosci., 17, 351-365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf, M.E. &amp; Ferrario, C.R. (2010) AMPA receptor plasticity in the nucleus accumbens after repeated exposure to cocaine. Neurosci. Biobehav. R., 35, 185-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao, C., Cho, J.R., Zhou, C., Treweek, J.B., Chan, K., McKinney, S.L., Yang, B. &amp; Gradinaru, V. (2016) Cholinergic mesopontine signals govern locomotion and reward through dissociable midbrain pathways. Neuron, 90, 333-347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin, R. &amp; French, E.D. (2000) A comparison of the effects of nicotine on dopamine and non-dopamine neurons in the rat ventral tegmental area: an in vitro electrophysiological study. Brain Res. Bull., 51, 507-514.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>You, Z.B., Wang, B., Zitzman, D., Azari, S. &amp; Wise, R.A. (2007) A role for conditioned ventral tegmental glutamate release in cocaine seeking. J. Neurosci., 27, 10546-10555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>You, Z.B., Wang, B., Zitzman, D. &amp; Wise, R.A. (2008) Acetylcholine release in the mesocorticolimbic dopamine system during cocaine seeking: conditioned and unconditioned contributions to reward and motivation. J. Neurosci., 28, 9021-9029.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan, T., Mameli, M., O'Connor, E.C., Dey, P.N., Verpelli, C., Sala, C., Perez-Otano, I., Lüscher, C. et al. (2013) Expression of cocaine-evoked synaptic plasticity by GluN3A-containing NMDA receptors. Neuron, 80, 1025-1038.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Zessen, R., Phillips, J.L., Budygin, E.A. &amp; Stuber, G.D. (2012) Activation of VTA GABA neurons disrupts reward consumption. Neuron, 73, 1184-1194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, X.F., Hu, X.T. &amp; White, F.J. (1998) Whole-cell plasticity in cocaine withdrawal: reduced sodium currents in nucleus accumbens neurons. J. Neurosci., 18, 488-498.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, L., Liu, Y. &amp; Chen, X. (2005) Carbachol induces burst firing of dopamine cells in the ventral tegmental area by promoting calcium entry through L-type channels in the rat. J. Physiol., 568, 469-481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
