<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30000146</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK501087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>National Library of Medicine (US)</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Bethesda (MD)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="lactmed">Drugs and Lactation Database (LactMed)</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2006</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2006</Year></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="lactmed" part="LM233">Quetiapine</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Maternal quetiapine doses of up to 400 mg daily produce doses in milk that are less than 1% of the maternal weight-adjusted dosage. Limited long-term follow-up of infants exposed to quetiapine indicates that infants generally developed normally. A safety scoring system finds quetiapine to be possible to use during breastfeeding.[1] Systematic reviews of second-generation antipsychotics concluded that quetiapine seemed to be the first- or second-choice agent during breastfeeding.[2-4] Monitor the infant for drowsiness and developmental milestones, especially if other antipsychotics are used concurrently.</AbstractText></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="lactmed" part="LM233" sec="LM233.Drug_Levels_and_Effects">Drug Levels and Effects</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="lactmed" part="LM233" sec="LM233.Substance_Identification">Substance Identification</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quetiapine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seroquel</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Co-Quetiapine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">111974-69-7</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quetiapine [INN:BAN]</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UNII-BGL0JSY5SI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BGL0JSY5SI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FK949E</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HSDB 7557</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">2-(2-(4-Dibenzo(b,f)(1,4)thiazepin-11-yl-1-piperazinyl)ethoxy)ethanol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ethanol, 2-(2-(4-dibenzo(b,f)(1,4)thiazepin-11-yl-1-piperazinyl)ethoxy)-</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Uguz F. A new safety scoring system for the use of psychotropic drugs during lactation. Am J Ther. 2021;28:e118–e126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen ER, Damkier P, Pedersen LH, et al.  Use of psychotropic drugs during pregnancy and breast-feeding. Acta Psychiatr Scand Suppl. 2015;132 Suppl 445:1–28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uguz F. Second-generation antipsychotics during the lactation period: A comparative systematic review on infant safety. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2016;36:244–52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27028982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacchiarotti I, Leon-Caballero J, Murru A, et al.  Mood stabilizers and antipsychotics during breastfeeding: Focus on bipolar disorder. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2016;26:1562–78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27568278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee A, Giesbrecht E, Dunn E, et al.  Excretion of quetiapine in breast milk. Am J Psychiatry. 2004;161:1715–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15337669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misri S, Corral M, Wardrop AA, et al.  Quetiapine augmentation in lactation: A series of case reports. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2006;26:508–11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16974194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rampono J, Kristensen JH, Ilett KF, et al.  Quetiapine and breast feeding. Ann Pharmacother. 2007;41:711–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17374621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruninger U, Meltzer V, Hiemke C, et al.  Pregnancy and lactation under treatment with quetiapin. Psychiatr Prax. 2007;34 Suppl 1:S75–6. doi: 10.1055/s-2006-940185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2006-940185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani-Brojeni P, Taguchi N, García-Bournissen F, et al. Quetiapine in human milk and simulation-based assessment of infant exposure. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2010;87 (Suppl. 1):S3-4. Abstract. doi:10.1038/clpt.2009.268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/clpt.2009.268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanoshima R, Yazdani-Brojeni P, Taguchi N, et al.  Quetiapine in human breast milk - population PK analysis of milk levels and simulated infant exposure. J Popul Ther Clin Pharmacol. 2012;19:e267–268. Abstract.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Var L, Ince I, Topuzoglu A, et al.  Management of postpartum manic episode without cessation of breastfeeding: A longitudinal follow up of drug excretion into breast milk. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2013;23 Suppl 2:S382. Abstract.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aydin B, Nayir T, Sahin S, et al.  Olanzapine and quetiapine use during breastfeeding: Excretion into breast milk and safe breastfeeding strategy. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2015;35:206–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25679127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdani-Brojeni P, Tanoshima R, Taguchi N, et al.  Quetiapine excretion into human breast milk. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2018;38:362–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29912789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastol J, Le Marois M, Guilhaumou R, et al.  Measuring drug concentrations in breast milk to improve therapeutic monitoring and patient adherence in bipolar disorder: A case report. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2022;56:96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33938286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Boekholt AA, Hartong EG, Huntjens-Fleuren H, et al.  Quetiapine concentrations during exclusive breastfeeding and maternal quetiapine use. Ann Pharmacother. 2015;49:743–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25975996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balke LD. Quetiapine effective in the treatment of bipolar affective disorder during pregnancy. World J Biol Psychiatry 2001;2:303S. Abstract P021-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seppala J. Quetiapine ('Seroquel') is effective and well tolerated in the treatment of psychotic depression during breast-feeding. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol 2004;7 (Suppl 2):S245. Abstract P01.431. doi:10.1017/S1461145704004547</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1461145704004547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritz S. Quetiapine monotherapy in post-partum onset bipolar disorder with a mixed affective state. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol 2005;15 (Suppl 3):S407. Abstract. doi:10.1016/S0924-977X(05)80825-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0924-977X(05)80825-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentile S. Quetiapine-fluvoxamine combination during pregnancy and while breastfeeding. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2006;9:158–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16683078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newport DJ, Ritchie JC, Knight BT, et al.  Venlafaxine in human breast milk and nursing infant plasma: Determination of exposure. J Clin Psychiatry. 2009;70:1304–10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19607765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lévesque S, Riley C. Fetal exposure to lamotrigine and quetiapine in two consecutive pregnancies. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2017;20:237–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27785634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma V, Sommerdyk C. Lamotrigine in the prevention of bipolar II postpartum depression. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord 2016;18:Letter. PMID: 27907274</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uguz F. Prophylactic use of olanzapine and quetiapine from pregnancy to the postpartum period in women with bipolar disorder: A case series. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2017;30:2569–71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27809629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha SK, Thomas Kishore M, Thippeswamy H, et al.  Adverse effects and short-term developmental outcomes of infants exposed to atypical antipsychotics during breastfeeding. Indian J Psychiatry. 2021;63:52–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8106424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34083820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viguera AC, Vanderkruik R, Gaccione P, et al.  Breastfeeding practices among women taking second-generation antipsychotics: findings from the National Pregnancy Registry for Atypical Antipsychotics. Arch Womens Ment Health. 2022;25:511–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34318375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atmaca M, Kuloglu M, Tezcan E, et al.  Quetiapine is not associated with increase in prolactin secretion in contrast to haloperidol. Arch Med Res. 2002;33:562–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12505103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maguire GA. Prolactin elevation with antipsychotic Medications: Mechanisms of action and clinical consequences. J Clin Psychiatry. 2002;63 Suppl 4:56–62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11913677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arvanitis LA, Miller BG. Multiple fixed doses of "Seroquel" (quetiapine) in patients with acute exacerbation of schizophrenia: A comparison with haloperidol and placebo. The seroquel trial 13 study group. Biol Psychiatry. 1997;42:233–46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9270900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glocker C, Grohmann R, Engel R, et al.  Galactorrhea during antipsychotic treatment: Results from AMSP, a drug surveillance program, between 1993 and 2015. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2021;271:1425–35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8563638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33768297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pae CU, Kim JJ, Lee CU, et al.  Very low dose quetiapine-induced galactorrhea in combination with venlafaxine. Hum Psychopharmacol. 2004;19:433–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15303249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30000146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
