<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30000386</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK501327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>National Library of Medicine (US)</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Bethesda (MD)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="lactmed">Drugs and Lactation Database (LactMed)</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2006</Year></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2006</Year></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="lactmed" part="LM451">Cabergoline</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Cabergoline is usually not used during breastfeeding because it suppresses lactation. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration considers cabergoline to be not indicated to suppress lactation because the similar drug bromocriptine has caused hypertension, stroke, seizures and psychosis when used for this purpose. However, two systematic reviews found that cabergoline was generally well tolerated for use in suppressing lactation, but dizziness, headache, nausea and vomiting occur occasionally.[1,2] A retrospective study of 225 women who received cabergoline postpartum had a maximum decrease in systolic blood pressure of 10.88 mm Hg at 20 to 24 hours after the dose.[3] Serious reactions are uncommon, but include thromboembolic and neurologic events. Psychiatric symptoms have occurred rarely. Some experts recommend cabergoline as a safer alternative to bromocriptine for lactation suppression, but others do not.[4-8] The disadvantage of cabergoline is that it has a half-life of about 68 hours, which means that any adverse effects might persist for a prolonged period of time. Women treated with cabergoline for pituitary adenomas who become pregnant can breastfed their infants with no apparent risk of recurrence. A treatment scheme has been reported for mothers with hypergalactia that uses low doses of cabergoline to decrease milk supply.[9]</AbstractText></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="lactmed" part="LM451" sec="LM451.Drug_Levels_and_Effects">Drug Levels and Effects</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="lactmed" part="LM451" sec="LM451.Substance_Identification">Substance Identification</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><KeywordList Owner="NLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cabergoline</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dostinex</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergolinum</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergolina</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergolinum [Latin]</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergolina [Spanish]</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">81409-90-7</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UNII-LL60K9J05T</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LL60K9J05T</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FCE 21336</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergoline [USAN:USP:INN:BAN]</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BRN 6020775</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">1-((6-Allylergolin-8beta-yl)carbonyl)-1-(3-(dimethylamino)propyl)-3-ethylurea</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ergoline-8-carboxamide, N-(3-(dimethylamino)propyl)-N-((ethylamino)carbonyl)-6-(2-propenyl)-, (8-beta)-</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ergoline-8beta-carboxamide, N-(3-(dimethylamino)propyl)-N-((ethylamino)carbonyl)-6-(2-propenyl)-</Keyword></KeywordList><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Harris K, Murphy KE, Horn D, et al.  Safety of cabergoline for postpartum lactation inhibition or suppression: A systematic review. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2020;42:308–15.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Boucoiran I, Tulloch KJ, et al.  Is cabergoline safe and effective for postpartum lactation inhibition? A systematic review. Int J Womens Health. 2020;12:159–70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32210637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphrey S, Baechler M, Schiff M, et al.  Cabergoline for postpartum lactation suppression: Effect on blood pressure and pulse. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35304744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anon. Inhibiting the onset of lactation: Is cabergoline an alternative to bromocriptine? Prescrire Int. 2015;24:276–7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26688910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcellin L, Chantry AA. J Gynecol Obstet Biol Reprod (Paris) 2015;44:1080–3. [Breast-feeding (part II): Lactation inhibition--Guidelines for clinical practice]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26527027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snellen M, Power J, Blankley G, et al.  Pharmacological lactation suppression with D2 receptor agonists and risk of postpartum psychosis: A systematic review. Aust N Z J Obstet Gynaecol. 2016;56:336–40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27297803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tulloch KJ, Dodin P, Tremblay-Racine F, et al.  Cabergoline: A review of its use in the inhibition of lactation for women living with HIV. J Int AIDS Soc. 2019;22:e25322. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31183987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fachi MM, de Deus Bueno L, de Oliveira DC, et al.  Efficacy and safety in the treatment of hyperprolactinemia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2021;46:1549–56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34137053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Eglash A, Mitchell KB, et al.  ABM Clinical Protocol #32: Management of hyperlactation. Breastfeed Med. 2020;15:129–34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32031417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melis GB, Gambacciani M, Paoletti AM, et al.  Dose-related prolactin inhibitory effect of the new long-acting dopamine receptor agonist cabergoline in normal cycling, puerperal, and hyperprolactinemic women. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1987;65:541–5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3624413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melis GB, Mais V, Paoletti AM, et al.  Prevention of puerperal lactation by a single oral administration of the new prolactin-inhibiting drug, cabergoline. Obstet Gynecol. 1988;71:311–4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3279351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caballero-Gordo A, López-Nazareno N, Calderay M, et al.  Oral cabergoline. Single-dose inhibition of puerperal lactation. J Reprod Med. 1991;36:717–21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1683403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giorda G, de Vincentiis S, Motta T, et al.  Cabergoline versus bromocriptine in suppression of lactation after cesarean delivery. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 1991;31:93–6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2037265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Multicentre, Study, Group, for, Cabergoline, in, Lactation, Inhibition. Single dose cabergoline versus bromocriptine in inhibition of puerperal lactation: Randomised, double blind, multicentre study. BMJ. 1991;302:1367–71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1670075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1676318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bracco PL, Armentano G, Pellegrini A, et al.  Minerva Ginecol. 1997;49:469–73. [Cabergoline in the inhibition of lactogenesis and suppression of lactopoiesis]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9463181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavlista D, Calda P, Zivny J. Ceska Gynekol. 2003;68:46–50. [Arrest of lactation after 2nd trimester abortion with a single dose of cabergoline in comparison with 10-day administration of teguride]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12708116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bravo-Topete EG, Mendoza-Hernandez F, Cejudo-Alvarez J, et al.  Cir Cir. 2004;72:5–9. [Cabergoline for inhibition of lactation]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15087045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auriemma RS, Perone Y, Di Sarno A, et al.  Results of a single-center observational 10-year survey study on recurrence of hyperprolactinemia after pregnancy and lactation. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;98:372–9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23162092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coban A, Bayraktar S, Yıldız N, et al.  A case study of early postpartum excessive breast engorgement: Is it related to feedback inhibition of lactation? J Hum Lact. 2021;37:414–8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33030995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucoiran I, Roy M, Poliquin V, et al.  Evaluation of cabergoline for lactation inhibition in women living with HIV. Int J STD AIDS. 2021;32:654–61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33612017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartell GS. Lactogenesis II onset following prolonged delay in a mother with a nonfunctioning macroadenoma treated with cabergoline: A case study in persistence. Clin Lact (Amarillo) 2021;12:22–9. doi: 10.1891/clinlact-d-20-00014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/clinlact-d-20-00014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30000386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
