<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30051292</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1546-9549</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2018</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current heart failure reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Heart Fail Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Peripartum Cardiomyopathy: an Update.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>297</StartPage>
          <EndPage>306</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>297-306</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11897-018-0404-x</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Peripartum cardiomyopathy (PPCM) is an idiopathic disorder defined as heart failure occurring in women during the last month of pregnancy and up to 5 months postpartum. In this review, we outline recent reports about the disease pathogenesis and management and highlight the use of diagnosis and prognosis biomarkers.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Novel data strengthen the implication of endothelial function in PPCM pathogenesis. The first international registry showed that patient presentations were similar globally, with heterogeneity in patient management and outcome. Despite large improvement in patient management and treatment, there is still a sub-group of women who die from PPCM or who will not recover their cardiac function. Remarkable advances in the comprehension of disease incidence, pathogenesis, and prognosis could be determined with multi-center and international registries.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIALS">ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT02590601.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Azibani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Feriel</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hatter Institute for Cardiovascular Research in Africa, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Cape Town, 4th floor Chris Barnard Building, Cape Town, South Africa. feriel.azibani@uct.ac.za.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sliwa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karen</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hatter Institute for Cardiovascular Research in Africa, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Cape Town, 4th floor Chris Barnard Building, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mary McKillop Institute, ACU, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT02590601</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Heart Fail Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101196487</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1546-9530</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009202" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiomyopathies</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014943" MajorTopicYN="N">Global Health</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009017" MajorTopicYN="N">Morbidity</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="N">trends</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058725" MajorTopicYN="N">Peripartum Period</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011249" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pregnancy Complications, Cardiovascular</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute heart failure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomarker</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Ethnicity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Peripartum cardiomyopathy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Pregnancy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Registry</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>CONFLICT OF INTEREST: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest. HUMAN AND ANIMAL RIGHTS AND INFORMED CONSENT: This article does not contain any studies with human or animal subjects performed by any of the authors.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051292</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6132730</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11897-018-0404-x</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11897-018-0404-x</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meadows WR. Postpartum heart disease. Am J Cardiol. 1960;6:788–802.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13768780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melvin JP., Jr Post-partal heart disease. Ann Intern Med. 1947;27(4):596–609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20268432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seftel H, Susser M. Maternity and myocardial failure in African women. Br Heart J. 1961;23:43–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1017731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13749643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demakis JG, Rahimtoola SH. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 1971;44(5):964–968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4255967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fett JD, Christie LG, Carraway RD, Murphy JG. Five-year prospective study of the incidence and prognosis of peripartum cardiomyopathy at a single institution. Mayo Clin Proc. 2005;80(12):1602–1606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16342653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanderson JE, Adesanya CO, Anjorin FI, Parry EH. Postpartum cardiac failure--heart failure due to volume overload? Am Heart J. 1979;97(5):613–621.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">433737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Damasceno A, Mayosi BM. Epidemiology and etiology of cardiomyopathy in Africa. Circulation. 2005;112(23):3577–3583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Mebazaa A, Petrie MC, Maggioni AP, Regitz-Zagrosek V, Schaufelberger M, Tavazzi L, van Veldhuisen DJ, Roos-Hesslink JW, Shah AJ, Seferovic PM, Elkayam U, van Spaendonck-Zwarts K, Bachelier-Walenta K, Mouquet F, Kraigher-Krainer E, Hall R, Ponikowski P, McMurray JJV, Pieske B. EURObservational Research Programme: a worldwide registry on peripartum cardiomyopathy (PPCM) in conjunction with the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on PPCM. Eur J Heart Fail. 2014;16(5):583–591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24591060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamara DM, Elkayam U, Alharethi R, Damp J, Hsich E, Ewald G, et al. Clinical outcomes for peripartum cardiomyopathy in North America: results of the IPAC study (investigations of pregnancy-associated cardiomyopathy). J Am Coll Cardiol. 2015;66(8):905–14. 10.1016/j.jacc.2015.06.1309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5645077</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26293760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Sliwa K. Pathophysiology and epidemiology of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2014;11(6):364–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24686946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauersachs J, Arrigo M, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Veltmann C, Coats AJ, Crespo-Leiro MG, et al.  Current management of patients with severe acute peripartum cardiomyopathy: practical guidance from the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Study Group on peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2016;18(9):1096–1105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27338866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soma-Pillay P, Seabe J, Sliwa K. The importance of cardiovascular pathology contributing to maternal death: confidential enquiry into maternal deaths in South Africa, 2011-2013. Cardiovasc J Afr. 2016;27(2):60–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4928161</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26895406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Petrie MC, Mebazaa A, Pieske B, Buchmann E, Regitz-Zagrosek V, Schaufelberger M, Tavazzi L, van Veldhuisen D, Watkins H, Shah AJ, Seferovic PM, Elkayam U, Pankuweit S, Papp Z, Mouquet F, McMurray J, Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Peripartum Cardiomyopathy  Current state of knowledge on aetiology, diagnosis, management, and therapy of peripartum cardiomyopathy: a position statement from the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2010;12(8):767–778.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20675664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkayam U, Akhter MW, Singh H, Khan S, Bitar F, Hameed A, Shotan A. Pregnancy-associated cardiomyopathy: clinical characteristics and a comparison between early and late presentation. Circulation. 2005;111(16):2050–2055.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15851613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haghikia A, Podewski E, Libhaber E, Labidi S, Fischer D, Roentgen P, Tsikas D, Jordan J, Lichtinghagen R, Kaisenberg CS, Struman I, Bovy N, Sliwa K, Bauersachs J, Hilfiker-Kleiner D. Phenotyping and outcome on contemporary management in a German cohort of patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Basic Res Cardiol. 2013;108(4):366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3709080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23812247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Forster O, Libhaber E, Fett JD, Sundstrom JB, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, et al.  Peripartum cardiomyopathy: inflammatory markers as predictors of outcome in 100 prospectively studied patients. Eur Heart J. 2006;27(4):441–446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16143707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora NP, Mohamad T, Mahajan N, Danrad R, Kottam A, Li T, et al.  Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Med Sci. 2014;347(2):112–117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23470270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tibazarwa K, Lee G, Mayosi B, Carrington M, Stewart S, Sliwa K. The 12-lead ECG in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Cardiovasc J Afr. 2012;23(6):322–329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3734749</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22337203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duran N, Gunes H, Duran I, Biteker M, Ozkan M. Predictors of prognosis in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2008;101(2):137–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18280479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Kaminski K, Podewski E, Bonda T, Schaefer A, Sliwa K, Forster O, Quint A, Landmesser U, Doerries C, Luchtefeld M, Poli V, Schneider MD, Balligand JL, Desjardins F, Ansari A, Struman I, Nguyen NQN, Zschemisch NH, Klein G, Heusch G, Schulz R, Hilfiker A, Drexler H. A cathepsin D-cleaved 16 kDa form of prolactin mediates postpartum cardiomyopathy. Cell. 2007;128(3):589–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17289576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Haghikia A, Berliner D, Vogel-Claussen J, Schwab J, Franke A, Schwarzkopf M, Ehlermann P, Pfister R, Michels G, Westenfeld R, Stangl V, Kindermann I, Kühl U, Angermann CE, Schlitt A, Fischer D, Podewski E, Böhm M, Sliwa K, Bauersachs J. Bromocriptine for the treatment of peripartum cardiomyopathy: a multicentre randomized study. Eur Heart J. 2017;38(35):2671–2679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837241</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Blauwet L, Tibazarwa K, Libhaber E, Smedema JP, Becker A, McMurray J, Yamac H, Labidi S, Struman I, Hilfiker-Kleiner D. Evaluation of bromocriptine in the treatment of acute severe peripartum cardiomyopathy: a proof-of-concept pilot study. Circulation. 2010;121(13):1465–1473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lecour S. Activation of the protective survivor activating factor enhancement (SAFE) pathway against reperfusion injury: does it go beyond the RISK pathway? J Mol Cell Cardiol. 2009;47(1):32–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19344728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowe GC, Jiang A, Arany Z. PGC-1 coactivators in cardiac development and disease. Circ Res. 2010;107(7):825–838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2955978</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20884884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forster O, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Ansari AA, Sundstrom JB, Libhaber E, Tshani W, Becker A, Yip A, Klein G, Sliwa K. Reversal of IFN-gamma, oxLDL and prolactin serum levels correlate with clinical improvement in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2008;10(9):861–868.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18768352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patten IS, Rana S, Shahul S, Rowe GC, Jang C, Liu L, Hacker MR, Rhee JS, Mitchell J, Mahmood F, Hess P, Farrell C, Koulisis N, Khankin EV, Burke SD, Tudorache I, Bauersachs J, Monte F, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Karumanchi SA, Arany Z. Cardiac angiogenic imbalance leads to peripartum cardiomyopathy. Nature. 2012;485(7398):333–338.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3356917</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22596155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macotela Y, Aguilar MB, Guzman-Morales J, Rivera JC, Zermeno C, Lopez-Barrera F, et al.  Matrix metalloproteases from chondrocytes generate an antiangiogenic 16 kDa prolactin. J Cell Sci. 2006;119(Pt 9):1790–1800.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16608881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halkein J, Tabruyn SP, Ricke-Hoch M, Haghikia A, Nguyen NQ, Scherr M, et al.  MicroRNA-146a is a therapeutic target and biomarker for peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Clin Invest. 2013;123(5):2143–2154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23619365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Skudicky D, Bergemann A, Candy G, Puren A, Sareli P. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: analysis of clinical outcome, left ventricular function, plasma levels of cytokines and Fas/APO-1. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2000;35(3):701–705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10716473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mebazaa A, Seronde MF, Gayat E, Tibazarwa K, Anumba DOC, Akrout N, Sadoune M, Sarb J, Arrigo M, Motiejunaite J, Laribi S, Legrand M, Deschamps L, Fazal L, Bouadma L, Collet C, Manivet P, Solal AC, Launay JM, Samuel JL, Sliwa K. Imbalanced angiogenesis in peripartum cardiomyopathy- diagnostic value of placenta growth factor. Circ J. 2017;81(11):1654–1661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28552862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seno A, Takeda Y, Matsui M, Okuda A, Nakano T, Nakada Y, Kumazawa T, Nakagawa H, Nishida T, Onoue K, Somekawa S, Watanabe M, Kawata H, Kawakami R, Okura H, Uemura S, Saito Y. Suppressed production of soluble Fms-like tyrosine kinase-1 contributes to myocardial remodeling and heart failure. Hypertension. 2016;68(3):678–687.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27480835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams JW, Sakata Y, Davis MG, Sah VP, Wang Y, Liggett SB, Chien KR, Brown JH, Dorn GW. Enhanced Galphaq signaling: a common pathway mediates cardiac hypertrophy and apoptotic heart failure. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1998;95(17):10140–10145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC21475</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9707614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayakawa Y, Chandra M, Miao W, Shirani J, Brown JH, Dorn GW, II, et al.  Inhibition of cardiac myocyte apoptosis improves cardiac function and abolishes mortality in the peripartum cardiomyopathy of Galpha(q) transgenic mice. Circulation. 2003;108(24):3036–3041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14638549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bozkurt B, Villaneuva FS, Holubkov R, Tokarczyk T, Alvarez RJ, Jr, MacGowan GA, et al.  Intravenous immune globulin in the therapy of peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1999;34(1):177–180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10400008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricke-Hoch M, Bultmann I, Stapel B, Condorelli G, Rinas U, Sliwa K, Scherr M, Hilfiker-Kleiner D. Opposing roles of Akt and STAT3 in the protection of the maternal heart from peripartum stress. Cardiovasc Res. 2014;101(4):587–596.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24448315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Skudicky D, Candy G, Bergemann A, Hopley M, Sareli P. The addition of pentoxifylline to conventional therapy improves outcome in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2002;4(3):305–309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12034156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xia G, Sun X, Zheng X, Wang J. Decreased expression of programmed death 1 on peripheral blood lymphocytes disrupts immune homeostasis in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2016;223:842–847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27580218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaouat G, Ledee-Bataille N, Dubanchet S, Zourbas S, Sandra O, Martal J. TH1/TH2 paradigm in pregnancy: paradigm lost? Cytokines in pregnancy/early abortion: reexamining the TH1/TH2 paradigm. Int Arch Allergy Immunol. 2004;134(2):93–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15153791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saito S, Sakai M, Sasaki Y, Tanebe K, Tsuda H, Michimata T. Quantitative analysis of peripheral blood Th0, Th1, Th2 and the Th1:Th2 cell ratio during normal human pregnancy and preeclampsia. Clin Exp Immunol. 1999;117(3):550–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1905376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10469061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wegmann TG, Lin H, Guilbert L, Mosmann TR. Bidirectional cytokine interactions in the maternal-fetal relationship: is successful pregnancy a TH2 phenomenon? Immunol Today. 1993;14(7):353–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8363725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schelbert EB, Elkayam U, Cooper LT, Givertz MM, Alexis JD, Briller J et al. Myocardial damage detected by late gadolinium enhancement cardiac magnetic resonance is uncommon in peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;6(4). doi:10.1161/JAHA.117.005472.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5533034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28373243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ntusi NB, Chin A. Characterisation of peripartum cardiomyopathy by cardiac magnetic resonance imaging. Eur Radiol. 2009;19(6):1324–1325.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19083243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bollen IAE, Ehler E, Fleischanderl K, Bouwman F, Kempers L, Ricke-Hoch M, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, dos Remedios CG, Krüger M, Vink A, Asselbergs FW, van Spaendonck-Zwarts KY, Pinto YM, Kuster DWD, van der Velden J. Myofilament remodeling and function is more impaired in peripartum cardiomyopathy compared with dilated cardiomyopathy and ischemic heart disease. Am J Pathol. 2017;187(12):2645–2658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28935576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leurent G, Baruteau AE, Larralde A, Ollivier R, Schleich JM, Boulmier D, Bedossa M, Langella B, le Breton H. Contribution of cardiac MRI in the comprehension of peripartum cardiomyopathy pathogenesis. Int J Cardiol. 2009;132(3):e91–e93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18258317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mouquet F, Lions C, de Groote P, Bouabdallaoui N, Willoteaux S, Dagorn J, Deruelle P, Lamblin N, Bauters C, Beregi JP. Characterisation of peripartum cardiomyopathy by cardiac magnetic resonance imaging. Eur Radiol. 2008;18(12):2765–2769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18642002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawano H, Tsuneto A, Koide Y, Tasaki H, Sueyoshi E, Sakamoto I, Hayashi T. Magnetic resonance imaging in a patient with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Intern Med. 2008;47(2):97–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18195498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Haghikia A, Nonhoff J, Bauersachs J. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: current management and future perspectives. Eur Heart J. 2015;36(18):1090–1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25636745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasmusson K, Brunisholz K, Budge D, Horne BD, Alharethi R, Folsom J, Connolly JJ, Stehlik J, Kfoury A. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: post-transplant outcomes from the United Network for Organ Sharing Database. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2012;31(2):180–186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22305380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasmusson KD, Stehlik J, Brown RN, Renlund DG, Wagoner LE, Torre-Amione G, Folsom JW, Silber DH, Kirklin JK, Cardiac Transplant Research Database Group  Long-term outcomes of cardiac transplantation for peri-partum cardiomyopathy: a multiinstitutional analysis. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2007;26(11):1097–1104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindheimer MD, Katz AI. Sodium and diuretics in pregnancy. N Engl J Med. 1973;288(17):891–894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4571247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lampert MB, Lang RM. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am Heart J. 1995;130(4):860–870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7572598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruys TP, Maggioni A, Johnson MR, Sliwa K, Tavazzi L, Schwerzmann M, et al.  Cardiac medication during pregnancy, data from the ROPAC. Int J Cardiol. 2014;177(1):124–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25499355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ponikowski P, Voors AA, Anker SD, Bueno H, Cleland JGF, Coats AJS, Falk V, González-Juanatey JR, Harjola VP, Jankowska EA, Jessup M, Linde C, Nihoyannopoulos P, Parissis JT, Pieske B, Riley JP, Rosano GMC, Ruilope LM, Ruschitzka F, Rutten FH, van der Meer P, ESC Scientific Document Group  2016 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure: the Task Force for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) developed with the special contribution of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J. 2016;37(27):2129–2200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27206819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arrigo M, Blet A, Mebazaa A. Bromocriptine for the treatment of peripartum cardiomyopathy: welcome on BOARD. Eur Heart J. 2017;38(35):2680–2682.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Mebazaa A, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Petrie MC, Maggioni AP, Laroche C, Regitz-Zagrosek V, Schaufelberger M, Tavazzi L, van der Meer P, Roos-Hesselink JW, Seferovic P, van Spandonck-Zwarts K, Mbakwem A, Böhm M, Mouquet F, Pieske B, Hall R, Ponikowski P, Bauersachs J. Clinical characteristics of patients from the worldwide registry on peripartum cardiomyopathy (PPCM): EURObservational Research Programme in conjunction with the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Study Group on PPCM. Eur J Heart Fail. 2017;19(9):1131–1141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28271625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duncker D, Haghikia A, Konig T, Hohmann S, Gutleben KJ, Westenfeld R, et al.  Risk for ventricular fibrillation in peripartum cardiomyopathy with severely reduced left ventricular function-value of the wearable cardioverter/defibrillator. Eur J Heart Fail. 2014;16(12):1331–1336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25371320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duncker D, Konig T, Hohmann S, Bauersachs J, Veltmann C. Avoiding untimely implantable cardioverter/defibrillator implantation by intensified heart failure therapy optimization supported by the wearable cardioverter/defibrillator—the prolong study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2017;6(1). doi:10.1161/JAHA.116.004512.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5523634</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28096098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouabdallaoui N, Mouquet F, Lebreton G, Demondion P, Le Jemtel TH, Ennezat PV. Current knowledge and recent development on management of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur Heart J Acute Cardiovasc Care. 2017;6(4):359–366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clapp JF, 3rd, Capeless E. Cardiovascular function before, during, and after the first and subsequent pregnancies. Am J Cardiol. 1997;80(11):1469–1473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9399724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hunter S, Robson SC. Adaptation of the maternal heart in pregnancy. Br Heart J. 1992;68(6):540–543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1025680</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1467047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang GY, Zhang LY, Long-Le MA, Wang LX. Clinical characteristics and risk factors for peripartum cardiomyopathy. Afr Health Sci. 2012;12(1):26–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23066416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Wang Y, Chen M, Zhao W, Wang X, Wang H, Zhang Z, Zhang J, Xu L, Chen J, Yang X, Zhang L. The correlation between peripartum cardiomyopathy and autoantibodies against cardiovascular receptors. PLoS One. 2014;9(1):e86770.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3900643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24466231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li W, Li H, Long Y. Clinical characteristics and long-term predictors of persistent left ventricular systolic dysfunction in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Can J Cardiol. 2016;32(3):362–368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26586094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casserly B, Klinger JR. Brain natriuretic peptide in pulmonary arterial hypertension: biomarker and potential therapeutic agent. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2009;3:269–287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20054445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Resnik JL, Hong C, Resnik R, Kazanegra R, Beede J, Bhalla V, Maisel A. Evaluation of B-type natriuretic peptide (BNP) levels in normal and preeclamptic women. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005;193(2):450–454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMurray JJ, Adamopoulos S, Anker SD, Auricchio A, Bohm M, Dickstein K, et al.  ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure 2012: the Task Force for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure 2012 of the European Society of Cardiology. Developed in collaboration with the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur J Heart Fail. 2012;14(8):803–869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22828712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walenta K, Schwarz V, Schirmer SH, Kindermann I, Friedrich EB, Solomayer EF, Sliwa K, Labidi S, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Bohm M. Circulating microparticles as indicators of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur Heart J. 2012;33(12):1469–1479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22307461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Damp J, Givertz MM, Semigran M, Alharethi R, Ewald G, Felker GM, et al. Relaxin-2 and soluble Flt1 levels in peripartum cardiomyopathy: results of the multicenter IPAC study. JACC Heart Fail. 2016;4(5):380–8. 10.1016/j.jchf.2016.01.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4851559</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26970832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sundrani D, Khot V, Pisal H, Mehendale S, Wagh G, Joshi A, Joshi S. Gestation dependant changes in angiogenic factors and their associations with fetal growth measures in normotensive pregnancy. PLoS One. 2013;8(1):e54153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3542273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23326589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palm M, Basu S, Larsson A, Wernroth L, Akerud H, Axelsson O. A longitudinal study of plasma levels of soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase 1 (sFlt1), placental growth factor (PlGF), sFlt1: PlGF ratio and vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF-A) in normal pregnancy. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2011;90(11):1244–1251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21568945</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wathen KA, Sarvela J, Stenman F, Stenman UH, Vuorela P. Changes in serum concentrations of soluble vascular endothelial growth factor receptor-1 after pregnancy. Hum Reprod. 2011;26(1):221–226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21097488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ansari AA, Fett JD, Carraway RE, Mayne AE, Onlamoon N, Sundstrom JB. Autoimmune mechanisms as the basis for human peripartum cardiomyopathy. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2002;23(3):301–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12402414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis JE, Ansari AA, Fett JD, Carraway RD, Randall HW, Mosunjac MI, et al.  Inhibition of progenitor dendritic cell maturation by plasma from patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy: role in pregnancy-associated heart disease. Clin Dev Immunol. 2005;12(4):265–273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2270740</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16584112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson SS, Ayaz SI, Levy PD. Relaxin: a novel agent for the treatment of acute heart failure. Pharmacotherapy. 2015;35(3):315–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25759289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fett JD, Ansari AA. Inflammatory markers and cytokines in peripartum cardiomyopathy: a delicate balance. Expert Opin Ther Targets. 2010;14(9):895–898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brar SS, Khan SS, Sandhu GK, Jorgensen MB, Parikh N, Hsu JW, et al.  Incidence, mortality, and racial differences in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2007;100(2):302–304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17631087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fett JD, Sundstrom BJ, Etta King M, Ansari AA. Mother-daughter peripartum cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2002;86(2–3):331–332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12419575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goland S, Modi K, Bitar F, Janmohamed M, Mirocha JM, Czer LS, et al.  Clinical profile and predictors of complications in peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Card Fail. 2009;15(8):645–650.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19786252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mielniczuk LM, Williams K, Davis DR, Tang AS, Lemery R, Green MS, et al.  Frequency of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2006;97(12):1765–1768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16765131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapa JB, Heiberger HB, Weinert L, Decara J, Lang RM, Hibbard JU. Prognostic value of echocardiography in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Obstet Gynecol. 2005;105(6):1303–1308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15932821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkayam U, Tummala PP, Rao K, Akhter MW, Karaalp IS, Wani OR, et al.  Maternal and fetal outcomes of subsequent pregnancies in women with peripartum cardiomyopathy. N Engl J Med. 2001;344(21):1567–1571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11372007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Forster O, Tibazarwa K, Libhaber E, Becker A, Yip A, et al.  Long-term outcome of peripartum cardiomyopathy in a population with high seropositivity for human immunodeficiency virus. Int J Cardiol. 2011;147(2):202–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19751951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarojini A, Sai Ravi Shanker A, Anitha M. Inflammatory markers-serum level of C-reactive protein, tumor necrotic factor-alpha, and Interleukin-6 as predictors of outcome for peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Obstet Gynaecol India. 2013;63(4):234–239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3763057</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24431648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu CL, Li YB, Zou YG, Zhang JM, Chen JB, Liu J, et al.  Troponin T measurement can predict persistent left ventricular dysfunction in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Heart. 2007;93(4):488–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1861492</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17065185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nonhoff J, Ricke-Hoch M, Mueller M, Stapel B, Pfeffer T, Kasten M, et al.  Serelaxin treatment promotes adaptive hypertrophy but does not prevent heart failure in experimental peripartum cardiomyopathy. Cardiovasc Res. 2017;113(6):598–608.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28453725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkayam U. Risk of subsequent pregnancy in women with a history of peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014;64(15):1629–1636.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25301468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Forster O, Zhanje F, Candy G, Kachope J, Essop R. Outcome of subsequent pregnancy in patients with documented peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2004;93(11):1441–1443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15165937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Haghikia A, Masuko D, Nonhoff J, Held D, Libhaber E, et al.  Outcome of subsequent pregnancies in patients with a history of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2017;19(12):1723–1728.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28345302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Petrie MC, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Mebazaa A, Jackson A, Johnson MR, et al.  Long-term prognosis, subsequent pregnancy, contraception and overall management of peripartum cardiomyopathy: practical guidance paper from the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Study Group on Peripartum Cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2018;20:951–962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29578284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roos-Hesselink JW, Cornette J, Sliwa K, Pieper PG, Veldtman GR, Johnson MR. Contraception and cardiovascular disease. Eur Heart J. 2015;36(27):1728–1734.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926560</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blauwet LA, Delgado-Montero A, Ryo K, Marek JJ, Alharethi R, Mather PJ, et al.  Right ventricular function in peripartum cardiomyopathy at presentation is associated with subsequent left ventricular recovery and clinical outcomes. Circ Heart Fail. 2016;9(5):e002756.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27166247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheppard R, Hsich E, Damp J, Elkayam U, Kealey A, Ramani G, et al.  GNB3 C825T polymorphism and myocardial recovery in peripartum cardiomyopathy: results of the multicenter investigations of pregnancy-associated cardiomyopathy study. Circ Heart Fail. 2016;9(3):e002683.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4770544</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26915373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamiya CA, Kitakaze M, Ishibashi-Ueda H, Nakatani S, Murohara T, Tomoike H, et al.  Different characteristics of peripartum cardiomyopathy between patients complicated with and without hypertensive disorders—results from the Japanese nationwide survey of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circ J. 2011;75(8):1975–1981.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21617320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S, Cho GJ, Park GU, Kim LY, Lee TS, Kim DY, et al.  Incidence, risk factors, and clinical characteristics of peripartum cardiomyopathy in South Korea. Circ Heart Fail. 2018;11(4):e004134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29626099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kayikcioglu M, Tokgozoglu L, Mutluer FO, Ural D, Biteker M. The rationale and design of the national peripartum cardiomyopathy registries in Turkey: the ARTEMIS-I and ARTEMIS-II studies. Turk Kardiyol Dern Ars. 2018;46(1):39–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29339690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
