<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30137800</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK519515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083">Achalasia</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Momodu</LastName><ForeName>Ifeanyi I.</ForeName><Initials>II</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Campbell University School of OM</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallen</LastName><ForeName>Jason M.</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Upstate Medical University</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Achalasia is not a common disorder in medicine. Most clinicians will not encounter a patient with this esophageal smooth muscle motility disorder, which occurs because the lower esophageal sphincter fails to relax. The esophagus also has a marked absence of peristalsis. In less than 50% of patients, the lower esophageal sphincter is hypertensive. This condition causes a functional obstruction at the gastroesophageal junction.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s13">Postoperative and Rehabilitation Care</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s14">Consultations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s15">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s16">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s17">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s18">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-17083" sec="article-17083.s22">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Achem SR, Crittenden J, Kolts B, Burton L. Long-term clinical and manometric follow-up of patients with nonspecific esophageal motor disorders. Am J Gastroenterol. 1992 Jul;87(7):825-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1615935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CASSELLA RR, ELLIS FH, BROWN AL. FINE-STRUCTURE CHANGES IN ACHALASIA OF ESOPHAGUS. II. ESOPHAGEAL SMOOTH MUSCLE. Am J Pathol. 1965 Mar;46:467-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1920367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14266221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisichella PM, Raz D, Palazzo F, Niponmick I, Patti MG. Clinical, radiological, and manometric profile in 145 patients with untreated achalasia. World J Surg. 2008 Sep;32(9):1974-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18575930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CASSELLA RR, ELLIS FH, BROWN AL. FINE-STRUCTURE CHANGES IN ACHALASIA OF THE ESOPHAGUS. I. VAGUS NERVES. Am J Pathol. 1965 Feb;46:279-88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1920351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14256751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francis DL, Katzka DA. Achalasia: update on the disease and its treatment. Gastroenterology. 2010 Aug;139(2):369-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20600038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misiewicz JJ, Waller SL, Anthony PP, Gummer JW. Achalasia of the cardia: pharmacology and histopathology of isolated cardiac sphincteric muscle from patients with and without achalasia. Q J Med. 1969 Jan;38(149):17-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5765090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raymond L, Lach B, Shamji FM. Inflammatory aetiology of primary oesophageal achalasia: an immunohistochemical and ultrastructural study of Auerbach's plexus. Histopathology. 1999 Nov;35(5):445-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10583560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadhwa V, Thota PN, Parikh MP, Lopez R, Sanaka MR. Changing Trends in Age, Gender, Racial Distribution and Inpatient Burden of Achalasia. Gastroenterology Res. 2017 Apr;10(2):70-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh R, Ghoshal UC, Misra A, Mittal B. Achalasia Is Associated With eNOS4a4a, iNOS22GA, and nNOS29TT Genotypes: A Case-control Study. J Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2015 Jul 30;21(3):380-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4496906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26088023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gockel I, Becker J, Wouters MM, Niebisch S, Gockel HR, Hess T, Ramonet D, Zimmermann J, Vigo AG, Trynka G, de León AR, de la Serna JP, Urcelay E, Kumar V, Franke L, Westra HJ, Drescher D, Kneist W, Marquardt JU, Galle PR, Mattheisen M, Annese V, Latiano A, Fumagalli U, Laghi L, Cuomo R, Sarnelli G, Müller M, Eckardt AJ, Tack J, Hoffmann P, Herms S, Mangold E, Heilmann S, Kiesslich R, von Rahden BH, Allescher HD, Schulz HG, Wijmenga C, Heneka MT, Lang H, Hopfner KP, Nöthen MM, Boeckxstaens GE, de Bakker PI, Knapp M, Schumacher J. Common variants in the HLA-DQ region confer susceptibility to idiopathic achalasia. Nat Genet. 2014 Aug;46(8):901-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24997987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker J, Haas SL, Mokrowiecka A, Wasielica-Berger J, Ateeb Z, Bister J, Elbe P, Kowalski M, Gawron-Kiszka M, Majewski M, Mulak A, Janiak M, Wouters MM, Schwämmle T, Hess T, Veits L, Niebisch S, Santiago JL, de León AR, de la Serna JP, Urcelay E, Annese V, Latiano A, Fumagalli U, Rosati R, Laghi L, Cuomo R, Lenze F, Sarnelli G, Müller M, von Rahden BH, Wijmenga C, Lang H, Czene K, Hall P, de Bakker PI, Vieth M, Nöthen MM, Schulz HG, Adrych K, Gąsiorowska A, Paradowski L, Wallner G, Boeckxstaens GE, Gockel I, Hartleb M, Kostic S, Dziurkowska-Marek A, Lindblad M, Nilsson M, Knapp M, Thorell A, Marek T, Dąbrowski A, Małecka-Panas E, Schumacher J. The HLA-DQβ1 insertion is a strong achalasia risk factor and displays a geospatial north-south gradient among Europeans. Eur J Hum Genet. 2016 Aug;24(8):1228-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4970678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldblum JR, Whyte RI, Orringer MB, Appelman HD. Achalasia. A morphologic study of 42 resected specimens. Am J Surg Pathol. 1994 Apr;18(4):327-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8141427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin H, Wang B, Zhang LL, Zhao W. Activated Eosinophils are Present in Esophageal Muscle in Patients with Achalasia of the Esophagus. Med Sci Monit. 2018 Apr 19;24:2377-2383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29672471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldblum JR, Rice TW, Richter JE. Histopathologic features in esophagomyotomy specimens from patients with achalasia. Gastroenterology. 1996 Sep;111(3):648-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8780569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurino-Neto RM, Herbella F, Schlottmann F, Patti M. EVALUATION OF ESOPHAGEAL ACHALASIA: FROM SYMPTOMS TO THE CHICAGO CLASSIFICATION. Arq Bras Cir Dig. 2018;31(2):e1376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6044194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29972404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckardt AJ, Eckardt VF. Current clinical approach to achalasia. World J Gastroenterol. 2009 Aug 28;15(32):3969-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2731945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19705490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torresan F, Ioannou A, Azzaroli F, Bazzoli F. Treatment of achalasia in the era of high-resolution manometry. Ann Gastroenterol. 2015 Jul-Sep;28(3):301-308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4480166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26130022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaninotto G, Annese V, Costantini M, Del Genio A, Costantino M, Epifani M, Gatto G, D'onofrio V, Benini L, Contini S, Molena D, Battaglia G, Tardio B, Andriulli A, Ancona E. Randomized controlled trial of botulinum toxin versus laparoscopic heller myotomy for esophageal achalasia. Ann Surg. 2004 Mar;239(3):364-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1356234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15075653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csendes A, Braghetto I, Henríquez A, Cortés C. Late results of a prospective randomised study comparing forceful dilatation and oesophagomyotomy in patients with achalasia. Gut. 1989 Mar;30(3):299-304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1378449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2651226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeckxstaens GE, Annese V, des Varannes SB, Chaussade S, Costantini M, Cuttitta A, Elizalde JI, Fumagalli U, Gaudric M, Rohof WO, Smout AJ, Tack J, Zwinderman AH, Zaninotto G, Busch OR, European Achalasia Trial Investigators  Pneumatic dilation versus laparoscopic Heller's myotomy for idiopathic achalasia. N Engl J Med. 2011 May 12;364(19):1807-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21561346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farhoomand K, Connor JT, Richter JE, Achkar E, Vaezi MF. Predictors of outcome of pneumatic dilation in achalasia. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2004 May;2(5):389-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15118976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonavina L, Nosadini A, Bardini R, Baessato M, Peracchia A. Primary treatment of esophageal achalasia. Long-term results of myotomy and Dor fundoplication. Arch Surg. 1992 Feb;127(2):222-6; discussion 227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1540102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Renteln D, Inoue H, Minami H, Werner YB, Pace A, Kersten JF, Much CC, Schachschal G, Mann O, Keller J, Fuchs KH, Rösch T. Peroral endoscopic myotomy for the treatment of achalasia: a prospective single center study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2012 Mar;107(3):411-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22068665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30137800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
