<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30178554</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0722</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>126 Suppl 1</Volume>
            <Issue>Suppl Suppl 1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2018</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European journal of oral sciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Oral Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Current concepts on Sjögren's syndrome - classification criteria and biomarkers.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>37</StartPage>
          <EndPage>48</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>37-48</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/eos.12536</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Sjögren's syndrome is a lymphoproliferative disease with autoimmune features characterized by mononuclear cell infiltration of exocrine glands, notably the lacrimal and salivary glands. These lymphoid infiltrations lead to dryness of the eyes (keratoconjunctivitis sicca), dryness of the mouth (xerostomia), and, frequently, dryness of other surfaces connected to exocrine glands. Sjögren's syndrome is associated with the production of autoantibodies because B-cell activation is a consistent immunoregulatory abnormality. The spectrum of the disease extends from an organ-specific autoimmune disorder to a systemic process and is also associated with an increased risk of B-cell lymphoma. Current treatments are mainly symptomatic. As a result of the diverse presentation of the syndrome, a major challenge remains to improve diagnosis and therapy. For this purpose an international set of classification criteria for primary Sjögren's syndrome has recently been developed and validated and seems well suited for enrolment in clinical trials. Salivary gland biopsies have been examined and histopathology standards have been developed, to be used in clinical trials and patient stratification. Finally, ultrasonography and saliva meet the need of non-invasive imaging and sampling methods for discovery and validation of disease biomarkers in Sjögren's syndrome.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2018 Eur J Oral Sci.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jonsson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roland</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9588-0260</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Broegelmann Research Laboratory, Department of Clinical Science, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brokstad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karl A</ForeName>
            <Initials>KA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0593-2731</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Broegelmann Research Laboratory, Department of Clinical Science, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jonsson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Malin V</ForeName>
            <Initials>MV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Dentistry - Section for Oral and Maxillofacial Radiology, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Delaleu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Broegelmann Research Laboratory, Department of Clinical Science, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2C SysBioMed, Contra, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Skarstein</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kathrine</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Gade Laboratory for Pathology, Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Haukeland University Hospital, Bergen, Norway.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Oral Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9504563</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0909-8836</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012469" MajorTopicYN="N">Salivary Glands</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012859" MajorTopicYN="N">Sjogren's Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Sjögren's syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">biomarkers</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">classification</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">histopathology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">ultrasonography</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178554</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6586012</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eos.12536</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sjögren H. Zur Kenntnis der Keratoconjunctivitis sicca. Acta Ophthalmol
1933; 11(Suppl): 1–151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chisholm DM, Mason DK. Labial salivary gland biopy in Sjögren's disease. J Clin Pathol
1968; 21: 656–660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC473887</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5697370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Greenspan JS, Daniels TE, Talal N, Sylvester RA. The histopathology of Sjögrens's syndrome in labial salivary gland biopsies. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol
1974; 37: 221–229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4589360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fisher BA, Jonsson R, Daniels T, Bombardieri M, Brown RM, Morgan P, Bombardieri S, Ng W‐F, Tzioufas AG, Vitali C, Shirlaw P, Haacke E, Costa S, Bootsma H, Devauchelle‐Pensec V, Radstake TR, Mariette X, Richards A, Stack R, Bowman SJ, Barone F. Standardisation of labial salivary gland histopathology in clinical trials in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
2017; 76: 1161–1168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5530351</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shiboski CH, Shiboski SC, Seror R, Criswell LA, Labetoulle M, Lietman TM, Rasmussen A, Scofield H, Vitali C, Bowman SJ, Mariette X; International Sjögren's Syndrome Criteria Working Group
. 2016 American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism classification criteria for primary Sjögren's syndrome: A consensus and data‐driven methodology involving three international patient cohorts. Ann Rheum Dis
2017; 76: 9–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27789466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vitali C, Del Papa N. Classification and diagnostic criteria in Sjögrens's syndrome: a long‐standing and still open controversy. Ann Rheum Dis
2017; 76: 1953–1954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Biomarkers Definitions Working Group
. Biomarkers and surrogate endpoints: preferred definitions and conceptual framework. Clin Pharmacol Ther
2001; 69(3): 89–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11240971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jonsson R, Brokstad K. Sjögren′s syndrome In: Austen KF, Frank MM, Atkinson JP, Cantor H, eds. Samter′s Immunologic Diseases, 6th edn
Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2001; chapter 40: 495–504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tong L, Koh V, Thong BY. Review of autoantigens in Sjögren's syndrome: an update. J Inflamm Res
2017; 10: 97–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5557906</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fayyaz A, Kurien BT, Scofield RH. Autoantibodies in Sjögren's Syndrome. Rheum Dis Clin North Am
2016; 42: 419–434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4955792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27431345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vitali C, Bombardieri S, Moutsopoulos HM, Balestrieri G, Bencivelli W, Bernstein RM, Bjerrum KB, Braga S, Coll J, de Vita S. Preliminary criteria for the classification of Sjögren's syndrome. Results of a prospective concerted action supported by the European Community. Arthritis Rheum
1993; 36: 340–347.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8452579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vitali C, Bombardieri S, Jonsson R, Moutsopoulos HM, Alexander EL, Carsons SE, Daniels TE, Fox PC, Fox RI, Kassan SS, Pillemer SR, Talal N, Weisman N; European Study Group on Classification Criteria for Sjögren's Syndrome
. Classification criteria for Sjögren's syndrome: a revised version of the European criteria proposed by the American‐European Consensus Group. Ann Rheum Dis
2002; 61: 554–558.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1754137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12006334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shiboski SC, Shiboski CH, Criswell L, Baer A, Challacombe S, Lanfranchi H, Schiødt M, Umehara H, Vivino F, Zhao Y, Dong Y, Greenspan D, Heidenreich AM, Helin P, Kirkham B, Kitagawa K, Larkin G, Li M, Lietman T, Lindegaard J, McNamara N, Sack K, Shirlaw P, Sugai S, Vollenweider C, Whitcher J, Wu A, Zhang S, Zhang W, Greenspan J, Daniels T; Sjögren's International Collaborative Clinical Alliance (SICCA) Research Groups
. American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for Sjögren's syndrome: a data‐driven, expert consensus approach in the Sjögren's International Collaborative Clinical Alliance cohort. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)
2012; 64: 475–487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3349440</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22563590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Clark G, Reichlin M, Tomasi TB Jr. Characterization of a soluble cytoplasmic antigen reactive with sera from patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Immunol
1969; 102: 117–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4179557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mattioli M, Reichlin M. Heterogeneity of RNA protein antigens reactive with sera of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Description of a cytoplasmic nonribosomal antigen. Arthritis Rheum
1974; 17: 421–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4212051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Alspaugh MA, Talal N, Tan EM. Differentiation and characterization of autoantibodies and their antigens in Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Rheum
1976; 19: 216–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1259795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Venables PJ, Smith PR, Maini RN. Purification and characterization of the Sjögren's syndrome A and B antigens. Clin Exp Immunol
1983; 54: 731–738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1536164</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6360447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Garberg H, Jonsson R, Brokstad KA. The serological pattern of autoantibodies to the Ro52, Ro60, and La48 autoantigens in primary Sjögren's syndrome patients and healthy controls. Scand J Rheumatol
2005; 34: 49–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15903026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wada K, Kamitani T. Autoantigen Ro52 is an E3 ubiquitin ligase. Biochem Biophys Res Commun
2006; 339: 415–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16297862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Campos‐Almaraz MD, Barbosa‐Cisneros O, Herrera‐Esparza R. Ro60 ribonucleoprotein inhibits transcription by T3 RNA polymerase in vitro. Rev Rheum Engl Ed
1999; 66: 310–314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10418058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tan EM. Antinuclear antibodies: diagnostic markers for autoimmune diseases and probes for cell biology. Adv Immunol
1989; 44: 93–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2646863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Markusse HM, Otten HG, Vroom TM, Smeets TJ, Fokkens N, Breedveld FC. Rheumatoid factor isotypes in serum and salivary fluid of patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome. Clin Immunol Immunopathol
1993; 66: 26–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8440071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Atkinson JC, Fox PC, Travis WD, Popek E, Katz RW, Balow JE, Pillemer SR. IgA rheumatoid factor and IgA containing immune complexes in primary Sjögren's syndrome. J Rheumatol
1989; 16: 1205–1210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2810277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Elagib KE, Børretzen M, Jonsson R, Haga HJ, Thoen J, Thompson KM, Natvig JB. Rheumatoid factors in primary Sjögren's syndrome (pSS) use diverse VH region genes, the majority of which show no evidence of somatic hypermutation. Clin Exp Immunol
1999; 117: 388–394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1905326</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10444275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bacman S, Sterin‐Borda L, Camusso JJ, Arana R, Hubscher O, Borda E. Circulating antibodies against rat parotid gland M3 muscarinic receptors in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Clin Exp Immunol
1996; 104: 454–459.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2200439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9099930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bacman S, Perez Leiros C, Sterin‐Borda L, Hubscher O, Arana R, Borda E. Autoantibodies against lacrimal gland M3 muscarinic acetylcholine receptors in patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci
1998; 39: 151–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9430556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Robinson CP, Brayer J, Yamachika S, Esch TR, Peck AB, Stewart CA, Peen E, Jonsson R, Humphreys‐Beher MG. Transfer of human serum IgG to NOD. Igμnull mice reveals a role for autoantibodies in the loss of secretory function of exocrine tissues in Sjögren's syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA
1998; 95: 7538–7543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC22675</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9636185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Waterman SA, Gordon TP, Rischmueller M. Inhibitory effects of muscarinic receptor autoantibodies on parasympathetic neurotransmission in Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Rheum
2000; 43: 1647–1654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10902771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Humphreys‐Beher MG, Brayer J, Yamachika S, Peck AB, Jonsson R. An alternative perspective to the immune response in autoimmune exocrinopathy: induction of functional quiescence rather than destructive autoaggression. Scand J Immunol
1999; 49: 7–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10023850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sumida T, Tsuboi H, Iizuka M, Asashima H, Matsumoto I. Anti‐M3 muscarinic acetylcholine receptor antibodies in patients with Sjögren's syndrome. Mod Rheumatol
2013; 23: 841–845.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sumida T, Tsuboi H, Iizuka M, Hirota T, Asashima H, Matsumoto I. The role of M3 muscarinic acetylcholine receptor reactive T cells in Sjögren's syndrome: acritical review. J Autoimmun
2014; 51: 44–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24397962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Deng C, Hu C, Chen S, Li J, Wen X, Wu Z, Li Y, Zhang F, Li Y. Meta‐analysis of anti‐muscarinic receptor type 3 antibodies for the diagnosis of Sjögren syndrome. PLoS ONE
2015; 10: e0116744.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309563</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25629973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Roescher N, Kingman A, Shirota Y, Chiorini JA, Illei GG. Peptide‐based ELISAs are not sensitive and specific enough to detect muscarinic receptor type 3 autoantibodies in serum from patients with Sjogren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
2011; 70: 235–236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6234417</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20498204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brun JG, Cuida M, Jacobsen H, Kloster R, Johannesen AC, Høyeraal HM, Jonsson R. Sjögren's syndrome in inflammatory rheumatic diseases: analysis of the leukocyte protein calprotectin in plasma and saliva. Scand J Rheumatol
1994; 23: 114–118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8016580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cuida M, Brun JG, Johannessen AC, Jonsson R. Immunohistochemical characterization of the cellular infiltrates in Sjögren's syndrome, rheumatoid arthritis and osteoarthritis with special reference to calprotectin‐producing cells. APMIS
1996; 104: 881–890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9048866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nordal HH, Brun JG, Halse AK, Madland TM, Fagerhol MK, Jonsson R. Calprotectin (S100A8/A9), S100A12, and EDTA‐resistant S100A12 complexes (ERAC) in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Scand J Rheumatol
2014; 43: 76–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24295066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Balarini GM, Zandonade E, Tanure L, Ferreira GA, Sardenberg WM, Serrano ÉV, Dias CC, Navarro TP, Nordal HH, Mydel PM, Brun JG, Brokstad KA, Gerdts E, Jonsson R, Valim V. Serum calprotectin is a biomarker of carotid atherosclerosis in patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2016; 34: 1006–1012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27749218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bergum B, Koro C, Delaleu N, Solheim M, Hellvard A, Binder V, Jonsson R, Valim V, Hammenfors DS, Jonsson MV, Mydel P. Antibodies against carbamylated proteins are present in primary Sjögren's syndrome and are associated with disease severity. Ann Rheum Dis
2016; 75: 1494–1500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4975850</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26350884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jonsson R, Theander E, Sjöström B, Brokstad K, Henriksson G. Autoantibodies present before symptom onset in primary Sjögren syndrome. JAMA
2013; 310: 1854–1855.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24193084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Theander E, Jonsson R, Sjöström B, Brokstad K, Olsson P, Henriksson G. Prediction of Sjögren's syndrome years before diagnosis and identification of patients with early onset and severe disease course by autoantibody profiling. Arthritis Rheumatol
2015; 67: 2427–2436.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26109563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vitali C, Moutsopoulos HM, Bombardieri S. The European Community study group on dianostic criteria for Sjögrens's syndrome. Sensitivity and specificity of tests for ocular and oral involvement for Sjögren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
1994; 53: 637–647.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1005429</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7979575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bowman SJ, Fox RI. Classification criteria for Sjögren’ syndrome: nothing ever stands still. Ann Rheum Dis
2014; 73: 1–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24092418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Risselada AP, Kruize AA, Goldschmeding R, Lafeber FP, Bijlsma JW, van Roon JA. The prognostic value of routinely performed minor salivary gland assessments in primary Sjogren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
2014; 73: 1537–1540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24525912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Theander E, Vasaitis L, Baecklund E, Nordmark G, Warfvinge G, Liedholm R, Brokstad K, Jonsson R, Jonsson MV. Lymphoid organisation in labial salivary gland biopsies is a possible predictor for the development of malignant lymphoma in primary Sjogren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
2011; 70: 1363–1368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3128323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cornec D, Costa S, Devauchelle‐Pensec V, Chiche L, Saraux A, Pers JO. Do high numbers of salivary gland‐infiltrating B cells predict better or worse outcomes after rituximab in patients with primary Sjogren's syndrome?
Ann Rheum Dis
2016; 75: e33–e209300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26895746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Pijpe J, Kalk WW, van der Wal JE, Vissink A, Kluin PM, Roodenburg JL, Bootsma H, Kallenberg CG, Spijkervet FK. Parotid gland biopsy compared with labial biopsy in the diagnosis of patients with primary Sjögrens syndrome. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2007; 46: 335–341.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16891656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sallusto F, Lanzavecchia A. Human Th17 cells in infection and autoimmunity. Microbes Infect
2009; 11: 620–624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19371794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Alunno A, Petrillo MG, Nocentini G, Bistoni O, Bartoloni E, Caterbi S, Bianchini R, Baldini C, Nicoletti I, Riccardi C, Gerli R. Characterization of a new regulatory CD4 +  T cell subset in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2013; 52: 1387–1396.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23674818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bohnhorst JØ, Bjørgan MB, Thoen JE, Jonsson R, Natvig JB, Thompson KM. Abnormal B cell differentiation in primary Sjögren's syndrome results in a depressed percentage of circulating memory B cells and elevated levels of soluble CD27 that correlate with Serum IgG concentration. Clin Immunol
2002; 103: 79–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11987988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aqrawi LA, Brokstad KA, Jakobsen K, Jonsson R, Skarstein K. Low number of memory B cells in the salivary glands of patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome. Autoimmunity
2012; 45: 547–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22849322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Salomonsson S, Jonsson M, Skarstein K, Brokstad KA, Hjelmström P, Wahren‐Herlenius M, Wahren‐Herlenius M, Jonsson R. Cellular basis of ectopic germinal center formation and autoantibody production in the target organ of patients with Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Rheum
2003; 48: 3187–3201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14613282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jonsson MV, Skarstein K. Follicular dendritic cells confirm lymphoid organization in the minor salivary glands of primary Sjögren's syndrome. J Oral Pathol Med
2008; 37: 515–521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18662248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Skarstein K, Aqrawi LA, Øijordsbakken G, Jonsson R, Liaaen Jensen JC. Adipose tissue is prominent in salivary glands of Sjögren's syndrome patients and appears to influence the microenvironment in these organs. Autoimmunity
2016; 49: 338–346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27206986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Leehan KM, Pezant NP, Rasmussen A, Grundahl K, Moore JS, Radfar L, Lewis DM, Stone DU, Lessard CJ, Rhodus NL, Segal BM, Kaufman CE, Scofield RH, Sivils KL, Montgomery C, Farris AD. Fatty infiltration of the minor salivary glands is a selective feature of aging but not Sjögren's syndrome. Autoimmunity
2017; 50: 451–457.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5730459</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28988489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Szyszko EA, Brokstad KA, Oijordsbakken G, Jonsson MV, Jonsson R, Skarstein K. Salivary glands of primary Sjögrens syndrome patients express factors vital for plasma cell survival. Arthritis Res Ther
2011; 13: R2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3241347</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21214903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aqrawi LA, Liaaen Jensen JC, Øijordsbakken G, Ruus A‐K, Nygård S, Holden M, Jonsson R, Galtung HK, Skarstein K. Signalling pathways identified in salivary glands from primary Sjögren's syndrome patients reveal enhanced adipose tissue development. Autoimmunity
2018; 51: 135–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29504848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mossel E, Delli K, van Nimwegen JF, Stel AJ, Kroese FGM, Spijkervet FKL, Vissink A, Bootsma H. Ultrasonography of major salivary glands compared with parotid and labial gland biopsy and classification criteria in patients with clinically suspected primary Sjögren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
2017; 76: 1883–1889.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28754802</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Haacke EA, van der Vegt B, Vissink A, Spijkervet FKL, Bootsma H, Kroese FGM. Germinal centres in diagnostic labial gland biopsies of patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome are not predictive for parotid MALT lymphoma development. Ann Rheum Dis
2017; 76: 1781–1784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Alegria GC, Costa S, Jousse‐Joulin S, Marcorelles P, Pers JO, Saraux A, Devauchelle‐Pensec V, Cornec D. What is the agreement between pathological features of parotid gland and labial salivary gland biopsies?
Ann Rheum Dis
2017; 77: e37
10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-212289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-212289</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jonsson MV, Baldini C. Major salivary gland ultrasonography in the diagnosis of Sjögren's syndrome: A place in the diagnostic criteria?
Rheum Dis Clin North Am
2016; 42: 501–517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27431351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hammenfors DS, Brun JG, Jonsson R, Jonsson MV. Diagnostic utility of major salivary gland ultrasonography in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2015; 33: 56–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25535773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kim JW, Lee H, Park SH, Kim SK, Choe JY, Kim JK. Salivary gland ultrasonography findings are associated with clinical, histological, and serologic features of Sjögren's syndrome. Scand J Rheumatol
2018; Feb 7: 1–8. 10.1080/03009742.2017.1374451. [Epub ahead of print] PMID: 29411664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03009742.2017.1374451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29411664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Theander E, Mandl T. Primary Sjogren's syndrome: The diagnostic and prognostic value of salivary gland ultrasonography using a simplified scoring system. Arthritis Care Res
2014; 66: 1102–1107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24339361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shimizu M, Okamura K, Yoshiura K, Ohyama Y, Nakamura S. Sonographic diagnosis of Sjögren syndrome: evaluation of parotid gland vascularity as a diagnostic tool. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod
2008; 106: 587–594.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jousse‐Joulin S, Devauchelle‐Pensec V, Morvan J, Guias B, Pennec Y, Pers JO, Daridon C, Jamin C, Renaudineau Y, Roué IQ, Cochener B, Bressollette L, Youinou P, Saraux A. Ultrasound assessment of salivary glands in patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome treated with rituximab: Quantitative and Doppler waveform analysis. Biologics
2007; 1: 311–319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2721315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19707340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jousse‐Joulin S, Devauchelle‐Pensec V, Cornec D, Marhadour T, Bressollette L, Gestin S, Pers JO, Nowak E, Saraux A. Brief report: ultrasonographic assessment of salivary gland response to rituximab in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Rheumatol
2015; 67: 1623–1628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25708147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jousse‐Joulin S, Nowak E, Cornec D, Brown J, Carr A, Carotti M, Fisher B, Fradin J, Hocevar A, Jonsson MV, Luciano N, Milic V, Rout J, Theander E, Stel A, Bootsma H, Vissink A, Baldini C, Baer A, Ng WF, Bowman S, Alavi Z, Saraux A, Devauchelle‐Pensec V. Salivary gland ultrasound abnormalities in primary Sjögren's syndrome: consensual US‐SG core items definition and reliability. RMD Open
2017; 3: e000364.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5575597</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28879042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mossel E, Arends S, van Nimwegen JF, Delli K, Stel AJ, Kroese FGM, Spijkervet FKL, Vissink A, Bootsma H, EULAR US‐pSS study group
. Scoring hypoechogenic areas in one parotid and one submandibular gland increases feasibility of ultrasound in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis
2018; 77: 556–562.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29233833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hocevar A, Ambrozic A, Rozman B, Kveder T, Tomsic M. Ultrasonographic changes of major salivary glands in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Diagnostic value of a novel scoring system. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2005; 44: 768–772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15741192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Baldini C, Luciano N, Tarantini G, Pascale R, Sernissi F, Mosca M, Caramella D, Bombardieri S. Salivary gland ultrasonography: a highly specific tool for the early diagnosis of primary Sjogren's syndrome. Arthritis Res Ther
2015; 17: 146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4461980</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26022533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Astorri E, Sutcliffe N, Richards PS, Suchak K, Pitzalis C, Bombardieri M, Tappuni AR. Ultrasound of the salivary glands is a strong predictor of labial gland biopsy histopathology in patients with sicca symptoms. J Oral Pathol Med
2016; 45: 450–454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26660860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Luciano N, Baldini C, Tarantini G, Ferro F, Sernissi F, Varanini V, Donati V, Martini D, Mosca M, Caramella D, Bombardieri S. Ultrasonography of major salivary glands: a highly specific tool for distinguishing primary Sjögren's syndrome from undifferentiated connective tissue diseases. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2015; 52: 2198–2204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26206346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cornec D, Jousse‐Joulin S, Pers JO, Marhadour T, Cochener B, Boisrame‐Gastrin S, Nowak E, Youinou P, Saraux A, Devauchelle‐Pensec V. Contribution of salivary gland ultrasonography to the diagnosis of Sjögren's syndrome: toward new diagnostic criteria?
Arthritis Rheum
2013; 65: 216–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23108632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cornec D, Jousse‐Joulin S, Marhadour T, Pers JO, Boisrame‐Gastrin S, Renaudineau Y, Saraux A, Devauchelle‐Pensec V. Salivary gland ultrasonography improves the diagnostic performance of the 2012 American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for Sjögren's syndrome. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2014; 53: 1604–1607.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24706989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Takagi Y, Sumi M, Nakamura H, Sato S, Kawakami A, Nakamura T. Salivary gland ultrasonography as a primary imaging tool for predicting efficacy of xerostomia treatment in patients with Sjögren's syndrome. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2016; 55: 237–245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Le Goff M, Cornec D, Jousse‐Joulin S, Guellec D, Costa S, Marhadour T, Le Berre R, Genestet S, Cochener B, Boisrame‐Gastrin S, Renaudineau Y, Pers JO, Saraux A, Devauchelle‐Pensec V. Comparison of 2002 AECG and 2016 ACR/EULAR classification criteria and added value of salivary gland ultrasonography in a patient cohort with suspected primary Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Res Ther
2017; 19: 269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717850</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29208023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jousse‐Joulin S, Gatineau F, Baldini C, Baer AN, Barone F, Bootsma H, Bowman S, Brito‐Zeron P, Cornec D, Doerner T, DeVita S, Fisher B, Hammenfors DS, Jonsson MV, Mariette X, Milic V, Nakamura H, Ng W‐F, Nowak E, Ramos‐Casals M, Rasmussen A, Seror R, Shiboski C, Nakamura T, Vissink A, Saraux A, Devauchelle‐Pensec V. Modification of the classification criteria for primary Sjögren syndrome: An International vignette survey. Arthritis Rheumatol
2017; 69: 1286–1288. Abstract Number: 877.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Anaya JM, Ogawa N, Talal N. Sjogren's syndrome in childhood. J Rheumatol
1995; 22: 1152–1158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7674246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lieberman SM. Childhood Sjogren syndrome: insights from adults and animal models. Curr Opin Rheumatol
2013; 25: 651–657.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4049091</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cimaz R, Casadei A, Rose C, Bartunkova J, Sediva A, Falcini F, Picco P, Taglietti M, Zulian F, Ten Cate R, Sztajnbok FR, Voulgari PV, Drosos AA. Primary Sjögren syndrome in the paediatric age: a multicentre survey. Eur J Pediatr
2003; 162: 661–665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nikitakis NG, Rivera H, Lariccia C, Papadimitriou JC, Sauk JJ. Primary Sjögren syndrome in childhood: report of a case and review of the literature. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod
2003; 96: 42–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12847443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bogdanovic R, Basta‐Jovanovic G, Putnik J, Stajic N, Paripovic A. Renal involvement in primary Sjogren syndrome of childhood: case report and literature review. Mod Rheumatol
2013; 23: 182–189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22484709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fang QG, Liu FY, Sun CF. Recurrent submandibular gland swelling as a first manifestation in a child with primary Sjogren syndrome. J Craniofac Surg
2013; 24: e413–e415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23851886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
de Souza TR, Silva IH, Carvalho AT, Gomes VB, Duarte AP, Leão JC, Gueiros LA. Juvenile Sjögren syndrome: distinctive age, unique findings. Pediatr Dent
2012; 34: 427–430.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23211922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nieto‐Gonzalez JC, Monteagudo I, Bello N, Martinez‐Estupinan L, Naredo E, Carreno L. Salivary gland ultrasound in children: a useful tool in the diagnosis of juvenile Sjögren's syndrome. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2014; 32: 578–580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24847722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jonsson MV, Delaleu N, Marthinussen MC, Jonsson R. Oral and dental manifestations of Sjögren's syndrome: current Approaches to diagnostics and therapy In: Fox RI, Fox C, eds. Sjögren's Syndrome: Current Topics of Pathogenesis and Therapy, 1st edn
New York: Springer, 2011; 221–242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Katsiougiannis S, Wong DT. The Proteomics of Saliva in Sjögren's Syndrome. Rheum Dis Clin North Am
2016; 42: 449–456.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4955829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27431347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hu S, Wang J, Meijer J, Ieong S, Xie Y, Yu T, Zhou H, Henry S, Vissink A, Pijpe J, Kallenberg C, Elashoff D, Loo JA, Wong DT. Salivary proteomic and genomic biomarkers for primary Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Rheum
2007; 56: 3588–3600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2856841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17968930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Baldini C, Giusti L, Ciregia F, Da Valle Y, Giacomelli C, Donadio E, Sernissi F, Bazzichi L, Giannaccini G, Bombardieri S, Lucacchini A. Proteomic analysis of saliva: a unique tool to distinguish primary Sjögren's syndrome from secondary Sjögren's syndrome and other sicca syndromes. Arthritis Res Ther
2011; 13: R194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3334644</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22117835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ambatipudi KS, Swatkoski S, Moresco JJ, Tu PG, Coca A, Anolik JH, Gucek M, Sanz I, Yates JR, Melvin JE. Quantitative proteomics of parotid saliva in primary Sjögren's syndrome. Proteomics
2012; 12: 3113–3120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3806318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22888089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kageyama G, Saegusa J, Irino Y, Tanaka S, Tsuda K, Takahashi S, Sendo S, Morinobu A. Metabolomics analysis of saliva from patients with primary Sjögren's syndrome. Clin Exp Immunol
2015; 182: 149–153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4608504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26201380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sreebny L, Zhu WX. Whole saliva and the diagnosis of Sjögren's syndrome: an evaluation of patients who complain of dry mouth and dry eyes. Part 2: Immunologic findings. Gerodontology
1996; 13: 44–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9452641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hu S, Vissink A, Arellano M, Roozendaal C, Zhou H, Kallenberg CG, Wong DT. Identification of autoantibody biomarkers for primary Sjögren's syndrome using protein microarrays. Proteomics
2011; 11: 1499–1507.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209962</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21413148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Delaleu N, Mydel P, Kwee I, Brun JG, Jonsson MV, Jonsson R. High fidelity between saliva proteomics and the biologic state of salivary glands defines biomarker signatures for primary Sjögren's syndrome. Arthritis Rheumatol
2015; 67: 1084–1095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25545990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Delaleu N, Mydel P, Brun JG, Jonsson MV, Alimonti A, Jonsson R. Sjögren's syndrome patients with ectopic germinal centers present with a distinct salivary proteome. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2016; 55: 1127–1137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26921905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Delaleu N, Madureira AC, Immervoll H, Jonsson R. Inhibition of experimental Sjögren's syndrome through immunization with HSP60 and its peptide amino acids 437‐460. Arthritis Rheum
2008; 58: 2318–2328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18668586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
