<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30247830</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK525955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230">Physiology, Pineal Gland</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilahi</LastName><ForeName>Sadia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beriwal</LastName><ForeName>Nitya</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Lady Hardinge Medical College</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ilahi</LastName><ForeName>Tahir B.</ForeName><Initials>TB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Unity Point Health/ OSF St. Francis MC</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>The pineal gland is an endocrine gland located in the posterior aspect of the cranial fossa in the brain. Its importance is in the circadian cycle of sleep and wakefulness. The pineal gland is also known as the epiphysis cerebri. The gland is pine cone-shaped and about 0.8 cm long. In an adult, it weighs about 0.1 g. It is an unpaired gland that resides between the thalamic bodies behind the habenular commissure. It is located near the corpora quadrigemina, which is behind the third ventricle. Cerebrospinal fluid bathes the gland through the pineal recess. The following are the relations of the pineal gland in the brain on the coronal section: <b>Superiorly: </b>Corpus callosum (splenium aspect). <b>Inferiorly: </b>Inferior and superior colliculi. <b>Superolateral: </b>Third ventricle choroid plexus. In a sagittal section, the following is seen: <b>Anterosuperior: </b>Thalamus and the habenular commissure. <b>Anteroinferior: </b>Cerebral aqueduct of Sylvius, posterior commissure, and the cerebral peduncle. <b>Posterosuperior: </b>Cerebral vein of Galen. <b>Inferiorly: </b>Quadrigemineal plate. The epiphysis cerebri is supplied by the adrenergic nerves. The neurons are sensitive to epinephrine. The sympathetic innervation is from the superior cervical ganglion, while the parasympathetic innervation is from the optic and pterygopalatine ganglia. The pineal stalk of the gland also has nerve fibers along with innervation from neurons from the trigeminal ganglion. The neurons from the trigeminal ganglion have nerve fibers that contain the PACAP, which is a neuropeptide.  The blood supply of the pineal gland is derived from the posterior cerebral artery from its choroidal branches. The internal cerebral vein drains the blood from the epiphysis cerebri. Histologically the gland consists of cells called pinealocytes and supporting cells.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s1">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s2">Cellular</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s3">Development</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s4">Function</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s5">Mechanism</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s6">Related Testing</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s7">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s8">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s9">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27230" sec="article-27230.s10">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>28</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Popović B, Velimirović M, Stojković T, Brajović G, De Luka SR, Milovanović I, Stefanović S, Nikolić D, Ristić-Djurović JL, Petronijević ND, Trbovich AM. The influence of ageing on the extrapineal melatonin synthetic pathway. Exp Gerontol. 2018 Sep;110:151-157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29906492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferri L, Filardi M, Moresco M, Pizza F, Vandi S, Antelmi E, Toni F, Zucchelli M, Pierangeli G, Plazzi G. Non-24-Hour Sleep-Wake Rhythm Disorder and Melatonin Secretion Impairment in a Patient With Pineal Cyst. J Clin Sleep Med. 2017 Nov 15;13(11):1355-1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5656486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28992833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meneses-Santos D, Buonfiglio DDC, Peliciari-Garcia RA, Ramos-Lobo AM, Souza DDN, Carpinelli AR, Carvalho CRO, Sertie RAL, Andreotti S, Lima FB, Afeche SC, Fioretto ET, Cipolla-Neto J, Marçal AC. Chronic treatment with dexamethasone alters clock gene expression and melatonin synthesis in rat pineal gland at night. Nat Sci Sleep. 2018;10:203-215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6054274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30046256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma H, Wang Z, Hu L, Zhang S, Zhao C, Yang H, Wang H, Fang Z, Wu L, Chen X. The melatonin-MT1 receptor axis modulates tumor growth in PTEN-mutated gliomas. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2018 Feb 19;496(4):1322-1330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29408377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass J, Takahashi JS. Circadian rhythms: Redox redux. Nature. 2011 Jan 27;469(7331):476-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3760156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21270881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy S, Reddy V, Sharma S.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. May 9, Physiology, Circadian Rhythm.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30137792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Nabi G, Yao L, Siddique R, Sajjad W, Kumar S, Duan P, Hou H. Health risks associated with genetic alterations in internal clock system by external factors. Int J Biol Sci. 2018;14(7):791-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruni O, Alonso-Alconada D, Besag F, Biran V, Braam W, Cortese S, Moavero R, Parisi P, Smits M, Van der Heijden K, Curatolo P. Current role of melatonin in pediatric neurology: clinical recommendations. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2015 Mar;19(2):122-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25553845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez IR, Mazuruk K, Schoen TJ, Chader GJ. Structural analysis of the human hydroxyindole-O-methyltransferase gene. Presence of two distinct promoters. J Biol Chem. 1994 Dec 16;269(50):31969-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7989373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veatch OJ, Pendergast JS, Allen MJ, Leu RM, Johnson CH, Elsea SH, Malow BA. Genetic variation in melatonin pathway enzymes in children with autism spectrum disorder and comorbid sleep onset delay. J Autism Dev Disord. 2015 Jan;45(1):100-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4289108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25059483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaste P, Clement N, Botros HG, Guillaume JL, Konyukh M, Pagan C, Scheid I, Nygren G, Anckarsäter H, Rastam M, Ståhlberg O, Gillberg IC, Melke J, Delorme R, Leblond C, Toro R, Huguet G, Fauchereau F, Durand C, Boudarene L, Serrano E, Lemière N, Launay JM, Leboyer M, Jockers R, Gillberg C, Bourgeron T. Genetic variations of the melatonin pathway in patients with attention-deficit and hyperactivity disorders. J Pineal Res. 2011 Nov;51(4):394-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21615493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Botros HG, Legrand P, Pagan C, Bondet V, Weber P, Ben-Abdallah M, Lemière N, Huguet G, Bellalou J, Maronde E, Beguin P, Haouz A, Shepard W, Bourgeron T. Crystal structure and functional mapping of human ASMT, the last enzyme of the melatonin synthesis pathway. J Pineal Res. 2013 Jan;54(1):46-57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22775292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feroze KB, Patel BC.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Nov 2, Parinaud Syndrome.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30247830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
