<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30252248</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK525992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409">Polyglandular Autoimmune Syndrome Type II</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Gurdeep</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Our Lady of Lourdes Memorial Hospital</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jialal</LastName><ForeName>Ishwarlal</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VA MEDICAL CENTER, MATHER , CA</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Polyglandular autoimmune syndrome (PAS) is a clustering of at least 2 or more endocrine diseases in a single patient. Common autoimmune polyglandular syndromes are PAS-1, PAS-2 and X-linked immune dysregulation polyendocrinopathy and enteropathy (IPEX). Recently, a new category has emerged. It is iatrogenic polyendocrinopathy due to use of immunoregulatory agents in patients with cancer. Ipilimumab which is used to treat metastatic cancer can cause hypophysitis. Polyglandular autoimmune syndrome type 2 (PAS-2) is an autoimmune disease with polygenic inheritance. It is also called Schmidt syndrome and Carpenter syndrome. The clustering of multiple endocrine diseases in a single patient was documented well before the classification of PAS came into existence. In 1926, Schmidt published 2 cases of Addison disease and chronic lymphocytic thyroiditis known as Schmidt syndrome. Five years later, in 1931, Rowntree and Snell reported the first case of Addison disease with hyperthyroidism and type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM).. Beaven et al. reviewed 66 cases, and Solomon et al. reviewed 113 cases of Addison disease and diabetes mellitus. Post-mortem investigation showed lymphocytic infiltration in the glands in the majority of these cases, confirming that it was an autoimmune disease. Carpenter confirmed the association of diabetes mellitus with Schmidt syndrome in a review of 142 cases of Schmidt syndrome and coined the term Carpenter syndrome, which is a triad of Addison disease, autoimmune thyroid disease, and TIDM. This review focuses on the diagnosis and management of PAS-2 defined by the cluster of T1DM, auto-immune thyroid disease, and Addison disease.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s10">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s11">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27409" sec="article-27409.s12">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Husebye ES, Anderson MS, Kämpe O. Autoimmune Polyendocrine Syndromes. N Engl J Med. 2018 Mar 22;378(12):1132-1141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6007870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperling MA, Angelousi A, Yau M.  Autoimmune Polyglandular Syndromes. In: Feingold KR, Anawalt B, Boyce A, Chrousos G, de Herder WW, Dhatariya K, Dungan K, Hershman JM, Hofland J, Kalra S, Kaltsas G, Koch C, Kopp P, Korbonits M, Kovacs CS, Kuohung W, Laferrère B, Levy M, McGee EA, McLachlan R, Morley JE, New M, Purnell J, Sahay R, Singer F, Sperling MA, Stratakis CA, Trence DL, Wilson DP, editors. Endotext [Internet] MDText.com, Inc.; South Dartmouth (MA): 2021. Apr 10, </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25905375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betterle C, Lazzarotto F, Presotto F. Autoimmune polyglandular syndrome Type 2: the tip of an iceberg? Clin Exp Immunol. 2004 Aug;137(2):225-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1809126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15270837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CARPENTER CC, SOLOMON N, SILVERBERG SG, BLEDSOE T, NORTHCUTT RC, KLINENBERG JR, BENNETT IL, HARVEY AM. SCHMIDT'S SYNDROME (THYROID AND ADRENAL INSUFFICIENCY). A REVIEW OF THE LITERATURE AND A REPORT OF FIFTEEN NEW CASES INCLUDING TEN INSTANCES OF COEXISTENT DIABETES MELLITUS. Medicine (Baltimore) 1964 Mar;43:153-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14132718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Förster G, Krummenauer F, Kühn I, Beyer J, Kahaly G. [Polyglandular autoimmune syndrome type II: epidemiology and forms of manifestation]. Dtsch Med Wochenschr. 1999 Dec 10;124(49):1476-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10629665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dittmar M, Kahaly GJ. Polyglandular autoimmune syndromes: immunogenetics and long-term follow-up. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2003 Jul;88(7):2983-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12843130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer G, Badenhoop K, Linder R. Addison's disease with polyglandular autoimmunity carries a more than 2·5-fold risk for adrenal crises: German Health insurance data 2010-2013. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 2016 Sep;85(3):347-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26896640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutolo M. Autoimmune polyendocrine syndromes. Autoimmun Rev. 2014 Feb;13(2):85-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandão Neto RA, de Carvalho JF. Diagnosis and classification of Addison's disease (autoimmune adrenalitis). Autoimmun Rev. 2014 Apr-May;13(4-5):408-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24424183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Ping F, Qi C, Xiao X. Delayed diagnosis with autoimmune polyglandular syndrome type 2 causing acute adrenal crisis: A case report. Medicine (Baltimore) 2016 Oct;95(42):e5062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5079318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27759634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gouda MR, Al-Amin A, Grabsch H, Donnellan C. A multidisciplinary approach to management of autoimmune polyendocrinopathy candidiasis ectodermal dystrophy (APECED). BMJ Case Rep. 2013 Jan 30;2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3604509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23370953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
