<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30349415</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-2736</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2018</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of blood medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Blood Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Evans syndrome: clinical perspectives, biological insights and treatment modalities.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>171</StartPage>
          <EndPage>184</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>171-184</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/JBM.S176144</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Evans syndrome (ES) is a rare and chronic autoimmune disease characterized by autoimmune hemolytic anemia and immune thrombocytopenic purpura with a positive direct anti-human globulin test. It is classified as primary and secondary, with the frequency in patients with autoimmune hemolytic anemia being 37%-73%. It predominates in children, mainly due to primary immunodeficiencies or autoimmune lymphoproliferative syndrome. ES during pregnancy is associated with high fetal morbidity, including severe hemolysis and intracranial bleeding with neurological sequelae and death. The clinical presentation can include fatigue, pallor, jaundice and mucosal bleeding, with remissions and exacerbations during the person's lifetime, and acute manifestations as catastrophic bleeding and massive hemolysis. Recent molecular theories explaining the physiopathology of ES include deficiencies of CTLA-4, LRBA, TPP2 and a decreased CD4/CD8 ratio. As in other autoimmune cytopenias, there is no established evidence-based treatment and steroids are the first-line therapy, with intravenous immunoglobulin administered as a life-saving resource in cases of severe immune thrombocytopenic purpura manifestations. Second-line treatment for refractory ES includes rituximab, mofetil mycophenolate, cyclosporine, vincristine, azathioprine, sirolimus and thrombopoietin receptor agonists. In cases unresponsive to immunosuppressive agents, hematopoietic stem cell transplantation has been successful, although it is necessary to consider its potential serious adverse effects. In conclusion, ES is a disease with a heterogeneous course that remains challenging to patients and physicians, with prospective clinical trials needed to explore potential targeted therapy to achieve an improved long-term response or even a cure.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jaime-Pérez</LastName>
            <ForeName>José Carlos</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Internal Medicine Division, Dr José E González University Hospital, School of Medicine of the Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Monterrey, Nuevo León, México, carjaime@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aguilar-Calderón</LastName>
            <ForeName>Patrizia Elva</ForeName>
            <Initials>PE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Internal Medicine Division, Dr José E González University Hospital, School of Medicine of the Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Monterrey, Nuevo León, México, carjaime@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Salazar-Cavazos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lorena</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Internal Medicine Division, Dr José E González University Hospital, School of Medicine of the Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Monterrey, Nuevo León, México, carjaime@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gómez-Almaguer</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Internal Medicine Division, Dr José E González University Hospital, School of Medicine of the Universidad Autónoma de Nuevo León, Monterrey, Nuevo León, México, carjaime@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Blood Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101550884</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1179-2736</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Evans syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HSCT</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IVIG</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune cytopenias</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low-dose rituximab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mofetil mycophenolate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sirolimus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Disclosure The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30349415</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6190623</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JBM.S176144</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">jbm-9-171</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans R, Takahashi K, Duane RT, Payne R, Liu C. Primary thrombocytopenic purpura and acquired haemolytic anemia: evidence for a common etiology. AMA Arch Intern Med. 1951;87(1):48–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14782741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedson SP. Blood-Platelet anti-serum, its specificity and role in the experimental production of purpura. J Pathol Bacteriol. 1922;24:94–104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathew P, Chen G, Wang W. Evans syndrome results of a national survey. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 1997;19(5):433–437.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9329465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savasan S, Warrier I, Ravindranath Y. The spectrum of Evans’ syndrome. Arch Dis Child. 1997;77(3):245–248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1717303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9370906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhingra KK, Jain D, Mandal S, Khurana N, Singh T, Gupta N. Evans syndrome: a study of six cases with review of literature. Hematology. 2008;13(6):356–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19055865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pui CH, Wilimas J, Wang W. Evans syndrome in childhood. J Pediatr. 1980;97(5):754–758.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7191890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aladjidi N, Leverger G, Leblanc T, et al.  New insights into childhood autoimmune hemolytic anemia: a French national observational study of 265 children. Haematologica. 2011;96(5):655–663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3084911</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21228033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Besnard C, Levy E, Aladjidi N, et al.  Pediatric-onset Evans syndrome: heterogeneous presentation and high frequency of monogenic disorders including LRBA and CTLA4 mutations. Clin Immunol. 2018;188:52–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michel M, Chanet V, Dechartres A, et al.  The spectrum of Evans syndrome in adults: new insight into the disease based on the analysis of 68 cases. Blood. 2009;114(15):3167–3172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19638626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaime-Pérez JC, Guerra-Leal LN, López-Razo ON, Méndez-Ramírez N, Gómez-Almaguer D. Experience with Evans syndrome in an academic referral center. Rev Bras Hematol Hemoter. 2015;37(4):230–235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4519700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26190425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norton A, Roberts I. Management of Evans syndrome. Br J Haematol. 2006;132(2):125–137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16398647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miano M. How I manage Evans syndrome and AIHA cases in children. Br J Haematol. 2016;172(4):524–534.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26625877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corrigan JJ, Jr, Boineau FG. Hemolytic-uremic syndrome. Pediatr Rev. 2001;22(11):365–369.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11691946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joly BS, Coppo P, Veyradier A. Thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura. Blood. 2017;129(21):2836–2846.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28416507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JA, Choi YB, Yi ES, et al.  Excellent outcome of medical treatment for Kasabach–Merritt syndrome: a single-center experience. Blood Res. 2016;51(4):256–260.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5234231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28090488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maguiness S, Guenther L. Kasabach–Merritt syndrome. J Cutan Med Surg. 2002;6(4):335–339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11951132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W, Herrod H, Pui CH, Presbury G, Wilimas J. Immunoregulatory abnormalities in Evans syndrome. Am J Hematol. 1983;15(4):381–390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6606357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt RE, Grimbacher B, Witte T. Autoimmunity and primary immunodeficiency: two sides of the same coin? Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2018;14(1):7–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29255211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo B, Fritz JM, Su HC, et al.  CHAI and LATAIE: new genetic diseases of CTLA-4 checkpoint insufficiency. Blood. 2016;128(8):1037–1042.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5000841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27418640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedline RH, Brown DS, Nguyen H, et al.  CD4+ regulatory T cells require CTLA-4 for the maintenance of systemic tolerance. J Exp Med. 2009;206(2):421–434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2646578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19188497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stepensky P, Rensing-Ehl A, Gather R, et al.  Early-onset Evans syndrome, immunodeficiency, and premature immunosenescence associated with tripeptidyl-peptidase II deficiency. Blood. 2015;125(5):753–761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4463807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25414442</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubtsov AV, Rubtsova K, Fischer A, et al.  Toll-like receptor 7 (TLR7)-driven accumulation of a novel CD11c+ B-cell population is important for the development of autoimmunity. Blood. 2011;118(5):1305–1315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3152497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21543762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karakantza M, Mouzaki A, Theodoropoulou M, Bussel JB, Maniatis A. Th1 and Th2 cytokines in a patient with Evans’ syndrome and profound lymphopenia. Br J Haematol. 2000;110(4):968–970.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costallat GL, Appenzeller S, Costallat LT. Evans syndrome and systemic lupus erythematosus: clinical presentation and outcome. Joint Bone Spine. 2012;79(4):362–364.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21944976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambotte O, Gelu-Simeon M, Maigne G, et al.  Pegylated interferon alpha-2a-associated life-threatening Evans’ syndrome in a patient with chronic hepatitis C. J Infect. 2005;51(3):e113–e115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16230187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shivalingaiah SK, Arpana J, Jain MK, Varghese VK. Hyperhomocysteinemia and Evan′s syndrome with uncal herniation for emergency splenectomy. Anesth Essays Res. 2015;9(1):118–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383129</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25886436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokoyama S, Kasahara M, Fukuda A, et al.  Evans syndrome after successful living-donor liver transplantation for neonatal giant cell hepatitis. Transplantation. 2007;84(6):798–799.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17893616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma S, Dasgupta S, Suman SK, Kumar U, Chitekela S. Disseminated tuberculosis with Evans syndrome: an uncommon presentation. Trop Doct. 2017;47(2):179–181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28118797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka Y, Masuya M, Katayama N, et al.  Development of mixed-type autoimmune hemolytic anemia and Evans’ syndrome following chicken pox infection in a case of low-titer cold agglutinin disease. Int J Hematol. 2006;84(3):220–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17050195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shatzel JJ, Donohoe K, Chu NQ, et al.  Profound autoimmune hemolysis and Evans syndrome in two asplenic patients with babesiosis. Transfusion. 2015;55(3):661–665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25354478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Font J, Jiménez S, Cervera R, et al.  Splenectomy for refractory Evans’ syndrome associated with antiphospholipid antibodies: report of two cases. Ann Rheum Dis. 2000;59(11):920–923.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rückert A, Glimm H, Lübbert M, Grüllich C. Successful treatment of life-threatening Evans syndrome due to antiphospholipid antibody syndrome by rituximab-based regimen: a case with long-term followup. Lupus. 2008;17(8):757–760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18625656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masson C, Brégeon C, Ifrah N, Berton V, Housseau F, Rénier JC. Evans’ syndrome caused by D-penicillamine in rheumatoid arthritis. Value of the corticoids–danazol combination. Rev Rhum Mal Osteoartic. 1991;58(7):519–522. French.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1925397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quinn JP, Gilligan OM, Horgan M. Evan’s syndrome complicating multicentric Castleman’s disease – dramatic response to rituximab. Eur J Haematol. 2004;73(5):384–385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15458520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dave P, Krishna K, Diwan AG. Evan’s syndrome revisited. J Assoc Physicians India. 2012;60:60–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23029746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeda K, Maruyama Y, Yokoyama M, et al.  Association of Graves’ disease with Evans’ syndrome in a patient with IgA nephropathy. Intern Med. 2001;40(10):1004–1010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11688823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yashiro M, Nagoshi H, Kasuga Y, et al.  Evans’ syndrome associated with Graves’ disease. Intern Med. 1996;35(12):987–990.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9031001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Muñoz R, Anton J, Rodriguez-Otero P, et al.  Common variable immunodeficiency and Evans syndrome complicated by autoimmune hemolysis due to anti-Jka auto-antibodies. Leuk Lymphoma. 2008;49(6):1220–1222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18452064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azizi G, Abolhassani H, Asgardoon MH, et al.  Autoimmunity in common variable immunodeficiency: epidemiology, pathophysiology and management. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2017;13(2):101–115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27636680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Podjasek JC, Abraham RS. Autoimmune cytopenias in common variable immunodeficiency. Front Immunol. 2012;3:189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3402902</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22837758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savas¸an S, Warrier I, Buck S, Kaplan J, Ravindranath Y. Increased lymphocyte Fas expression and high incidence of common variable immunodeficiency disorder in childhood Evans’ syndrome. Clin Immunol. 2007;125(3):224–229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17936685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paaske H, Srensen CW, Astrup L. Evans’ syndrome in IgA deficiency. Episodic autoimmune haemolytic anaemia and thrombocytopenia during a 10 years observation period. Scand J Haematol. 1982:265–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7146824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roca B, Ferrán G, Simón E, Cortés V. Lymphoid hyperplasia of the lung and Evans’ syndrome in IgA deficiency. Am J Med. 1999;106(1):121–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10320128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bechir A, Haifa R, Nesrine BS, et al.  Multiple myeloma associated with an Evan’s syndrome. Pan Afr Med J. 2016;25:127.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5325491</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28292089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto G, Hosoi M, Miyagawa T, et al.  Evans syndrome with cytomegalovirus infection followed by emerging peripheral T-cell lymphoma. Ann Hematol. 2012;91(1):123–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21437588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shlamovitz GZ, Johar S. A case of Evans’ syndrome following influenza vaccine. J Emerg Med. 2013;44(2):e149–e151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez E, Domingo P. Evans’s syndrome triggered by recombinant hepatitis B vaccine. Clin Infect Dis. 1992;15(6):1051.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1457642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyun D, Kim D, Jung J, Sohn S, Lee J, Lee K. A case of Epstein– Barr virus infection presented as Evans syndrome. Blood Res. 1998;33(3):438–442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozgönenel B, Moonka D, Savas¸an S. Fulminant hepatitis B following rituximab therapy in a patient with Evans syndrome and large B-cell lymphoma. Am J Hematol. 2006;81(4):302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16550511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubota T, Daibata M, Kobayashi M, Taguchi H. [Malignant lymphoma of the lung associated with Evans’ syndrome: report of a case]. [Article in Japanese] Nihon Kokyuki Gakkai Zasshi. 2002;40(12):965–969.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12692949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D’Ambrosio D, Tomaselli V, Gargiulo G, Roselli M, della-Morte D, Abete P. Evans syndrome presented with marginal zone lymphoma and duodenal neuroendocrine tumor in an elderly woman. Int J Gerontol. 2016;10(4):237–239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amid A, Leung E. Evans syndrome secondary to HIV infection. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2013;35(6):490–491.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23887732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canale VC, Smith CH. Chronic lymphadenopathy simulating malignant lymphoma. J Pediatr. 1967;70(6):891–899.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4165068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garrido Colino C. Avances en el conocimiento y manejo del síndrome linfoproliferativo autoinmune. An Pediatr. 2014;80(2):122.e1–12122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira JB, Bleesing JJ, Dianzani U, et al.  Revised diagnostic criteria and classification for the autoimmune lymphoproliferative syndrome (ALPS): report from the 2009 NIH International Workshop. Blood. 2010;116(14):e35–e40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953894</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20538792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seif AE, Manno CS, Sheen C, Grupp SA, Teachey DT. Identifying autoimmune lymphoproliferative syndrome in children with Evans syndrome: a multi-institutional study. Blood. 2010;115(11):2142–2145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20068224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teachey DT, Manno CS, Axsom KM, et al.  Unmasking Evans syndrome: T-cell phenotype and apoptotic response reveal autoimmune lymphoproliferative syndrome (ALPS) Blood. 2005;105(6):2443–2448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15542578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thakur N, Chandra J, Dhingra B, Singh V. Pediatric lupus: varied haematological picture and presentation. Indian J Hematol Blood Transfus. 2015;31(1):68–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275535</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25548448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lube GE, Ferriani MP, Campos LM, et al.  Evans syndrome at childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus diagnosis: a large multicenter study. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2016;63(7):1238–1243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27018636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tokgoz H, Caliskan U, Atas B, Ozbek O, Tavil B. Spontaneous rupture of the spleen in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus initially presented as Evans syndrome. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2014;36(1):e39–e41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23389505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendonca S, Srivastava S, Kapoor R, Gupta D, Gupta P, Sharma ML. Evans syndrome and its link with systemic lupus erythematosus. Saudi J Kidney Dis Transpl. 2016;27(1):147–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26787583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kittaka K, Dobashi H, Baba N, et al.  A case of Evans syndrome combined with systemic lupus erythematosus successfully treated with rituximab. Scand J Rheumatol. 2008;37(5):390–393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18609263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamimoto Y, Horiuchi T, Tsukamoto H, et al.  A dose-escalation study of rituximab for treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus and Evans’ syndrome: immunological analysis of B cells, T cells and cytokines. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2008;47(6):821–827.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18397955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musso M, Porretto F, Crescimanno A, et al.  Autologous peripheral blood stem and progenitor (CD34+) cell transplantation for systemic lupus erythematosus complicated by Evans syndrome. Lupus. 1998;7(7):492–494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9796853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohkawara H, Furukawa M, Ikeda K, et al.  Steroid-resistant autoimmune myelofibrosis in a patient with autoimmune hepatitis and Evans syndrome complicated with increased expression of TGF-β in the bone marrow: a case report. Int J Hematol. 2017;106(5):718–724.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28584963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiniakos DG, Brain JG, Bury YA. Role of histopathology in autoimmune hepatitis. Dig Dis. 2015;33(2):53–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26642062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korkmaz H, Bugdaci MS, Temel T, Dagli M, Karabagli P. Autoimmune hepatitis–primary biliary cirrhosis overlap syndrome concomitant with immune hemolytic anemia and immune thrombocytopenic purpura (Evans syndrome) Clin Res Hepatol Gastroenterol. 2013;37(2):e45–e50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23273499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarasvaraparn C, Imran H, Siddiqui A, Wilson F, Gremse DA. Association of autoimmune hepatitis type 1 in a child with Evans syndrome. World J Hepatol. 2017;9(23):1008–1012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5569276</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28878866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carey EJ, Somaratne K, Rakela J. Successful rituximab therapy in refractory autoimmune hepatitis and Evans syndrome. Rev Med Chil. 2011;139(11):1484–1487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22446656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Reilly A, Murphy J, Rawe S, Garvey M. Chronic lymphocytic leukemia: a review of front-line treatment options, with a focus on elderly CLL patients. Clin Lymphoma Myeloma Leuk. 2018;18(4):249–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29477297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno C, Hodgson K, Ferrer G, et al.  Autoimmune cytopenia in chronic lymphocytic leukemia: prevalence, clinical associations, and prognostic significance. Blood. 2010;116(23):4771–4776.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20736453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carli G, Visco C, Falisi E, et al.  Evans syndrome secondary to chronic lymphocytic leukaemia: presentation, treatment, and outcome. Ann Hematol. 2016;95(6):863–870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27001309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dal Bo M, Rossi FM, Rossi D, et al.  13q14 Deletion size and number of deleted cells both influence prognosis in chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Genes Chromosomes Cancer. 2011;50(8):633–643.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21563234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bader-Meunier B, Aladjidi N, Bellmann F, et al.  Rituximab therapy for childhood Evans syndrome. Haematologica. 2007;92(12):1691–1694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18055994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang WC. Evans syndrome in childhood: pathophysiology, clinical course, and treatment. Am J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 1988;10(4):330–338.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3071168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demanelis K, Sriplung H, Meza R, et al.  Differences in childhood leukemia incidence and survival between Southern Thailand and the United States: a population-based analysis. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2015;62(10):1790–1798.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4546554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25962869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverstein MN, Heck FJ. Acquired hemolytic anemia and associated thrombocytopenic purpura: with special reference to Evans syndrome. Proc Staff Meet Mayo Clin. 1962;28(37):122–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13912960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidel MG. Autoimmune and other cytopenias in primary immunodeficiencies: pathomechanisms, novel differential diagnoses, and treatment. Blood. 2014;124(15):2337–2344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4192747</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25163701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pasquet M, Aladjidi N, Guiton C, et al.  Romiplostim in children with chronic immune thrombocytopenia (ITP): the French Experience. Br J Haematol. 2014;164(2):266–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24152194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aladjidi N, Fernandes H, Leblanc T, et al.  Evans syndrome in children: long-term outcome in a prospective French national observational cohort. Front Pediatr. 2015;3:79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4586429</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26484337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sankaran S, Robinson SE. Immune thrombocytopenia and pregnancy. Obstet Med. 2011;4(4):140–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4989643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27579112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phupong V, Sareepapong W, Witoonpanich P. Evans syndrome and pregnancy: a case report. BJOG. 2004;111(3):274–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14961891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ni H, Chen P, Spring CM, et al.  A novel murine model of fetal and neonatal alloimmune thrombocytopenia: response to intravenous IgG therapy. Blood. 2006;107(7):2976–2983.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1895387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16317099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lefkou E, Nelson-Piercy C, Hunt BJ. Evans’ syndrome in pregnancy: a systematic literature review and two new cases. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2010;149(1):10–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantadakis E, Farmaki E. Natural history, pathogenesis, and treatment of Evans syndrome in children. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2017;39(6):413–419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28654461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mizutani H, Furubayashi T, Imai Y, et al.  Mechanisms of corticosteroid action in immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP): experimental studies using ITP-prone mice, (NZW × BXSB) F1. Blood. 1992;79(4):942–947.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1737103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flores-Montes OA, Escobar-Orduño MC, Lozano-Garcidueñas M, Valle-Leal JG. Síndrome de Evans en lactantes. Bol Med Hosp Infant Mex. 2017;74(2):141–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flores G, Cunningham-Rundles C, Newland AC, Bussel JB. Efficacy of intravenous immunoglobulin in the treatment of autoimmune hemolytic anemia: results in 73 patients. Am J Hematol. 1993;44(4):237–242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8237993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godeau B, Bierling P. Treatment of idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura in adults. Presse Med. 2008;37(9):1292–1298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18644317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson D, Ali K, Blanchette V, et al.  Guidelines on the use of intravenous immune globulin for hematologic conditions. Transfus Med Rev. 2007;21(2 Suppl 1):S9–S56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17397769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilgartner MW, Bussel J. Use of intravenous gamma globulin for the treatment of autoimmune neutropenia of childhood and autoimmune hemolytic anemia. Am J Med. 1987;83(4A):25–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3118705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz U, Achiron A, Sherer Y, Shoenfeld Y. Safety of intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) therapy. Autoimmun Rev. 2007;6(4):257–259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17317619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sherer Y, Levy Y, Langevitz P, Rauova L, Fabrizzi F, Shoenfeld Y. Adverse effects of intravenous immunoglobulin therapy. Pharmacology. 2000;62:133–137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11287813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Mcquilten ZK, Wood EM, Aubron C. Intravenous immunoglobulin in critically ill adults: when and what is the evidence? J Crit Care. 2015;30(3):652.e9–e16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25702845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reff ME, Carner K, Chambers KS, et al.  Depletion of B cells in vivo by a chimeric mouse human monoclonal antibody to CD20. Blood. 1994;83(2):435–445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7506951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zecca M, Nobili B, Ramenghi U, et al.  Rituximab for the treatment of refractory autoimmune hemolytic anemia in children. Blood. 2003;101(10):3857–3861.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shanafelt TD, Madueme HL, Wolf RC, Tefferi A. Rituximab for immune cytopenia in adults: idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura, autoimmune hemolytic anemia, and Evans syndrome. Mayo Clin Proc. 2003;78(11):1340–1346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14601692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodella E, Pacquola E, Bianchini E, Ramazzina E, Paolini R. Consolidation treatment with rituximab induces complete and persistent remission of mixed type Evans syndrome. Blood Coagul Fibrinolysis. 2008;19(4):315–318.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18469554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jubinsky PT, Rashid N. Successful treatment of a patient with mixed warm and cold antibody mediated Evans syndrome and glucose intolerance. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2005;45(3):347–350.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15704210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park CY, Chung CH. A patient with mixed type evans syndrome: efficacy of rituximab treatment. J Korean Med Sci. 2006;21(6):1115–1116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2721940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17179698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantadakis E, Danilatou V, Stiakaki E, Kalmanti M. Rituximab for refractory Evans syndrome and other immune-mediated hematologic diseases. Am J Hematol. 2004;77(3):303–310.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15495242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knecht H, Baumberger M, Tobòn A, Steck A. Sustained remission of CIDP associated with Evans syndrome. Neurology. 2004;63(4):730–732.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15326255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urban C, Benesch M, Sovinz P, Schwinger W, Lackner H. Fatal Evans’ syndrome after matched unrelated donor transplantation for hyper-IgM syndrome. Eur J Haematol. 2004;72(6):444–447.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15128425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galor A, O’Brien T. Rituximab treatment for relapsed autoimmune hemolytic anemia in Evans syndrome. Int J Hematol. 2003;78(4):335–336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14686491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seipelt G, Böhme A, Koschmieder S, Hoelzer D. Effective treatment with rituximab in a patient with refractory prolymphocytoid transformed B-chronic lymphocytic leukemia and Evans syndrome. Ann Hematol. 2001;80(3):170–173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11320903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-Raheem MM, Potti A, Kobrinsky N. Severe Evans’s syndrome secondary to interleukin-2 therapy: treatment with chimeric monoclonal anti-CD20 antibody. Ann Hematol. 2001;80(9):543–545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11669305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard J, Hoffbrand AV, Prentice HG, Mehta A. Mycophenolate mofetil for the treatment of refractory auto-immune haemolytic anaemia and auto-immune thrombocytopenia purpura. Br J Haematol. 2002;117(3):712–715.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12028047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miano M, Ramenghi U, Russo G, et al.  Mycophenolate mofetil for the treatment of children with immune thrombocytopenia and Evans syndrome. A retrospective data review from the Italian Association of Paediatric Haematology/Oncology. Br J Haematol. 2016;175(3):490–495.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27447678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miano M, Scalzone M, Perri K, et al.  Mycophenolate mofetil and Sirolimus as second or further line treatment in children with chronic refractory primitive or secondary autoimmune cytopenias: a single centre experience. Br J Haematol. 2015;171(2):247–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26058843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guirat-Dhouib N, Mellouli F, Kouki R, Bejaoui M. Successful treatment of mycophenolate mofetil in a child with refractory Evans syndrome. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2010;32(6):e244.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20628320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farruggia P, Macaluso A, Tropia S, et al.  Effectiveness of cyclosporine and mycophenolate mofetil in a child with refractory Evans syndrome. Pediatr Rep. 2011;3(2):e15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3133497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21772952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao VK, Dugan F, Dale JK, et al.  Use of mycophenolate mofetil for chronic, refractory immune cytopenias in children with autoimmune lymphoproliferative syndrome. Br J Haematol. 2005;129(4):534–538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15877736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuda S, Koyasu S. Mechanisms of action of cyclosporine. Immunopharmacology. 2000;47(2-3):119–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10878286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Earnshaw I, Thachil J. Example of the drug interaction between ciclosporin and orlistat, resulting in relapse of Evan’s syndrome. BMJ Case Rep. 2016;2016:bcr2016217246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5093755</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27793869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janić D, Krivokapiić-Dokmanović L, Jovanović N, Lazić J, Rodić P, Janković S. Glucocorticoid-resistant Evans’ syndrome successfully controlled with low-dose cyclosporine. Int J Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2011;49(10):622–625.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21961487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uçar B, Akgün N, Aydoğdu SD, Kirel B, Idem S. Treatment of refractory Evans’ syndrome with cyclosporine and prednisone. Pediatr Int. 1999;41(1):104–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10200147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rackoff WR, Manno CS. Treatment of refractory Evans syndrome with alternate-day cyclosporine and prednisone. Am J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 1994;16(2):156–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8166369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emilia G, Messora C, Longo G, Bertesi M. Long-term salvage treatment by cyclosporin in refractory autoimmune haematological disorders. Br J Haematol. 1996;93(2):341–344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8639426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu H, Shao Z, Jing L. The effectiveness of cyclosporin A in the treatment of autoimmune hemolytic anemia and Evans syndrome. Zhonghua Xue Ye Xue Za Zhi. 2001;22(11):581–583. Chinese.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11855146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scaradavou A, Bussel J. Evans syndrome. Results of a pilot study utilizing a multiagent treatment protocol. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 1995;17(4):290–295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7583383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duperier T, Felsher J, Brody F. Laparoscopic splenectomy for Evans syndrome. Surg Laparosc Endosc Percutan Tech. 2003;13(1):45–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12598759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Pankaj P, Wang X, Wang Y, Peng B. Splenectomy in the management of Evans syndrome in adults: long-term follow up of 32 patients. Surg Pract. 2014;18(1):15–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leone G, Pizzigallo E. Bacterial infections following splenectomy for malignant and nonmalignant hematologic diseases. Mediterr J Hematol Infect Dis. 2015;7(1):e2015057.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4621170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26543526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price S, Shaw P, Kirk J, et al.  Causes and consequences of splenectomy in ALPS-FAS. Blood. 2010;116(21):3908.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bickenbach KA, Gonen M, Labow DM, et al.  Indications for and efficacy of splenectomy for haematological disorders. Br J Surg. 2013;100(6):794–800.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23436638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monga V, Maliske SM, Perepu U. Fatal pulmonary embolism following splenectomy in a patient with Evan’s syndrome: case report and review of the literature. Thromb J. 2017;15:18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5496165</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28680366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahlmann M, Hempel G. The effect of cyclophosphamide on the immune system: implications for clinical cancer therapy. Cancer Chemother Pharmacol. 2016;78(4):661–671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27646791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodsky RA. High-dose chemotherapy in patients with severe autoimmune disease. Ann Intern Med. 1998;129:1031–1035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9867758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michallet AS, Rossignol J, Cazin B, Ysebaert L. Rituximab–cyclophosphamide–dexamethasone combination in management of autoimmune cytopenias associated with chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Leuk Lymphoma. 2011;52(7):1401–1403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21699387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gombakis N, Trahana M, Athanassiou M, Kanakoudi-Tsakalidou F. Evans syndrome: successful management with multi-agent treatment including intermediate-dose intravenous cyclophosphamide. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 1999;21(3):248–249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10363861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osterborg A, Karlsson C, Lundin J. Alemtuzumab to treat refractory autoimmune hemolytic anemia or thrombocytopenia in chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Curr Hematol Malig Rep. 2009;4(1):47–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20425438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung WW, Hwang GY, Tse E, Kwong YL. Alemtuzumab induced complete remission of autoimmune hemolytic anemia refractory to corticosteroids, splenectomy and rituximab. Haematologica. 2006;91(5 Suppl):ECR13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16709521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez-Almaguer D, Solano-Genesta M, Tarín-Arzaga L, et al.  Low-dose rituximab and alemtuzumab combination therapy for patients with steroid-refractory autoimmune cytopenias. Blood. 2010;116(23):4783–4785.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20841509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willis F, Marsh JC, Bevan DH, et al.  The effect of treatment with Campath-1H in patients with autoimmune cytopenias. Br J Haematol. 2001;114(4):891–898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11564082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez-Almaguer D, Colunga-Pedraza PR, Gómez-de León A, Gutiérrez-Aguirre CH, Cantú-Rodríguez OG, Jaime-Pérez JC. Eltrombopag, low-dose rituximab, and dexamethasone combination as frontline treatment of newly diagnosed immune thrombocytopaenia. Br J Haematol. 2017 Dec 21; Epub.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29270980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz-Arguelles GJ, Ruiz-Delgado GJ, Velázquez-Sánchez-de-Cima S, Zamora-Ortiz G. Simultaneous romiplostin, eltrombopag, and prednisone were successful in severe thrombocytopenia of Evans syndrome refractory to hydrocortisone, splenectomy, intravenous IgG, and rituximab. Hematology. 2013;18(3):175–177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23321502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Nieto JA, Martin-Suarez I, Quattrino S, et al.  The efficacy of romiplostim in the treatment of severe thrombocytopenia associated to Evans syndrome refractory to rituximab. Lupus. 2011;20(12):1321–1323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21719526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaughn JE, Anwer F, Deeg HJ. Treatment of refractory ITP and Evans syndrome by haematopoietic cell transplantation: is it indicated, and for whom? Vox Sang. 2016;110(1):5–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4780370</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26178735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raetz E, Beatty PG, Adams RH. Treatment of severe Evans syndrome with an allogeneic cord blood transplant. Bone Marrow Transplant. 1997;20(5):427–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9339762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oyama Y, Papadopoulos EB, Miranda M, Traynor AE, Burt RK. Allogeneic stem cell transplantation for Evans syndrome. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2001;28(9):903–905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11781654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huhn RD, Fogarty PF, Nakamura R, et al.  High-dose cyclophosphamide with autologous lymphocyte-depleted peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) support for treatment of refractory chronic autoimmune thrombocytopenia. Blood. 2003;101(1):71–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12393623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urban C, Lackner H, Sovinz P, et al.  Successful unrelated cord blood transplantation in a 7-year-old boy with Evans syndrome refractory to immunosuppression and double autologous stem cell transplantation. Eur J Haematol. 2006;76(6):526–530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Passweg JR. Haematopoietic stem cell transplantation for immune thrombopenia and other refractory autoimmune cytopenias. Best Pract Res Clin Haematol. 2004;17(2):305–315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15302342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benesch M, Urban C, Platzbecker U, Passweg J. Stem cell transplantation for patients with Evans syndrome. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2009;5(3):341–348.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20477011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Au WY, Lo CM, Hawkins BR, Ma ES, Lie AK, Kwong YL. Evans’ syndrome complicating chronic graft versus host disease after cadaveric liver transplantation. Transplantation. 2001;72(3):527–528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11502987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page KM, Mendizabal AM, Prasad VK, et al.  Posttransplant autoimmune hemolytic anemia and other autoimmune cytopenias are increased in very young infants undergoing unrelated donor umbilical cord blood transplantation. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2008;14(10):1108–1117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3735356</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18804040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato I, Okada H, Nishida T, et al.  Evans syndrome after autologous peripheral blood stem cell transplantation for recurrent Hodgkin lymphoma. Pediatr Int. 2016;58(9):933–936.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27577012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keung Y-K, Cobos E, Bolanos-Meade J, Issarachai S, Brideau A, Morgan D. Evans syndrome after autologous bone marrow transplant for recurrent Hodgkin’s disease. Bone Marrow Transplant. 1997;20(12):1099–1101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9466285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamezaki K, Fukuda T, Makino S, Harada M. Evans’ syndrome following autologous peripheral blood stem cell transplantation for non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma. Clin Lab Haematol. 2004;26(4):291–293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15279667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chihara D, Sakamoto T, Arimoto-Miyamoto K, et al.  Refractory Evans syndrome after autologous stem cell transplantation for multiple myeloma: management with a second transplantation. Intern Med. 2010;49(7):683–687.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20371959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hwang-Bo S, Kim SK, Lee JW, et al.  Treatment and response of autoimmune cytopenia occurring after allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation in children. Blood Res. 2017;52(2):119–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5503889</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28698848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kheirouri S, Hadi V, Alizadeh M. Immunomodulatory effect of Nigella sativa oil on T lymphocytes in patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Immunol Invest. 2016;45(4):271–283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27100726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baghdadi H, Abdel-Aziz N, Ahmed NS, et al.  Ameliorating role exerted by Al-Hijamah in autoimmune diseases: effect on serum autoantibodies and inflammatory mediators. Int J Health Sci (Qassim) 2015;9(2):207–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4538900</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26309442</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El Sayed SM, Baghdadi H, Abou-Taleb A, et al.  Al-hijamah and oral honey for treating thalassemia, conditions of iron overload, and hyperferremia: toward improving the therapeutic outcomes. J Blood Med. 2014;5:219–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4222535</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25382989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teachey DT, database on the Internet  Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia. Sirolimus for autoimmune disease of blood cells. Clin trials.  [Accessed May 21, 2018].  Available from:  https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00392951. NLM identifier: NCT00392951.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bride KL, Vincent T, Smith-Whitley K, et al.  Sirolimus is effective in relapsed/refractory autoimmune cytopenias: results of a prospective multi-institutional trial. Blood. 2016;127(1):17–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705607</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26504182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kashif M, Qureshi A, Adil SN, Khurshid M. Successful use of rituximab in Evans syndrome and refractory immune thrombocytopenic purpura. J Pak Med Assoc. 2010;60(1):64–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20055286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotb R, Pinganaud C, Trichet C, et al.  Efficacy of mycophenolate mofetil in adult refractory auto-immune cytopenias: a single center preliminary study. Eur J Haematol. 2005;75(1):60–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15946312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodsky RA, Petri M, Smith BD, et al.  Immunoablative high-dose cyclophosphamide without stem-cell rescue for refractory, severe autoimmune disease. Ann Intern Med. 1998;129(12):1031–1035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9867758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
