<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30442604</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-8955</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>66</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>IEEE transactions on ultrasonics, ferroelectrics, and frequency control</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>IEEE Trans Ultrason Ferroelectr Freq Control</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of High-Intensity Ultrasound on Strength of Surgical Mesh When Treating Biofilm Infections.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>38</StartPage>
          <EndPage>44</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>38-44</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/TUFFC.2018.2881358</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The use of cavitation-based ultrasound histotripsy to treat infections on surgical mesh has shown great potential. However, any impact of the therapy on the mesh must be assessed before the therapy can be applied in the clinic. The goal of this study was to determine if the cavitation-based therapy would reduce the strength of the mesh thus compromising the functionality of the mesh. First, Staphylococcus aureus biofilms were grown on the surgical mesh samples and exposed to high-intensity ultrasound pulses. For each exposure, the effectiveness of the therapy was confirmed by counting the number of colony forming units (CFUs) on the mesh. Most of the exposed meshes had no CFUs with an average reduction of 5.4-log<sub>10</sub> relative to the sham exposures. To quantify the impact of the exposure on mesh strength, the force required to tear the mesh and the maximum mesh expansion before damage were quantified for control, sham, and exposed mesh samples. There was no statistical difference between the exposed and sham/control mesh samples in terms of ultimate tensile strength and corresponding mesh expansion. The only statistical difference was with respect to mesh orientation relative to the applied load. The tensile strength increased by 1.36 N while the expansion was reduced by 1.33 mm between different mesh orientations.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bigelow</LastName>
            <ForeName>Timothy A</ForeName>
            <Initials>TA</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thomas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Clayton L</ForeName>
            <Initials>CL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huaiqing</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Itani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kamal M F</ForeName>
            <Initials>KMF</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R21 EB020722</GrantID>
            <Acronym>EB</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>IEEE Trans Ultrason Ferroelectr Freq Control</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9882735</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0885-3010</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018441" MajorTopicYN="N">Biofilms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000528" MajorTopicYN="Y">radiation effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015169" MajorTopicYN="N">Colony Count, Microbial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Biological</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013211" MajorTopicYN="N">Staphylococcus aureus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000528" MajorTopicYN="Y">radiation effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013526" MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical Mesh</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014464" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ultrasonic Therapy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442604</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1519305</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6378954</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TUFFC.2018.2881358</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olson ME, Ceri H, Morck DW, Buret AG, and Read RR, “Biofilm bacteria: formation and comparative susceptibility to antibiotics,”
Can J Vet Res, vol. 66, pp. 86–92,
2002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC226988</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11989739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cochrane DM, Brown MR, Anwar H, Weller PH, Lam K, and Costerton JW, “Antibody response to Pseudomonas aeruginosa surface protein antigens in a rat
model of chronic lung infection,” J Med Microbiol, vol. 27, pp.
255–261, 1988
1988.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3143837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Beer D, Stoodley P, and Lewandowski Z, “Measurement of local diffusion coefficients in biofilms by microinjection and confocal
microscopy,” Biotechnology and Bioengineering, vol. 53, pp.
151–158, 1997.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18633959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodgers J, Phillips F, and Olliff C, “The effects of extracellular slime from Staphylococcus epidermidis on phagocytic
ingestion and killing,”FEMS Immunology and Medical Microbiology, vol.
9, pp. 109–115, 1994.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7804161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vuong C, Voyich JM, Fischer ER, Braughton KR, Whitney AR,DeLeo FR, et al., “Polysaccharide intercellular adhesin (PIA) protects Staphylococcus
epidermidis against major components of the human innate immune system,” Cellular
Microbiology, vol. 6, pp. 269–275,
2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14764110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trautner BW and Darouiche RO, “Catheter-associated infections: pathogenesis affects prevention,”
Arch Intern Med, vol. 164, pp. 842–850,
2004
2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15111369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bigelow TA, Northagen T, Hill TM, and Sailer FC, “The destruction of Escherichia coli biofilms using high-intensity focused
ultrasound,” Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 35, pp.
1026–1031, 2009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19171416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Bigelow TA, Halverson LJ, Middendorf JM, and Rusk B, “Minimization of treatment time for in vitro 1.1 MHz destruction of Pseudomonas
aeruginosa biofilms by high-intensity focused ultrasound,” Ultrasonics,
vol. 52, pp. 668–675, 2012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bigelow TA, Thomas CL, Wu H, and Itani KMF, “Histotripsy treatment ofS. aureus biofilms on surgical mesh samples under varying
pulse durations,” IEEE Transactions on Ultrasonics, Ferroelectrics, and Frequency
Control, vol. 64, pp. 1420–1428,
2017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5819746</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28650808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bigelow TA, Thomas CL, Wu H, and Itani KMF, “Histotripsy treatment of S. Aureus biofilms on surgical mesh samples under
varying scan parameters,” IEEE Transactions on Ultrasonics, Ferroelectrics, and Frequency
Control, vol. 65, pp. 1017–1024,
2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6602080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29856719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson GG, Palermo JJ, Schilling JD, Roth R, Heuser J, and Hultgren SJ, “Intracellular bacterial biofilm-like pods in urinary tract infections,”
Science, vol. 301, pp. 105–107, 2003
2003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12843396</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rutala WA and Weber DJ, “Reprocessing endoscopes: United States perspective,” J Hosp
Infect, vol. 56, pp. 27–39, 2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15110120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rutala WA and Weber DJ, “FDA labeling requirements for disinfection of endoscopes: A counterpoint,”
Infection Control and Hospital Epidemiology vol. 16, pp.
231–235, 1995.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7636171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmen JC, Roeder BL, Nelson JL, Robison Ogilvie RL, Robison RA, Schaalje GB, et al., “Treatment of biofilm infections on implants with low-frequency ultrasound and
antibiotics,” American Journal of Infection Control, vol. 33, pp.
78–82, 2005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1361257</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15761406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mavros M, Athanasiou S, Alexiou V, Mitsikostas P, Peppas G, and Falagas M, “Risk factors for mesh-related infections after hernia repair surgery: A meta-analysis of cohort
studies,” World Journal of Surgery, vol. 35, pp.
2389–2398, 2011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21913136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falagas ME and Kasiakou SK, “Mesh-related infections after hernia repair surgery,” Clinical
Microbiology and Infection, vol. 11, pp. 3–8,
2005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15649297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanchez VM, Abi-Haidar YE, and Itani KMF, “Mesh infection in ventral incisional hernia repair: Incidence, contributing factors, and
treatment,” Surgical Infections, vol. 12, pp.
205–210, 2011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21767146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amid P, “Classification of biomaterials and their related complications in abdominal wall hernia
surgery,” Hernia, vol. 1, pp.
15–21, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lüning T and Spillenaar-Bilgen EJ, “Parastomal hernia: complications of extra-peritoneal onlay mesh placement,”
Hernia, vol. 13, pp. 487–490,
2009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19322626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gracewski SM, Miao H, and Dalecki D, “Ultrasonic excitation of a bubble near a rigid or deformable sphere: Implications for
ultrasonically induced hemolysis,” The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America,
vol. 117, pp. 1440–1447, 2005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15807031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brujan EA, “The role of cavitation microjets in the therapeutic applications of
ultrasound,” Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 30,PP.
381–387, 2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15063520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fong SW, Klaseboer E, Turangan CK, Khoo BC, and Hung KC, “Numerical analysis of a gas bubble near bio-materials in an ultrasound
field,” Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 32, pp.
925–942, 2006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16785014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiu KY, Cheng FT, and Man HC, “Evolution of surface roughness of some metallic materials in cavitation
erosion,” Ultrasonics, vol. 43,pp.
713–716, 2005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16126092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blake JR and Gibson DC, “Cavitation bubbles near boundaries,”Annual Review of Fluid
Mechanics, vol. 19, pp. 99–123,
1987.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearson A, Blake JR, and Otto SR, “Jets in bubbles,” Journal of Engineering Mathematics, vol.
48, pp. 391–412, 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lima MM, Godoy C, Modenesi PJ, Avelar-Batista JC, Davison A, and Matthews A, “Coating fracture toughness determined by Vickers indentation: an important parameter in cavitation
erosion resistance of WC–Co thermally sprayed coatings,” Surface and Coatings
Technology, vol. 177–178, pp. 489–496,
2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hattori S and Itoh T, “Cavitation erosion resistance of plastics,” Wear, vol.
271, pp. 1103–1108, 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown SHM, Carr JA, Ward SR, and Lieber RL, “Passive mechanical properties of rat abdominal wall muscles suggest an important role of the
extracellular connective tissue matrix,” Journal of Orthopaedic Research, vol.
30, pp. 1321–1326, 2012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3337947</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22267257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogneva IV, Lebedev DV, and Shenkman BS, “Transversal stiffness and young’s modulus of single fibers from rat soleus muscle probed by
atomic force microscopy,” Biophysical Journal, vol. 98, pp.
418–424, 2010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2814213</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20141755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogan F and Celebi MS, “Quasi-nonlinear deformation modeling of a human liver based on artificial and experimental
data,” The International Journal of Medical Robotics and Computer Assisted Surgery,
vol. 12,PP,410–420, 2016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26459224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J and Bigelow TA, “Experimental investigation of the effect of stiffness, exposure time and scan direction on the
dimension of ultrasound histotripsy lesions,” Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology,
vol. 37, pp. 1865–1873, 2011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21963031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Bigelow TA, Davis G, Avendano A, Shrotriya P, Bergler K, et al., “Dependence of ablative ability of high-intensity focused ultrasound cavitation-based
histotripsy on mechanical properties of agar,” The Journal of the Acoustical Society of
America, vol. 136, pp. 3018–3027,
2014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25480051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Bigelow TA, and Nagaraju R, “Precision control of lesions by high-intensity focused ultrasound cavitation-based histotripsy
through varying pulse duration,” IEEE Transactions on Ultrasonics, Ferro-electrics and
Frequency Control vol. 60, pp. 1401–1411,
2013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25004507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlaisavljevich E, Kim Y, Owens G, Roberts W, Cain C, and Xu Z, “Effects of tissue mechanical properties on susceptibility to histotripsy-induced tissue
damage,” Physics in Medicine and Biology, vol. 59, pp.
253–270, 2014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4888779</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24351722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlaisavljevich E, Lin K-W, Maxwell A, Warnez MT, Mancia L, Singh R, et al., “Effects of ultrasound frequency and tissue stiffness on the histotripsy intrinsic
threshold for cavitation,” Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol.
41, pp. 1651–1667, 2015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4426049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25766571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlaisavljevich E, Maxwell A, Warnez M, Johnsen E, Cain C, and Zhen X, “Histotripsy-induced cavitation cloud initiation thresholds in tissues of different mechanical
properties,” IEEE Transactions on Ultrasonics, Ferroelectrics, and Frequency Control
vol. 61, pp. 341–352, 2014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4158820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24474139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Wear KA, and Harris GR, “Variation of high-intensity therapeutic ultrasound (HITU) pressure field characterization: Effects
of hydrophone choice, nonlinearity, spatial averaging and complex deconvolution,” Ultrasound in
Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 43, pp. 2329–2342,
2017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5639436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radulescu EG, Lewin PA, Goldstein A, and Nowicki A, “Hydrophone spatial averaging corrections from 1 to 40 MHz,” IEEE
Transactions on Ultrasonics, Ferroelectrics, and Frequency Control, vol. 48, pp.
1575–1580, 2001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11800120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xing G, Yang P, He L, and Feng X, “Spatial averaging effects of hydrophone on field characterization of planar transducer using
Fresnel approximation,” Ultrasonics, vol. 71, pp.
51–58, 2016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27268164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canney MS, Bailey MR, and Crum LA, “Acoustic characterization of high intensity focused ultrasound fields: A combined measurement and
modeling approach,” J. Acoust. Soc. Am, vol. 124, pp.
2406–2420, 2008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2677345</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19062878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sapozhnikov OA, Tsysar SA, Khokhlova VA, and Kreider W, “Acoustic holography as a metrological tool for characterizing medical ultrasound sources and
fields,” The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, vol. 138,
pp. 1515–1532, 2015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4575327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26428789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuldashev PV, Kreider W, Sapozhnikov OA, Farr N, Partanen A, Bailey MR, et al., “Characterization of nonlinear ultrasound fields of 2D therapeutic
arrays,” IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium : [proceedings]. IEEE International Ultrasonics
Symposium, vol. 2012, pp. 1–4,
2012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4507577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26203345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Treeby BE, Jaros J, Rendell AP, and Cox BT, “Modeling nonlinear ultrasound propagation in heterogeneous media with power law absorption using a
k-space pseudospectral method,” The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, vol.
131, pp. 4324–4336, 2012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22712907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Bigelow TA, and Riesberg GM, “Impact of preconditioning pulse on lesion formation during high-intensity focused ultrasound
histotripsy,” Ultrasound in Medicine &amp; Biology, vol. 38, pp.
1918–1929, 2012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22929656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Bigelow TA, and Whitley EM, “Assessment of ultrasound histotripsy–induced damage toex vivo porcine
muscle,” Journal of Ultra-sound in Medicine, vol. 32, pp.
69–82, 2013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23269712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
