<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30521191</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK534770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542">Postpartum Cardiomyopathy</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mubarik</LastName><ForeName>Ateeq</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oak hill hospital</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chippa</LastName><ForeName>Venu</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Indiana university</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iqbal</LastName><ForeName>Arshad Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oak Hill Hospital, Brooksville, FL</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Postpartum cardiomyopathy is a rare form of congestive heart failure of unknown etiology. Heart failure in peripartum period was first described in 1849. The current diagnostic criteria for peripartum cardiomyopathy include1. Cardiac failure in a previously healthy woman in the last month of pregnancy or within 5 months of delivery.2. Absence of a determinable etiology for the cardiac failure.3. Absence of demonstrable cardiac disease prior to last month of pregnancy.4. Echocardiographic evidence of diminished left ventricular systolic function. Its incidence and prevalence are highly variable depending on the race and geographic regions. Its clinical outcome is also diverse from complete recovery to death. Postpartum cardiomyopathy is a diagnosis of exclusion. </AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s13">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s14">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27542" sec="article-27542.s15">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Brar SS, Khan SS, Sandhu GK, Jorgensen MB, Parikh N, Hsu JW, Shen AY. Incidence, mortality, and racial differences in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2007 Jul 15;100(2):302-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17631087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntusi NB, Mayosi BM. Aetiology and risk factors of peripartum cardiomyopathy: a systematic review. Int J Cardiol. 2009 Jan 09;131(2):168-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18722678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolte D, Khera S, Aronow WS, Palaniswamy C, Mujib M, Ahn C, Jain D, Gass A, Ahmed A, Panza JA, Fonarow GC. Temporal trends in incidence and outcomes of peripartum cardiomyopathy in the United States: a nationwide population-based study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2014 Jun 04;3(3):e001056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4309108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24901108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isezuo SA, Abubakar SA. Epidemiologic profile of peripartum cardiomyopathy in a tertiary care hospital. Ethn Dis. 2007 Spring;17(2):228-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17682350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan JA, Qureshi A, Ramejo BB, Kamran A. Peripartum cardiomyopathy characteristics and outcome in a tertiary care hospital. J Pak Med Assoc. 2010 May;60(5):377-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20527612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandit V, Shetty S, Kumar A, Sagir A. Incidence and outcome of peripartum cardiomyopathy from a tertiary hospital in South India. Trop Doct. 2009 Jul;39(3):168-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mielniczuk LM, Williams K, Davis DR, Tang AS, Lemery R, Green MS, Gollob MH, Haddad H, Birnie DH. Frequency of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2006 Jun 15;97(12):1765-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16765131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farber PA, Glasgow LA. Viral myocarditis during pregnancy: encephalomyocarditis virus infection in mice. Am Heart J. 1970 Jul;80(1):96-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4316715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warraich RS, Sliwa K, Damasceno A, Carraway R, Sundrom B, Arif G, Essop R, Ansari A, Fett J, Yacoub M. Impact of pregnancy-related heart failure on humoral immunity: clinical relevance of G3-subclass immunoglobulins in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am Heart J. 2005 Aug;150(2):263-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16086928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampert MB, Weinert L, Hibbard J, Korcarz C, Lindheimer M, Lang RM. Contractile reserve in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy and recovered left ventricular function. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1997 Jan;176(1 Pt 1):189-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9024112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wencker D, Chandra M, Nguyen K, Miao W, Garantziotis S, Factor SM, Shirani J, Armstrong RC, Kitsis RN. A mechanistic role for cardiac myocyte apoptosis in heart failure. J Clin Invest. 2003 May;111(10):1497-504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC155051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12750399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drexler H. Changes in the peripheral circulation in heart failure. Curr Opin Cardiol. 1995 May;10(3):268-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7612976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cénac A, Simonoff M, Moretto P, Djibo A. A low plasma selenium is a risk factor for peripartum cardiomyopathy. A comparative study in Sahelian Africa. Int J Cardiol. 1992 Jul;36(1):57-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1428253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sliwa K, Damasceno A, Mayosi BM. Epidemiology and etiology of cardiomyopathy in Africa. Circulation. 2005 Dec 06;112(23):3577-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopp L, Haider B, Iffy L. Myocardial infarction postpartum in patients taking bromocriptine for the prevention of breast engorgement. Int J Cardiol. 1996 Dec 13;57(3):227-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9024910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampert MB, Lang RM. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am Heart J. 1995 Oct;130(4):860-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7572598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koide T, Saito Y, Sakamoto T, Murao S. Peripartal cardiomyopathy in Japan. A critical reappraisal of the concept. Jpn Heart J. 1972 Nov;13(6):488-501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4539938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bültmann BD, Klingel K, Näbauer M, Wallwiener D, Kandolf R. High prevalence of viral genomes and inflammation in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005 Aug;193(2):363-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demakis JG, Rahimtoola SH. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 1971 Nov;44(5):964-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4255967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bassett JM, Burks AH, Levine DH, Pinches RA, Visser GH. Maternal and fetal metabolic effects of prolonged ritodrine infusion. Obstet Gynecol. 1985 Dec;66(6):755-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3934609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbard JU, Lindheimer M, Lang RM. A modified definition for peripartum cardiomyopathy and prognosis based on echocardiography. Obstet Gynecol. 1999 Aug;94(2):311-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10432149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan A, Paré E, Shah S. Peripartum Cardiomyopathy: a Review for the Clinician. Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med. 2018 Sep 29;20(11):91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30269217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma GG, Fang Q, Wang FX. The effect of beta-blockers on mortality in patients with heart failure and atrial fibrillation: A meta-analysis of observational cohort and randomized controlled studies. Cardiol J. 2019;26(6):744-752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaddipati VC, Patel AA, Cohen AJ. The Use of a Novel Heart Failure Agent in the Treatment of Pregnancy-Associated Cardiomyopathy. Case Rep Cardiol. 2017;2017:9561405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5584348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28890834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sliwa K, Blauwet L, Tibazarwa K, Libhaber E, Smedema JP, Becker A, McMurray J, Yamac H, Labidi S, Struman I, Struhman I, Hilfiker-Kleiner D. Evaluation of bromocriptine in the treatment of acute severe peripartum cardiomyopathy: a proof-of-concept pilot study. Circulation. 2010 Apr 06;121(13):1465-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20308616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mouquet F, Mostefa Kara M, Lamblin N, Coulon C, Langlois S, Marquie C, de Groote P. Unexpected and rapid recovery of left ventricular function in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy: impact of cardiac resynchronization therapy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2012 May;14(5):526-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22447949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaméogo NV, Samadoulougou AK, Kagambèga LJ, Kologo KJ, Millogo GRC, Thiam A, Guenancia C, Zansonré P. Maternal and fetal prognosis of subsequent pregnancy in black African women with peripartum cardiomyopathy. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2018 Jun 18;18(1):119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6006934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29914408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dayoub EJ, Datwani H, Lewey J, Groeneveld PW. One-Year Cardiovascular Outcomes in Patients With Peripartum Cardiomyopathy. J Card Fail. 2018 Oct;24(10):711-715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30194024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honigberg MC, Sarma AA. Pregnancy Among Survivors of Childhood Cancer: Cardiovascular Considerations. Curr Treat Options Cardiovasc Med. 2018 Jun 19;20(7):54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29923132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30521191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
