<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30575651</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-233X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>133</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Obstetrics and gynecology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Obstet Gynecol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Peripartum Cardiomyopathy.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>167</StartPage>
          <EndPage>179</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>167-179</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/AOG.0000000000003011</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Peripartum cardiomyopathy is defined by left ventricular dysfunction and development of cardiac failure without a known cause and occurring in the final month of pregnancy and up to 5 months postpartum. Peripartum cardiomyopathy is an important and steadily increasing cause of pregnancy-associated morbidity and mortality. The incidence of peripartum cardiomyopathy in the United States has been estimated recently as 1 in 2,230 births and approximately 1 in 1,000 births worldwide. The etiopathogenesis of peripartum cardiomyopathy remains elusive; however, it is generally thought to be from a two-hit hypothesis in which an underlying cardiomyocyte protein mutation results in apoptosis mediated by vascular and hormonal actions. Clinical recognition is integral to the management of this disease, because there must be careful exclusion of alternative etiologies. Although there are no disease-specific therapies, management of peripartum cardiomyopathy is based on treatment of heart failure and its symptoms, repressing neurohormonal responses, and preventing long-term sequelae. Ventricular function recovery and rates of recurrence of peripartum cardiomyopathy vary by ethnicity and geography. Mortality rates associated with peripartum cardiomyopathy range from 3% to 40%, depending on geographic location. In this review, normal cardiovascular adaptations in pregnancy are summarized and current evidence-based clinical management of the disease is discussed.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cunningham</LastName>
            <ForeName>F Gary</ForeName>
            <Initials>FG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center at Dallas, Dallas, Texas.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Byrne</LastName>
            <ForeName>John J</ForeName>
            <Initials>JJ</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nelson</LastName>
            <ForeName>David B</ForeName>
            <Initials>DB</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Obstet Gynecol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0401101</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0029-7844</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009202" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiomyopathies</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018743" MajorTopicYN="Y">Perinatal Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058725" MajorTopicYN="N">Peripartum Period</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011249" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy Complications, Cardiovascular</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011644" MajorTopicYN="N">Puerperal Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018487" MajorTopicYN="N">Ventricular Dysfunction, Left</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30575651</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000003011</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006250-201901000-00023</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demakis JG, Rahimtoola SH, Sutton GC, Meadows WR, Szanto PB, Tobin JR, et al. Natural course of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circulation 1971;44:1053–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melvin JP Jr. Post-partal heart disease. Ann Intern Med 1947;27:596–609.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hull E, Hidden E. Postpartal heart failure. South Med J 1938;31:265–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearson GD, Veille JC, Rahimtoola SH, Hsia J, Oakley CM, Hosenpud JD, et al. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute and Office of Rare Diseases (National Institutes of Health) workshop recommendations and review. JAMA 2000;283:1183–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDorman MF, Declercq E, Cabral H, Morton C. Recent increases in the U.S. maternal mortality rate: disentangling trends from measurement issues. Obstet Gynecol 2016;128:447–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Creanga AA, Syverson C, Seed K, Callaghan WM. Pregnancy-related mortality in the United States, 2011-2013. Obstet Gynecol 2017;130:366–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Mebazaa A, Petrie MC, Maggioni AP, Regitz-Zagrosek V, et al. EURObservational Research Programme: a worldwide registry on peripartum cardiomyopathy (PPCM) in conjunction with the heart failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on PPCM. Eur J Heart Fail 2014;16:583–91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfeffer TJ, Hilfiker-Kleiner D. Pregnancy and heart disease: pregnancy-associated hypertension and peripartum cardiomyopathy. Curr Probl Cardiol 2018;43:364–88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fillmore SJ, Parry EH. The evolution of peripartal heart failure in Zaria, Nigeria. Some etiologic factors. Circulation 1977;56:1058–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lampert MB, Lang RM. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am Heart J 1995;130:860–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham FG, Pritchard JA, Hankins GD, Anderson PL, Lucas MJ, Armstrong KF. Peripartum heart failure: idiopathic cardiomyopathy or compounding cardiovascular events? Obstet Gynecol 1986;67:157–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mielniczuk LM, Williams L, Davis DR, Tang AS, Lemery R, Green MS, et al. Frequency of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol 2006;97:1765–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Haghikia A, Nonhoff J, Bauersachs J. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: current management and future perspectives. Eur Heart J 2015;36:1090–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark SL, Cotton DB, Lee W, Bishop C, Hill T, Southwick J, et al. Central hemodynamic assessment of normal term pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol 1989;161:1439–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson LL. Maternal cardiac disease: update for the clinician. Obstet Gynecol 2012;119:345–59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hibbard JU, Shroff SG, Cunningham FG. Cardiovascular alterations in normal and preeclamptic pregnancies. In: Taylor RN, Roberts JM, Cunningham FG, editors. Chesley's hypertensive disorders in pregnancy. 4th ed. Amsterdam (the Netherlands): Academic Press; 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clapp JF 3rd, Capeless E. Cardiovascular function before, during, and after the first and subsequent pregnancies. Am J Cardiol 1997;80:1469–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin RB, Nelson DB, Stewart R, Matulevicius S, McIntire DD, Cunningham FG. Impact of pregnancy on maternal cardiac atria. Am J Perinatol 2017;34:1097–101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ducas RA, Elliott JE, Melnyk SF, Premecz S, DaSilva M, Cleverly K, et al. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance in pregnancy: insights from the cardiac hemodynamic imaging and remodeling in pregnancy (CHIRP) study. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson 2014;16:1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart RD, Nelson DB, Matulevicius SA, Morgan JL, McIntire DD, Drazner MH, et al. Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging to assess the impact of maternal habitus on cardiac remodeling during pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2016;214:640.e1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savu O, Jurcuţ R, Guişcă S, van Mieghem T, Gussi I, Popescu BA, et al. Morphological and functional adaptation of the maternal heart during pregnancy. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging 2012;5:289–97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arany Z, Elkayam U. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circulation 2016;133:1397–409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkayam U. Clinical characteristics of peripartum cardiomyopathy in the United States: diagnosis, prognosis, and management. J Am Coll Cardiol 2011;58:659–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gentry MB, Dias JK, Luis A, Patel R, Thornton J, Reed GL. African-American women have a higher risk for developing peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol 2010;55:654–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindley KJ, Conner SN, Cahill AG, Novak E, Mann DL. Impact of preeclampsia on clinical and functional outcomes in women with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circ Heart Fail 2017;10. pii: e003797.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolte D, Khera S, Aronow WS, Palaniswamy C, Mujib M, Ahn C, et al. Temporal trends in incidence and outcomes of peripartum cardiomyopathy in the United States: a nationwide population-based study. J Am Heart Assoc 2014;3:e001056.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bello N, Rendon ISH, Arany Z. The relationship between preeclampsia and peripartum cardiomyopathy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol 2013;62:1715–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bultmann BD, Klingel K, Nabauer M, Wallwiener D, Kandolf R. High prevalence of viral genomes and inflammation in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2005;193:363–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Kaminski K, Podewski E, Bonda T, Schaefer A, Sliwa K, et al. A cathepsin D-cleaved 16 kDa form of prolactin mediates postpartum cardiomyopathy. Cell 2007;128:589–600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halkein J, Tabruyn SP, Ricke-Hoch M, Haghikia A, Nguyen NQ, Scherr M, et al. MicroRNA-146a is a therapeutic target and biomarker for peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Clin Invest 2013;123:2143–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morales A, Painter T, Li R, Siegfried JD, Li D, Norton N, et al. Rare variant mutations in pregnancy-associated or peripartum cardiomyopathy. Circulation 2010;121:2176–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Haghikia A, Masuko D, Nonhoff J, Held D, Libhaber E, et al. Outcome of subsequent pregnancies in patients with a history of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail 2017;19:1723–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patten IS, Rana S, Shahul S, Rowe GC, Jang C, Liu L, et al. Cardiac angiogenic imbalance leads to peripartum cardiomyopathy. Nature 2012;485:333–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maynard SE, Venkatesha S, Thadhani R, Karumanchi SA. Soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase 1 and endothelial dysfunction in the pathogenesis of preeclampsia. Pediatr Res 2005;57:1R–7R.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham FG. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: we’ve come a long way but…. Obstet Gynecol 2012;120:992–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bello NA, Arany Z. Molecular mechanisms of peripartum cardiomyopathy: a vascular/hormonal hypothesis. Trends Cardiovasc Med 2015;25:499–504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hibbard JU, Lindheimer M, Lang RM. A modified definition for peripartum cardiomyopathy and prognosis based on echocardiography. Obstet Gynecol 1999;94:311–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Mebazza A, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Petrie MC, Maggioni AP, Laroche C, et al. Clinical characteristics of patients from the worldwide registry on peripartum cardiomyopathy (PPCM): EURObservational Research Programme in conjunction with the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Study Group on PPCM. Eur J Heart Fail 2017;19:1131–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Resnik JL, Hong C, Resnik R, Kazanegra R, Beede J, Bhalla V, et al. Evaluation of B-type natriuretic peptide (BNP) levels in normal and preeclamptic women. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2005;193:450–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burlingame JM, Yamasato K, Ahn HJ, Seto T, Tang WHW. B-type natriuretic peptide and echocardiography reflect volume changes during pregnancy. J Perinat Med 2017;45:577–83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewey J, Haythe J. Cardiomyopathy in pregnancy. Semin Perinat 2014;38:309–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora NP, Mohamad T, Mahajan N, Danrad R, Kottam A, Li T, et al. Cardiac magnetic resonance imaging in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Am J Med Sci 2014;347:112–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schelbert EB, Elkayam U, Cooper LT, Givertz MM, Alexis JD, Briller J, et al. Myocardial damage detected by late gadolinium enhancement cardiac magnetic resonance is uncommon in peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Am Heart Assoc 2017;3. pii: e005472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel P, Roy A, Javid R, Dalton JA. A contemporary review of peripartum cardiomyopathy. Clin Med 2017;17:316–21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkayam U, Jalnapurkar S, Barakat M. Peripartum cardiomyopathy. Cardiol Clin 2012;30:435–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruys TP, Roos-Hesselink JW, Pijuan-Domènech A, Vasario E, Gaisin IR, Iung B, et al. Is a planned caesarean section in women with cardiac disease beneficial? Heart 2015;101:530–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ituk US, Habib AS, Polin CM, Allen TK. Anesthetic management and outcomes of parturients with dilated cardiomyopathy in an academic centre. Can J Anaesth 2015;62:278–88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapoor PM, Goyal S, Irpachi K, Smita B. Importance of transesophageal echocardiography in peripartum cardiomyopathy undergoing lower section cesarean section under regional anesthesia. J Anaesthesiol Clin Pharmacol 2014;30:427–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sepehrvand N, Ezekowitz JA. Oxygen therapy in patients with acute heart failure: friend or foe? JACC Heart Fail 2016;4:783–90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohler ER, Sorensen LC, Ghali JK, Schocken DD, Willis PW, Bowers JA, et al. Role of cytokines in the mechanism of action of amlodipine: the PRAISE Heart Failure Trial. Prospective Randomized Amlodipine Survival Evaluation. J Am Coll Cardiol 1997;30:35–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Skudicky D, Bergemann A, Candy G, Puren A, Sareli P. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: analysis of clinical outcome, left ventricular function, plasma levels of cytokines and Fas/APO-1. J Am Coll Cardiol 2000;35:701–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pyatt JR, Dubey G. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: current understanding, comprehensive management review and new developments. Postgrad Med J 2011;87:34–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goland S, Modi K, Bitar F, Janmohamed M, Mirocha JM, Czer LS, et al. Clinical profile and predictors of complications in peripartum cardiomyopathy. J Card Fail 2009;15:645–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasmussen K, Brunischolz K, Budge D, Horne BD, Alharethi R, Folsom J, et al. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: post-transplant outcomes from the United Network for Organ Sharing Database. J Heart Lung Transplant 2012;31:180–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forster O, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Ansara AA, Sundstrom JB, Libhaber E, Tshani W, et al. Reversal of IFN-gamma, oxLDL and prolactin serum levels correlate with clinical improvement in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail 2008;10:861–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arany Z. Understanding peripartum cardiomyopathy. Annu Rev Med 2018;69:165–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sliwa K, Blauwet L, Tibazarwa K, Libhaber E, Smedema JP, Becker A, et al. Evaluation of bromocriptine in the treatment of acute severe peripartum cardiomyopathy: a proof-of-concept pilot study. Circulation 2010;121:1465–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Haghikia A, Berliner D, Vogel-Claussen J, Schwab J, Franke A, et al. Bromocriptine for the treatment of peripartum cardiomyopathy: a multicentre randomized study. Eur Heart J 2017;38:2671–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis KM, Jatlaoui TC, Tepper NK, Zapata LB, Horton LG, Jamieson DJ, et al. U.S. selected practice recommendations for contraceptive use, 2016. MMWR Recomm Rep 2016;65:1–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkayam U, Tummala PP, Rao K, Akhter MW, Karaalp IS, Wani OR, et al. Maternal and fetal outcomes of subsequent pregnancies in women with peripartum cardiomyopathy [published erratum appears in N Engl J Med 2001;345:552]. N Engl J Med 2001;344:1567–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Codsi E, Rose CH, Blauwet LA. Subsequent pregnancy outcomes in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Obstet Gynecol 2018;131:322–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Modi KA, Illum S, Jariatul K, Caldito G, Reddy PC. Poor outcome in indigent patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy in the United States. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2009;201:171.e1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamara DM, Elkayam U, Alharethi R, Damp J, Hsich E, Ewald G, et al. IPAC Investigators. Clinical outcomes for peripartum cardiomyopathy in North America: results of the IPAC study (Investigations of Pregnancy-Associated Cardiomyopathy). J Am Coll Cardiol 2015;66:905–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irizarry OC, Levine LD, Lewey J, Boyer T, Riis V, Elovitz MA, et al. Comparison of clinical characteristics and outcomes of peripartum cardiomyopathy between African American and non-African American women. JAMA Cardiol 2017;2:1256–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duran N, Günes H, Duran I, Biteker M, Ozkan M. Predictors of prognosis in patients with peripartum cardiomyopathy. Int J Gynaecol Obstet 2008;101:137–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desai D, Moodley J, Naidoo D. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: experience at king Edward VIII Hospital, Durban, South Africa and a review of the literature. Trop Doct 1995;25:118–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harper MA, Meyer RE, Berg CJ. Peripartum cardiomyopathy: population-based birth prevalence and 7-year mortality. Obstet Gynecol 2012;120:1013–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
