<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">30657166</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1467-8624</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>91</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Child development</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Child Dev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of Literacy Interventions on Reading Skills in Low- and Middle-Income Countries: A Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>638</StartPage>
          <EndPage>660</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>638-660</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cdev.13204</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Reading skills are foundational for daily lives, academic achievement, and careers. In this study, we systematically reviewed literacy interventions in low- and middle-income countries, and estimated their effects on children's reading skills using a meta-analytic approach. A total of 67 studies (N = 213,464) from 32 countries found in various databases (e.g., PsycINFO, ERIC) and sources (e.g., United States Agency for International Development) met our inclusion criteria. The results revealed an overall effect of .30 across various literacy outcomes. Effects varied for different outcomes, such that largest effects were found in emergent literacy skills (e.g., .40) and the smallest effects in reading comprehension (.25) and oral language skills (.20). Effects also varied as a function of other features such as teacher training support.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2019 Society for Research in Child Development.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Young-Suk G</ForeName>
            <Initials>YG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4328-3843</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of California, Irvine.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hansol</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6912-7128</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Korea Military Academy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zuilkowski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephanie S</ForeName>
            <Initials>SS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Florida State University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Child Dev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372725</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0009-3920</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003906" MajorTopicYN="N">Developing Countries</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004493" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000067010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Literacy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011932" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reading</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657166</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cdev.13204</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Abeberese, A. B., Kumler, T. J., &amp; Linden, L. L. (2014). Improving reading skills by encouraging children to read in school: A randomized evaluation of the Sa Aklat Sisikat reading program in the Philippines. Journal of Human Resources, 49, 611-633. https://doi.org/10.3368/jhr.49.3.611</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Abrami, P. C., Wade, C. A., Lysenko, L., Marsh, J., &amp; Gioko, A. (2016). Using educational technology to develop early literacy skills in Sub-Saharan Africa. Education and Information Technologies, 21, 945-964. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10639-014-9362-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams, M. (1990). Beginning to read: Thinking and learning about print. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akyeampong, K., Lussier, K., Pryor, J., &amp; Westbrook, J. (2013). Improving teaching and learning of basic maths and reading in Africa: Does teacher preparation count? International Journal of Educational Development, 33, 272-282. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijedudev.2012.09.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alonzo, C. N., Yeomans-Maldonado, C., Murphy, K. A., Bevens, B.; LARRC. (2016). Predicting second grade listening comprehension using prekindergarten measures. Topics in Language Disorders, 36, 3123-3333. https://doi.org/10.1097/TLD.0000000000000102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Alvarez-Marinelli, H., Blanco, M., Lara-Alecio, R., Irby, B. J., Tong, F., Stanley, K., &amp; Fan, Y. (2016). Computer assisted English language learning in Costa Rican elementary schools: An experimental study. Computer Assisted Language Learning, 29, 103-126. https://doi.org/10.1080/09588221.2014.903977</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Research Institute (2014). Education support program: Implementation, and initial results of remedial reading activities in Egypt. Available in https://www.air.org/sites/default/files/downloads/report/ESP%20Remedial%20Reading%20Report%20Egypt_July%202014.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Azami, S., &amp; Pava, C. (2014). Literacy boost Afghanistan: Year 1 endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Badiable, A., Guajardo, J., Fermin, R., &amp; Robis, E. J. C. (2013). Literacy boost Metro Manila: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ball, J. (2011). Enhancing learning of children from diverse language backgrounds: Mother tongue-based bilingual or multilingual education in early childhood and early primary school years. Victoria, BC: Early Childhood Development Intercultural Partnerships, University of Victoria.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee, A. V., Banerji, R., Duflo, E., Glennerster, R., &amp; Khemani, S. (2010). Pitfalls of participatory programs: Evidence from a randomized evaluation in education in India. American Economic Journal: Economic Policy, 2(1), 1-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Banerjee, A., Cole, S., Duflo, E., &amp; Linden, L. (2007). Remedying education: Evidence from two randomized experiments in India. Quarterly Journal of Economics, 122, 1235-1264. https://doi.org/10.1162/qjec.122.3.1235</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Banerji, R., Berry, J., &amp; Shotland, M. (2014). The impact of mother literacy and participation programs on child learning: Evidence from a randomized evaluation in India. Cambridge, MA: Abdul Latif Jameel Poverty Action Lab (J-PAL).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnes, M. A., Ahmed, Y., Barth, A., &amp; Francis, D. J. (2015). The relation of knowledge-text integration processes and reading comprehension in 7th- to 12th-grade students. Scientific Studies of Reading, 19, 253-272. https://doi.org/10.1080/10888438.2015.1022650</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Bekman, S., Aksu-Koç, A., &amp; Erguvanlı-Taylan, E. (2011). Effectiveness of an intervention program for six-year-olds: A summer-school model. European Early Childhood Education Research Journal, 19, 409-431. https://doi.org/10.1080/1350293X.2011.623508</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benavot, A., &amp; Gad, L. (2004). Actual instructional time in African primary schools: Factors that reduce school quality in developing countries. Prospects, 34, 291-310. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11125-004-5309-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borenstein, M., Hedges, L., Higgins, J., &amp; Rothstein, H. (2009). Introduction to meta-analysis. Chichester, UK: Wiley. https://doi.org/10.1002/9780470743386</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bracken, S. S., &amp; Fischel, J. E. (2008). Family reading behavior and early literacy skills in preschool children from low-income backgrounds. Early Education &amp; Development, 19(1), 45-67. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409280701838835</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Brombacher, A., Stern, J., Nordstrum, L., Cummiskey, C., &amp; Mulcahy-Dunn, A. (2014). Education data for decision making (EdData II): National early grade literacy and numeracy survey-Jordan. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronfenbrenner, U. (1979). The Ecology of Human Development: Experiments by Nature and Design. Cambridge, Massachusetts: Harvard University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Brown, C. (2013). Literacy boost Indonesia: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Bulat, J., Brombacher, A., Slade, T., Iriondo-Perez, J., Kelly, M., &amp; Edwards, S. (2014). PAQUED: DRC Projet d'Amélioration de la Qualité de l'Education (PAQUED): Endline Report of Early Grade Reading Assessment (EGRA) and early grade mathematics assessment (EGMA). Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bunyi, G. W., Wangia, J., Magoma, C. M., Limboro, C. M., &amp; Akyeampong, K. (2011). Learning to teach reading and mathematics and influences on practice: A study of teacher education in Kenya. Brighton, UK: University of Sussex, Centre for International Education.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bus, A. G., van IJzendorn, M. H., &amp; Pellegrini, A. D. (1995). Joint book reading makes for success in learning to read: A meta-analysis on intergenerational transmission of literacy. Review of Educational Research, 65, 1-21. https://doi.org/10.3102/00346543065001001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cain, K., Oakhill, J., &amp; Bryant, P. (2004). Children's reading comprehension ability: Concurrent prediction by working memory, verbal ability, and component skills. Journal of Educational Psychology, 96, 31-42. https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.96.1.31</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chansa-Kabali, T., Serpell, R., &amp; Lyytinen, H. (2014). Contextual analysis of home environment factors influencing the acquisition of early reading skills in Zambian families. Journal of Psychology in Africa, 24, 410-419. https://doi.org/10.1080/14330237.2014.997008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christenson, S. L., &amp; Thurlow, M. L. (2004). School dropouts: Prevention, considerations, interventions, and challenges. Current Directions in Psychological Science, 13, 36-39. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0963-7214.2004.01301010.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins, P., &amp; Messaoud-Galusi, S. (2012). Student performance on the Early Grade Reading Assessment (EGRA) in Yemen. Prepared for USAID by RTI International under the Education Data for Decision Making (EdData II) Project, Task Order No. EHC-E-07-04- 00004-00. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conn, K. M. (2017). Identifying effective education interventions in Sub-Saharan Africa: A meta-analysis of impact evaluations. Review of Educational Research, 87, 863-898. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654317712025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Courtney, J., &amp; Gravelle, M. (2014). What makes the difference? An analysis of a reading intervention programme implemented in rural schools in Cambodia. Compare: A Journal of Comparative and International Education, 44, 416-434. https://doi.org/10.1080/03057925.2013.765287</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cromley, J. G., &amp; Azevedo, R. (2007). Testing and refining the direct and inferential mediation model of reading comprehension. Journal of Educational Psychology, 99, 311-325. https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.99.2.311</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Crouch, L., Korda, M., &amp; Mumo, D. (2009). Improvements in reading skills in Kenya: An experiment in the Malindi District. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cummins, J. (1979). Linguistic interdependence and the educational development of bilingual children. Review of Educational Research, 49, 222-251. https://doi.org/10.3102/00346543049002222</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cummins, J. (1984). Wanted: A theoretical framework for relating language proficiency to academic achievement among bilingual students. In C. Rivera (Ed.), Language proficiency and academic achievement (pp. 2-9). Clevedon, UK: Multilingual Matters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniel, S. S., Walsh, A. K., Goldston, D. B., Arnold, E. M., Reboussin, B. A., &amp; Wood, F. B. (2006). Suisidality, school dropout, and reading problems among adolescents. Journal of Learning Disabilities, 39, 507-514. https://doi.org/10.1177/00222194060390060301</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Dixon, P., Schagen, I., &amp; Seedhouse, P. (2011). The impact of an intervention on children's reading and spelling ability in low-income schools in India. School Effectiveness and School Improvement, 22, 461-482. https://doi.org/10.1080/09243453.2011.625125</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowd, A. J., &amp; Friedlander, E. W. (2016). Home literacy environment data facilitate all children reading. UNESCO Institute of Statistics, understanding what works in oral reading assessments (pp. 22-29). Montreal, QC: UNESCO.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Dowd, A. J., &amp; Mabeti, F. (2011). Literacy boost Malawi: Year 2 report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubeck, M. M., Jukes, M. C. H., Brooker, S. J., Drake, T. L., &amp; Inyega, H. N. (2015). Designing a program of teacher professional development to support beginning reading acquisition in coastal Kenya. International Journal of Educational Development, 41, 88-96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijedudev.2014.11.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubeck, M. M., Jukes, M. C. H., &amp; Okello, G. (2012). Early primary literacy instruction in Kenya. Comparative Education Review, 56, 48-68. https://doi.org/10.1086/660693</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Dunlop, M. (2015). Literacy boost Metro Manila: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duval, S., &amp; Tweedie, R. (2000). Trim and fill: A simple funnel-plot-based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis. Biometrics, 56(2), 455-463. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.0006-341X.2000.00455.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dynia, J. M., Lawton, K., Logan, J. A. R., &amp; Justice, L. M. (2014). Comparing emergent-literacy skills and home-literacy environment of children with autism and their peers. Topics in Early Childhood Special Education, 34, 142-153. https://doi.org/10.1177/0271121414536784</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Education Development Center. (2014a). 2014 final evaluation report: Teachers’ literacy knowledge, instructional practices, and their students’ reading performance in PQUED-supported schools in the Democratic Republic of The Democratic Republic of Congo. Washington, DC: USAID.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Education Development Center. (2014b). When teachers understand what they're doing, students learn: Evidence from EDC's reading program in the Democratic Republic of Congo. Waltham, MA: EDC Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Education Development Center. (2015). Continued reading success in the DRC: Projet d'Amélioration de la Qualité de l'Education (PAQUED). Waltham, MA: EDC Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Education Development Center. (2016). USAID/Philippines Basa Pilipinas program. Final outcome evaluation report: 2013-2016. Waltham, MA: EDC Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egger, M., Smith, G. D., Schneider, M., &amp; Minder, C. (1997). Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. British Medical Journal, 315, 629-634. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elleman, A. M., Lindo, E. J., Morphy, P., &amp; Compton, D. L. (2009). The impact of vocabulary instruction on passage-level comprehension of school-age children: A meta-analysis. Journal of Research on Educational Effectiveness, 2, 1-44. https://doi.org/10.1080/19345740802539200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Ergül, C., Akoğlu, G., Sarıca, A. D., Karaman, G., Tufan, M., Bahap-Kudret, Z., &amp; Deniz, Z. (2016). An adapted dialogic reading program for Turkish kindergarteners from low socio-economic backgrounds. Journal of Education and Training Studies, 4, 179-194. https://doi.org/10.11114/jets.v4i7.1565</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florit, E., Roch, M., Altoè, G., &amp; Levorato, M. C. (2009). Listening comprehension in preschoolers: The role of memory. British Journal of Developmental Psychology, 27, 935-951. https://doi.org/10.1348/026151008X397189</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florit, E., Roch, M., &amp; Levorato, M. C. (2014). Listening text comprehension in preschoolers: A longitudinal study on the role of semantic components. Reading and Writing: An Interdisciplinary Journal, 27, 793-817. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11145-013-9464-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francis, D. J., Shaywitz, S. E., Stuebing, K. K., Shaywitz, B. A., &amp; Fletcher, J. M. (1996). Developmental lag versus deficit models of reading disability: A longitudinal, individual grown curves analysis. Journal of Educational Psychology, 88, 3-17. https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.88.1.3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Friedland, A., Gilman, M., Johnson, M., &amp; Demeke, A. (2017). Does reading-while-listening enhance students’ reading fluency? Preliminary results from school experiments in rural Uganda. Journal of Education and Practice, 8, 82-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Friedlander, E., &amp; Goldenberg, C. (Eds.). (2016). Literacy boost in Rwanda: Impact evaluation of a 2-year randomized control trial. Stanford, CA: Stanford University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Friedlander, E., Hordofa, T., Diyana, F., Hassen, S., Mohammed, O., &amp; Dowd, A. J. (2012). Literacy boost Dendi, Ethiopia: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuchs, L. S., Fuchs, D., Hosp, M. K., &amp; Jenkins, J. R. (2001). Oral reading fluency as an indicator of reading competence: A theoretical, empirical, and historical analysis. Scientific Studies of Reading, 5, 239-256. https://doi.org/10.1207/S1532799XSSR0503_3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gamero Burón, C., &amp; Lassibille, G. (2016). Job satisfaction among primary school personnel in Madagascar. Journal of Development Studies, 52, 1628-1646. https://doi.org/10.1080/00220388.2016.1187726</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glewwe, P., Kremer, M., &amp; Moulin, S. (2009). Many children left behind? Textbooks and test scores in Kenya. American Economic Journal: Applied Economics, 1, 112-135. https://doi.org/10.1257/app.1.1.112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Goodman, G., &amp; Dent, V. F. (2017). Studying the effectiveness of the storytelling/story-acting (STSA) play intervention on Ugandan preschoolers’ emergent literacy, oral language, and theory of mind in two rural Ugandan community libraries. In R. L. Steen (Ed.), Emerging research in play therapy, child counseling, and consultation (pp. 182-213). Hershey, PA: IGI Global. https://doi.org/10.4018/APMHBS</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gove, A., &amp; Cvelich, P. (2011). Early reading: Igniting education for all. A report by the early grade learning community of practice (Rev. ed.). Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham, J., &amp; Kelly, S. (2018). How effective are early grade reading interventions?: A review of the evidence (Policy research working paper; No. 8292). Washington, DC: World Bank.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Guajardo, J., Hossain, M., Nath, B. K. D., &amp; Dowd, A. J. (2013). Literacy boost Bangladesh: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Guajardo, J., Night, C. S., Heijnen, E., Komakech, C., P'kech, E. A., Odwong, O. D., … Dowd, A. J. (2012). Literacy boost Uganda: Midline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanushek, E. A., &amp; Woesman, L. (2012). Do better schools lead to more growth? Cognitive skills, economic outcomes, and causation. Journal of Economic Growth, 17, 267-321. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10887-012-9081-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*He, F., Linden, L. L., &amp; MacLeod, M. (2008). How to teach English in India: Testing the relative productivity of instruction methods with Pratham English Language Education Program. Unpublished manuscript, Columbia University, New York, NY.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*He, F., Linden, L. L., &amp; MacLeod, M. (2009). A better way to teach children to read? Evidence from a randomized controlled trial. Unpublished working paper, Columbia University, New York, NY.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedges, L. V. (1981). Distribution theory for Glass's estimator of effect size and related estimators. Journal of Educational Statistic, 6, 107-128. https://doi.org/10.3102/10769986006002107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez, D. J. (2011). Double jeopardy: How third-grade reading skills and poverty influence high school graduation. The Annie E. Casey Foundation.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill, C. J., Bloom, H. S., Black, A. R., &amp; Lipsey, M. W. (2008). Empirical benchmarks for interpreting effect sizes in research. Child Development Perspectives, 2, 172-177. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1750-8606.2008.00061.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Hollingsworth, S., &amp; Gains, P. (2009). Integrated education program. The systematic method for reading success (SMRS) in South Africa: A literacy intervention between EGRA pre- and post-assessments. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hox, J. J., Moerbeek, M., &amp; van de Schoot, R. (2010). Multilevel analysis: Techniques and applications. New York, NY: Routledge. https://doi.org/10.4324/9780203852279</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenkins, J. R., Fuchs, L. S., van den Broek, P., Espin, C., &amp; Deno, S. L. (2003). Sources of individual differences in reading comprehension and reading fluency. Journal of Educational Psychology, 95, 719-729. https://doi.org/10.1037/0022-0663.95.4.719</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Jere-Folotiya, J., Chansa-Kabali, T., Munachaka, J. C., Sampa, F., Yalukanda, C., Westerholm, J., … Lyytinen, H. (2014). The effect of using a mobile literacy game to improve literacy levels of grade one students in Zambian schools. Educational Technology Research and Development, 62, 417-436. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11423-014-9342-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Jonason, C., Guajardo, F., Nath, B. D., &amp; Hossain, M. (2014). Literacy &amp; numeracy boost Bangladesh: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Jonason, C., &amp; Solomon, S. (2014). Literacy boost Somali Region, Ethiopia: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Karki, V., &amp; Dowd, A. J. (2013). Literacy boost Kapilvastu, Nepal: Year 1 report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kendeou, P., Bohn-Gettler, C. M., White, M. J., &amp; van den Broek, P. (2008). Children's inference generation across different media. Journal of Research in Reading, 31, 259-272. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-9817.2008.00370.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y.-S. G. (2016). Direct and mediated effects of language and cognitive skills on comprehension or oral narrative texts (listening comprehension) for children. Journal of Experimental Child Psychology, 141, 101-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jecp.2015.08.003doi:10.1016/j.jecp.2015.08.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y.-S. G. (2017). Why the simple view of reading is not simplistic: Unpacking the simple view of reading using a direct and indirect effect model of reading (DIER). Scientific Studies of Reading, 21, 310-333. https://doi.org/10.1080/10888438.2017.1291643</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y.-S. G., Boyle, H., Zuilkowski, S., &amp; Nakamura, P. (2016). The landscape report on early grade literacy skills. Washington, DC: United States Agency for International Development (USAID). Retrieved from https://globalreadingnetwork.net/publications-and-research/landscape-report-early-grade-literacy</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y.-S., Petscher, Y., Schatschneider, C., &amp; Foorman, B. (2010). Does growth rate in oral reading fluency matter in predicting reading comprehension? Journal of Educational Psychology, 102, 652-667. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0019643</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y.-S. G., &amp; Wagner, R. K. (2015). Text (oral) reading fluency as a construct in reading development: An investigation of its mediating role for children from Grades 1 to 4. Scientific Studies of Reading, 19, 224-242. https://doi.org/10.1080/10888438.2015.1007375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*King, S., Korda, M., Nordstrum, L., &amp; Edwards, S. (2015). Liberia teacher training program: Endline assessment of the impact of early grade reading and mathematics interventions in Liberia. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher, D, Liberati, A, Tetzlaff, J, &amp; Altman, D. G., the PRISMA Group (2009). Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 6(7): e1000097. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1000097</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Lai, F., Zhang, L., Qu, Q., Hu, X., Shi, Y., Boswell, M., &amp; Rozelle, S. (2012). Does computer-assisted learning improve learning outcomes? Evidence from a randomized experiment in public schools in rural minority areas in Qinghai (Working Paper No. 237). Stanford, CA: Rural Education Action Project.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, H., Warschauer, M., &amp; Lee, J. H. (in press). The effects of corpus use on second language vocabulary learning: A multilevel meta-analysis. Applied Linguistics. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1093/applin/amy012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, J., &amp; Zuilkowski, S. S. (2015). “Making do”: Teachers’ coping strategies for dealing with textbook shortages in urban Zambia. Teaching and Teacher Education, 48, 117-128. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2015.02.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Leer, J., &amp; Navaratnam, S. (2016). Literacy boost: Sri Lanka: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lepola, J., Lynch, J., Laakkonen, E., Silvén, M., &amp; Niemi, P. (2012). The role of inference making and other language skills in the development of narrative listening comprehension in 4- to 6-year old children. Reading Research Quarterly, 47, 259-282. https://doi.org/10.1002/rrq.020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lounkaew, K. (2013). Explaining urban-rural differences in educational achievement in Thailand: Evidence from PISA literacy data. Economics of Education Review, 37, 213-225. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.econedurev.2013.09.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Lucas, A. M., McEwan, P. J., Ngware, M., &amp; Oketch, M. (2014). improving early-grade literacy in east Africa: Experimental evidence from Kenya and Uganda. Journal of Policy Analysis and Management, 33, 950-976. https://doi.org/10.1002/pam.21782</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Macdonald, K., Brinkman, S., Jarvie, W., Machuca-Sierra, M., McDonall, K., Messaoud-Galusi, S., … Vu, B. T. (2017). Pedagogy versus school readiness: The impact of a randomized reading instruction intervention and community-based playgroup intervention on early grade reading outcomes in Tonga. Washington, DC: World Bank.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Malik, S. S., Balfour, B. J. V., Nzabonimpa, J. P., Cozzolino, S., Dib, G., &amp; Dowd, A. J. (2015). Endline evaluation of Rwandan children's book initiative (RCBI). Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McEwan, P. J. (1999). Recruitment of rural teachers in developing countries: An economic analysis. Teaching and Teacher Education, 15, 849-859. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0742-051X(99)00025-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McEwan, P. J. (2015). Improving learning in primary schools of developing countries: A meta-analysis of randomized experiments. Review of Educational Research, 85, 353-394. https://doi.org/10.3102/0034654314553127</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Moulvi, Z. F., &amp; Pava, C. (2014). Literacy boost Quetta, Pakistan: Year 2 report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Moulvi, Z. F., Pisani, L., Dowd, A. J., Burki, E., &amp; Mithani, S. S. (2014). PEPAS literacy boost Pakistan: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulkeen, A., &amp; Chen, D. (2008). Teachers for rural schools: Experiences in Lesotho, Malawi, Mozambique, Tanzania, and Uganda. Washington, DC: World Bank.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Mungoi, D., Mandlante, N., Nhatuve, I., Mahangue, D., Fonseca, J., &amp; Dowd, A. J. (2010). Endline report of early literacy among pre-school and primary school children in Gaza Province, Mozambique. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Murad, C. R., &amp; Topping, K. J. (2000). Parents as reading tutors for first graders in Brazil. School Psychology International, 21, 152-171. https://doi.org/10.1177/0143034300212003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Nagarajan, G., Carneiro, P., Chiappetta, M., Fuller, B., Gonzales, E., Sinclair, B., &amp; Mapondera, A. (2015). Midline report: Impact evaluation of the early grade reading activity. Lilongwe, Malawi: USAID.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Early Literacy Panel. (2008). Developing early literacy: Report of the National Early Literacy Panel. Washington, DC: National Institute for Family Literacy.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. (2000). Teaching children to read: An evidence based assessment of the scientific research literature on reading and its implications for reading instruction. Washington, DC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*NORC at the University of Chicago. (2017). Performance and impact evaluation of the USAID/Uganda school health and reading program. Kampala, Uganda: USAID.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oakhill, J. V., Cain, K., &amp; Bryant, P. E. (2003). The dissociation of word reading and text comprehension: Evidence from component skills. Language and Cognitive Processes, 18, 443-468. https://doi.org/10.1080/01690960344000008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Opel, A., Ameer, S. S., &amp; Aboud, F. E. (2009). The effect of preschool dialogic reading on vocabulary among rural Bangladeshi children. International Journal of Educational Research, 48(1), 12-20. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijer.2009.02.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paris, A. H., &amp; Paris, S. G. (2003). Assessing narrative comprehension in young children. Reading Research Quarterly, 38, 36-76. https://doi.org/10.1598/RRQ.38.1.3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perfetti, C., Landi, N., &amp; Oakhill, J. (2005). The acquisition of reading comprehension skill. In M. J. Snowling &amp; C. Hulme (Eds.), The science of reading: A handbook (pp. 227-247). Oxford, UK: Blackwell. https://doi.org/10.1002/9780470757642</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perfetti, C., &amp; Stafura, J. (2014). Word knowledge in a theory of reading comprehension. Scientific Studies of Reading, 18, 22-37. https://doi.org/10.1080/10888438.2013.827687</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Pickard, M. (2013). Save the Children international basic education program: Tiana project endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Pinto, C. (2010). Literacy boost Kailali, Nepal: Year 1 report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piper, B., &amp; Korda, M. (2011). EGRA Plus: Liberia. Program evaluation report. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Piper, B., &amp; Kwayumba, D. (2014). USAID/Kenya primary math and reading (PRIMR) initiative: Kisumu information and communication technology (ICT) intervention endline report. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piper, B., Zuilkowski, S. S., Kwayumba, D., &amp; Strigel, C. (2016). Does technology improve reading outcomes? Comparing the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of ICT interventions for early grade reading in Kenya. International Journal of Educational Development, 49, 204-214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piper, B., Zuilkowski, S. S., &amp; Ong'ele, S. (2016). Implementing mother tongue instruction in the real world: Results from a medium-scale randomized controlled trial in Kenya. Comparative Education Review, 60, 776-807. https://doi.org/10.1086/688493</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Pisani, L., &amp; Alvarado, M. (2014). Literacy boost El Salvador: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Pisani, L., Satyaning, N. L. P., Giri, B., Alesbury, C., &amp; de Fretes, M. (2014). Literacy boost Belajar Indonesia: Midline &amp; endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Pouezevara, S., Costello, M., &amp; Banda, O. (2013). ABE/LINK Malawi Teacher Professional Development Support (MTPDS) Malawi Reading Intervention Early Grade Reading Assessment (EGRA) final assessment-2012. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pratt, T. C., Turanovic, J. J., &amp; Cullen, F. T. (2016). Revisiting the criminological consequences of exposure to fetal testosterone: A meta-analysis of the 2D:4D digit ratio. Criminology, 54, 587-620. https://doi.org/10.1111/1745-9125.12115</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Ralaingita, W., &amp; Wetterberg, A. (2011). Gauging program effectiveness with EGRA: Impact evaluations in South Africa and Mali. In A. Gove &amp; A. Wetterberg (Eds.), The Early Grade Reading Assessment: Applications and interventions to improve basic literacy (pp. 83-112). Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI Press. https://doi.org/10.3768/rtipress.2011.bk.0007.1109</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raudenbush, S. W., &amp; Bryk, A. S. (2002). Hierarchical linear models: Applications and data analysis methods. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riedel, B. W. (2007). The relation between DIBELS, reading comprehension, and vocabulary in urban first-grade students. Reading Research Quarterly, 42, 546-567. https://doi.org/10.1598/RRQ.42.4.5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raudenbush, S.W., Bryk, A.S, &amp; Congdon, R. (2011). HLM 7.00 for Windows [Computer software]. Lincolnwood, IL: Scientific Software International, Inc.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roehrig, A. D., Petscher, Y., Nettles, S. M., Hudson, R. F., &amp; Torgesen, J. K. (2008). Accuracy of the DIBELS oral reading fluency measure for predicting third grade reading comprehension outcomes. Journal of School Psychology, 46, 343-366. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsp.2007.06.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Rosenkranz, E., Jonason, E., &amp; Kajangwa, D. (2014). Literacy boost Burundi: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>RTI International (2009). Evaluation initiales des competences fondamentales en lecture-ecriture base sure l'utilisation de l'outil “EGRA” adapted en Francais et en Arabe au Mali. Produced under the USAID Mali PHARE project : Bamako, Mali. Downloaded from file:///C:/Users/Helen%20Boyle/Downloads/PHARE_Rapport_EGRA_2009_final_word%20(1).pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International. (2011a). EGRA plus: Liberia program evaluation report. Monrovia, Liberia: USAID.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International. (2011b). Improved reading performance in grade 2 GILO-supported schools vs. control schools. Research Triangle Park, NC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International. (2014). USAID/Kenya primary math and reading (PRIMR) initiative: Final report. Research Triangle Park, NC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International (2015a). The Primary Math and Reading (PRIMR) initiative, DFID/Kenya rural expansion programme: Bungoma and Machakos endline study. Research Triangle Park, NC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International (2015b). Tout TimounAp Li-ToTAL (all children reading): Final report. Research Triangle Park, NC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International (2016). Nigeria reading and access research activity (RARA): Results of an approach to improve early grade reading in Hausa in Bauchi and Sokoto states. Research Triangle Park, NC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*RTI International (2017). Prioritizing reform, innovation, and opportunities for Reaching Indonesia's Teachers, Administrators, and Students (USAID PRIORITAS) final project report. Research Triangle Park, NC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rugh, A. B. (2012). International development in practice: Education assistance in Egypt, Pakistan, and Afghanistan. New York, NY: Palgrave McMillan. https://doi.org/10.1057/9781137012883</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Sailors, M., Hoffman, J. V., Pearson, P. D., Beretvas, S. N., &amp; Matthee, B. (2010). The effects of first-and second-language instruction in rural South African schools. Bilingual Research Journal, 33(1), 21-41. https://doi.org/1080/15235881003733241</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*SCI Haiti. (2013). Reading is the future, Lekti se Lavni: Baseline-Endline assessments report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senechal, M., LeFevre, J., Thomas, E. M., &amp; Daley, K. E. (1998). Differential effects of home literacy experiences on the development of oral and written language. Reading Research Quarterly, 33, 96-116. https://doi.org/10.1598/RRQ.33.1.5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Shah-Wundenberg, M., Wyse, D., &amp; Chaplain, R. (2013). Parents helping their children learn to read: The effectiveness of paired reading and hearing reading in a developing country context. Journal of Early Childhood Literacy, 13, 471-500. https://doi.org/10.1177/1468798412438067</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snow, C. E., &amp; Kim, Y.-S. (2007). Large problem spaces: The challenge of vocabulary for English language learners. In R. K. Wagner, A. Muse, &amp; K. Tannenbaum (Eds.), Vocabulary acquisition and its implications for reading comprehension (pp. 123-139). New York, NY: Guilford.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snow, C. E., &amp; Matthews, T. J. (2016). Reading and language in the early grades. The Future of Children, 26, 57-74. https://doi.org/10.1353/foc.2016.0012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Spratt, J., King, S., &amp; Bulat, J. (2013). Independent evaluation of the effectiveness of Institut pour l'Education Populaire's “Read-Learn-Lead” (RLL) program in Mali: Endline report. Research Triangle Park, NC: RTI International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tompkins, V., Guo, Y., &amp; Justice, L. M. (2013). Inference generation, story comprehension, and language in the preschool years. Reading and Writing: An Interdisciplinary Journal, 26, 403-429. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11145-012-9374-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trudell, B., &amp; Piper, B. (2014). Whatever the law says: Language policy implementation and early-grade literacy achievement in Kenya. Current Issues in Language Planning, 15(1), 4-21. https://doi.org/10.1080/14664208.2013.856985</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNESCO. (2012). Adult and youth literacy. Montreal, QC: UNESCO Institute for Statistics.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNESCO. (2017a). Global education monitoring report 2017/18: Accountability in education. Paris, France: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNESCO. (2017b). More than one-half of children and adolescents are not learning worldwide. Fact Sheet No. 46, UIS/FS/2017/ED/46. Montreal, QC: UNESCO Institute for Statistics. Retrieved from http://uis.unesco.org/sites/default/files/documents/fs46-more-than-half-children-not-learning-en-2017.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNICEF &amp; UNESCO Institute of Statistics. (2014). All children in school by 2015: Global initiative on out-of-school children, regional report, West and Central Africa. West and Central Africa: UNICEF Regional Office.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uwezo. (2012). Are our children learning? Literacy and numeracy across East Africa. Nairobi, Kenya: Author. Retrieved from http://www.uwezo.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/RO_2012_UwezoEastAfricaReport.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaughn, S., Cirino, P. T., Linan-Thompson, S., Mathes, P. G., Carlson, C. D., Hagan, E. C., … Francis, D. J. (2006). Effectiveness of a Spanish intervention and an English intervention for English-language learners at risk for reading problems. American Educational Research Journal, 43, 449-487. https://doi.org/10.3102/00028312043003449</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vavrus, F., &amp; Bartlett, L. (2012). Comparative pedagogies and epistemological diversity: Social and materials contexts of teaching in Tanzania. Comparative Education Review, 56, 634-658. https://doi.org/10.1086/667395</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vellutino, F. R., Tunmer, W. E., Jaccard, J. J., &amp; Chen, R. (2007). Components of reading ability: Multivariate evidence for a convergent skills model of reading development. Scientific Studies of Reading, 11, 3-32. https://doi.org/10.1080/10888430709336632</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verger, A., Novella, M., &amp; Altinyelken, H. K. (Eds.). (2012). Global education policy and international development: New agendas, issues and policies. New York, NY: Bloomsbury Academic.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wawire, B., &amp; Kim, Y.-S. G. (2018). Cross-language transfer of phonological awareness and letter knowledge: Causal evidence and nature of transfer. Scientific Studies of Reading, 22, 443-461. https://doi.org/10.1080/10888438.2018.1474882</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*Wickramasekara, P., Navaratnam, S., &amp; Guajardo, J. (2014). Literacy boost, Gampaha District Sri Lanka: Endline report. Fairfield, CT: Save the Children Headquarters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>*World Bank. (2016). Implementation completion report: Reading education (READ-PNG) project. Washington, DC: Author.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
