<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30671455</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2314-6141</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2018</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2018</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BioMed research international</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Res Int</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Effectiveness of Physical Exercise on Bone Density in Osteoporotic Patients.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>4840531</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>4840531</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4840531</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1155/2018/4840531</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Physical exercise is considered an effective means to stimulate bone osteogenesis in osteoporotic patients. The authors reviewed the current literature to define the most appropriate features of exercise for increasing bone density in osteoporotic patients. Two types emerged: (1) <i>weight-bearing aerobic exercises</i>, i.e., walking, stair climbing, jogging, and Tai Chi. Walking alone did not appear to improve bone mass; however it is able to limit its progressive loss. In fact, in order for the weight-bearing exercises to be effective, they must reach the mechanical intensity useful to determine an important ground reaction force. (2) <i>Strength and resistance exercises</i>: these are carried out with loading (lifting weights) or without (swimming, cycling). For this type of exercise to be effective a joint reaction force superior to common daily activity with sensitive muscle strengthening must be determined. These exercises appear extremely site-specific, able to increase muscle mass and BMD only in the stimulated body regions. Other suggested protocols are multicomponent exercises and whole body vibration. <i>Multicomponent exercises</i> consist of a combination of different methods (aerobics, strengthening, progressive resistance, balancing, and dancing) aimed at increasing or preserving bone mass. These exercises seem particularly indicated in deteriorating elderly patients, often not able to perform exercises of pure reinforcement. However, for these protocols to be effective they must always contain a proportion of strengthening and resistance exercises. Given the variability of the protocols and outcome measures, the results of these methods are difficult to quantify. Training with <i>whole body vibration (WBV):</i> these exercises are performed with dedicated devices, and while it seems they have effect on enhancing muscle strength, controversial findings on improvement of BMD were reported. WBV seems to provide good results, especially in improving balance and reducing the risk of falling; in this, WBV appears more efficient than simply walking. Nevertheless, contraindications typical of senility should be taken into account.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Benedetti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria Grazia</ForeName>
            <Initials>MG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2623-8506</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Unit, IRCCS-Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Furlini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giulia</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Unit, IRCCS-Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation Unit, IRCCS-Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Letizia Mauro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giulia</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rehabilitation Unit, Paolo Giaccone Hospital, Palermo, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Biomed Res Int</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101600173</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015519" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone Density</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010024" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoporosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014732" MajorTopicYN="N">Vibration</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="N">Walking</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30671455</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323511</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/4840531</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez-Cabello A., Ara I., González-Agüero A., Casajús J. A., Vicente-Rodríguez G. Effects of training on bone mass in older adults: a systematic review. Sports Medicine. 2012;42(4):301–325. doi: 10.2165/11597670-000000000-00000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11597670-000000000-00000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22376192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonaiuti D., Arioli G., Diana G., et al.  SIMFER rehabilitation treatment guidelines in postmenopausal and senile osteoporosis. European Journal of Physical and Rehabilitation Medicine. 2005;41(4):315–337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16474287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonaiuti D., Shea B., Iovine R., et al.  Exercise for preventing and treating osteoporosis in postmenopausal women. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews (Online) 2002;(3):p. CD000333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12137611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson M. E., Rejeski W. J., Blair S. N., et al.  Physical activity and public health in older adults: recommendation from the American College of Sports Medicine and the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2007;116(9):1094–1105. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.185650.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.107.185650</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohrt W. M., Bloomfield S. A., Little K. D., Nelson M. E., Yingling V. R. Physical activity and bone health. Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise. 2004;36(11):1985–1996. doi: 10.1249/01.MSS.0000142662.21767.58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/01.MSS.0000142662.21767.58</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15514517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikander R., Sievänen H., Heinonen A., Daly R. M., Uusi-Rasi K., Kannus P. Targeted exercise against osteoporosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis for optimising bone strength throughout life. BMC Medicine. 2010;8, article 47 doi: 10.1186/1741-7015-8-47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-8-47</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20663158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori T., Crandall C. J., Ganz D. A. Cost-effectiveness of combined oral bisphosphonate therapy and falls prevention exercise for fracture prevention in the USA. Osteoporosis International. 2017;28(2):585–595. doi: 10.1007/s00198-016-3772-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-016-3772-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27726000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guadalupe-Grau A., Fuentes T., Guerra B., Calbet J. A. L. Exercise and bone mass in adults. Sports Medicine. 2009;39(6):439–468. doi: 10.2165/00007256-200939060-00002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00007256-200939060-00002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19453205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hingorjo M. R., Zehra S., Saleem S., Qureshi M. A. Serum Interleukin-15 and its relationship with adiposity Indices before and after short-term endurance exercise. Pakistan Journal of Medical Sciences. 2018;34(5) doi: 10.12669/pjms.345.15516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12669/pjms.345.15516</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6191778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30344562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morseth B., Emaus N., Jørgensen L. Physical activity and bone: The importance of the various mechanical stimuli for bone mineral density. A review. Norsk epidemiologi. 2011;20(2):173–178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zehnacker C. H., Bemis-Dougherty A. Effect of weighted exercises on bone mineral density in post menopausal women a systematic review. Journal of Geriatric Physical Therapy. 2007;30(2):79–88. doi: 10.1519/00139143-200708000-00007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00139143-200708000-00007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18171491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langsetmo L., Hitchcock C. L., Kingwell E. J., et al.  Physical activity, body mass index and bone mineral density-associations in a prospective population-based cohort of women and men: The Canadian Multicentre Osteoporosis Study (CaMos) Bone. 2012;50(1):401–408. doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2011.11.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bone.2011.11.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossini M., Adami S., Bertoldo F., et al.  Guidelines for the diagnosis, prevention and management of osteoporosis. Reumatismo. 2016;68(1):1–39. doi: 10.4081/reumatismo.2016.870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/reumatismo.2016.870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27339372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMahon M. What impact does aquatic therapy have on bone density in postmenopausal women? If it has a positive or maintenance effect, what are the programme parameters that facilitate these outcomes? Aqualines: The Journal of the Hydrotherapy Association of Chartered Physiotherapists. 2017;29(1):8–21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howe T. E., Shea B., Dawson L. J., et al.  Exercise for preventing and treating osteoporosis in postmenopausal women. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2011;2011(7):1–167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polidoulis I., Beyene J., Cheung A. M. The effect of exercise on pQCT parameters of bone structure and strength in postmenopausal women - A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Osteoporosis International. 2012;23(1):39–51. doi: 10.1007/s00198-011-1734-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-011-1734-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21811864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martyn-St James M., Carroll S. Meta-analysis of walking for preservation of bone mineral density in postmenopausal women. Bone. 2008;43(3):521–531. doi: 10.1016/j.bone.2008.05.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bone.2008.05.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18602880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma D., Wu L., He Z. Effects of walking on the preservation of bone mineral density in perimenopausal and postmenopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Menopause. 2013;20(11):1216–1226. doi: 10.1097/gme.0000000000000100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/gme.0000000000000100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolam K. A., van Uffelen J. G. Z., Taaffe D. R. The effect of physical exercise on bone density in middle-aged and older men: a systematic review. Osteoporosis International. 2013;24(11):2749–2762. doi: 10.1007/s00198-013-2346-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-013-2346-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23552825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelley G. A., Kelley K. S., Kohrt W. M. Effects of ground and joint reaction force exercise on lumbar spine and femoral neck bone mineral density in postmenopausal women: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders. 2012;13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chow T. H., Lee B. Y., Ang A. B. F., Cheung V. Y. K., Ho M. M. C., Takemura S. The effect of Chinese martial arts Tai Chi Chuan on prevention of osteoporosis: A systematic review. Journal of Orthopaedic Translation. 2018;12:74–84. doi: 10.1016/j.jot.2017.06.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jot.2017.06.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29662781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Z., Chen H., Berger M. R., Zhang L., Guo H., Huang Y. Effects of tai chi exercise on bone health in perimenopausal and postmenopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoporosis International. 2016;27(10):2901–2911. doi: 10.1007/s00198-016-3626-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-016-3626-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27216996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Kam D., Smulders E., Weerdesteyn V., Smits-Engelsman B. C. M. Exercise interventions to reduce fall-related fractures and their risk factors in individuals with low bone density: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Osteoporosis International. 2009;20(12):2111–2125. doi: 10.1007/s00198-009-0938-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-009-0938-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19421702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martyn-St James M., Carroll S. A meta-analysis of impact exercise on postmenopausal bone loss: the case for mixed loading exercise programmes. British Journal of Sports Medicine. 2009;43(12):898–908. doi: 10.1136/bjsm.2008.052704.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsm.2008.052704</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18981037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varahra A., Rodrigues I. B., MacDermid J. C., Bryant D., Birmingham T. Exercise to improve functional outcomes in persons with osteoporosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoporosis International. 2018;29(2):265–286. doi: 10.1007/s00198-017-4339-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-017-4339-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serra A. J. Different land-based exercise training programs to improve bone health in postmenopausal women. Medical Science and Technology. 2013;54:158–163. doi: 10.12659/MST.889899.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MST.889899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James M. M.-S., Carroll S. Effects of different impact exercise modalities on bone mineral density in premenopausal women: A meta-analysis. Journal of Bone and Mineral Metabolism. 2010;28(3):251–267. doi: 10.1007/s00774-009-0139-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00774-009-0139-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20013013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J., Lombardi G., Jiao W., Banfi G. Effects of Exercise on Bone Status in Female Subjects, from Young Girls to Postmenopausal Women: An Overview of Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses. Sports Medicine. 2016;46(8):1165–1182. doi: 10.1007/s40279-016-0494-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40279-016-0494-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26856338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slatkovska L., Alibhai S. M. H., Beyene J., Cheung A. M. Effect of whole-body vibration on BMD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoporosis International. 2010;21(12):1969–1980. doi: 10.1007/s00198-010-1228-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-010-1228-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5226820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20407890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma C., Liu A., Sun M., Zhu H., Wu H. Effect of whole-body vibration on reduction of bone loss and fall prevention in postmenopausal women: a meta-analysis and systematic review. Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research. 2016;11(1) doi: 10.1186/s13018-016-0357-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13018-016-0357-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4758089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26888467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merriman H., Jackson K. The effects of whole-body vibration training in aging adults: A systematic review. Journal of Geriatric Physical Therapy. 2009;32(3):134–145. doi: 10.1519/00139143-200932030-00009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/00139143-200932030-00009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20128338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira L. C., Oliveira R. G., Pires-Oliveira D. A. Effects of whole body vibration on bone mineral density in postmenopausal women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Osteoporosis International. 2016;27(10):2913–2933. doi: 10.1007/s00198-016-3618-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-016-3618-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27145947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fratini A., Bonci T., Bull A. M., Nazarian A. Whole body vibration treatments in postmenopausal women can improve bone mineral density: Results of a stimulus focussed meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(12) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0166774.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0166774</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5132247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27907000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lau R. W. K., Liao L.-R., Yu F., Teo T., Chung R. C. K., Pang M. Y. C. The effects of whole body vibration therapy on bone mineral density and leg muscle strength in older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinical Rehabilitation. 2011;25(11):975–988. doi: 10.1177/0269215511405078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215511405078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21849376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jepsen D. B., Thomsen K., Hansen S., Jørgensen N. R., Masud T., Ryg J. Effect of whole-body vibration exercise in preventing falls and fractures: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2017;7(12) doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2017-018342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2017-018342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6027066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29289937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banfi G., Colombini A., Lombardi G., Lubkowska A. Metabolic markers in sports medicine. Advances in Clinical Chemistry. 2012;56:1–54. doi: 10.1016/B978-0-12-394317-0.00015-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-394317-0.00015-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22397027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreoli A., Celi M., Volpe S. L., Sorge R., Tarantino U. Long-term effect of exercise on bone mineral density and body composition in post-menopausal ex-elite athletes: A retrospective study. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition. 2012;66(1):69–74. doi: 10.1038/ejcn.2011.104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejcn.2011.104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21673718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bean J. F., Vora A., Frontera W. R. Benefits of exercise for community-dwelling older adults. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation. 2004;85(3):S31–S42. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2004.03.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2004.03.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebeling P. R., Daly R. M., Kerr D. A., Kimlin M. G. An evidence-informed strategy to prevent osteoporosis in australia an outline of the building healthy bones throughout life white paper. Medical Journal of Australia. 2013;198(2) supplement 1:90–91. doi: 10.5694/mja12.11363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5694/mja12.11363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23373498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Multanen J., Nieminen M. T., Häkkinen A., et al.  Effects of high-impact training on bone and articular cartilage: 12-month randomized controlled quantitative MRI study. Journal of Bone and Mineral Research. 2014;29(1):192–201. doi: 10.1002/jbmr.2015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbmr.2015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23775755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung A. M., Giangregorio L. Mechanical stimuli and bone health: What is the evidence? Current Opinion in Rheumatology. 2012;24(5):561–566. doi: 10.1097/BOR.0b013e3283570238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0b013e3283570238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22832826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watts N. B., Adler R. A., Bilezikian J. P. Osteoporosis in men: an endocrine society clinical practice guideline. The Journal of Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism. 2012;97(6):1802–1822. doi: 10.1210/jc.2011-3045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/jc.2011-3045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22675062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daly R. M. Exercise and nutritional approaches to prevent frail bones, falls and fractures: an update. Climacteric. 2017;20(2):119–124. doi: 10.1080/13697137.2017.1286890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13697137.2017.1286890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28286988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou L., Wang C., Chen K., et al.  The Effect of Taichi Practice on Attenuating Bone Mineral Density Loss: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2017;14(9):p. 1000. doi: 10.3390/ijerph14091000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph14091000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5615537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28862661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee M. S., Pittler M. H., Shin B.-C., Ernst E. Tai Chi for osteoporosis: a systematic review. Osteoporosis International. 2008;19(2):139–146. doi: 10.1007/s00198-007-0486-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-007-0486-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17955276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blake H., Hawley H. Effects of tai chi exercise on physical and psychological health of older people. Current Aging Science. 2012;5(1):19–27. doi: 10.2174/1874609811205010019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874609811205010019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21762093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerr D., Morton A., Dick I., Prince R. Exercise effects on bone mass in postmenopausal women are site-specific and load-dependent. Journal of Bone and Mineral Research. 1996;11(2):218–225. doi: 10.1002/jbmr.5650110211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbmr.5650110211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8822346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinaki M., Itoi E., Wahner H. W., et al.  Stronger back muscles reduce the incidence of vertebral fractures: A prospective 10 year follow-up of postmenopausal women. Bone. 2002;30(6):836–841. doi: 10.1016/S8756-3282(02)00739-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S8756-3282(02)00739-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12052450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bemben D. A., Bemben M. G. Dose-response effect of 40 weeks of resistance training on bone mineral density in older adults. Osteoporosis International. 2011;22(1):179–186. doi: 10.1007/s00198-010-1182-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-010-1182-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20195844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson V. P., McKean M. R., Slater G. J., Kerr A., Burkett B. J. Low-Load Very High-Repetition Resistance Training Attenuates Bone Loss at the Lumbar Spine in Active Post-menopausal Women. Calcified Tissue International. 2015;96(6, article no. 9976):490–499. doi: 10.1007/s00223-015-9976-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00223-015-9976-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25772806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giangregorio L. M., Papaioannou A., MacIntyre N. J., et al.  Too Fit to Fracture: Exercise recommendations for individuals with osteoporosis or osteoporotic vertebral fracture. Osteoporosis International. 2014;25(3):821–835. doi: 10.1007/s00198-013-2523-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-013-2523-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5112023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24281053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopewell S., Adedire O., Copsey B. J., et al.  Multifactorial and multiple component interventions for preventing falls in older people living in the community. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews. 2016;2016(6)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30035305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beck B. R., Daly R. M., Singh M. A. F., Taaffe D. R. Exercise and Sports Science Australia (ESSA) position statement on exercise prescription for the prevention and management of osteoporosis. Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport. 2017;20(5):438–445. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2016.10.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2016.10.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27840033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harding A., Beck B. Exercise, osteoporosis, and bone geometry. Sports. 2017;5(2):p. 29. doi: 10.3390/sports5020029.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/sports5020029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5968984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29910388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt N. M., Schmitt J., Dören M. The role of physical activity in the prevention of osteoporosis in postmenopausal women-An update. Maturitas. 2009;63(1):34–38. doi: 10.1016/j.maturitas.2009.03.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.maturitas.2009.03.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19356867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao R., Zhao M., Xu Z. The effects of differing resistance training modes on the preservation of bone mineral density in postmenopausal women: a meta-analysis. Osteoporosis International. 2015;26(5):1605–1618. doi: 10.1007/s00198-015-3034-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-015-3034-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemmler W., Von Stengel S., Engelke K., Häberle L., Kalender W. A. Exercise effects on bone mineral density, falls, coronary risk factors, and health care costs in older women: The randomized controlled senior fitness and prevention (SEFIP) study. JAMA Internal Medicine. 2010;170(2):179–185. doi: 10.1001/archinternmed.2009.499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2009.499</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kukuljan S., Nowson C. A., Bass S. L., et al.  Effects of a multi-component exercise program and calcium-vitamin-D 3-fortified milk on bone mineral density in older men: A randomised controlled trial. Osteoporosis International. 2009;20(7):1241–1251. doi: 10.1007/s00198-008-0776-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00198-008-0776-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18958384</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marques E. A., Mota J., Machado L., et al.  Multicomponent training program with weight-bearing exercises elicits favorable bone density, muscle strength, and balance adaptations in older women. Calcified Tissue International. 2011;88(2):117–129. doi: 10.1007/s00223-010-9437-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00223-010-9437-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21113584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marques E. A., Mota J., Carvalho J. Exercise effects on bone mineral density in older adults: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. AGE. 2011;34(6):1493–1515. doi: 10.1007/s11357-011-9311-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11357-011-9311-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3528362</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21922251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dionello C. F., Sá-Caputo D., Pereira H. V. F. S., et al.  Effects of whole body vibration exercises on bone mineral density of women with postmenopausal osteoporosis without medications: Novel findings and literature review. Journal of Musculoskeletal and Neuronal Interactions. 2016;16(3):193–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5114342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27609034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
