<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30725795</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK537110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827">Syringomyelia</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shenoy</LastName><ForeName>Varadaraya Satyanarayan</ForeName><Initials>VS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rajiv Gandhi Medical College, CSMH</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sampath</LastName><ForeName>Raghuram</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florida Atlantic University Advanced Neuroscience Network</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Syringomyelia, at its core, is a disorder of abnormal cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) circulation. A syrinx is a fluid-filled cavity that anatomically lies within the spinal cord parenchyma or the central canal. This entity is most frequently associated with a CM-I, although other known causes include spinal cord tumor, trauma, and post-traumatic or infectious adhesive arachnoiditis. Although syringomyelia predominantly presents with sensory symptoms such as pain and temperature insensitivity, in most cases it is an incidental finding. The discovery of syringomyelia is becoming more common because of the increased use of MRI in the routine evaluation of back and neck pain. The natural history of patients with syringomyelia is variable and unpredictable punctuated with periods of stability and progression. Although professionals do not completely understand the natural history of syringomyelia, the clinical course progresses over months to years, with an early rapid deterioration that gradually slows down. It is also understood that sudden jolting of the head, a prolonged bout of coughing may bring a sudden onset of symptoms in a previously asymptomatic patient presumably because of an increase in tonsillar descent. Syringomyelia accounts for up to 5% of paraplegia. The quality of life in syringomyelia patients is comparable with that of patients with heart failure or malignant neoplasms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s10">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s11">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s12">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s13">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s14">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s15">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29827" sec="article-29827.s19">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Greitz D. Unraveling the riddle of syringomyelia. Neurosurg Rev. 2006 Oct;29(4):251-63; discussion 264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16752160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milhorat TH, Chou MW, Trinidad EM, Kula RW, Mandell M, Wolpert C, Speer MC. Chiari I malformation redefined: clinical and radiographic findings for 364 symptomatic patients. Neurosurgery. 1999 May;44(5):1005-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10232534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy AK, Slimack NP, Ganju A. Idiopathic syringomyelia: retrospective case series, comprehensive review, and update on management. Neurosurg Focus. 2011 Dec;31(6):E15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klekamp J, Batzdorf U, Samii M, Bothe HW. Treatment of syringomyelia associated with arachnoid scarring caused by arachnoiditis or trauma. J Neurosurg. 1997 Feb;86(2):233-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9010425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roser F, Ebner FH, Sixt C, Hagen JM, Tatagiba MS. Defining the line between hydromyelia and syringomyelia. A differentiation is possible based on electrophysiological and magnetic resonance imaging studies. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2010 Feb;152(2):213-9; discussion 219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19533016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanov EI, Mendelevich EG. Syrinx size and duration of symptoms predict the pace of progressive myelopathy: retrospective analysis of 103 unoperated cases with craniocervical junction malformations and syringomyelia. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2002 May;104(2):90-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11932037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mampalam TJ, Andrews BT, Gelb D, Ferriero D, Pitts LH. Presentation of type I Chiari malformation after head trauma. Neurosurgery. 1988 Dec;23(6):760-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3216976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams B. Post-traumatic syringomyelia, an update. Paraplegia. 1990 Jun;28(5):296-313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2235038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sixt C, Riether F, Will BE, Tatagiba MS, Roser F. Evaluation of quality of life parameters in patients who have syringomyelia. J Clin Neurosci. 2009 Dec;16(12):1599-603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19818628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weier K, Naegelin Y, Thoeni A, Hirsch JG, Kappos L, Steinbrich W, Radue EW, Gass A. Non-communicating syringomyelia: a feature of spinal cord involvement in multiple sclerosis. Brain. 2008 Jul;131(Pt 7):1776-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18515871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brickell KL, Anderson NE, Charleston AJ, Hope JK, Bok AP, Barber PA. Ethnic differences in syringomyelia in New Zealand. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006 Aug;77(8):989-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16549414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speer MC, Enterline DS, Mehltretter L, Hammock P, Joseph J, Dickerson M, Ellenbogen RG, Milhorat TH, Hauser MA, George TM. Review Article: Chiari Type I Malformation with or Without Syringomyelia: Prevalence and Genetics. J Genet Couns. 2003 Aug;12(4):297-311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26141174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GARDNER WJ, ANGEL J. The mechanism of syringomyelia and its surgical correction. Clin Neurosurg. 1958;6:131-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13826542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams B. Pathogenesis of syringomyelia. Lancet. 1972 Nov 04;2(7784):969-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4116840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams B. On the pathogenesis of syringomyelia: a review. J R Soc Med. 1980 Nov;73(11):798-806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1437943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7017117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield EH, Muraszko K, Shawker TH, Patronas NJ. Pathophysiology of syringomyelia associated with Chiari I malformation of the cerebellar tonsils. Implications for diagnosis and treatment. J Neurosurg. 1994 Jan;80(1):3-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8271018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milhorat TH, Miller JI, Johnson WD, Adler DE, Heger IM. Anatomical basis of syringomyelia occurring with hindbrain lesions. Neurosurgery. 1993 May;32(5):748-54; discussion 754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8492850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honey CM, Martin KW, Heran MKS. Syringomyelia Fluid Dynamics and Cord Motion Revealed by Serendipitous Null Point Artifacts during Cine MRI. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2017 Sep;38(9):1845-1847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7963706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28751514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball MJ, Dayan AD. Pathogenesis of syringomyelia. Lancet. 1972 Oct 14;2(7781):799-801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4116236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield EH. Pathogenesis of Chiari I - Pathophysiology of Syringomyelia: Implications for Therapy: A Summary of 3 Decades of Clinical Research. Neurosurgery. 2017 Sep 01;64(CN_suppl_1):66-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koyanagi I, Houkin K. Pathogenesis of syringomyelia associated with Chiari type 1 malformation: review of evidences and proposal of a new hypothesis. Neurosurg Rev. 2010 Jul;33(3):271-84; discussion 284-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weig SG, Buckthal PE, Choi SK, Zellem RT. Recurrent syncope as the presenting symptom of Arnold-Chiari malformation. Neurology. 1991 Oct;41(10):1673-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1922816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batzdorf U, Khoo LT, McArthur DL. Observations on spine deformity and syringomyelia. Neurosurgery. 2007 Aug;61(2):370-7; discussion 377-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milhorat TH, Mu HT, LaMotte CC, Milhorat AT. Distribution of substance P in the spinal cord of patients with syringomyelia. J Neurosurg. 1996 Jun;84(6):992-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8847594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant R, Hadley DM, Macpherson P, Condon B, Patterson J, Bone I, Teasdale GN. Syringomyelia: cyst measurement by magnetic resonance imaging and comparison with symptoms, signs and disability. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1987 Aug;50(8):1008-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1032229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3655805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii K, Natori Y, Nakagaki H, Fukui M. Management of syringomyelia associated with Chiari malformation: comparative study of syrinx size and symptoms by magnetic resonance imaging. Surg Neurol. 1991 Oct;36(4):281-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1948628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel A, Desai K. Surgery for syringomyelia: an analysis based on 163 surgical cases. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2000;142(3):293-301; discussion 301-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10819260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauer UM, Freude G, Danz B, Kunz U. Cardiac-gated phase-contrast magnetic resonance imaging of cerebrospinal fluid flow in the diagnosis of idiopathic syringomyelia. Neurosurgery. 2008 Dec;63(6):1139-44; discussion 1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyste GN, Menezes AH, VanGilder JC. Symptomatic Chiari malformations. An analysis of presentation, management, and long-term outcome. J Neurosurg. 1989 Aug;71(2):159-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2746341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attal N, Parker F, Tadié M, Aghakani N, Bouhassira D. Effects of surgery on the sensory deficits of syringomyelia and predictors of outcome: a long term prospective study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2004 Jul;75(7):1025-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15201364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TT, Alameda GJ, Camilo E, Green BA. Surgical treatment of post-traumatic myelopathy associated with syringomyelia. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2001 Dec 15;26(24 Suppl):S119-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11805618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hida K, Iwasaki Y, Koyanagi I, Sawamura Y, Abe H. Surgical indication and results of foramen magnum decompression versus syringosubarachnoid shunting for syringomyelia associated with Chiari I malformation. Neurosurgery. 1995 Oct;37(4):673-8; discussion 678-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8559295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant R, Hadley DM, Lang D, Condon B, Johnston R, Bone I, Teasdale GM. MRI measurement of syrinx size before and after operation. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1987 Dec;50(12):1685-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1032615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3437304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logue V, Edwards MR. Syringomyelia and its surgical treatment--an analysis of 75 patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1981 Apr;44(4):273-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC490948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7241155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleck TP, Shannon KM. Disordered swallowing due to a syrinx: correction by shunting. Neurology. 1984 Nov;34(11):1497-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6493500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhonen MG, Menezes AH, Sawin PD, Weinstein SL. Scoliosis in pediatric Chiari malformations without myelodysplasia. J Neurosurg. 1992 Jul;77(1):69-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1607974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson NF, Buchwald D, Goldberg J, Maravilla KR, Noonan C, Guan Q, Ellenbogen RG. Is Chiari I malformation associated with fibromyalgia? Neurosurgery. 2011 Feb;68(2):443-8; discussion 448-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21135714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller DM, Oro' JJ. Prospective analysis of presenting symptoms among 265 patients with radiographic evidence of Chiari malformation type I with or without syringomyelia. J Am Acad Nurse Pract. 2004 Mar;16(3):134-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15130068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
