<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">30725774</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK537089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143">Reentry Arrhythmia</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goyal</LastName><ForeName>Amandeep</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kansas Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Senst</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universitätsklinikum Halle</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhyan</LastName><ForeName>Poonam</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeltser</LastName><ForeName>Roman</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hofstra Northwell School of Medicine</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Reentry describes a self-sustaining cardiac rhythm abnormality. In reentry, the action potential propagates in a circus-like closed loop manner. It is a disorder of impulse conduction and thus describes one kind of arrhythmogenesis and is differentiated from disorders of impulse generation such as automaticity and triggered activity. First studies investigating reentry are over 100 years old and go back to Mines and Garrey. Dysrhythmias based on the reentry mechanism include atrial tachyarrhythmias such as atrial flutter (AFlut), atrioventricular nodal reentry (AVNRT), atrioventricular reentry (AVRT) like Wolff-Parkinson-White (WPW) syndrome and ventricular reentry such as bundle branch reentry (BBR). The pathophysiologic importance of reentry and utility as a treatment target in atrial fibrillation (AFib) is part of ongoing research. The main task of the heart is to produce cardiac output. Therefore myocardiocytes contract in a highly orchestrated and rhythmic manner. Proper electro-mechanic coupling (EMC) translates electric stimulation into contraction. The action potential runs from the sinus node (SN) via right atrial pathways through the atrioventricular node (AVN) and the His bundle down the Purkinje fibers (His-Purkinje system, HPS) to the ventricular myocardium. Cells are either in an excited or resting condition. From the resting potential, the cell is depolarized until the crossing of a critical threshold, which then causes an action potential (AP). Following the action potential, there is a period of refractoriness (refractory period, RP) when another trigger cannot activate the cell. Wavelength (WL) or cycle length (CL) is the time between two action potentials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s11">Pertinent Studies and Ongoing Trials</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s12">Consultations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s13">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s14">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s15">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-143" sec="article-143.s17">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Paterson DJ. Arrhythmia: 100 years on from George Ralph Mines. J Physiol. 2013 Sep 01;591(17):4065-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24742770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wit AL, Cranefield PF. Reentrant excitation as a cause of cardiac arrhythmias. Am J Physiol. 1978 Jul;235(1):H1-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">677321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aguilar M, Nattel S. The pioneering work of George Mines on cardiac arrhythmias: groundbreaking ideas that remain influential in contemporary cardiac electrophysiology. J Physiol. 2016 May 01;594(9):2377-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26607760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmermann V, Dejgaard LA, Haugaa KH, Edwards AG, Sundnes J, McCulloch AD, Wall ST. An integrative appraisal of mechano-electric feedback mechanisms in the heart. Prog Biophys Mol Biol. 2017 Nov;130(Pt B):404-417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5716869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts JD, Gollob MH, Young C, Connors SP, Gray C, Wilton SB, Green MS, Zhu DW, Hodgkinson KA, Poon A, Li Q, Orr N, Tang AS, Klein GJ, Wojciak J, Campagna J, Olgin JE, Badhwar N, Vedantham V, Marcus GM, Kwok PY, Deo RC, Scheinman MM. Bundle Branch Re-Entrant Ventricular Tachycardia: Novel Genetic Mechanisms in a Life-Threatening Arrhythmia. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2017 Mar;3(3):276-288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29759522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delacretaz E, Ganz LI, Soejima K, Friedman PL, Walsh EP, Triedman JK, Sloss LJ, Landzberg MJ, Stevenson WG. Multi atrial maco-re-entry circuits in adults with repaired congenital heart disease: entrainment mapping combined with three-dimensional electroanatomic mapping. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2001 May;37(6):1665-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11345382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saremi F, Sánchez-Quintana D, Mori S, Muresian H, Spicer DE, Hassani C, Anderson RH. Fibrous Skeleton of the Heart: Anatomic Overview and Evaluation of Pathologic Conditions with CT and MR Imaging. Radiographics. 2017 Sep-Oct;37(5):1330-1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28820653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes N, Derval N, Hascoët S, Zhao A, Amet D, Le Bloa M, Maltret A, Heitz F, Thambo JB, Marijon E. Ablation of supraventricular arrhythmias in adult congenital heart disease: A contemporary review. Arch Cardiovasc Dis. 2017 May;110(5):334-345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28359691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandapati R, Walsh EP, Triedman JK. Pericaval and periannular intra-atrial reentrant tachycardias in patients with congenital heart disease. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2003 Feb;14(2):119-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12693488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapel GF, Reichlin T, Wijnmaalen AP, Piers SR, Holman ER, Tedrow UB, Schalij MJ, Stevenson WG, Zeppenfeld K. Re-entry using anatomically determined isthmuses: a curable ventricular tachycardia in repaired congenital heart disease. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2015 Feb;8(1):102-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25422392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellison KE, Friedman PL, Ganz LI, Stevenson WG. Entrainment mapping and radiofrequency catheter ablation of ventricular tachycardia in right ventricular dysplasia. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1998 Sep;32(3):724-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9741518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stark SI, Arthur A, Lesh MD. Radiofrequency catheter ablation of ventricular tachycardia in right ventricular cardiomyopathy: use of concealed entrainment to identify the slow conduction isthmus bounded by an aneurysm and the tricuspid annulus. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1996 Oct;7(10):967-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8894939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox JL, Boineau JP, Schuessler RB, Kater KM, Ferguson TB, Cain ME, Lindsay BD, Smith JM, Corr PB, Hogue CB. Electrophysiologic basis, surgical development, and clinical results of the maze procedure for atrial flutter and atrial fibrillation. Adv Card Surg. 1995;6:1-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7894763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milberg P, Pott C, Eckardt L, Breithardt G. [Heart hypertrophy and heart failure--experimental findings for arrhythmogenesis]. Dtsch Med Wochenschr. 2008 Dec;133 Suppl 8:S285-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19085808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page RL, Joglar JA, Caldwell MA, Calkins H, Conti JB, Deal BJ, Estes NA, Field ME, Goldberger ZD, Hammill SC, Indik JH, Lindsay BD, Olshansky B, Russo AM, Shen WK, Tracy CM, Al-Khatib SM, Evidence Review Committee Chair‡  2015 ACC/AHA/HRS Guideline for the Management of Adult Patients With Supraventricular Tachycardia: Executive Summary: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines and the Heart Rhythm Society. Circulation. 2016 Apr 05;133(14):e471-505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26399662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enriquez A, Frankel DS, Baranchuk A. Pathophysiology of ventricular tachyarrhythmias : From automaticity to reentry. Herzschrittmacherther Elektrophysiol. 2017 Jun;28(2):149-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28567491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CF, Cheung JW, Ip JE, Thomas G, Yang H, Sharma S, Markowitz SM, Lerman BB. Unifying Algorithm for Mechanistic Diagnosis of Atrial Tachycardia. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2016 Aug;9(8)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27516463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mines GR. On dynamic equilibrium in the heart. J Physiol. 1913 Jul 18;46(4-5):349-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1420430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16993210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abildskov JA, Lux RL. Spiral waves in a computer model of cardiac excitation. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 1994 May;17(5 Pt 1):944-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7517529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waks JW, Josephson ME. Mechanisms of Atrial Fibrillation - Reentry, Rotors and Reality. Arrhythm Electrophysiol Rev. 2014 Aug;3(2):90-100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4711504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26835073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rensma PL, Allessie MA, Lammers WJ, Bonke FI, Schalij MJ. Length of excitation wave and susceptibility to reentrant atrial arrhythmias in normal conscious dogs. Circ Res. 1988 Feb;62(2):395-410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3338122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janse MJ, Coronel R, Wilms-Schopman FJ, de Groot JR. Mechanical effects on arrhythmogenesis: from pipette to patient. Prog Biophys Mol Biol. 2003 May-Jul;82(1-3):187-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12732278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilmour RF, Watanabe M. Dynamics of circus movement re-entry across canine Purkinje fibre-muscle junctions. J Physiol. 1994 May 01;476(3):473-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1160461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8057255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allessie MA, Bonke FI, Schopman FJ. Circus movement in rabbit atrial muscle as a mechanism of tachycardia. III. The "leading circle" concept: a new model of circus movement in cardiac tissue without the involvement of an anatomical obstacle. Circ Res. 1977 Jul;41(1):9-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">862147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comtois P, Kneller J, Nattel S. Of circles and spirals: bridging the gap between the leading circle and spiral wave concepts of cardiac reentry. Europace. 2005 Sep;7 Suppl 2:10-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16102499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zykov V, Krekhov A, Bodenschatz E. Fast propagation regions cause self-sustained reentry in excitable media. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017 Feb 07;114(6):1281-1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5307440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28123066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandit SV, Jalife J. Rotors and the dynamics of cardiac fibrillation. Circ Res. 2013 Mar 01;112(5):849-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23449547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antzelevitch C. In vivo human demonstration of phase 2 reentry. Heart Rhythm. 2005 Aug;2(8):804-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1474078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16051113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukas A, Antzelevitch C. Phase 2 reentry as a mechanism of initiation of circus movement reentry in canine epicardium exposed to simulated ischemia. Cardiovasc Res. 1996 Sep;32(3):593-603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8881520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen YJ, Tai CT, Hsieh MH, Tsai CF, Lin WS, Chen SA. Dependence of electrogram duration in right posteroseptal atrium and atrium-pulmonary vein junction on pacing site: mechanism and implications regarding atrioventricular nodal reentrant tachycardia and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2000 May;11(5):506-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10826929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagishita A, Yamauchi Y, Miyamoto T, Hirao K. Electrophysiological evidence of localized reentry as a trigger and driver of atrial fibrillation at the junction of the superior vena cava and right atrium. HeartRhythm Case Rep. 2017 Mar;3(3):164-166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5420070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28491795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haïssaguerre M, Jaïs P, Shah DC, Takahashi A, Hocini M, Quiniou G, Garrigue S, Le Mouroux A, Le Métayer P, Clémenty J. Spontaneous initiation of atrial fibrillation by ectopic beats originating in the pulmonary veins. N Engl J Med. 1998 Sep 03;339(10):659-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9725923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suenari K, Lin YJ, Chang SL, Lo LW, Hu YF, Tuan TC, Huang SY, Tai CT, Nakano Y, Kihara Y, Tsao HM, Wu TJ, Chen SA. Relationship between arrhythmogenic pulmonary veins and the surrounding atrial substrate in patients with paroxysmal atrial fibrillation. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2011 Apr;22(4):405-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20958838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldo AL. Mechanisms of atrial flutter and atrial fibrillation: distinct entities or two sides of a coin? Cardiovasc Res. 2002 May;54(2):217-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12062328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WG, Friedman PL, Sager PT, Saxon LA, Kocovic D, Harada T, Wiener I, Khan H. Exploring postinfarction reentrant ventricular tachycardia with entrainment mapping. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1997 May;29(6):1180-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9137211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosío FG, Martín-Peñato A, Pastor A, Nuñez A, Goicolea A. Atypical flutter: a review. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2003 Nov;26(11):2157-69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14622320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cabrera JA, Sanchez-Quintana D, Ho SY, Medina A, Anderson RH. The architecture of the atrial musculature between the orifice of the inferior caval vein and the tricuspid valve: the anatomy of the isthmus. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1998 Nov;9(11):1186-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9835263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ROSENBLUETH A, GARCIA RAMOS J. Studies on flutter and fibrillation; the influence of artificial obstacles on experimental auricular flutter. Am Heart J. 1947 May;33(5):677-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20238579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puech P. The P wave: correlation of surface and intra-atrial electrograms. Cardiovasc Clin. 1974;6(1):43-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4140029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai CT, Chen SA. Cavotricuspid isthmus: anatomy, electrophysiology, and long-term outcome of radiofrequency ablation. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2009 Dec;32(12):1591-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19843312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obel OA, Camm AJ. Supraventricular tachycardia. ECG diagnosis and anatomy. Eur Heart J. 1997 May;18 Suppl C:C2-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9152669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Varma N, Badhwar N, Tanel RE, Sundara S, Lee RJ, Lee BK, Tseng ZH, Marcus GM, Kim AM, Olgin JE, Scheinman MM. Prospective observations in the clinical and electrophysiological characteristics of intra-isthmus reentry. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2010 Oct;21(10):1099-106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20455984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latcu DG, Bun SS, Saoudi N. Intra-isthmus reentry: diagnosis at-a-glance. Europace. 2014 Feb;16(2):251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24158259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saoudi N, Latcu DG. Intra-isthmus reentry: another form of typical atrial flutter? J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2010 Oct;21(10):1107-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20550609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sánchez-Quintana D, Anderson RH, Cabrera JA, Climent V, Martin R, Farré J, Ho SY. The terminal crest: morphological features relevant to electrophysiology. Heart. 2002 Oct;88(4):406-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1767383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12231604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosío FG. The right atrium as an anatomic set-up for re-entry: electrophysiology goes back to anatomy. Heart. 2002 Oct;88(4):325-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1767362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12231579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawamura I, Fukamizu S, Miyazawa S, Hojo R. Biatrial tachycardia utilizing Bachmann bundle. Heart Rhythm. 2018 Aug;15(8):1277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29627434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyazawa S, Fukamizu S, Kawamura I, Hojo R. Macroreentrant atrial tachycardia detouring the epicardium at the anterior wall of the left atrium. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2019 Feb;30(2):263-264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilber DJ, Kopp DE, Glascock DN, Kinder CA, Kall JG. Catheter ablation of the mitral isthmus for ventricular tachycardia associated with inferior infarction. Circulation. 1995 Dec 15;92(12):3481-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8521570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi T, Fukamizu S, Mitsuhashi T, Kitamura T, Aoyama Y, Hojo R, Sugawara Y, Sakurada H, Hiraoka M, Fujita H, Momomura SI. Peri-Mitral Atrial Tachycardia Using the Marshall Bundle Epicardial Connections. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2016 Feb;2(1):27-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inagaki D, Hojo R, Fukamizu S, Sakurada H, Hiraoka M. Adenosine-sensitive atrial tachycardia originating from the anterior mitral annulus. HeartRhythm Case Rep. 2018 Nov;4(11):542-544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6241165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30479956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heidbüchel H. How to ablate typical 'slow/fast' AV nodal reentry tachycardia. Europace. 2000 Jan;2(1):15-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11225592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y. His electrogram alternans (Zhang's phenomenon) and a new model of dual pathway atrioventricular node conduction. J Interv Card Electrophysiol. 2016 Jan;45(1):19-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26614299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu JC, Lauer MR, Young C, Liem LB, Hou C, Sung RJ. Localization of the origin of the atrioventricular junctional rhythm induced during selective ablation of slow-pathway conduction in patients with atrioventricular node reentrant tachycardia. Am Heart J. 1996 May;131(5):937-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8615313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spach MS, Josephson ME. Initiating reentry: the role of nonuniform anisotropy in small circuits. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1994 Feb;5(2):182-209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8186887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voss F, Eckardt L, Busch S, Estner HL, Steven D, Sommer P, von Bary C, Neuberger HR. [AV-reentrant tachycardia and Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome : Diagnosis and treatment]. Herzschrittmacherther Elektrophysiol. 2016 Dec;27(4):381-389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27878364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reithmann C. [Bundle branch reentry VT : Diagnosis, mapping, and ablation]. Herzschrittmacherther Elektrophysiol. 2017 Jun;28(2):193-198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28484841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanck Z, Jazayeri M, Dhala A, Deshpande S, Sra J, Akhtar M. Bundle branch reentry: a mechanism of ventricular tachycardia in the absence of myocardial or valvular dysfunction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1993 Nov 15;22(6):1718-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8227845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanck Z, Dhala A, Deshpande S, Sra J, Jazayeri M, Akhtar M. Bundle branch reentrant ventricular tachycardia: cumulative experience in 48 patients. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1993 Jun;4(3):253-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8269297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nageh MF, Schwartz J, Mokabberi R, Dabiesingh D, Kalamkarian N. Bundle branch reentry with His dissociation-The His bundle: Bystander or participant? HeartRhythm Case Rep. 2018 Aug;4(8):378-381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6092638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30116713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ideker RE, Rogers JM, Fast V, Li L, Kay GN, Pogwizd SM. Can mapping differentiate microreentry from a focus in the ventricle? Heart Rhythm. 2009 Nov;6(11):1666-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2784110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19793684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>el-Sherif N. The mechanism of supraventricular tachycardia. Ectopic (parasystolic) focus versus re-entry. J Electrocardiol. 1974;7(2):169-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4132557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garan H, Ruskin JN. Localized reentry. Mechanism of induced sustained ventricular tachycardia in canine model of recent myocardial infarction. J Clin Invest. 1984 Aug;74(2):377-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC370488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6746899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai YT, Lee KL. Interfascicular macroreentry versus intrafascicular microreentry. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1996 Mar;7(3):275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8867302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kocovic DZ, Harada T, Friedman PL, Stevenson WG. Characteristics of electrograms recorded at reentry circuit sites and bystanders during ventricular tachycardia after myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1999 Aug;34(2):381-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10440149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WG, Khan H, Sager P, Saxon LA, Middlekauff HR, Natterson PD, Wiener I. Identification of reentry circuit sites during catheter mapping and radiofrequency ablation of ventricular tachycardia late after myocardial infarction. Circulation. 1993 Oct;88(4 Pt 1):1647-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8403311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WG, Sager PT, Friedman PL. Entrainment techniques for mapping atrial and ventricular tachycardias. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1995 Mar;6(3):201-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7620645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldo AL, Henthorn RW. Use of transient entrainment during ventricular tachycardia to localize a critical area in the reentry circuit for ablation. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 1989 Jan;12(1 Pt 2):231-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2466258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldo AL. Atrial flutter: entrainment characteristics. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 1997 Mar;8(3):337-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9083885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugada P, Wellens HJ. Entrainment as an electrophysiologic phenomenon. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1984 Feb;3(2 Pt 1):451-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6693633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veenhuyzen GD, Quinn FR. Principles of entrainment: diagnostic utility for supraventricular tachycardia. Indian Pacing Electrophysiol J. 2008 Feb 01;8(1):51-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2231607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18270602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almendral J. Resetting and entrainment of reentrant arrhythmias: part II: informative content and practical use of these responses. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2013 May;36(5):641-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23330693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WG, Sager PT, Natterson PD, Saxon LA, Middlekauff HR, Wiener I. Relation of pace mapping QRS configuration and conduction delay to ventricular tachycardia reentry circuits in human infarct scars. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1995 Aug;26(2):481-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7608454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attin M. Electrophysiology study: a comprehensive review. Am J Crit Care. 2001 Jul;10(4):260-73; quiz 274-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11432214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lévy S, Ricard P. Using the right drug: a treatment algorithm for regular supraventricular tachycardias. Eur Heart J. 1997 May;18 Suppl C:C27-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9152672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Touboul P, Vexler RM, Chatelain MT. Re-entry via Mahaim fibres as a possible basis for tachycardia. Br Heart J. 1978 Jul;40(7):806-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC483488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">687479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almendral J, Caulier-Cisterna R, Rojo-Álvarez JL. Resetting and entrainment of reentrant arrhythmias: part I: concepts, recognition, and protocol for evaluation: surface ECG versus intracardiac recordings. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2013 Apr;36(4):508-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3666092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23305213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosío FG. Atrial Flutter, Typical and Atypical: A Review. Arrhythm Electrophysiol Rev. 2017 Jun;6(2):55-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5522718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28835836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreira W, Timmermans C, Wellens HJ, Mizusawa Y, Philippens S, Perez D, Rodriguez LM. Can common-type atrial flutter be a sign of an arrhythmogenic substrate in paroxysmal atrial fibrillation? Clinical and ablative consequences in patients with coexistent paroxysmal atrial fibrillation/atrial flutter. Circulation. 2007 Dec 11;116(24):2786-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18040030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu PH, Wang WB, Wang DJ, Shieh SM, Sung PK. Three types of atrioventricular reciprocating tachycardia using bilateral accessory pathways in a patient with Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. J Electrocardiol. 1989 Apr;22(2):173-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2708934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen TH, Tsai ML, Chang PC, Wo HT, Chou CC, Wen MS, Wang CC, Yeh SJ, Wu D. Risk factors of recurrence and complication in radiofrequency catheter ablation of atrioventricular reentrant tachycardia in children and adolescents. Cardiol Young. 2013 Oct;23(5):682-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23328409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nademanee K, McKenzie J, Kosar E, Schwab M, Sunsaneewitayakul B, Vasavakul T, Khunnawat C, Ngarmukos T. A new approach for catheter ablation of atrial fibrillation: mapping of the electrophysiologic substrate. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004 Jun 02;43(11):2044-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15172410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell J, Redfearn D. Ablation of complex fractionated atrial electrograms in catheter ablation for AF; where have we been and where are we going? Curr Cardiol Rev. 2012 Nov;8(4):347-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3492817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22920481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau DH, Zeemering S, Maesen B, Kuklik P, Verheule S, Schotten U. Catheter Ablation Targeting Complex Fractionated Atrial Electrogram in Atrial Fibrillation. J Atr Fibrillation. 2013 Oct-Nov;6(3):907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5153035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berenfeld O, Jalife J. Complex fractionated atrial electrograms: is this the beast to tame in atrial fibrillation? Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2011 Aug;4(4):426-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3244075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayan SM, Krummen DE, Shivkumar K, Clopton P, Rappel WJ, Miller JM. Treatment of atrial fibrillation by the ablation of localized sources: CONFIRM (Conventional Ablation for Atrial Fibrillation With or Without Focal Impulse and Rotor Modulation) trial. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2012 Aug 14;60(7):628-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3416917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22818076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krummen DE, Swarup V, Narayan SM. The role of rotors in atrial fibrillation. J Thorac Dis. 2015 Feb;7(2):142-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4321066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25713729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi S, Sueda T. Development of the Maze procedure and the contribution of Japanese surgeons. Gen Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2017 Mar;65(3):144-152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27854045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sueda T. History and development of surgical procedures for atrial fibrillation. Surg Today. 2015 Dec;45(12):1475-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25735737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asirvatham SJ, Stevenson WG. Mapping Reentry: In, Out, Into, or In Two? Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2016 May;9(5):e003609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27153878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz M, Rodman D, Lowenstein SR. Recognition and treatment of multifocal atrial tachycardia: a critical review. J Emerg Med. 1994 May-Jun;12(3):353-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8040593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haissaguerre M, Shah AJ, Cochet H, Hocini M, Dubois R, Efimov I, Vigmond E, Bernus O, Trayanova N. Intermittent drivers anchoring to structural heterogeneities as a major pathophysiological mechanism of human persistent atrial fibrillation. J Physiol. 2016 May 01;594(9):2387-98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26890861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kapa S, Asirvatham SJ. Atrial fibrillation: focal or reentrant or both?: a new autonomic lens to examine an old riddle. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2009 Aug;2(4):345-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19808489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saoudi N, Cosio F, Waldo A, Chen SA, Iesaka Y, Lesh M, Saksena S, Salerno J, Schoels W. Classification of atrial flutter and regular atrial tachycardia according to electrophysiologic mechanism and anatomic bases: a statement from a joint expert group from the Working Group of Arrhythmias of the European Society of Cardiology and the North American Society of Pacing and Electrophysiology. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2001 Jul;12(7):852-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11469446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau DH, Volders PG, Kohl P, Prinzen FW, Zaza A, Kääb S, Oto A, Schotten U, European Heart Rhythm Association  Opportunities and challenges of current electrophysiology research: a plea to establish 'translational electrophysiology' curricula. Europace. 2015 May;17(5):825-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25691491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albert CM, Stevenson WG. The Future of Arrhythmias and Electrophysiology. Circulation. 2016 Jun 21;133(25):2687-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4930113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27324363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
