<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">30832578</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2164</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>04</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMC genomics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Genomics</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Genomic analysis of Leptospira interrogans serovar Paidjan and Dadas isolates from carrier dogs and comparative genomic analysis to detect genes under positive selection.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>168</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>168</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">168</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12864-019-5562-z</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Leptospirosis is an emerging infectious disease worldwide that can cause high morbidity and mortality rates in humans and animals. The causative spirochetes have reservoirs in mammalian hosts, but there has been limited analysis of the genomes of isolates recovered from animals. The aims of this study were to characterize genomic features of two Leptospira interrogans strains recently isolated from asymptomatic dogs in Thailand (strains CUDO5 and CDUO8), and to perform comparative genome analyses with other strains. Molecular adaptive evolution in L. interrogans as signaled by positive selection also was analyzed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Whole genome sequence analysis revealed that strains CUDO5 and CUDO8 had genome sizes of approximately 4.9 Mbp with 35.1% GC contents. Using monoclonal antibodies, strains CUDO5 and CUDO8 were identified as serovars Paidjan and Dadas, respectively. These strains harbored genes known to be associated with acute and chronic infections. Using Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms phylogeny (SNPs) with 97 L. interrogans strains, CUDO5 and CUDO8 had closest genetic relatedness with each other. Nevertheless, the serovar determinant region (rfb locus) showed variations in the genes encoding sugar biosynthesis. Amongst 13 representative L. interrogans strains examined for molecular adaptive evolution through positive selection under the site-model of Phylogenetic Analysis of Maximum Likelihood, genes responsible for iron acquisition (tlyA and hbpA), motility (fliN2, flgK, and flhB) and thermal adaptation (lpxD1) were under increased selective pressure.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">L. interrogans serovar Paidjan strain CUDO5 and serovar Dadas strain CUDO8 had close genetic relatedness as analyzed by SNPs phylogeny. They contained genes with established roles in acute and chronic leptospirosis. The rfb locus in both serovars showed gene variation associated with sugar biosynthesis. Positive selection analysis indicated that genes encoding factors involved in motility, temperature adaptation, and iron acquisition were under strong positive selection in L. interrogans. These may be associated with adaptation in the early stages of infection.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kurilung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alongkorn</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Veterinary Science, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Keeratipusana</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chantisa</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bioinformatics and Data Management for Research Unit, Office for Research and Development, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suriyaphol</LastName>
            <ForeName>Prapat</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bioinformatics and Data Management for Research Unit, Office for Research and Development, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hampson</LastName>
            <ForeName>David J</ForeName>
            <Initials>DJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases and Public Health, College of Veterinary Medicine and Life Sciences, City University of Hong Kong, Kowloon Tong, Hong Kong SAR.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prapasarakul</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nuvee</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6409-4622</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Veterinary Science, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand. nuvee.p@chula.ac.th.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Diagnosis and Monitoring of Animal Pathogens Research Unit, Department of Microbiology, Faculty of Veterinary Science, Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand. nuvee.p@chula.ac.th.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMC Genomics</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100965258</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1471-2164</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn">
          <RefSource>BMC Genomics. 2019 Mar 28;20(1):246</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">30922217</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D023281" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genomics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007921" MajorTopicYN="N">Leptospira interrogans</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007922" MajorTopicYN="N">Leptospirosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012641" MajorTopicYN="N">Selection, Genetic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D065288" MajorTopicYN="N">Serogroup</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013785" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Thailand</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dog</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leptospira interrogans</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Positive selection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Serovar Dadas</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Serovar Paidjan</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>ETHICS APPROVAL AND CONSENT TO PARTICIPATE: <i>L. interrogans</i> serovar Paidjan strain CUDO5 and serovar Dadas strain CUDO8 were isolated from the urine of asymptomatic dogs in Nan province, Thailand (year 2014). Animal sampling and biosafety consideration in this study were approved by the Chulalongkorn University Animal Care and Use Committee (CU-ACUC; Protocol number 1531075) and the Institutional Biosafety Committee (CU-VET-IBC; Protocol number 18310430). CONSENT FOR PUBLICATION: Not applicable. COMPETING INTERESTS: The authors declare that they have no competing interests. PUBLISHER’S NOTE: Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832578</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6399948</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12864-019-5562-z</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12864-019-5562-z</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adler B, de la Pena Moctezuma A. Leptospira and leptospirosis. Vet Microbiol. 2010;140(3–4):287–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19345023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wuthiekanun V, Sirisukkarn N, Daengsupa P, Sakaraserane P, Sangkakam A, Chierakul W, Smythe LD, Symonds ML, Dohnt MF, Slack AT, et al.  Clinical diagnosis and geographic distribution of leptospirosis, Thailand. Emerg Infect Dis. 2007;13(1):124–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2725830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17370525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evangelista K, Coburn J. Leptospira as an emerging pathogen: a review of its biology, pathogenesis and host immune responses. Future Microbiol. 2010;5(9):1413–1425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20860485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa F, Hagan JE, Calcagno J, Kane M, Torgerson P, Martinez-Silveira MS, Stein C, Abela-Ridder B, Ko AI. Global morbidity and mortality of leptospirosis: a systematic review. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2015;9(9):e0003898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4574773</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26379143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren SX, Fu G, Jiang XG, Zeng R, Miao YG, Xu H, Zhang YX, Xiong H, Lu G, Lu LF, et al.  Unique physiological and pathogenic features of Leptospira interrogans revealed by whole-genome sequencing. Nature. 2003;422(6934):888–893.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12712204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fouts DE, Matthias MA, Adhikarla H, Adler B, Amorim-Santos L, Berg DE, Bulach D, Buschiazzo A, Chang YF, Galloway RL, et al.  What makes a bacterial species pathogenic?:comparative genomic analysis of the genus Leptospira. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2016;10(2):e0004403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4758666</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26890609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y, Zhu Y, Wang Y, Chang YF, Zhang Y, Jiang X, Zhuang X, Zhu Y, Zhang J, Zeng L, et al.  Whole genome sequencing revealed host adaptation-focused genomic plasticity of pathogenic Leptospira. Sci Rep. 2016;6:20020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4735792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26833181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bulach DM, Zuerner RL, Wilson P, Seemann T, McGrath A, Cullen PA, Davis J, Johnson M, Kuczek E, Alt DP, et al.  Genome reduction in Leptospira borgpetersenii reflects limited transmission potential. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103(39):14560–14565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1599999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toft C, Andersson SG. Evolutionary microbial genomics: insights into bacterial host adaptation. Nat Rev Genet. 2010;11(7):465–475.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20517341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguileta G, Lengelle J, Marthey S, Chiapello H, Rodolphe F, Gendrault A, Yockteng R, Vercken E, Devier B, Fontaine MC, et al.  Finding candidate genes under positive selection in non-model species: examples of genes involved in host specialization in pathogens. Mol Ecol. 2010;19(2):292–306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20041992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguileta G, Refregier G, Yockteng R, Fournier E, Giraud T. Rapidly evolving genes in pathogens: methods for detecting positive selection and examples among fungi, bacteria, viruses and protists. Infect Genet Evol. 2009;9(4):656–670.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshizaki S, Umemura T, Tanaka K, Watanabe K, Hayashi M, Muto Y. Genome-wide evidence of positive selection in Bacteroides fragilis. Comput Biol Chem. 2014;52:43–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25215651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojas TCG, Lobo FP, Hongo JA, Vicentini R, Verma R, Maluta RP, da Silveira WD. Genome-wide survey of genes under positive selection in avian pathogenic Escherichia coli strains. Foodborne Pathog Dis. 2017;14(5):245–252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28398866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen L, Bollback JP, Dimmic M, Hubisz M, Nielsen R. Genes under positive selection in Escherichia coli. Genome Res. 2007;17(9):1336–1343.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950902</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17675366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang H, Zhou T, Zhong Y, Jin Q. Genes under positive selection in Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Comput Biol Chem. 2011;35(5):319–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22000803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soyer Y, Orsi RH, Rodriguez-Rivera LD, Sun Q, Wiedmann M. Genome wide evolutionary analyses reveal serotype specific patterns of positive selection in selected Salmonella serotypes. BMC Evol Biol. 2009;9:264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2784778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19912661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao P, Guo D, Liu J, Jiang Q, Xu Z, Qu L. Genome-wide analyses reveal genes subject to positive eelection in Pasteurella multocida. Front Microbiol. 2017;8:961.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5447721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makarova KS, Wolf YI, Alkhnbashi OS, Costa F, Shah SA, Saunders SJ, Barrangou R, Brouns SJ, Charpentier E, Haft DH, et al.  An updated evolutionary classification of CRISPR-Cas systems. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2015;13(11):722–736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5426118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26411297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurilung A, Chanchaithong P, Lugsomya K, Niyomtham W, Wuthiekanun V, Prapasarakul N. Molecular detection and isolation of pathogenic Leptospira from asymptomatic humans, domestic animals and water sources in Nan province, a rural area of Thailand. Res Vet Sci. 2017;115:146–154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28384550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebrahimizadeh W, Rajabibazl M. Bacteriophage vehicles for phage display: biology, mechanism, and application. Curr Microbiol. 2014;69(2):109–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24638925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decker CF, Hawkins RE, Simon GL. Infections with Pseudomonas paucimobilis. Clin Infect Dis. 1992;14(3):783–784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1562669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majumdar S, Zhao P, Pfister NT, Compton M, Olson S, Glover CV, 3rd, Wells L, Graveley BR, Terns RM, Terns MP. Three CRISPR-Cas immune effector complexes coexist in Pyrococcus furiosus. RNA. 2015;21(6):1147–1158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4436667</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25904135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marraffini LA, Sontheimer EJ. CRISPR interference limits horizontal gene transfer in staphylococci by targeting DNA. Science. 2008;322(5909):1843–1845.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2695655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19095942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picardeau M. Virulence of the zoonotic agent of leptospirosis: still terra incognita? Nat Rev Microbiol. 2017;15(5):297–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28260786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mira A, Martin-Cuadrado AB, D'Auria G, Rodriguez-Valera F. The bacterial pan-genome:a new paradigm in microbiology. Int Microbiol. 2010;13(2):45–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20890839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patra KP, Choudhury B, Matthias MM, Baga S, Bandyopadhya K, Vinetz JM. Comparative analysis of lipopolysaccharides of pathogenic and intermediately pathogenic Leptospira species. BMC Microbiol. 2015;15:244.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4628369</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26518696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riegert AS, Young NM, Watson DC, Thoden JB, Holden HM. Structure of the external aldimine form of PglE, an aminotransferase required for N,N'-diacetylbacillosamine biosynthesis. Protein Sci. 2015;24(10):1609–1616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26178292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nascimento AL, Ko AI, Martins EA, Monteiro-Vitorello CB, Ho PL, Haake DA, Verjovski-Almeida S, Hartskeerl RA, Marques MV, Oliveira MC, et al.  Comparative genomics of two Leptospira interrogans serovars reveals novel insights into physiology and pathogenesis. J Bacteriol. 2004;186(7):2164–2172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC374407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15028702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corvaglia AR, Francois P, Hernandez D, Perron K, Linder P, Schrenzel J. A type III-like restriction endonuclease functions as a major barrier to horizontal gene transfer in clinical Staphylococcus aureus strains. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107(26):11954–11958.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2900679</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20547849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canchaya C, Proux C, Fournous G, Bruttin A, Brussow H. Prophage genomics. Microbiol Mol Biol Rev. 2003;67(2):238–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC156470</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12794192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X, Kim Y, Ma Q, Hong SH, Pokusaeva K, Sturino JM, Wood TK. Cryptic prophages help bacteria cope with adverse environments. Nat Commun. 2010;1:147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3105296</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro BJ, David LA, Friedman J, Alm EJ. Looking for Darwin's footprints in the microbial world. Trends Microbiol. 2009;17(5):196–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19375326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko AI, Goarant C, Picardeau M. Leptospira: the dawn of the molecular genetics era for an emerging zoonotic pathogen. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2009;7(10):736–747.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19756012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraga TR, Barbosa AS, Isaac L. Leptospirosis: aspects of innate immunity, immunopathogenesis and immune evasion from the complement system. Scand J Immunol. 2011;73(5):408–419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21204903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parrow NL, Fleming RE, Minnick MF. Sequestration and scavenging of iron in infection. Infect Immun. 2013;81(10):3503–3514.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3811770</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23836822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomes-Solecki M, Santecchia I, Werts C. Animal models of leptospirosis: of mice and hamsters. Front Immunol. 2017;8:58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5318464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28270811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fontana C, Lambert A, Benaroudj N, Gasparini D, Gorgette O, Cachet N, Bomchil N, Picardeau M. Analysis of a spontaneous non-motile and avirulent mutant shows that FliM is required for full endoflagella assembly in Leptospira interrogans. PLoS One. 2016;11(4):e0152916.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4820103</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27044038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao S, Sun A, Ojcius DM, Wu S, Zhao J, Yan J. Inactivation of the fliY gene encoding a flagellar motor switch protein attenuates mobility and virulence of Leptospira interrogans strain Lai. BMC Microbiol. 2009;9:253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3224694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20003186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Powell DA, Shaffer SA, Rasko DA, Pelletier MR, Leszyk JD, Scott AJ, Masoudi A, Goodlett DR, Wang X, et al.  LPS remodeling is an evolved survival strategy for bacteria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2012;109(22):8716–8721.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3365160</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22586119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eshghi A, Henderson J, Trent MS, Picardeau M. Leptospira interrogans lpxD homologue is required for thermal acclimatization and virulence. Infect Immun. 2015;83(11):4314–4321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4598399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26283339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kassegne K, Hu W, Ojcius DM, Sun D, Ge Y, Zhao J, Yang XF, Li L, Yan J. Identification of collagenase as a critical virulence factor for invasiveness and transmission of pathogenic Leptospira species. J Infect Dis. 2014;209(7):1105–1115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24277745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monahan AM, Callanan JJ, Nally JE. Review paper: host-pathogen interactions in the kidney during chronic leptospirosis. Vet Pathol. 2009;46(5):792–799.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19429975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ristow P, Bourhy P, Kerneis S, Schmitt C, Prevost MC, Lilenbaum W, Picardeau M. Biofilm formation by saprophytic and pathogenic leptospires. Microbiology. 2008;154(Pt 5):1309–1317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18451039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nally JE, Chow E, Fishbein MC, Blanco DR, Lovett MA. Changes in lipopolysaccharide O antigen distinguish acute versus chronic Leptospira interrogans infections. Infect Immun. 2005;73(6):3251–3260.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1111870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15908349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monahan AM, Callanan JJ, Nally JE. Proteomic analysis of Leptospira interrogans shed in urine of chronically infected hosts. Infect Immun. 2008;76(11):4952–4958.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2573331</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18765721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobrindt U, Zdziarski J, Salvador E, Hacker J. Bacterial genome plasticity and its impact on adaptation during persistent infection. Int J Med Microbiol. 2010;300(6):363–366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurilung A, Keeratipusana C, Suriyaphol P, Prapasarakul N. Draft genome sequence of a Leptospira interrogans strain isolated from the urine of an asymptomatic dog in Thailand. Genome Announc. 2018;6(4):e01140-17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5786668</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29371342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coil D, Jospin G, Darling AE. A5-miseq: an updated pipeline to assemble microbial genomes from Illumina MiSeq data. Bioinformatics. 2015;31(4):587–589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25338718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assefa S, Keane TM, Otto TD, Newbold C, Berriman M. ABACAS: algorithm-based automatic contiguation of assembled sequences. Bioinformatics. 2009;25(15):1968–1969.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2712343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19497936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swain MT, Tsai IJ, Assefa SA, Newbold C, Berriman M, Otto TD. A post-assembly genome-improvement toolkit (PAGIT) to obtain annotated genomes from contigs. Nat Protoc. 2012;7(7):1260–1284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3648784</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22678431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seemann T. Prokka: rapid prokaryotic genome annotation. Bioinformatics. 2014;30(14):2068–2069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24642063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziz RK, Bartels D, Best AA, DeJongh M, Disz T, Edwards RA, Formsma K, Gerdes S, Glass EM, Kubal M, et al.  The RAST server: rapid annotations using subsystems technology. BMC Genomics. 2008;9:75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18261238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arndt D, Grant JR, Marcu A, Sajed T, Pon A, Liang Y, Wishart DS. PHASTER: a better, faster version of the PHAST phage search tool. Nucleic Acids Res. 2016;44(W1):W16–W21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4987931</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27141966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Q, Ye Y. Not all predicted CRISPR-Cas systems are equal: isolated cas genes and classes of CRISPR like elements. BMC Bioinformatics. 2017;18(1):92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5294841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28166719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biswas A, Gagnon JN, Brouns SJ, Fineran PC, Brown CM. CRISPRTarget: bioinformatic prediction and analysis of crRNA targets. RNA Biol. 2013;10(5):817–827.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23492433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen L, Zheng D, Liu B, Yang J, Jin Q. VFDB 2016: hierarchical and refined dataset for big data analysis--10 years on. Nucleic Acids Res. 2016;44(D1):D694–D697.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702877</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26578559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murray GL. The molecular basis of leptospiral pathogenesis. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2015;387:139–186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rost B. Twilight zone of protein sequence alignments. Protein Eng. 1999;12(2):85–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10195279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez NF, Gundersen GW, Rahman A, Grimes ML, Rikova K, Hornbeck P, Ma’ayan A. Clustergrammer, a web-based heatmap visualization and analysis tool for high-dimensional biological data. Sci Data. 2017;4:170151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5634325</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28994825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter M, Rossello-Mora R, Oliver Glockner F, Peplies J. JSpeciesWS: a web server for prokaryotic species circumscription based on pairwise genome comparison. Bioinformatics. 2016;32(6):929–931.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5939971</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26576653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Treangen TJ, Ondov BD, Koren S, Phillippy AM. The harvest suite for rapid core-genome alignment and visualization of thousands of intraspecific microbial genomes. Genome Biol. 2014;15(11):524.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4262987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stamatakis A. RAxML version 8: a tool for phylogenetic analysis and post-analysis of large phylogenies. Bioinformatics. 2014;30(9):1312–1313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3998144</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24451623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H, Gao S, Lercher MJ, Hu S, Chen WH. EvolView, an online tool for visualizing, annotating and managing phylogenetic trees. Nucleic Acids Res. 2012;40(Web Server issue):W569–W572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3394307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22695796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaudhari NM, Gupta VK, Dutta C. BPGA- an ultra-fast pan-genome analysis pipeline. Sci Rep. 2016;6:24373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4829868</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27071527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tettelin H, Riley D, Cattuto C, Medini D. Comparative genomics: the bacterial pan-genome. Curr Opin Microbiol. 2008;11(5):472–477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19086349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huerta-Cepas J, Forslund K, Coelho LP, Szklarczyk D, Jensen LJ, von Mering C, Bork P. Fast genome-wide functional annotation through orthology assignment by eggNOG-mapper. Mol Biol Evol. 2017;34(8):2115–2122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5850834</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28460117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Contreras-Moreira B, Vinuesa P. GET_HOMOLOGUES, a versatile software package for scalable and robust microbial pangenome analysis. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2013;79(24):7696–7701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3837814</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24096415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suyama M, Torrents D, Bork P. PAL2NAL: robust conversion of protein sequence alignments into the corresponding codon alignments. Nucleic Acids Res. 2006;34(Web Server issue):W609–W612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1538804</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Z. PAML 4: phylogenetic analysis by maximum likelihood. Mol Biol Evol. 2007;24(8):1586–1591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17483113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Z, Wong WS, Nielsen R. Bayes empirical bayes inference of amino acid sites under positive selection. Mol Biol Evol. 2005;22(4):1107–1118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruen TC, Philippe H, Bryant D. A simple and robust statistical test for detecting the presence of recombination. Genetics. 2006;172(4):2665–2681.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1456386</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16489234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin D, Rybicki E. RDP: detection of recombination amongst aligned sequences. Bioinformatics. 2000;16(6):562–563.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10980155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the false discovery rate - a practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. J Roy Stat Soc B Met. 1995;57(1):289–300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dabney A, Storey JD, Warnes GR: qvalue: Q-value estimation for false discovery rate control. R package version 12420 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelley LA, Mezulis S, Yates CM, Wass MN, Sternberg MJ. The Phyre2 web portal for protein modeling, prediction and analysis. Nat Protoc. 2015;10(6):845–858.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5298202</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25950237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alikhan NF, Petty NK, Ben Zakour NL, Beatson SA. BLAST ring Image generator (BRIG): simple prokaryote genome comparisons. BMC Genomics. 2011;12:402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3163573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21824423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
