<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31088546</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>14</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of Kinesio tape on lower limb muscle strength, hop test, and vertical jump performances: a meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>212</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>212</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">212</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-019-2564-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To date, published systematic reviews concerning the effects of Kinesio Taping (KT) on muscle strength have not analysed facilitatory and inhibitory applications separately. As a result, their results could be substantially affected by clinical heterogeneity. This meta-analysis was conducted to determine the effectiveness of using a facilitatory application of KT for lower limb muscle strength and functional performance (distance in a single-leg hop and vertical jump height) in individuals without disabilities and in those with musculoskeletal conditions (muscle fatigue, chronic musculoskeletal diseases, and post-operative orthopaedic conditions).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Searches were conducted on six major electronic databases. Randomised controlled trials that used facilitatory KT were included. Standardised mean differences (SMDs) were calculated and random-effects models were used for analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirty-seven randomised controlled trials were included. KT was superior to controls for improving lower limb muscle strength in individuals with muscle fatigue (short-term effect, pooled SMD = 0.53, 95% CI = 0.09 to 0.96; long-term effect, pooled SMD = 0.61, 95% CI = 0.12 to 1.11) and in individuals with chronic musculoskeletal diseases (pooled SMD = 1.24, 95% CI = 0.33 to 2.16) with large effect sizes. The use of KT in populations without disabilities was not supported. There is insufficient evidence for the effect of KT on functional performance in individuals with musculoskeletal conditions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Contrary to prior research, the existing evidence shows that KT can improve lower limb muscle strength in individuals with muscle fatigue and chronic musculoskeletal diseases. The effect sizes produced in this meta-analysis show that KT may be superior to some existing treatments for these conditions. In addition, this study suggests that practitioners may wish to avoid the use of KT in individuals without disabilities.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">PROSPERO registration number CRD42017075490 , registered on 21 November 2017.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ming Lok</ForeName>
            <Initials>ML</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>JC School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, The Jockey Club School of Public Health Building, Prince of Wales Hospital, Shatin, New Territories, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zuyao</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>JC School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, The Jockey Club School of Public Health Building, Prince of Wales Hospital, Shatin, New Territories, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Benny Chung-Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>BC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>JC School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, The Jockey Club School of Public Health Building, Prince of Wales Hospital, Shatin, New Territories, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Shenzhen Research Institute, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ka Chun</ForeName>
            <Initials>KC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>JC School of Public Health and Primary Care, Faculty of Medicine, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, The Jockey Club School of Public Health Building, Prince of Wales Hospital, Shatin, New Territories, Hong Kong, China. marc@cuhk.edu.hk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Shenzhen Research Institute, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen, China. marc@cuhk.edu.hk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D023362">Evaluation Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D035002" MajorTopicYN="N">Lower Extremity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018763" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Fatigue</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009140" MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional performance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Knee osteoarthritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle fatigue</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle strength</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patellofemoral pain syndrome</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>ETHICS APPROVAL AND CONSENT TO PARTICIPATE: No formal ethical approval and consent to participate are required due to no collection of primary data. CONSENT FOR PUBLICATION: No consent for publication is required due to no personal data included. COMPETING INTERESTS: The authors declare that they have no competing interests. PUBLISHER’S NOTE: Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088546</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518687</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-019-2564-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-019-2564-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guner S, Alsancak S, Koz M. Effect of two different kinesio taping techniques on knee kinematics and kinetics in young females. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27(10):3093–3096.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4668142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vithoulk I, Beneka A, Malliou P, Aggelousis N, Karatsolis K, Diamantopoulos K. The effects of kinesio-taping® on quadriceps strength during isokinetic exercise in healthy non athlete women. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2010;18(1):1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuo YL, Huang YC. Effects of the application direction of Kinesio taping on isometric muscle strength of the wrist and fingers of healthy adults — a pilot study. J Phys Ther Sci. 2013;25(3):287–291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeung SS, Yeung EW. Acute effects of kinesio taping on knee extensor peak torque and stretch reflex in healthy adults. Medicine (Baltimore) 2016;95(4):e2615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5291586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26825916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Wei-Ting, Hong Chang-Zern, Chou Li-Wei. The Kinesio Taping Method for Myofascial Pain Control. Evidence-Based Complementary and Alternative Medicine. 2015;2015:1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4491400</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26185522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang WD, Chen FC, Lee CL, Lin HY, Lai PT. Effects of Kinesio taping versus McConnell taping for patellofemoral pain syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2015;2015:471208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4491411</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26185517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu Z, Li X, Chen R, Guo C. Kinesio taping improves pain and function in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Surg. 2018;59:27–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parreira Pdo C, Costa Lda C, Hespanhol LC, Jr, Lopes AD, Costa LO. Current evidence does not support the use of Kinesio taping in clinical practice: a systematic review. J Physiother. 2014;60(1):31–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim EC, Tay MG. Kinesio taping in musculoskeletal pain and disability that lasts for more than 4 weeks: is it time to peel off the tape and throw it out with the sweat? A systematic review with meta-analysis focused on pain and also methods of tape application. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(24):1558–1566.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25595290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Csapo R, Alegre LM. Effects of kinesio(®) taping on skeletal muscle strength-a meta-analysis of current evidence. J Sci Med Sport. 2015;18(4):450–456.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25027771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn IK, Kim YL, Bae YH, Lee SM. Immediate effects of kinesiology taping of quadriceps on motor performance after muscle fatigued induction. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2015;2015:410526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4503544</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26246835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boobphachart D, Manimmanakorn N, Manimmanakorn A, Thuwakum W, Hamlin MJ. Effects of elastic taping, non-elastic taping and static stretching on recovery after intensive eccentric exercise. Res Sports Med. 2017;25(2):181–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28121177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boozari S, Sanjari MA, Amiri A, Ebrahimi TI. Effect of gastrocnemius kinesio taping on countermovement jump performance and vertical stiffness following muscle fatigue. J Sport Rehabil. 2018;27(4):306–311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28513277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haksever B, Kinikli GL, Tunay VB, Karahan S, Donmez G. Effect of kinesiotaping intervention on knee muscle strength and delayed onset muscle soreness pain following eccentric fatigue training. Turkish Journal of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation. 2016;27(1):12–18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeung SS, Yeung EW, Sakunkaruna Y, Mingsoongnern S, Hung WY, Fan YL, et al.  Acute effects of kinesio taping on knee extensor peak torque and electromyographic activity after exhaustive isometric knee extension in healthy young adults. Clin J Sport Med. 2015;25(3):284–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25010152</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baştürk D, Gökdemir K, Kaya M, Ünüvar BS, Taşkin H, Erkmen N. Effect of kinesio taping on fuctional performance in football players. Sport Scientific And Practical Aspects. 2015;12(2):39–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung RT, Yau QK, Wong K, Lau P, So A, Chan N, et al.  Kinesiology tape does not promote vertical jumping performance: a deceptive crossover trial. Man Ther. 2016;21:89–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26139360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dos Santos Glória IP, Politti F, Leal Junior ECP, Lucareli PRG, Herpich CM, Antonialli FC, et al.  Kinesio taping does not alter muscle torque, muscle activity or jumping performance in professional soccer players: a randomized, placebo-controlled, blind, clinical trial. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2017;30(4):869–877.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28282794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandes de Jesus J, de Almeida Novello A, Bezerra Nakaoka G, Curcio Dos Reis A, Fukuda TY, Fernandes Bryk F. Kinesio taping effect on quadriceps strength and lower limb function of healthy individuals: A blinded, controlled, randomized, clinical trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2016;18:27–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26708093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Jesus JF, Franco YR, Nannini SB, Nakaoka GB, Dos Reis AC, Bryk FF. The effects of varied tensions of kinesiology taping on quadriceps strength and lower limb function. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2017;12(1):85–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296714</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28217419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guedes R, Bottaro M, Magalhães I, Trindade M, Brown LE, Jd C, et al.  The effects of kinesiotaping on quadriceps muscle performance at different velocities: a randomized controlled trial. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2016;24(2):149–156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee NH, Jung HC, Ok G, Lee S. Acute effects of kinesio taping on muscle function and self-perceived fatigue level in healthy adults. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(6):757–764.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28287046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lins CA, Borges DT, Macedo LB, Costa KS, Brasileiro JS. Delayed effect of kinesio taping on neuromuscular performance, balance, and lower limb function in healthy individuals: a randomized controlled trial. Braz J Phys Ther. 2016;20(3):231–239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4946839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27437714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magalhães I, Bottaro M, Mezzarane RA, Neto FR, Rodrigues BA, Ferreira-Júnior JB, et al.  Kinesiotaping enhances the rate of force development but not the neuromuscular efficiency of physically active young men. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2016;28:123–129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27128956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magalhães I, Bottaro M, Freitas JR, Carmo J, Matheus JP, Carregaro RL. Prolonged use of kinesiotaping does not enhance functional performance and joint proprioception in healthy young males: randomized controlled trial. Braz J Phys Ther. 2016;20(3):213–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4946837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27437712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostaghim N, Jahromi MK, Shirazzi ZR, Salesi M. The effect of quadriceps femoris muscle kinesio taping on physical fitness indices in non-injured athletes. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2016;56(12):1526–1533.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27029956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poon KY, Li SM, Roper MG, Wong MK, Wong O, Cheung RT. Kinesiology tape does not facilitate muscle performance: a deceptive controlled trial. Man Ther. 2015;20(1):130–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25150913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serra MV, Vieira ER, Brunt D, Goethel MF, Goncalves M, Quemelo PR. Kinesio taping effects on knee extension force among soccer players. Braz J Phys Ther. 2015;19(2):152–158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4481836</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25789557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson V, Douris P, Fukuroku T, Kuzniewski M, Dias J, Figueiredo P. The immediate and long-term effects of kinesiotape® on balance and functional performance. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2016;11(2):247–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4827367</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27104058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anandkumar S, Sudarshan S, Nagpal P. Efficacy of kinesio taping on isokinetic quadriceps torque in knee osteoarthritis: a double blinded randomized controlled study. Physiother Theory Pract. 2014;30(6):375–383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24617598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aydoğdu O, Sari Z, Yurdalan SU, Polat MG. Clinical outcomes of kinesio taping applied in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. 2017;30(5):1045–1051.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28655128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhanakotti S, Samuel RK, Thakar M, Doshi S, Vadsola K. Effects of additional kinesiotaping over the conventional physiotherapy exercise on pain, quadriceps strength and knee functional disability in knee osteoarthritis participants- a randomized controlled study. Int J Health Sci Res. 2016;6(1):221–229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaya Mutlu E, Mustafaoglu R, Birinci T, Razak OA. Does kinesio taping of the knee improve pain and functionality in patients with knee osteoarthritis?: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;96(1):25–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27149590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim KM, Davis B, Hertel J, Hart J. Effects of kinesio taping in patients with quadriceps inhibition: a randomized, single-blinded study. Phys Ther Sport. 2017;24:67–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28126423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balki S, Goktas HE, Oztemur Z. Kinesio taping as a treatment method in the acute phase of ACL reconstruction: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Acta Orthop Traumatol Turc. 2016;50(6):628–634.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6197419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27784622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balki S, Goktas HE. Short-term effects of the kinesio taping(R) on early postoperative hip muscle weakness in male patients with hamstring autograft or allograft anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction. J Sport Rehabil. 2017:1–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29252113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harput G, Ulusoy B, Ozer H, Baltaci G, Richards J. External supports improve knee performance in anterior cruciate ligament reconstructed individuals with higher kinesiophobia levels. Knee. 2016;23(5):807–812.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27460554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira AK, Borges DT, Lins CA, Cavalcanti RL, Macedo LB, Brasileiro JS. Immediate effects of kinesio taping (®) on neuromuscular performance of quadriceps and balance in individuals submitted to anterior cruciate ligament reconstruction: a randomized clinical trial. J Sci Med Sport. 2016;19(1):2–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen CH, Huang TS, Chai HM, Jan MH, Lin JJ. Two stretching treatments for the hamstrings: proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation versus kinesio taping. J Sport Rehabil. 2013;22(1):59–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23069636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bicici S, Karatas N, Baltaci G. Effect of athletic taping and kinesiotaping® on measurements of functional performance in basketball players with chronic inversion ankle sprains. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2012;7(2):154–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325641</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegedus EJ, McDonough SM, Bleakley C, Baxter D, Cook CE. Clinician-friendly lower extremity physical performance tests in athletes: a systematic review of measurement properties and correlation with injury. Part 2--the tests for the hip, thigh, foot and ankle including the star excursion balance test. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(10):649–656.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25614536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chou R, Huffman LH. American pain society, American College of Physicians. Medications for acute and chronic low back pain: a review of the evidence for an American pain society/American College of Physicians clinical practice guideline. Ann Intern Med. 2007;147(7):505–514.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Słupik A, Dwornik M, Bialoszewski D, Zych E. Effect of kinesio taping on bioelectrical activity of vastus medialis muscle. Preliminary report. Ortop Traumatol Rehabil. 2007;9(6):644–651.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18227756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knapik JJ, Ramos MU. Isokinetic and isometric torque relationships in the human body. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1980;61(2):64–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7369840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kase K, Wallis J, Kase T.  Clinical therapeutic applications of the kinesio taping method. 2. Tokyo: Ken Ikai Co. Ltd.; 2003. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teasell R, Bayona N, Marshall S, Cullen N, Bayley M, Chundamala J, et al.  A systematic review of the rehabilitation of moderate to severe acquired brain injuries. Brain Inj. 2007;21(2):107–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17364527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warren GL, Park ND, Maresca RD, McKibans KI, Millard-Stafford ML. Effect of caffeine ingestion on muscular strength and endurance: a meta-analysis. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(7):1375–1387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rastogi R, Davis AM, Chesworth BM. A cross-sectional look at patient concerns in the first six weeks following primary total knee arthroplasty. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2007;5:48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1950700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17678532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Hoyo M, Alvarez-Mesa A, Sanudo B, Carrasco L, Dominguez S. Immediate effect of kinesio taping on muscle response in young elite soccer players. J Sport Rehabil. 2013;22(1):53–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23006787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koç I, Güzel NA, Baltacı G, Akarçeşme C. The effect of kinesiotaping on isokinetic knee strength during long term volleyball training program. Turkish Journal of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation. 2016;27(3):89–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korman P, Straburzyńska-Lupa A, Rutkowski R, Gruszczyński J, Lewandowski J, Straburzyński-Lupa M, et al.  Kinesio taping does not alter quadriceps isokinetic strength and power in healthy nonathletic men: a prospective crossover study. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:626257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4706860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26819953</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aktas G, Baltacı G. Does kinesiotaping increase knee muscles strength and functional performance? Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2011;19(3):149–155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu TC, Wong AM, Pei YC, Wu KP, Chou SW, Lin YC. Effect of kinesio taping on muscle strength in athletes-a pilot study. J Sci Med Sport. 2008;11(2):198–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17588814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lins CA, Neto FL, Amorim AB, Macedo Lde B, Brasileiro JS. Kinesio taping(®) does not alter neuromuscular performance of femoral quadriceps or lower limb function in healthy subjects: randomized, blind, controlled, clinical trial. Man Ther. 2013;18(1):41–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunes GS, de Noronha M, Cunha HS, Ruschel C, Borges NG., Jr Effect of kinesio taping on jumping and balance in athletes: a crossover randomized controlled trial. J Strength Cond Res. 2013;27(11):3183–3189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23439339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vercelli S, Sartorio F, Foti C, Colletto L, Virton D, Ronconi G, et al.  Immediate effects of kinesiotaping on quadriceps muscle strength: a single-blind, placebo-controlled crossover trial. Clin J Sport Med. 2012;22(4):319–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22450591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong OM, Cheung RT, Li RC. Isokinetic knee function in healthy subjects with and without kinesio taping. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13(4):255–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23068902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aytar A, Ozunlu N, Surenkok O, Baltacı G, Oztop P, Karatas M. Initial effects of kinesio® taping in patients with patellofemoral pain syndrome: a randomized, double-blind study. Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2011;19(2):135–142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nédélec M, McCall A, Carling C, Legall F, Berthoin S, Dupont G. Recovery in soccer : part ii-recovery strategies. Sports Med. 2013;43(1):9–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23315753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leeder J, Gissane C, van Someren K, Gregson W, Howatson G. Cold water immersion and recovery from strenuous exercise: a meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2012;46(4):233–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21947816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill J, Howatson G, van Someren K, Leeder J, Pedlar C. Compression garments and recovery from exercise-induced muscle damage: a meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2014;48(18):1340–1346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23757486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo J, Li L, Gong Y, Zhu R, Xu J, Zou J, et al.  Massage alleviates delayed onset muscle soreness after strenuous exercise: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Physiol. 2017;8:747.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5623674</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29021762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruce-Brand RA, Walls RJ, Ong JC, Emerson BS, O'Byrne JM, Moyna NM. Effects of home-based resistance training and neuromuscular electrical stimulation in knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2012;13:118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3493368</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22759883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartholdy C, Juhl C, Christensen R, Lund H, Zhang W, Henriksen M. The role of muscle strengthening in exercise therapy for knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-regression analysis of randomized trials. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2017;47(1):9–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28438380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giggins O, Fullen B, Coughlan G. Neuromuscular electrical stimulation in the treatment of knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil. 2012;26(10):867–881.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22324059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Windisch C, Brodt S, Rohner E, Matziolis G. Effects of kinesio taping compared to arterio-venous impulse system on limb swelling and skin temperature after total knee arthroplasty. Int Orthop. 2017;41(2):301–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27688220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar-Ferrandiz ME, Castro-Sanchez AM, Mataran-Penarrocha GA, Guisado-Barrilao R, Garcia-Rios MC, Moreno-Lorenzo C. A randomized controlled trial of a mixed kinesio taping-compression technique on venous symptoms, pain, peripheral venous flow, clinical severity and overall health status in postmenopausal women with chronic venous insufficiency. Clin Rehabil. 2014;28(1):69–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23426563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang JM, Lee JH. Is kinesio taping to generate skin convolutions effective for increasing local blood circulation? Med Sci Monit. 2018;24:288–293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5776879</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29332101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodward KA, Unnithan V, Hopkins ND. Forearm skin blood flow after kinesiology taping in healthy soccer players: an exploratory investigation. J Athl Train. 2015;50(10):1069–1075.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen Trevor J., Jones Tyson, Tsay Anthony, Morgan David L., Proske Uwe. Muscle damage produced by isometric contractions in human elbow flexors. Journal of Applied Physiology. 2018;124(2):388–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29074710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocyigit F, Acar M, Turkmen MB, Kose T, Guldane N, Kuyucu E. Kinesio taping or just taping in shoulder subacromial impingement syndrome? A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Physiother Theory Pract. 2016;32(7):501–508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27617500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konishi Y. Tactile stimulation with kinesiology tape alleviates muscle weakness attributable to attenuation of Ia afferents. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16(1):45–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22682093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tu SJ, Woledge RC, Morrissey D. Does 'Kinesio tape' alter thoracolumbar fascia movement during lumbar flexion? An observational laboratory study. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2016;20(4):898–905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27814872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Findley T, Chaudhry H, Dhar S. Transmission of muscle force to fascia during exercise. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2015;19(1):119–123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25603751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal NA, Torner JC, Felson D, Niu J, Sharma L, Lewis CE, et al.  The effect of thigh strength on incident radiographic and symptomatic knee osteoarthritis in the multicenter osteoarthritis (MOST) study. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;61(9):1210–1217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2830551</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher David, Liberati Alessandro, Tetzlaff Jennifer, Altman Douglas G. Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses: The PRISMA Statement. PLoS Medicine. 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
