<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31082100</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK541056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920">Cardiomyopathy Imaging</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khalil</LastName><ForeName>Hassan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The George Washington University</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alzahrani</LastName><ForeName>Talal</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The George Washington University</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Cardiomyopathies are a heterogenic group of diseases of the myocardium, which further classify into primary “confined to the heart, “or secondary “related to systemic disease.” The primary cardiomyopathies are divided into genetic “including hypertrophic, arrhythmogenic right ventricular, left ventricular noncompaction, Danon glycogen storage disease and others”; and acquired “including acute myocarditis, stress-induced (Takotsubo), peripartum, and tachycardia-induced cardiomyopathies." The secondary cardiomyopathies occur due to systemic diseases. These include infiltrative diseases such as amyloidosis, Gaucher disease, Hunter disease, and Hurler disease. Storage diseases, medication toxicity, inflammatory disease, and endocrinology diseases can also lead to secondary cardiomyopathy. Diagnosis of the etiology of cardiomyopathy starts with a thorough history and physical exam, including obtaining detailed social and family history, a careful review of medication and substance use, and followed by diagnostic tools including electrocardiogram, laboratory testing, imaging studies, and may require a myocardial biopsy to reach the definitive diagnosis. Echocardiogram, cardiac MRI, cardiac CT, and nuclear medicine imaging are the primary imaging modalities used for both work up and follow up on patients with cardiomyopathies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s1">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s2">Plain Films</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s3">Computed Tomography</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s4">Magnetic Resonance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s5">Nuclear Medicine</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s6">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s7">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18920" sec="article-18920.s8">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Maron BJ, Towbin JA, Thiene G, Antzelevitch C, Corrado D, Arnett D, Moss AJ, Seidman CE, Young JB, American Heart Association. Council on Clinical Cardiology, Heart Failure and Transplantation Committee. Quality of Care and Outcomes Research and Functional Genomics and Translational Biology Interdisciplinary Working Groups. Council on Epidemiology and Prevention  Contemporary definitions and classification of the cardiomyopathies: an American Heart Association Scientific Statement from the Council on Clinical Cardiology, Heart Failure and Transplantation Committee; Quality of Care and Outcomes Research and Functional Genomics and Translational Biology Interdisciplinary Working Groups; and Council on Epidemiology and Prevention. Circulation. 2006 Apr 11;113(14):1807-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badgett RG, Mulrow CD, Otto PM, Ramírez G. How well can the chest radiograph diagnose left ventricular dysfunction? J Gen Intern Med. 1996 Oct;11(10):625-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8945695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parada H, Carrasco HA, Añez N, Fuenmayor C, Inglessis I. Cardiac involvement is a constant finding in acute Chagas' disease: a clinical, parasitological and histopathological study. Int J Cardiol. 1997 Jun 27;60(1):49-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9209939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbel R, Schweizer P, Krebs W, Meyer J, Effert S. Sensitivity and specificity of two-dimensional echocardiography in detection of impaired left ventricular function. Eur Heart J. 1984 Jun;5(6):477-89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6745290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas DE, Wheeler R, Yousef ZR, Masani ND. The role of echocardiography in guiding management in dilated cardiomyopathy. Eur J Echocardiogr. 2009 Dec;10(8):iii15-21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19889654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang RM, Badano LP, Mor-Avi V, Afilalo J, Armstrong A, Ernande L, Flachskampf FA, Foster E, Goldstein SA, Kuznetsova T, Lancellotti P, Muraru D, Picard MH, Rietzschel ER, Rudski L, Spencer KT, Tsang W, Voigt JU. Recommendations for cardiac chamber quantification by echocardiography in adults: an update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2015 Jan;28(1):1-39.e14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25559473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sengeløv M, Jørgensen PG, Jensen JS, Bruun NE, Olsen FJ, Fritz-Hansen T, Nochioka K, Biering-Sørensen T. Global Longitudinal Strain Is a Superior Predictor of All-Cause Mortality in Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2015 Dec;8(12):1351-1359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26577264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamo L, Perry A, Novak E, Makan M, Lindman BR, Mann DL. Abnormal Global Longitudinal Strain Predicts Future Deterioration of Left Ventricular Function in Heart Failure Patients With a Recovered Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction. Circ Heart Fail. 2017 Jun;10(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5505492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28559418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun JP, James KB, Yang XS, Solankhi N, Shah MS, Arheart KL, Thomas JD, Stewart WJ. Comparison of mortality rates and progression of left ventricular dysfunction in patients with idiopathic dilated cardiomyopathy and dilated versus nondilated right ventricular cavities. Am J Cardiol. 1997 Dec 15;80(12):1583-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9416940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Groote P, Millaire A, Foucher-Hossein C, Nugue O, Marchandise X, Ducloux G, Lablanche JM. Right ventricular ejection fraction is an independent predictor of survival in patients with moderate heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1998 Oct;32(4):948-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9768716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sliwa K, Hilfiker-Kleiner D, Petrie MC, Mebazaa A, Pieske B, Buchmann E, Regitz-Zagrosek V, Schaufelberger M, Tavazzi L, van Veldhuisen DJ, Watkins H, Shah AJ, Seferovic PM, Elkayam U, Pankuweit S, Papp Z, Mouquet F, McMurray JJ, Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Peripartum Cardiomyopathy  Current state of knowledge on aetiology, diagnosis, management, and therapy of peripartum cardiomyopathy: a position statement from the Heart Failure Association of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on peripartum cardiomyopathy. Eur J Heart Fail. 2010 Aug;12(8):767-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20675664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigna C, Russo A, De Rito V, Perna GP, Testa M, Lombardo A, Lanna P, Langialonga T, Salvatori MP, Fanelli R, Loperfido F. Regional wall motion analysis by dobutamine stess echocardiography to distinguish between ischemic and nonischemic dilated cardiomyopathy. Am Heart J. 1996 Mar;131(3):537-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8604635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White HD, Norris RM, Brown MA, Brandt PW, Whitlock RM, Wild CJ. Left ventricular end-systolic volume as the major determinant of survival after recovery from myocardial infarction. Circulation. 1987 Jul;76(1):44-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3594774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acquatella H. Echocardiography in Chagas heart disease. Circulation. 2007 Mar 06;115(9):1124-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salles G, Xavier S, Sousa A, Hasslocher-Moreno A, Cardoso C. Prognostic value of QT interval parameters for mortality risk stratification in Chagas' disease: results of a long-term follow-up study. Circulation. 2003 Jul 22;108(3):305-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12835217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acquatella H, Asch FM, Barbosa MM, Barros M, Bern C, Cavalcante JL, Echeverria Correa LE, Lima J, Marcus R, Marin-Neto JA, Migliore R, Milei J, Morillo CA, Nunes MCP, Campos Vieira ML, Viotti R. Recommendations for Multimodality Cardiac Imaging in Patients with Chagas Disease: A Report from the American Society of Echocardiography in Collaboration With the InterAmerican Association of Echocardiography (ECOSIAC) and the Cardiovascular Imaging Department of the Brazilian Society of Cardiology (DIC-SBC). J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2018 Jan;31(1):3-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. American Association for Thoracic Surgery. American Society of Echocardiography. American Society of Nuclear Cardiology. Heart Failure Society of America. Heart Rhythm Society. Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions. Society of Thoracic Surgeons. Gersh BJ, Maron BJ, Bonow RO, Dearani JA, Fifer MA, Link MS, Naidu SS, Nishimura RA, Ommen SR, Rakowski H, Seidman CE, Towbin JA, Udelson JE, Yancy CW. 2011 ACCF/AHA guideline for the diagnosis and treatment of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2011 Dec;142(6):1303-38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22093712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron MS, Olivotto I, Betocchi S, Casey SA, Lesser JR, Losi MA, Cecchi F, Maron BJ. Effect of left ventricular outflow tract obstruction on clinical outcome in hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. N Engl J Med. 2003 Jan 23;348(4):295-303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12540642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron MS, Olivotto I, Zenovich AG, Link MS, Pandian NG, Kuvin JT, Nistri S, Cecchi F, Udelson JE, Maron BJ. Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy is predominantly a disease of left ventricular outflow tract obstruction. Circulation. 2006 Nov 21;114(21):2232-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17088454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nistri S, Olivotto I, Betocchi S, Losi MA, Valsecchi G, Pinamonti B, Conte MR, Casazza F, Galderisi M, Maron BJ, Cecchi F. Prognostic significance of left atrial size in patients with hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (from the Italian Registry for Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy). Am J Cardiol. 2006 Oct 01;98(7):960-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiemstra YL, Debonnaire P, Bootsma M, van Zwet EW, Delgado V, Schalij MJ, Atsma DE, Bax JJ, Marsan NA. Global Longitudinal Strain and Left Atrial Volume Index Provide Incremental Prognostic Value in Patients With Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2017 Jul;10(7)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiemstra YL, Debonnaire P, van Zwet EW, Bootsma M, Schalij MJ, Bax JJ, Delgado V, Marsan NA. Development of and Progression of Overt Heart Failure in Nonobstructive Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2018 Aug 15;122(4):656-662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30205890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib G, Bucciarelli-Ducci C, Caforio ALP, Cardim N, Charron P, Cosyns B, Dehaene A, Derumeaux G, Donal E, Dweck MR, Edvardsen T, Erba PA, Ernande L, Gaemperli O, Galderisi M, Grapsa J, Jacquier A, Klingel K, Lancellotti P, Neglia D, Pepe A, Perrone-Filardi P, Petersen SE, Plein S, Popescu BA, Reant P, Sade LE, Salaun E, Slart RHJA, Tribouilloy C, Zamorano J, EACVI Scientific Documents Committee. Indian Academy of Echocardiography  Multimodality Imaging in Restrictive Cardiomyopathies: An EACVI expert consensus document In collaboration with the "Working Group on myocardial and pericardial diseases" of the European Society of Cardiology Endorsed by The Indian Academy of Echocardiography. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2017 Oct 01;18(10):1090-1121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28510718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunaratnam K, Wong LH, Nasis A, Ellims A, Nandurkar D, Soo G, Cameron J, Troupis J. Review of cardiomyopathy imaging. Eur J Radiol. 2013 Oct;82(10):1763-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23827801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seward JB, Casaclang-Verzosa G. Infiltrative cardiovascular diseases: cardiomyopathies that look alike. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010 Apr 27;55(17):1769-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20413025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein AL, Hatle LK, Burstow DJ, Taliercio CP, Seward JB, Kyle RA, Bailey KR, Gertz MA, Tajik AJ. Comprehensive Doppler assessment of right ventricular diastolic function in cardiac amyloidosis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1990 Jan;15(1):99-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2295749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee GY, Kim K, Choi JO, Kim SJ, Kim JS, Choe YH, Grogan MA, Jeon ES. Cardiac amyloidosis without increased left ventricular wall thickness. Mayo Clin Proc. 2014 Jun;89(6):781-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24702732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellavia D, Pellikka PA, Abraham TP, Al-Zahrani GB, Dispenzieri A, Oh JK, Bailey KR, Wood CM, Lacy MQ, Miyazaki C, Miller FA. Evidence of impaired left ventricular systolic function by Doppler myocardial imaging in patients with systemic amyloidosis and no evidence of cardiac involvement by standard two-dimensional and Doppler echocardiography. Am J Cardiol. 2008 Apr 01;101(7):1039-45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18359328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baccouche H, Maunz M, Beck T, Gaa E, Banzhaf M, Knayer U, Fogarassy P, Beyer M. Differentiating cardiac amyloidosis and hypertrophic cardiomyopathy by use of three-dimensional speckle tracking echocardiography. Echocardiography. 2012 Jul;29(6):668-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22486396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel AR, Dubrey SW, Mendes LA, Skinner M, Cupples A, Falk RH, Davidoff R. Right ventricular dilation in primary amyloidosis: an independent predictor of survival. Am J Cardiol. 1997 Aug 15;80(4):486-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9285663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blankstein R, Waller AH. Evaluation of Known or Suspected Cardiac Sarcoidosis. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2016 Mar;9(3):e000867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26926267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeudy J, Burke AP, White CS, Kramer GB, Frazier AA. Cardiac sarcoidosis: the challenge of radiologic-pathologic correlation: from the radiologic pathology archives. Radiographics. 2015 May-Jun;35(3):657-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galderisi M. Diastolic dysfunction and diabetic cardiomyopathy: evaluation by Doppler echocardiography. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006 Oct 17;48(8):1548-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17045886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saguner AM, Vecchiati A, Baldinger SH, Rüeger S, Medeiros-Domingo A, Mueller-Burri AS, Haegeli LM, Biaggi P, Manka R, Lüscher TF, Fontaine G, Delacrétaz E, Jenni R, Held L, Brunckhorst C, Duru F, Tanner FC. Different prognostic value of functional right ventricular parameters in arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy/dysplasia. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2014 Mar;7(2):230-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24515411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad A, Lerman A, Rihal CS. Apical ballooning syndrome (Tako-Tsubo or stress cardiomyopathy): a mimic of acute myocardial infarction. Am Heart J. 2008 Mar;155(3):408-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18294473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh K, Neil CJ, Nguyen TH, Stansborough J, Chong CR, Dawson D, Frenneaux MP, Horowitz JD. Dissociation of early shock in takotsubo cardiomyopathy from either right or left ventricular systolic dysfunction. Heart Lung Circ. 2014 Dec;23(12):1141-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25043578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biagini E, Ragni L, Ferlito M, Pasquale F, Lofiego C, Leone O, Rocchi G, Perugini E, Zagnoni S, Branzi A, Picchio FM, Rapezzi C. Different types of cardiomyopathy associated with isolated ventricular noncompaction. Am J Cardiol. 2006 Sep 15;98(6):821-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16950194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenni R, Oechslin E, Schneider J, Attenhofer Jost C, Kaufmann PA. Echocardiographic and pathoanatomical characteristics of isolated left ventricular non-compaction: a step towards classification as a distinct cardiomyopathy. Heart. 2001 Dec;86(6):666-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1730012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11711464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andreini D, Pontone G, Pepi M, Ballerini G, Bartorelli AL, Magini A, Quaglia C, Nobili E, Agostoni P. Diagnostic accuracy of multidetector computed tomography coronary angiography in patients with dilated cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2007 May 22;49(20):2044-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17512361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalisz K, Rajiah P. Computed tomography of cardiomyopathies. Cardiovasc Diagn Ther. 2017 Oct;7(5):539-556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5716950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29255695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clayton B, Roobottom C, Morgan-Hughes G. Assessment of the myocardium with cardiac computed tomography. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2014 Jun;15(6):603-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24578413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karamitsos TD, Francis JM, Myerson S, Selvanayagam JB, Neubauer S. The role of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009 Oct 06;54(15):1407-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19796734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bello D, Shah DJ, Farah GM, Di Luzio S, Parker M, Johnson MR, Cotts WG, Klocke FJ, Bonow RO, Judd RM, Gheorghiade M, Kim RJ. Gadolinium cardiovascular magnetic resonance predicts reversible myocardial dysfunction and remodeling in patients with heart failure undergoing beta-blocker therapy. Circulation. 2003 Oct 21;108(16):1945-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14557364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fett JD. The role of MRI in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2009 Oct 02;137(2):185-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18684520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marmursztejn J, Vignaux O, Goffinet F, Cabanes L, Duboc D. Delayed-enhanced cardiac magnetic resonance imaging features in peripartum cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2009 Nov 12;137(3):e63-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochitte CE, Oliveira PF, Andrade JM, Ianni BM, Parga JR, Avila LF, Kalil-Filho R, Mady C, Meneghetti JC, Lima JA, Ramires JA. Myocardial delayed enhancement by magnetic resonance imaging in patients with Chagas' disease: a marker of disease severity. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005 Oct 18;46(8):1553-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16226184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickers C, Wilke NM, Jerosch-Herold M, Casey SA, Panse P, Panse N, Weil J, Zenovich AG, Maron BJ. Utility of cardiac magnetic resonance imaging in the diagnosis of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Circulation. 2005 Aug 09;112(6):855-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16087809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silbiger JJ. Abnormalities of the Mitral Apparatus in Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: Echocardiographic, Pathophysiologic, and Surgical Insights. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2016 Jul;29(7):622-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27146120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrigan CJ, Appelbaum E, Maron BJ, Buros JL, Gibson CM, Lesser JR, Udelson JE, Manning WJ, Maron MS. Significance of papillary muscle abnormalities identified by cardiovascular magnetic resonance in hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2008 Mar 01;101(5):668-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18308018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maron MS, Hauser TH, Dubrow E, Horst TA, Kissinger KV, Udelson JE, Manning WJ. Right ventricular involvement in hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2007 Oct 15;100(8):1293-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17920373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germans T, Wilde AA, Dijkmans PA, Chai W, Kamp O, Pinto YM, van Rossum AC. Structural abnormalities of the inferoseptal left ventricular wall detected by cardiac magnetic resonance imaging in carriers of hypertrophic cardiomyopathy mutations. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006 Dec 19;48(12):2518-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17174192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syed IS, Glockner JF, Feng D, Araoz PA, Martinez MW, Edwards WD, Gertz MA, Dispenzieri A, Oh JK, Bellavia D, Tajik AJ, Grogan M. Role of cardiac magnetic resonance imaging in the detection of cardiac amyloidosis. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2010 Feb;3(2):155-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20159642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruberg FL, Appelbaum E, Davidoff R, Ozonoff A, Kissinger KV, Harrigan C, Skinner M, Manning WJ. Diagnostic and prognostic utility of cardiovascular magnetic resonance imaging in light-chain cardiac amyloidosis. Am J Cardiol. 2009 Feb 15;103(4):544-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2680134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19195518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulten E, Agarwal V, Cahill M, Cole G, Vita T, Parrish S, Bittencourt MS, Murthy VL, Kwong R, Di Carli MF, Blankstein R. Presence of Late Gadolinium Enhancement by Cardiac Magnetic Resonance Among Patients With Suspected Cardiac Sarcoidosis Is Associated With Adverse Cardiovascular Prognosis: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2016 Sep;9(9):e005001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5449111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27621357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharkey SW, Windenburg DC, Lesser JR, Maron MS, Hauser RG, Lesser JN, Haas TS, Hodges JS, Maron BJ. Natural history and expansive clinical profile of stress (tako-tsubo) cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2010 Jan 26;55(4):333-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20117439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peritz DC, Vaughn A, Ciocca M, Chung EH. Hypertrabeculation vs left ventricular noncompaction on echocardiogram: a reason to restrict athletic participation? JAMA Intern Med. 2014 Aug;174(8):1379-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24911984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>García-Orta R, Mahía-Casado P, Gómez de Diego JJ, Barba-Cosials J, Rodriguez-Palomares JF, Aguadé-Bruix S, Candell-Riera J. Update on cardiac imaging techniques 2013. Rev Esp Cardiol (Engl Ed) 2014 Feb;67(2):127-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24795120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simões MV, Pintya AO, Bromberg-Marin G, Sarabanda AV, Antloga CM, Pazin-Filho A, Maciel BC, Marin-Neto JA. Relation of regional sympathetic denervation and myocardial perfusion disturbance to wall motion impairment in Chagas' cardiomyopathy. Am J Cardiol. 2000 Nov 01;86(9):975-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11053710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miranda CH, Figueiredo AB, Maciel BC, Marin-Neto JA, Simões MV. Sustained ventricular tachycardia is associated with regional myocardial sympathetic denervation assessed with 123I-metaiodobenzylguanidine in chronic Chagas cardiomyopathy. J Nucl Med. 2011 Apr;52(4):504-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21441532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirani J, Dilsizian V. Nuclear cardiac imaging in hypertrophic cardiomyopathy. J Nucl Cardiol. 2011 Feb;18(1):123-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20737262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blankstein R, Osborne M, Naya M, Waller A, Kim CK, Murthy VL, Kazemian P, Kwong RY, Tokuda M, Skali H, Padera R, Hainer J, Stevenson WG, Dorbala S, Di Carli MF. Cardiac positron emission tomography enhances prognostic assessments of patients with suspected cardiac sarcoidosis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014 Feb 04;63(4):329-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3955730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24140661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ning N, Guo HH, Iagaru A, Mittra E, Fowler M, Witteles R. Serial Cardiac FDG-PET for the Diagnosis and Therapeutic Guidance of Patients With Cardiac Sarcoidosis. J Card Fail. 2019 Apr;25(4):307-311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30825644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noordzij W, Glaudemans AW, Longhi S, Slart RH, Lorenzini M, Hazenberg BP, Rapezzi C. Nuclear imaging for cardiac amyloidosis. Heart Fail Rev. 2015 Mar;20(2):145-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25424887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorbala S, Vangala D, Semer J, Strader C, Bruyere JR, Di Carli MF, Moore SC, Falk RH. Imaging cardiac amyloidosis: a pilot study using ¹⁸F-florbetapir positron emission tomography. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2014 Sep;41(9):1652-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24841414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrikopoulou E, Bhambhvani P. Nuclear imaging of cardiac amyloidosis. J Nucl Cardiol. 2019 Apr;26(2):505-508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28822085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perugini E, Guidalotti PL, Salvi F, Cooke RM, Pettinato C, Riva L, Leone O, Farsad M, Ciliberti P, Bacchi-Reggiani L, Fallani F, Branzi A, Rapezzi C. Noninvasive etiologic diagnosis of cardiac amyloidosis using 99mTc-3,3-diphosphono-1,2-propanodicarboxylic acid scintigraphy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2005 Sep 20;46(6):1076-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16168294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapezzi C, Quarta CC, Guidalotti PL, Pettinato C, Fanti S, Leone O, Ferlini A, Longhi S, Lorenzini M, Reggiani LB, Gagliardi C, Gallo P, Villani C, Salvi F. Role of (99m)Tc-DPD scintigraphy in diagnosis and prognosis of hereditary transthyretin-related cardiac amyloidosis. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2011 Jun;4(6):659-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21679902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokhari S, Castaño A, Pozniakoff T, Deslisle S, Latif F, Maurer MS. (99m)Tc-pyrophosphate scintigraphy for differentiating light-chain cardiac amyloidosis from the transthyretin-related familial and senile cardiac amyloidoses. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging. 2013 Mar 01;6(2):195-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3727049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23400849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul M, Wichter T, Kies P, Gerss J, Wollmann C, Rahbar K, Eckardt L, Breithardt G, Schober O, Schulze-Bahr E, Schäfers M. Cardiac sympathetic dysfunction in genotyped patients with arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy and risk of recurrent ventricular tachyarrhythmias. J Nucl Med. 2011 Oct;52(10):1559-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21908389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi N, Ishida Y, Maeno M, Hirose Y, Kawano S, Fukuoka S, Hayashida K, Kuribayashi S, Hamada S, Yamada N, Takamiya M, Shimomura K, Ohe T. [Significance of 123I-metaiodobenzylguanidine SPECT for detecting left ventricular involvement in patients with arrhythmogenic right ventricular dysplasia]. Kaku Igaku. 1996 Jan;33(1):57-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8819715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimarelli S, Imperiale A, Ben-Sellem D, Rischner J, Detour J, Morel O, Ohlmann P, Constantinesco A. Nuclear medicine imaging of takotsubo cardiomyopathy: typical form and midventricular ballooning syndrome. J Nucl Cardiol. 2008 Jan-Feb;15(1):137-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18242491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31082100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
