<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31335079</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK544359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236">Neuroanatomy, Nucleus Raphe</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walker</LastName><ForeName>Emily P.</ForeName><Initials>EP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Creighton University School of Medicine</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tadi</LastName><ForeName>Prasanna</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Asram Medical College, Eluru, India</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>The raphe nuclei are positioned midline in the brainstem throughout the midbrain, pons, and medulla. These nuclei contain primarily serotonergic neurons, which release serotonin (5-hydroxytryptamine) with autocrine and paracrine effects, as well as synaptic connections. Serotonin generation comes from L-tryptophan via a two-step process catalyzed by tryptophan hydroxylase and L-aromatic amino acid decarboxylase. Upon release, serotonin binds a 5-HT receptor postsynaptically, subtypes of which exert different physiologic effects. Presynaptic 5-HT autoreceptors modulate the subsequent release of serotonin. The serotonin reuptake transporter (SERT) is responsible for presynaptic reuptake. Serotonin primarily metabolized by monoamine oxidase.  The more rostral nuclei located in the midbrain and rostral pons – caudal linear nucleus, dorsal raphe, and median raphe – have projections which extend to forebrain structures. These projections modulate behavioral and emotional functioning, including mood regulation, memory, and sleep-wake cycle. The caudal nuclei of the caudal pons and medulla– raphe magnus, raphe obscurus, and raphe pallidus – primarily project to spinal cord structures; this occurs via parallel projections to ventral, intermediate, and dorsal columns. They modulate nociception and movement. A decrease of serotonergic input to the limbic system has been the longstanding and primary model for the pathogenesis of major depression. Decreased synthesis of serotonin, low-affinity binding to post-synaptic receptors, increased the response of presynaptic autoreceptors, and rapid degradation of serotonin all carry links to clinical depression. These differences in physiology are often due to genetic polymorphisms, explaining increased susceptibility in patients with a family history of depression. While the pathogenesis of depression is understood to be multifactorial in most patients, augmentation of serotonergic transmission with selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) has been the longstanding first-line treatment for depression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s1">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s2">Structure and Function</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s3">Blood Supply and Lymphatics</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s4">Surgical Considerations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s5">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s6">Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s7">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28236" sec="article-28236.s9">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mohammad-Zadeh LF, Moses L, Gwaltney-Brant SM. Serotonin: a review. J Vet Pharmacol Ther. 2008 Jun;31(3):187-99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18471139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornung JP. The human raphe nuclei and the serotonergic system. J Chem Neuroanat. 2003 Dec;26(4):331-43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14729135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikuta T, Matsuo K, Harada K, Nakashima M, Hobara T, Higuchi N, Higuchi F, Otsuki K, Shibata T, Watanuki T, Matsubara T, Yamagata H, Watanabe Y. Disconnectivity between Dorsal Raphe Nucleus and Posterior Cingulate Cortex in Later Life Depression. Front Aging Neurosci. 2017;9:236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28824410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnay Y, Léger L. Brain serotonergic circuitries. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2010;12(4):471-87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21319493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang QP, Nakai Y. The dorsal raphe: an important nucleus in pain modulation. Brain Res Bull. 1994;34(6):575-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7922601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatu L, Moulin T, Bogousslavsky J, Duvernoy H. Arterial territories of human brain: brainstem and cerebellum. Neurology. 1996 Nov;47(5):1125-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8909417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Párraga RG, Possatti LL, Alves RV, Ribas GC, Türe U, de Oliveira E. Microsurgical anatomy and internal architecture of the brainstem in 3D images: surgical considerations. J Neurosurg. 2016 May;124(5):1377-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26517774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen PM, Sloley SS, Vitores AA, Carballosa-Gautam MM, Brambilla R, Hentall ID. Prolonged stimulation of a brainstem raphe region attenuates experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. Neuroscience. 2017 Mar 27;346:395-402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5337132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28147248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowen PJ, Browning M. What has serotonin to do with depression? World Psychiatry. 2015 Jun;14(2):158-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4471964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26043325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blier P, El Mansari M. Serotonin and beyond: therapeutics for major depression. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci. 2013;368(1615):20120536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang S, Wu X, Hu X, Wang T, Jin F. Recognizing Depression from the Microbiota⁻Gut⁻Brain Axis. Int J Mol Sci. 2018 May 29;19(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6032096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29843470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patetsos E, Horjales-Araujo E. Treating Chronic Pain with SSRIs: What Do We Know? Pain Res Manag. 2016;2016:2020915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4947493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volpi-Abadie J, Kaye AM, Kaye AD. Serotonin syndrome. Ochsner J. 2013 Winter;13(4):533-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3865832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24358002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
