<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31335045</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK544325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481">Infectious Colitis</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azer</LastName><ForeName>Samy A.</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King Saud University, King Khalid UH</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tuma</LastName><ForeName>Faiz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Michigan University</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Colonic infection by bacteria, viruses, or parasites results in an inflammatory-type of diarrhea and accounts for the majority of cases presenting with acute diarrhea. These patients present with purulent, bloody, and mucoid loose bowel motions, fever, tenesmus, and abdominal pain. Common bacteria causing bacterial colitis include <i>Campylobacter jejuni</i>, <i>Salmonella</i>, <i>Shigella</i>, <i>Escherichia coli</i>, <i>Yersinia enterocolitica</i>, <i>Clostridium difficile</i>, and <i>Mycobacterium tuberculosis</i>. Common causes of viral colitis include <i>Norovirus</i>, <i>Rotavirus</i>, <i>Adenovirus</i>, and <i>Cytomegalovirus</i>. Parasitic infestation, such as <i>Entamoeba histolytica</i>, a protozoan parasite, is capable of invading the colonic mucosa and causing colitis. Sexually transmitted infection affecting the rectum merit consideration during assessment. These diseases can occur in patients with HIV infection and men who have sex with men and may include <i>Neisseria gonorrhoeae</i>, <i>Chlamydia trachomatis,</i> Herpes simplex, and <i>Treponema pallidum</i>. The patients present with rectal symptoms that mimic inflammatory bowel disease, including rectal pain, tenesmus, bloody mucoid discharge, and urgency. Detailed medical history and identification of specific associated risks are essential in establishing the diagnosis. Stool microscopy and culture and endoscopy are crucial to the diagnosis. However, stool culture helps in the diagnosis of less than 50% of patients presenting with bacterial colitis, and endoscopic examinations usually reveal non-specific pathological changes. Therefore, an approach is needed to evaluate and diagnose the cause of colitis and exclude non-infectious causes. This activity discusses current strategies to diagnose and manage infectious colitis and how to make a high index of suspicion based on clinical presentation and use investigation methods to reach a final diagnosis. This activity discusses the etiology, epidemiology, pathophysiology, clinical presentation, evaluation, differential diagnosis, complications, and management of patients with infectious colitis.  </AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s13">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s14">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s15">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s16">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-23481" sec="article-23481.s19">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Uhlich GA, Sinclair JR, Warren NG, Chmielecki WA, Fratamico P. Characterization of Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli isolates associated with two multistate food-borne outbreaks that occurred in 2006. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2008 Feb;74(4):1268-72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tarr PI, Gordon CA, Chandler WL. Shiga-toxin-producing Escherichia coli and haemolytic uraemic syndrome. Lancet. 2005 Mar 19-25;365(9464):1073-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15781103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newitt S, MacGregor V, Robbins V, Bayliss L, Chattaway MA, Dallman T, Ready D, Aird H, Puleston R, Hawker J. Two Linked Enteroinvasive Escherichia coli Outbreaks, Nottingham, UK, June 2014. Emerg Infect Dis. 2016 Jul;22(7):1178-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4918187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27314432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewkes J, Larson HE, Price AB, Sanderson PJ, Davies HA. Aetiology of acute diarrhoea in adults. Gut. 1981 May;22(5):388-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1419238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7250751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scallan E, Hoekstra RM, Angulo FJ, Tauxe RV, Widdowson MA, Roy SL, Jones JL, Griffin PM. Foodborne illness acquired in the United States--major pathogens. Emerg Infect Dis. 2011 Jan;17(1):7-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3375761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21192848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reveles KR, Lee GC, Boyd NK, Frei CR. The rise in Clostridium difficile infection incidence among hospitalized adults in the United States: 2001-2010. Am J Infect Control. 2014 Oct;42(10):1028-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25278388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherian JJ, Lobo I, Sukhlecha A, Chawan U, Kshirsagar NA, Nair BL, Sawardekar L. Treatment outcome of extrapulmonary tuberculosis under Revised National Tuberculosis Control Programme. Indian J Tuberc. 2017 Apr;64(2):104-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28410692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han JK, Kim SH, Choi BI, Yeon KM, Han MC. Tuberculous colitis. Findings at double-contrast barium enema examination. Dis Colon Rectum. 1996 Nov;39(11):1204-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8918425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karagiannis S, Papaioannou D, Goulas S, Psilopoulos D, Mavrogiannis C. Intestinal tuberculosis in a patient on infliximab treatment. Gastrointest Endosc. 2008 Jun;67(7):1178-9; discussion 1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18329027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanley SL. Amoebiasis. Lancet. 2003 Mar 22;361(9362):1025-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12660071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada Y, Matsui T, Matake H, Sakurai T, Yamamoto J, Kikuchi Y, Yorioka M, Tsuda S, Yao T, Yao S, Haraoka S, Iwashita A. Intractable ulcerative colitis caused by cytomegalovirus infection: a prospective study on prevalence, diagnosis, and treatment. Dis Colon Rectum. 2003 Oct;46(10 Suppl):S59-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14530660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissessor M, Fairley CK, Read T, Denham I, Bradshaw C, Chen M. The etiology of infectious proctitis in men who have sex with men differs according to HIV status. Sex Transm Dis. 2013 Oct;40(10):768-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24275725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slimings C, Riley TV. Antibiotics and hospital-acquired Clostridium difficile infection: update of systematic review and meta-analysis. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2014 Apr;69(4):881-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24324224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin A, Yaari S, Stoff R, Caplan O, Wolf DG, Israeli E. Diagnosis of Cytomegalovirus Infection during Exacerbation of Ulcerative Colitis. Digestion. 2017;96(3):142-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessurun J. The Differential Diagnosis of Acute Colitis: Clues to a Specific Diagnosis. Surg Pathol Clin. 2017 Dec;10(4):863-885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29103537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plastaras L, Vuitton L, Badet N, Koch S, Di Martino V, Delabrousse E. Acute colitis: differential diagnosis using multidetector CT. Clin Radiol. 2015 Mar;70(3):262-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25522900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stauffer W, Ravdin JI. Entamoeba histolytica: an update. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2003 Oct;16(5):479-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14502002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di X, Bai N, Zhang X, Liu B, Ni W, Wang J, Wang K, Liang B, Liu Y, Wang R. A meta-analysis of metronidazole and vancomycin for the treatment of Clostridium difficile infection, stratified by disease severity. Braz J Infect Dis. 2015 Jul-Aug;19(4):339-49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26001980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falzon D, Schünemann HJ, Harausz E, González-Angulo L, Lienhardt C, Jaramillo E, Weyer K. World Health Organization treatment guidelines for drug-resistant tuberculosis, 2016 update. Eur Respir J. 2017 Mar;49(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5399349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28331043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hook EW. Syphilis. Lancet. 2017 Apr 15;389(10078):1550-1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27993382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque R, Huston CD, Hughes M, Houpt E, Petri WA. Amebiasis. N Engl J Med. 2003 Apr 17;348(16):1565-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12700377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoner BP, Cohen SE. Lymphogranuloma Venereum 2015: Clinical Presentation, Diagnosis, and Treatment. Clin Infect Dis. 2015 Dec 15;61 Suppl 8:S865-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26602624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dean R, Gill D, Buchan D. Salmonella colitis as an unusual cause of elevated serum lipase. Am J Emerg Med. 2017 May;35(5):800.e5-800.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27865572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papaconstantinou HT, Thomas JS. Bacterial colitis. Clin Colon Rectal Surg. 2007 Feb;20(1):18-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2780149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20011357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Autenrieth DM, Baumgart DC. Toxic megacolon. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2012 Mar;18(3):584-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22009735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horiki N, Furukawa K, Kitade T, Sakuno T, Katsurahara M, Harada T, Tano S, Yamada R, Hamada Y, Inoue H, Tanaka K, Gabazza EC, Ishii N, Fukuda K, Omata F, Fujita Y, Tachibana H, Takei Y. Endoscopic findings and lesion distribution in amebic colitis. J Infect Chemother. 2015 Jun;21(6):444-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25787830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Törnblom H, Holmvall P, Svenungsson B, Lindberg G. Gastrointestinal symptoms after infectious diarrhea: a five-year follow-up in a Swedish cohort of adults. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2007 Apr;5(4):461-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17445752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
