<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">31389814</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6963</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>31</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in rheumatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Lupus nephritis: challenges and progress.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>682</StartPage>
          <EndPage>688</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>682-688</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000642</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">The management of lupus nephritis remains unsatisfactory due to insufficiently effective treatment regimens and the dearth of reliable predictors of disease onset or progression to guide individualized therapeutic decisions. This review summarizes new findings related to lupus nephritis over the last 18 months and discusses clinical needs that should be considered to advance trials of mechanism-based therapeutic strategies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Collaborative teams are addressing how to improve disease definitions and are developing predictive models for disease onset, disease response and risk of flare in individual patients. More attention is being paid to clinical trial design. Advanced technologic approaches are allowing the analysis of small amounts of human tissue and urine in unprecedented detail so as to discover new pathogenic mechanisms and identify disease biomarkers. Novel therapies continue to be tested in disease models and include new strategies to protect renal tissue from cell damage and fibrosis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">The collaborative efforts of patients, clinical and translational researchers, the pharmaceutical industry and funding sources are needed to advance therapies for lupus nephritis. Specialized clinical centers can then deliver optimal and more personalized patient care that will improve patient outcomes.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Davidson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anne</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Autoimmunity, Musculoskeletal and Hematologic Diseases, Feinstein Institute for Medical Research, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aranow</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cynthia</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mackay</LastName>
            <ForeName>Meggan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AR064811</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R03 AI109324</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9000851</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1040-8711</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007166">Immunosuppressive Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019468" MajorTopicYN="Y">Disease Management</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007166" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppressive Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="N">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest. None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31389814</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1053452</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6812494</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000642</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moroni G, Vercelloni PG, Quaglini S, Gatto M, Gianfreda D, Sacchi L, et al.
Changing patterns in clinical-histological presentation and renal outcome over the last five decades in a cohort of 499 patients with lupus nephritis. Annals of the rheumatic diseases. 2018;77(9):1318–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29730634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tektonidou MG, Dasgupta A, Ward MM. Risk of End-Stage Renal Disease in Patients With Lupus Nephritis, 1971–2015: A Systematic Review and Bayesian Meta-Analysis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68(6):1432–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5071782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bajema IM, Wilhelmus S, Alpers CE, Bruijn JA, Colvin RB, Cook HT, et al.
Revision of the International Society of Nephrology/Renal Pathology Society classification for lupus nephritis: clarification of definitions, and modified National Institutes of Health activity and chronicity indices. Kidney international. 2018;93(4):789–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yap DYH, Kwan LPY, Ma MKM, Mok MMY, Chan GCW, Chan TM. Preemptive immunosuppressive treatment for asymptomatic serological reactivation may reduce renal flares in patients with lupus nephritis: a cohort study. Nephrology, dialysis, transplantation : official publication of the European Dialysis and Transplant Association - European Renal Association. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29509932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen DN, Fan L, Wu YX, Zhou Q, Chen W, Yu XQ. A Predictive Model for Estimation Risk of Proliferative Lupus Nephritis. Chinese medical journal. 2018;131(11):1275–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5987496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29786038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwon OC, Lee JS, Ghang B, Kim YG, Lee CK, Yoo B, et al.
Predicting eventual development of lupus nephritis at the time of diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism. 2018;48(3):462–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mackay M, Dall’Era M, Fishbein J, Kalunian K, Lesser M, Sanchez-Guerrero J, et al.
Establishing Surrogate Kidney End Points for Lupus Nephritis Clinical Trials: Development and Validation of a Novel Approach to Predict Future Kidney Outcomes. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30225865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamirou F, Lauwerys BR, Dall’Era M, Mackay M, Rovin B, Cervera R, et al.
A proteinuria cut-off level of 0.7 g/day after 12 months of treatment best predicts long-term renal outcome in lupus nephritis: data from the MAINTAIN Nephritis Trial. Lupus science &amp; medicine. 2015;2(1):e000123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4654096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26629352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ugolini-Lopes MR, Seguro LPC, Castro MXF, Daffre D, Lopes AC, Borba EF, et al.
Early proteinuria response: a valid real-life situation predictor of long-term lupus renal outcome in an ethnically diverse group with severe biopsy-proven nephritis?
Lupus science &amp; medicine. 2017;4(1):e000213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5724342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shidham G, Ayoub I, Birmingham D, Hebert P, Rovin B, Diamond B, et al.
Limited Reliability of the Spot Urine Protein/Creatinine Ratio in the Longitudinal Evaluation of Patients With Lupus Nephritis. Kidney international reports. 2018;3(5):1057–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6127448</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30197972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayoub I, Nelson J, Rovin BH. Induction Therapy for Lupus Nephritis: the Highlights. Current rheumatology reports. 2018;20(10):60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30109511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Group AT. Treatment of lupus nephritis with abatacept: the Abatacept and Cyclophosphamide Combination Efficacy and Safety Study. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2014;66(11):3096–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528976</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25403681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kello N, Khoury LE, Marder G, Furie R, Zapantis E, Horowitz DL. Secondary thrombotic microangiopathy in systemic lupus erythematosus and antiphospholipid syndrome, the role of complement and use of eculizumab: Case series and review of literature. Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30598332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen DC, Hu WChvc. Lupus podocytopathy: a distinct entity of lupus nephritis. Journal of nephrology. 2018;31(5):629–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29270846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang KT, Tseng CH, Hsieh TY, Chen DYT. Induction therapy for membranous lupus nephritis: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. International journal of rheumatic diseases. 2018;21(6):1163–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29879319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An Y, Zhou Y, Bi L, Liu B, Wang H, Lin J, et al.
Combined immunosuppressive treatment (CIST) in lupus nephritis: a multicenter, randomized controlled study. Clinical rheumatology. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30488367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang M, Qi C, Zha Y, Chen J, Luo P, Wang L, et al.
Leflunomide versus cyclophosphamide in the induction treatment of proliferative lupus nephritis in Chinese patients: a randomized trial. Clinical rheumatology. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30426311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rovin BH, Solomons N, Pendergraft WF 3rd, Dooley MA, Tumlin J, Romero-Diaz J, et al.
A randomized, controlled double-blind study comparing the efficacy and safety of dose-ranging voclosporin with placebo in achieving remission in patients with active lupus nephritis. Kidney international. 2019;95(1):219–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30420324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sin FE, Isenberg D. An evaluation of voclosporin for the treatment of lupus nephritis. Expert opinion on pharmacotherapy. 2018;19(14):1613–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30207816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aranow C, Dall’Era M, Byron M, Ding L, Smilek D, Diamond B, et al.
Phase 2 trial of induction therapy with antiCD20 (rituximab) followed by maintenance therapy with anti-BAFF (belimumab) in patients with active lupus nephritis. Annals of the rheumatic diseases. 2018:FRI0305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urowitz MB, Ohsfeldt RL, Wielage RC, Kelton KA, Asukai Y, Ramachandran S. Organ damage in patients treated with belimumab versus standard of care: a propensity score-matched comparative analysis. Annals of the rheumatic diseases. 2019;78(3):372–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng J, Xie H, Zhu L, Luo L, Xie H. Maintenance therapy for lupus nephritis with mycophenolate mofetil or azathioprine. A meta-analysis. Clinical nephrology. 2019;91(3):172–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30686286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tunnicliffe DJ, Palmer SC, Henderson L, Masson P, Craig JC, Tong A, et al.
Immunosuppressive treatment for proliferative lupus nephritis. The Cochrane database of systematic reviews. 2018;6:Cd002922.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6513226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29957821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok CC. Is Treat-to-target in Lupus Nephritis Realistic in Clinical Practice?
Current rheumatology reviews. 2019;15(1):2–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29623845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moroni G, Gatto M, Raffiotta F, Binda V, Frangou E, Lightstone L, et al.
Can we withdraw immunosuppressants in patients with lupus nephritis in remission?
An expert debate. Autoimmunity reviews. 2018;17(1):11–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29108824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Rosa M, Azzato F, Toblli JE, De Rosa G, Fuentes F, Nagaraja HN, et al.
A prospective observational cohort study highlights kidney biopsy findings of lupus nephritis patients in remission who flare following withdrawal of maintenance therapy. Kidney international. 2018;94(4):788–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30045812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malvar A, Pirruccio P, Alberton V, Lococo B, Recalde C, Fazini B, et al.
Histologic versus clinical remission in proliferative lupus nephritis. Nephrology, dialysis, transplantation
2017;32(8):1338–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26250434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman CH, Collins J, Zhang Z, Xu C, Subramanian SV, Kawachi I, et al.
Azathioprine and Mycophenolate Mofetil Adherence Patterns and Predictors among Medicaid Beneficiaries with Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Arthritis care &amp; research. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6482109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30354025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jorge A, Wallace ZS, Lu N, Zhang Y, Choi HK. Renal Transplantation and Survival Among Patients With Lupus Nephritis: A Cohort Study. Annals of internal medicine. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6739121</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30665236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dall’Era M, Bruce IN, Gordon C, Manzi S, McCaffrey J, Lipsky PE. Current challenges in the development of new treatments for lupus. Annals of the rheumatic diseases. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30636212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung SA, Brown EE, Williams AH, Ramos PS, Berthier CC, Bhangale T, et al.
Lupus nephritis susceptibility loci in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Journal of the American Society of Nephrology : JASN. 2014;25(12):2859–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4243339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24925725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan SQ, Khan I, Gupta V. CD11b Activity Modulates Pathogenesis of Lupus Nephritis. Frontiers in medicine. 2018;5:52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5862812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29600248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin L, Du Y, Ding H, Haque A, Hicks J, Pedroza C, et al.
Bradykinin 1 receptor blockade subdues systemic autoimmunity, renal inflammation, and blood pressure in murine lupus nephritis. Arthritis research &amp; therapy. 2019;21(1):12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6325757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30621761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiu C, Huang S, Park J, Park Y, Ko YA, Seasock MJ, et al.
Renal compartment-specific genetic variation analyses identify new pathways in chronic kidney disease. Nature medicine. 2018;24(11):1721–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6301011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30275566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok A, Solomon O, Nayak RR, Coit P, Quach HL, Nititham J, et al.
Genome-wide profiling identifies associations between lupus nephritis and differential methylation of genes regulating tissue hypoxia and type 1 interferon responses. Lupus science &amp; medicine. 2016;3(1):e000183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5174796</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28074145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanata CM, Nititham J, Taylor KE, Chung SA, Torgerson DG, Seldin MF, et al.
Genetic contributions to lupus nephritis in a multi-ethnic cohort of systemic lupus erythematous patients. PloS one. 2018;13(6):e0199003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023154</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29953444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freedman BI, Limou S, Ma L, Kopp JB. APOL1-Associated Nephropathy: A Key Contributor to Racial Disparities in CKD. American journal of kidney diseases : the official journal of the National Kidney Foundation. 2018;72(5s1):S8–s16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6200346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30343724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freedman BI, Moxey-Mims M. The APOL1 Long-Term Kidney Transplantation Outcomes Network-APOLLO. Clinical journal of the American Society of Nephrology : CJASN. 2018;13(6):940–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5989686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29703792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liarski VM, Sibley A, van Panhuys N, Ai J, Chang A, Kennedy D, et al.
Quantifying in situ adaptive immune cell cognate interactions in humans. Nature immunology. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6474677</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30778242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Der E, Suryawanshi H, Morozov P, Kustagi M, Goilav B, Ranabathou S, et al.
Tubular cell and keratinocyte single-cell transcriptomics applied to lupus nephritis reveal type I IFN and fibrosis relevant pathways. Nat Immunol. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6584054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31110316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arazi A, Rao DA, Berthier CC, Davidson A, Liu Y, Hoover PJ, et al.
The immune cell landscape in kidneys of lupus nephritis patients. Nature Immunology (in press).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tilstra JS, Avery L, Menk AV, Gordon RA, Smita S, Kane LP, et al.
Kidney-infiltrating T cells in murine lupus nephritis are metabolically and functionally exhausted. The Journal of clinical investigation. 2018;128(11):4884–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6205402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30130253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishimoto D, Kirino Y, Tamura M, Takeno M, Kunishita Y, Takase-Minegishi K, et al.
Dysregulated heme oxygenase-1(low) M2-like macrophages augment lupus nephritis via Bach1 induced by type I interferons. Arthritis research &amp; therapy. 2018;20(1):64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5894134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29636091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azzouz D, Omarbekova A, Heguy A, Schwudke D, Gisch N, Rovin BH, et al.
Lupus nephritis is linked to disease-activity associated expansions and immunity to a gut commensal. Annals of the rheumatic diseases. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6585303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30782585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dehner C, Fine R, Kriegel MA. The microbiome in systemic autoimmune disease: mechanistic insights from recent studies. Current opinion in rheumatology. 2019;31(2):201–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6408954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30624285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manfredo Vieira S, Hiltensperger M, Kumar V, Zegarra-Ruiz D, Dehner C, Khan N, et al.
Translocation of a gut pathobiont drives autoimmunity in mice and humans. Science (New York, NY). 2018;359(6380):1156–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5959731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29590047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anania VG, Yu K, Pingitore F, Li Q, Rose CM, Liu P, et al.
Discovery and qualification of candidate urinary biomarkers of disease activity in lupus nephritis. Journal of proteome research. 2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30525646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi H, Jia J, Li D, Wei L, Shang W, Zheng Z. Blood oxygen level dependent magnetic resonance imaging for detecting pathological patterns in lupus nephritis patients: a preliminary study using a decision tree model. BMC nephrology. 2018;19(1):33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29426280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding Y, Nie LM, Pang Y, Wu WJ, Tan Y, Yu F, et al.
Composite urinary biomarkers to predict pathological tubulointerstitial lesions in lupus nephritis. Lupus. 2018;27(11):1778–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30020021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok CC, Soliman S, Ho LY, Mohamed FA, Mohamed FI, Mohan C. Urinary angiostatin, CXCL4 and VCAM-1 as biomarkers of lupus nephritis. Arthritis research &amp; therapy. 2018;20(1):6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5765646</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29325582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitagawa A, Tsuboi N, Yokoe Y, Katsuno T, Ikeuchi H, Kajiyama H, et al.
Urinary levels of the leukocyte surface molecule CD11b associate with glomerular inflammation in lupus nephritis. Kidney international. 2019;95(3):680–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30712924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burbano C, Gomez-Puerta JA, Munoz-Vahos C, Vanegas-Garcia A, Rojas M, Vasquez G, et al.
HMGB1(+) microparticles present in urine are hallmarks of nephritis in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. European journal of immunology. 2019;49(2):323–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30537116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanley S, Mok CC, Vanarsa K, Habazi D, Li J, Predoza C, et al.
Identification of Low-Abundance Urinary Biomarkers in Lupus Nephritis using Electrochemiluminescence Immunoassays. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aljaberi N, Bennett M, Brunner HI, Devarajan P. Proteomic profiling of urine: implications for lupus nephritis. Expert review of proteomics. 2019;16(4):303–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693508</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30855196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caster DJEadcle, Merchant MLK, Klein JB, Powell DWK. Precision medicine in lupus nephritis: can biomarkers get us there?
Translational research : the journal of laboratory and clinical medicine. 2018;201:26–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6415919</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30179587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunner HI, Gulati G, Klein-Gitelman MS, Rouster-Stevens KA, Tucker L, Ardoin SP, et al.
Urine biomarkers of chronic kidney damage and renal functional decline in childhood-onset systemic lupus erythematosus. Pediatr Nephrol. 2019;34(1):117–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6294330</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30159624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Tao Y, Liu Y, Zhao Y, Song C, Zhou B, et al.
Rapid detection of urinary soluble intercellular adhesion molecule-1 for determination of lupus nephritis activity. Medicine. 2018;97(26):e11287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039621</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29953010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jourde-Chiche N, Whalen E, Gondouin B, Speake C, Gersuk V, Dussol B, et al.
Modular transcriptional repertoire analyses identify a blood neutrophil signature as a candidate biomarker for lupus nephritis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2017;56(3):477–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28031441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wither JE, Prokopec SD, Noamani B, Chang NH, Bonilla D, Touma Z, et al.
Identification of a neutrophil-related gene expression signature that is enriched in adult systemic lupus erythematosus patients with active nephritis: Clinical/pathologic associations and etiologic mechanisms. PloS one. 2018;13(5):e0196117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5942792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29742110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang S, Wu M, Chiriboga L, Zeck B, Belmont HM. Membrane attack complex (mac) deposition in lupus nephritis is associated with hypertension and poor clinical response to treatment. Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism. 2018;48(2):256–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29395256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson HR, Medjeral-Thomas NR, Gilmore AC, Trivedi P, Seyb K, Farzaneh-Far R, et al.
Glomerular membrane attack complex is not a reliable marker of ongoing C5 activation in lupus nephritis. Kidney international. 2019;95(3):655–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6389546</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30655025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma H, Liu C, Shi B, Zhang Z, Feng R, Guo M, et al.
Mesenchymal Stem Cells Control Complement C5 Activation by Factor H in Lupus Nephritis. EBioMedicine. 2018;32:21–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6020800</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29885865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mizui M, Tsokos GC. Targeting Regulatory T Cells to Treat Patients With Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Frontiers in immunology. 2018;9:786.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin Y, Choi SC, Xu Z, Perry DJ, Seay H, Croker BP, et al.
Normalization of CD4+ T cell metabolism reverses lupus. Sci Transl Med. 2015;7(274):274ra18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5292723</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25673763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pham GS, Wang LA, Mathis KW. Pharmacological potentiation of the efferent vagus nerve attenuates blood pressure and renal injury in a murine model of systemic lupus erythematosus. American journal of physiology Regulatory, integrative and comparative physiology. 2018;315(6):R1261–r71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6425635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30332305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wada Y, Gonzalez-Sanchez HM, Weinmann-Menke J, Iwata Y, Ajay AK, Meineck M, et al.
IL-34-Dependent Intrarenal and Systemic Mechanisms Promote Lupus Nephritis in MRL-Fas(lpr) Mice. Journal of the American Society of Nephrology : JASN. 2019;30(2):244–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6362618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30622154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qing X, Chinenov Y, Redecha P, Madaio M, Roelofs JJ, Farber G, et al.
iRhom2 promotes lupus nephritis through TNF-alpha and EGFR signaling. The Journal of clinical investigation. 2018;128(4):1397–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5873859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29369823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maeda K, Otomo K, Yoshida N, Abu-Asab MS, Ichinose K, Nishino T, et al.
CaMK4 compromises podocyte function in autoimmune and nonautoimmune kidney disease. The Journal of clinical investigation. 2018;128(8):3445–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6063476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu R, Guo C, Wang S, Huang Y, Jin O, Hu H, et al.
Podocyte Activation of NLRP3 Inflammasomes Contributes to the Development of Proteinuria in Lupus Nephritis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2017;69(8):1636–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5568813</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28544564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu R, Xia Y, Li M, Mao R, Guo C, Zhou M, et al.
Pim-1 as a therapeutic target in human lupus nephritis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lv W, Booz GW, Fan F, Wang Y, Roman RJ. Oxidative Stress and Renal Fibrosis: Recent Insights for the Development of Novel Therapeutic Strategies. Frontiers in physiology. 2018;9:105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5820314</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29503620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li SY, Susztak K. The Role of Peroxisome Proliferator-Activated Receptor gamma Coactivator 1alpha (PGC-1alpha) in Kidney Disease. Seminars in nephrology. 2018;38(2):121–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5958619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29602395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broder A, Mowrey WB, Khan HN, Jovanovic B, Londono-Jimenez A, Izmirly P, et al.
Tubulointerstitial damage predicts end stage renal disease in lupus nephritis with preserved to moderately impaired renal function: A retrospective cohort study. Seminars in arthritis and rheumatism. 2018;47(4):545–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5927553</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28803673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obrisca B, Jurubita R, Andronesi A, Sorohan B, Achim C, Bobeica R, et al.
Histological predictors of renal outcome in lupus nephritis: the importance of tubulointerstitial lesions and scoring of glomerular lesions. Lupus. 2018;27(9):1455–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29759047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwon OC, Park Y, Lee JS, Oh JS, Kim YG, Lee CK, et al.
Non-albumin proteinuria as a parameter of tubulointerstitial inflammation in lupus nephritis. Clinical rheumatology. 2019;38(1):235–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30094751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
