<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31418407</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2165-0497</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>7</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Microbiology spectrum</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Microbiol Spectr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Metabolism of the Gram-Positive Bacterial Pathogen <i>Listeria monocytogenes</i>.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/microbiolspec.GPP3-0066-2019</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Bacterial metabolism represents the biochemical space that bacteria can manipulate to produce energy, reducing equivalents and building blocks for replication. Gram-positive pathogens, such as <i>Listeria monocytogenes</i>, show remarkable flexibility, which allows for exploitation of diverse biological niches from the soil to the intracytosolic space. Although the human host represents a potentially rich source for nutrient acquisition, competition for nutrients with the host and hostile host defenses can constrain bacterial metabolism by various mechanisms, including nutrient sequestration. Here, we review metabolism in the model Gram-positive bacterium, <i>L. monocytogenes</i>, and highlight pathways that enable the replication, survival, and virulence of this bacterial pathogen.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sauer</LastName>
            <ForeName>John-Demian</ForeName>
            <Initials>JD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology and Immunology, University of Wisconsin- Madison, Madison, WI 53706.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Herskovits</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anat A</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Microbiology and Biotechnology, The George S. Wise Faculty of Life Sciences, Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>O'Riordan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mary X D</ForeName>
            <Initials>MXD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, University of Michigan Medical School, Ann Arbor, MI 48109.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AI109048</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AI137070</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Microbiol Spectr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101634614</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2165-0497</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001426">Bacterial Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001426" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015964" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation, Bacterial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008089" MajorTopicYN="N">Listeria monocytogenes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008088" MajorTopicYN="N">Listeriosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31418407</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1020381</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6699642</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/microbiolspec.GPP3-0066-2019</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toledo-Arana A, Dussurget O, Nikitas G, Sesto N, Guet-Revillet H, Balestrino D, Loh E, Gripenland J, Tiensuu T, Vaitkevicius K, Barthelemy M, Vergassola M, Nahori MA, Soubigou G, Regnault B, Coppee JY, Lecuit M, Johansson J, Cossart P. 2009. 
The Listeria transcriptional landscape from saprophytism to virulence. Nature
459:950–956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19448609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glaser P, Frangeul L, Buchrieser C, Rusniok C, Amend A, Baquero F, Berche P, Bloecker H, Brandt P, Chakraborty T, Charbit A, Chetouani F, Couve E, de Daruvar A, Dehoux P, Domann E, Dominguez-Bernal G, Duchaud E, Durant L, Dussurget O, Entian KD, Fsihi H, Portillo FG, Garrido P, Gautier L, Goebel W, Gomez-Lopez N, Hain T, Hauf J, Jackson D, Jones LM, Kaerst U, Kreft J, Kuhn M, Kunst F, Kurapkat G, Madueno E, Maitournam A, Vicente JM, Ng E, Nedjari H, Nordsiek G, Novella S, de Pablos B, Perez-Diaz JC, Purcell R, Remmel B, Rose M, Schlueter T, Simoes N, Tierrez A, Vazquez-Boland JA, Voss H, Wehland J, Cossart P. 2001. 
Comparative genomics of Listeria species. Science
294:849–852.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11679669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>den Bakker HC, Cummings CA, Ferreira V, Vatta P, Orsi RH, Degoricija L, Barker M, Petrauskene O, Furtado MR, Wiedmann M. 2010. 
Comparative genomics of the bacterial genus Listeria: Genome evolution is characterized by limited gene acquisition and limited gene loss. BMC Genomics
11:688.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3019230</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21126366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maury MM, Tsai YH, Charlier C, Touchon M, Chenal-Francisque V, Leclercq A, Criscuolo A, Gaultier C, Roussel S, Brisabois A, Disson O, Rocha EPC, Brisse S, Lecuit M. 2016. 
Uncovering Listeria monocytogenes hypervirulence by harnessing its biodiversity. Nat Genet
48:308–313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4768348</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26829754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hain T, Chatterjee SS, Ghai R, Kuenne CT, Billion A, Steinweg C, Domann E, Karst U, Jansch L, Wehland J, Eisenreich W, Bacher A, Joseph B, Schar J, Kreft J, Klumpp J, Loessner MJ, Dorscht J, Neuhaus K, Fuchs TM, Scherer S, Doumith M, Jacquet C, Martin P, Cossart P, Rusniock C, Glaser P, Buchrieser C, Goebel W, Chakraborty T. 2007. 
Pathogenomics of Listeria spp. Int J Med Microbiol
297:541–557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17482873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatterjee SS, Hossain H, Otten S, Kuenne C, Kuchmina K, Machata S, Domann E, Chakraborty T, Hain T. 2006. 
Intracellular gene expression profile of Listeria monocytogenes. Infect Immun
74:1323–1338.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1360297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16428782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hain T, Ghai R, Billion A, Kuenne CT, Steinweg C, Izar B, Mohamed W, Mraheil M, Domann E, Schaffrath S, Karst U, Goesmann A, Oehm S, Puhler A, Merkl R, Vorwerk S, Glaser P, Garrido P, Rusniok C, Buchrieser C, Goebel W, Chakraborty T. 2012. 
Comparative genomics and transcriptomics of lineages I, II, and III strains of Listeria monocytogenes. BMC Genomics
13:144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3464598</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Severino P, Dussurget O, Vencio RZ, Dumas E, Garrido P, Padilla G, Piveteau P, Lemaitre JP, Kunst F, Glaser P, Buchrieser C. 2007. 
Comparative transcriptome analysis of Listeria monocytogenes strains of the two major lineages reveals differences in virulence, cell wall, and stress response. Appl Environ Microbiol
73:6078–6088.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2075013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17704270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welshimer HJ. 1963. 
Vitamin Requirements of Listeria Monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
85:1156–1159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC278298</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14044009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Premaratne RJ, Lin WJ, Johnson EA. 1991. 
Development of an improved chemically defined minimal medium for Listeria monocytogenes. Appl Environ Microbiol
57:3046–3048.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC183920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1746963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phan-Thanh L, Gormon T. 1997. 
A chemically defined minimal medium for the optimal culture of Listeria. Int J Food Microbiol
35:91–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9081230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai HN, Hodgson DA. 2003. 
Development of a synthetic minimal medium for Listeria monocytogenes. Appl Environ Microbiol
69:6943–6945.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC262277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14602660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grubmuller S, Schauer K, Goebel W, Fuchs TM, Eisenreich W. 2014. 
Analysis of carbon substrates used by Listeria monocytogenes during growth in J774A.1 macrophages suggests a bipartite intracellular metabolism. Front Cell Infect Microbiol
4:156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4217532</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25405102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eylert E, Schar J, Mertins S, Stoll R, Bacher A, Goebel W, Eisenreich W. 2008. 
Carbon metabolism of Listeria monocytogenes growing inside macrophages. Mol Microbiol
69:1008–1017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18627458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becavin C, Koutero M, Tchitchek N, Cerutti F, Lechat P, Maillet N, Hoede C, Chiapello H, Gaspin C, Cossart P. 2017. 
Listeriomics: an Interactive Web Platform for Systems Biology of Listeria. mSystems
2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350546</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28317029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedman ME, Roessler WG. 1961. 
Growth of Listeria monocytogenes in defined media. J Bacteriol
82:528–533.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC279201</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13895282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joseph B, Goebel W. 2007. 
Life of Listeria monocytogenes in the host cells’ cytosol. Microbes Infect
9:1188–1195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17719818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romick TL, Fleming HP, McFeeters RF. 1996. 
Aerobic and anaerobic metabolism of Listeria monocytogenes in defined glucose medium. Appl Environ Microbiol
62:304–307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167799</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8572709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe AJ. 2005. 
The acetate switch. Microbiol Mol Biol Rev
69:12–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1082793</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15755952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller-Herbst S, Wustner S, Muhlig A, Eder D, Fuchs TM, Held C, Ehrenreich A, Scherer S. 2014. 
Identification of genes essential for anaerobic growth of Listeria monocytogenes. Microbiology
160:752–765.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24451174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen GY, McDougal CE, D’Antonio MA, Portman JL, Sauer JD. 2017. 
A Genetic Screen Reveals that Synthesis of 1,4-Dihydroxy-2-Naphthoate (DHNA), but Not Full-Length Menaquinone, Is Required for Listeria monocytogenes Cytosolic Survival. MBio
8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5362031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28325762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feehily C, O’Byrne CP, Karatzas KA. 2013. 
Functional gamma-Aminobutyrate Shunt in Listeria monocytogenes: role in acid tolerance and succinate biosynthesis. Appl Environ Microbiol
79:74–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3536111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23064337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schar J, Stoll R, Schauer K, Loeffler DI, Eylert E, Joseph B, Eisenreich W, Fuchs TM, Goebel W. 2010. 
Pyruvate carboxylase plays a crucial role in carbon metabolism of extra- and intracellularly replicating Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
192:1774–1784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20097852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenreich W, Slaghuis J, Laupitz R, Bussemer J, Stritzker J, Schwarz C, Schwarz R, Dandekar T, Goebel W, Bacher A. 2006. 
13C isotopologue perturbation studies of Listeria monocytogenes carbon metabolism and its modulation by the virulence regulator PrfA. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
103:2040–2045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1413697</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welshimer HJ. 1960. 
Survival of Listeria monocytogenes in soil. J Bacteriol
80:316–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC278866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13784295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weis J, Seeliger HP. 1975. 
Incidence of Listeria monocytogenes in nature. Appl Microbiol
30:29–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC187108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">807164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowe MJ, Jackson ED, Mori JG, Bell CR. 1997. 
Listeria monocytogenes survival in soil and incidence in agricultural soils. J Food Prot
60:1201–1207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31207734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox E, O’Mahony T, Clancy M, Dempsey R, O’Brien M, Jordan K. 2009. 
Listeria monocytogenes in the Irish Dairy Farm Environment. J Food Prot
72:1450–1456.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19681268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strawn LK, Fortes ED, Bihn EA, Nightingale KK, Gröhn YT, Worobo RW, Wiedmann M, Bergholz PW. 2013. 
Landscape and meteorological factors affecting prevalence of three food-borne pathogens in fruit and vegetable farms. Appl Environ Microbiol
79:588–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3553790</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23144137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vivant AL, Garmyn D, Piveteau P. 2013. 
Listeria monocytogenes, a down-to-earth pathogen. Front Cell Infect Microbiol
3:87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24350062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Locatelli A, Spor A, Jolivet C, Piveteau P, Hartmann A. 2013. 
Biotic and abiotic soil properties influence survival of Listeria monocytogenes in soil. PLoS One
8:e75969.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24116083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin HP, Casey PG, Cotter J, Gahan CG, Hill C. 2011. 
Factors affecting survival of Listeria monocytogenes and Listeria innocua in soil samples. Arch Microbiol
193:775–785.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21611773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stoll R, Goebel W. 2010. 
The major PEP-phosphotransferase systems (PTSs) for glucose, mannose and cellobiose of Listeria monocytogenes, and their significance for extra- and intracellular growth. Microbiology
156:1069–1083.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ake FM, Joyet P, Deutscher J, Milohanic E
2011. 
Mutational analysis of glucose transport regulation and glucose-mediated virulence gene repression in Listeria monocytogenes. Mol Microbiol
81:274–293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21564334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>den Bakker HC, Desjardins CA, Griggs AD, Peters JE, Zeng Q, Young SK, Kodira CD, Yandava C, Hepburn TA, Haas BJ, Birren BW, Wiedmann M. 2013. 
Evolutionary dynamics of the accessory genome of Listeria monocytogenes. PLoS One
8:e67511.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3692452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23825666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>den Bakker HC, Bowen BM, Rodriguez-Rivera LD, Wiedmann M. 2012. 
FSL J1–208, a virulent uncommon phylogenetic lineage IV Listeria monocytogenes strain with a small chromosome size and a putative virulence plasmid carrying internalin-like genes. Appl Environ Microbiol
78:1876–1889.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3298151</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piveteau P, Depret G, Pivato B, Garmyn D, Hartmann A. 2011. 
Changes in gene expression during adaptation of Listeria monocytogenes to the soil environment. PLoS One
6:e24881.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3179493</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21966375</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vivant AL, Desneux J, Pourcher AM, Piveteau P. 2017. 
Transcriptomic Analysis of the Adaptation of Listeria monocytogenes to Lagoon and Soil Matrices Associated with a Piggery Environment: Comparison of Expression Profiles. Front Microbiol
8:1811.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5623016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29018416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mertins S, Joseph B, Goetz M, Ecke R, Seidel G, Sprehe M, Hillen W, Goebel W, Muller-Altrock S. 2007. 
Interference of components of the phosphoenolpyruvate phosphotransferase system with the central virulence gene regulator PrfA of Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
189:473–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1797385</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17085572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuchs TM, Eisenreich W, Kern T, Dandekar T. 2012. 
Toward a Systemic Understanding of Listeria monocytogenes Metabolism during Infection. Front Microbiol
3:23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3271275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vasanthakrishnan RB, de Las Heras A, Scortti M, Deshayes C, Colegrave N, Vazquez-Boland JA. 2015. 
PrfA regulation offsets the cost of Listeria virulence outside the host. Environ Microbiol
17:4566–4579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737189</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26178789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gahan CGM, Hill C. 2014. 
Listeria monocytogenes: survival and adaptation in the gastrointestinal tract. Front Cell Infect Microbiol
4:9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24551601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becattini S, Littmann ER, Carter RA, Kim SG, Morjaria SM, Ling L, Gyaltshen Y, Fontana E, Taur Y, Leiner IM, Pamer EG. 2017. 
Commensal microbes provide first line defense against Listeria monocytogenes infection. J Exp Med
214:1973–1989.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5502438</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28588016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Light SH, Su L, Rivera-Lugo R, Cornejo JA, Louie A, lavarone AT, Ajo-Franklin CM, Portnoy DA. 2018. 
A flavin-based extracellular electron transfer mechanism in diverse Gram-positive bacteria. Nature
562:140–144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6221200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209391</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sousa S, Lecuit M, Cossart P. 2005. 
Microbial strategies to target, cross or disrupt epithelia. Curr Opin Cell Biol
17:489–498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16102958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slaghuis J, Goetz M, Engelbrecht F, Goebel W. 2004. 
Inefficient replication of Listeria innocua in the cytosol of mammalian cells. J Infect Dis
189:393–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14745696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goetz M, Bubert A, Wang G, Chico-Calero I, Vazquez-Boland JA, Beck M, Slaghuis J, Szalay AA, Goebel W. 2001. 
Microinjection and growth of bacteria in the cytosol of mammalian host cells. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
98:12221–12226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC59795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11572936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hwang C, Sinskey AJ, Lodish HF. 1992. 
Oxidized redox state of glutathione in the endoplasmic reticulum. Science
257:1496–1502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1523409</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Llopis J, McCaffery JM, Miyawaki A, Farquhar MG, Tsien RY. 1998. 
Measurement of cytosolic, mitochondrial, and Golgi pH in single living cells with green fluorescent proteins. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
95:6803–6808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC22642</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9618493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piez KA, Eagle H. 1958. 
The free amino acid pool of culture human cells. J Biol Chem
231:533–545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13538989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ray K, Marteyn B, Sansonetti PJ, Tang CM. 2009. 
Life on the inside: the intracellular lifestyle of cytosolic bacteria. Nat Rev Microbiol
7:333–340.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanman LE, Qian Y, Eisele NA, Ng TM, van der Linden WA, Monack DM, Weerapana E, Bogyo M. 2016. 
Disruption of glycolytic flux is a signal for inflammasome signaling and pyroptotic cell death. Elife
5:e13663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4846378</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27011353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wynosky-Dolfi MA, Snyder AG, Philip NH, Doonan PJ, Poffenberger MC, Avizonis D, Zwack EE, Riblett AM, Hu B, Strowig T, Flavell RA, Jones RG, Freedman BD, Brodsky IE. 2014. 
Oxidative metabolism enables Salmonella evasion of the NLRP3 inflammasome. J Exp Med
211:653–668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3978275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24638169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joseph B, Mertins S, Stoll R, Schar J, Umesha KR, Luo Q, Muller-Altrock S, Goebel W. 2008. 
Glycerol metabolism and PrfA activity in Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
190:5412–5430.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18502850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chico-Calero I, Suarez M, Gonzalez-Zorn B, Scortti M, Slaghuis J, Goebel W, European Listeria Genome Consortium, T., Vazquez-Boland JA. 2002. 
Hpt, a bacterial homolog of the microsomal glucose- 6-phosphate translocase, mediates rapid intracellular proliferation in Listeria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
99:431–436.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC117577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11756655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobel L, Sigal N, Borovok I, Ruppin E, Herskovits AA. 2012. 
Integrative genomic analysis identifies isoleucine and CodY as regulators of Listeria monocytogenes virulence. PLoS Genet
8:e1002887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3435247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22969433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ripio MT, Brehm K, Lara M, Suarez M, Vazquez-Boland JA. 1997. 
Glucose-1-phosphate utilization by Listeria monocytogenes is PrfA dependent and coordinately expressed with virulence factors. J Bacteriol
179:7174–7180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC179662</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9371468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joseph B, Przybilla K, Stuhler C, Schauer K, Slaghuis J, Fuchs TM, Goebel W. 2006. 
Identification of Listeria monocytogenes genes contributing to intracellular replication by expression profiling and mutant screening. J Bacteriol
188:556–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1347271</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16385046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsoy O, Ravcheev D, Mushegian A. 2009. 
Comparative genomics of ethanolamine utilization. J Bacteriol
191:7157–7164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2786565</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19783625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geoffroy C, Raveneau J, Beretti JL, Lecroisey A, Vazquez-Boland JA, Alouf JE, Berche P. 1991. 
Purification and characterization of an extracellular 29-kilodalton phospholipase C from Listeria monocytogenes. Infect Immun
59:2382–2388.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC258022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1904842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schauer K, Geginat G, Liang C, Goebel W, Dandekar T, Fuchs TM. 2010. 
Deciphering the intracellular metabolism of Listeria monocytogenes by mutant screening and modelling. BMC Genomics
11:573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3091722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20955543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haber A, Friedman S, Lobel L, Burg-Golani T, Sigal N, Rose J, Livnat-Levanon N, Lewinson O, Herskovits AA. 2017. 
L-glutamine Induces Expression of Listeria monocytogenes Virulence Genes. PLoS Pathog
13:e1006161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5289647</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28114430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klarsfeld AD, Goossens PL, Cossart P. 1994. 
Five Listeria monocytogenes genes preferentially expressed in infected mammalian cells: plcA, purH, purD, pyrE and an arginine ABC transporter gene, arp J. Mol Microbiol
13:585–597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7997171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marquis H, Bouwer HG, Hinrichs DJ, Portnoy DA. 1993. 
Intracytoplasmic growth and virulence of Listeria monocytogenes auxotrophic mutants. Infect Immun
61:3756–3760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC281074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8359896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng C, Wang X, Dong Z, Shao C, Yang Y, Fang W, Fang C, Wang H, Yang M, Jiang L, Zhou X, Song H. 2015. 
Aminopeptidase T of M29 Family Acts as A Novel Intracellular Virulence Factor for Listeria monocytogenes Infection. Sci Rep
5:17370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4661694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26610705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perry KJ, Higgins DE. 2013. 
A differential fluorescence-based genetic screen identifies Listeria monocytogenes determinants required for intracellular replication. J Bacteriol
195:3331–3340.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3719552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23687268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verheul A, Rombouts FM, Beumer RR, Abee T. 1995. 
An ATP-dependent L-carnitine transporter in Listeria monocytogenes Scott A is involved in osmoprotection. J Bacteriol
177:3205–3212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC177012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7768820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verheul A, Hagting A, Amezaga MR, Booth IR, Rombouts FM, Abee T. 1995. 
A di- and tripeptide transport system can supply Listeria monocytogenes Scott A with amino acids essential for growth. Appl Environ Microbiol
61:226–233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC167277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7887604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xayarath B, Marquis H, Port GC, Freitag NE. 2009. 
Listeria monocytogenes CtaP is a multifunctional cysteine transport-associated protein required for bacterial pathogenesis. Mol Microbiol
74:956–973.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802666</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19818015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camejo A, Buchrieser C, Couve E, Carvalho F, Reis O, Ferreira P, Sousa S, Cossart P, Cabanes D. 2009. 
In vivo transcriptional profiling of Listeria monocytogenes and mutagenesis identify new virulence factors involved in infection. PLoS Pathog
5:e1000449.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2679221</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borezee E, Pellegrini E, Berche P. 2000. 
OppA of Listeria monocytogenes, an oligopeptide-binding protein required for bacterial growth at low temperature and involved in intracellular survival. Infect Immun
68:7069–7077.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11083832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wouters JA, Hain T, Darji A, Hufner E, Wemekamp-Kamphuis H, Chakraborty T, Abee T. 2005. 
Identification and characterization of Di- and tripeptide transporter DtpT of Listeria monocytogenes EGD-e. Appl Environ Microbiol
71:5771–5778.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1265990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillmaier N, Gotz A, Schulz A, Eisenreich W, Goebel W. 2012. 
Metabolic responses of primary and transformed cells to intracellular Listeria monocytogenes. PLoS One
7:e52378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3528701</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23285016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowd GC, Joyce SA, Hill C, Gahan CG. 2011. 
Investigation of the mechanisms by which Listeria monocytogenes grows in porcine gallbladder bile. Infect Immun
79:369–379.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3019883</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20937762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matern A, Pedrolli D, Grosshennig S, Johansson J, Mack M. 2016. 
Uptake and Metabolism of Antibiotics Roseoflavin and 8-Demethyl-8-Aminoriboflavin in Riboflavin-Auxotrophic Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
198:3233–3243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5105903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27672192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karpowich NK, Song JM, Cocco N, Wang DN. 2015. 
ATP binding drives substrate capture in an ECF transporter by a release-and-catch mechanism. Nat Struct Mol Biol
22:565–571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4634891</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26052893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schauer K, Stolz J, Scherer S, Fuchs TM. 2009. 
Both thiamine uptake and biosynthesis of thiamine precursors are required for intracellular replication of Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
191:2218–2227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655527</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19181806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keeney KM, Stuckey JA, O’Riordan MX. 2007. 
LplAI-dependent utilization of host lipoyl peptides enables Listeria cytosolic growth and virulence. Mol Microbiol
66:758–770.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2367003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen QH, Hagar JA, O’Riordan MX, Cronan JE. 2011. A complex lipoate utilization pathway in Listeria monocytogenes. J Biol Chem
2011/July/20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3173067</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21768091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Riordan M, Moors MA, Portnoy DA. 2003. 
Listeria intracellular growth and virulence require host-derived lipoic acid. Science
302:462–464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14564012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Y, O’Riordan MXD. 2010. 
Branched-Chain Fatty Acids Promote Listeria monocytogenes Intracellular Infection and Virulence. Infect Immun
78:4667–4673.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2976352</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20823206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan DI, Vogel HJ. 2010. 
Current understanding of fatty acid biosynthesis and the acyl carrier protein. Biochem J
430:1–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20662770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao J, Rock CO. 2017. 
Exogenous fatty acid metabolism in bacteria. Biochimie.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5665373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28668270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujita Y, Matsuoka H, Hirooka K. 2007. 
Regulation of fatty acid metabolism in bacteria. Mol Microbiol
66:829–839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17919287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y-M, Rock CO. 2008. 
Membrane lipid homeostasis in bacteria. Nat Rev Microbiol
6:222–233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18264115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh AK, Zhang Y-M, Zhu K, Subramanian C, Li Z, Jayaswal RK, Gatto C, Rock CO, Wilkinson BJ. 2009. 
FabH selectivity for anteiso branched-chain fatty acid precursors in low-temperature adaptation in Listeria monocytogenes. FEMS Microbiol Lett
301:188–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2818224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19863661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annous BA, Becker LA, Bayles DO, Labeda DP, Wilkinson BJ. 1997. 
Critical role of anteiso-C15:0 fatty acid in the growth of Listeria monocytogenes at low temperatures. Appl Environ Microbiol
63:3887–3894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC168698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9327552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh VK, Hattangady DS, Giotis ES, Singh AK, Chamberlain NR, Stuart MK, Wilkinson BJ. 2008. 
Insertional inactivation of branched-chain alpha-keto acid dehydrogenase in Staphylococcus aureus leads to decreased branched-chain membrane fatty acid content and increased susceptibility to certain stresses. Appl Environ Microbiol
74:5882–5890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2565972</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18689519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keeney K, Colosi L, Weber W, O’Riordan M. 2009. 
Generation of Branched-Chain Fatty Acids through Lipoate-Dependent Metabolism Facilitates Intracellular Growth of Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
191:2187–2196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655518</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19181817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Y, Wilkinson BJ, Standiford TJ, Akinbi HT, O’Riordan MX. 2012. 
Fatty Acids Regulate Stress Resistance and Virulence Factor Production for Listeria monocytogenes. J Bacteriol
194:5274–5284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3457240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22843841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milenbachs AA, Brown DP, Moors M, Youngman P. 1997. 
Carbon-source regulation of virulence gene expression in Listeria monocytogenes. Mol Microbiol
23:1075–1085.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9076743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deutscher J, Kuster E, Bergstedt U, Charrier V, Hillen W. 1995. 
Protein kinase-dependent HPr/CcpA interaction links glycolytic activity to carbon catabolite repression in gram-positive bacteria. Mol Microbiol
15:1049–1053.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7623661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herro R, Poncet S, Cossart P, Buchrieser C, Gouin E, Glaser P, Deutscher J
2005. 
How seryl-phosphorylated HPr inhibits PrfA, a transcription activator of Listeria monocytogenes virulence genes. J Mol Microbiol Biotechnol
9:224–234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16415595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vu-Khac H, Miller KW. 2009. 
Regulation of mannose phosphotransferase system permease and virulence gene expression in Listeria monocytogenes by the EII(t)Man transporter. Appl Environ Microbiol
75:6671–6678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19734332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Portman JL, Dubensky SB, Peterson BN, Whiteley AT, Portnoy DA. 2017. 
Activation of the Listeria monocytogenes Virulence Program by a Reducing Environment. MBio
8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5646252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29042499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reniere ML, Whiteley AT, Portnoy DA. 2016. 
An In Vivo Selection Identifies Listeria monocytogenes Genes Required to Sense the Intracellular Environment and Activate Virulence Factor Expression. PLoS Pathog
12:e1005741.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4945081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27414028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobel L, Sigal N, Borovok I, Belitsky BR, Sonenshein AL, Herskovits AA. 2015. 
The metabolic regulator CodY links Listeria monocytogenes metabolism to virulence by directly activating the virulence regulatory gene prfA. Mol Microbiol
95:624–644.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4329120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25430920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner M, Lobel L, Borovok I, Sigal N, Herskovits AA. 2018. 
Controlled branched-chain amino acids auxotrophy in Listeria monocytogenes allows isoleucine to serve as a host signal and virulence effector. PLoS Genet
14:e1007283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5864092</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29529043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu CD. 2006. 
Pathways and regulation of bacterial arginine metabolism and perspectives for obtaining arginine overproducing strains. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol
70:261–272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan S, Begley M, Gahan CG, Hill C. 2009. 
Molecular characterization of the arginine deiminase system in Listeria monocytogenes: regulation and role in acid tolerance. Environ Microbiol
11:432–445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19196274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng C, Dong Z, Han X, Sun J, Wang H, Jiang L, Yang Y, Ma T, Chen Z, Yu J, Fang W, Song H. 2017. 
Listeria monocytogenes 10403S Arginine Repressor ArgR Finely Tunes Arginine Metabolism Regulation under Acidic Conditions. Front Microbiol
8:145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5291005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28217122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loh E, Dussurget O, Gripenland J, Vaitkevicius K, Tiensuu T, Mandin P, Repoila F, Buchrieser C, Cossart P, Johansson J. 2009. 
A trans-acting riboswitch controls expression of the virulence regulator PrfA in Listeria monocytogenes. Cell
139:770–779.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19914169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meister A, Anderson ME. 1983. 
Glutathione. Annu Rev Biochem
52:711–760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6137189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reniere ML, Whiteley AT, Hamilton KL, John SM, Lauer P, Brennan RG, Portnoy DA. 2015. 
Glutathione activates virulence gene expression of an intracellular pathogen. Nature
517:170–173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4305340</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25567281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall M, Grundstrom C, Begum A, Lindberg MJ, Sauer UH, Almqvist F, Johansson J, Sauer-Eriksson AE. 2016. 
Structural basis for glutathione-mediated activation of the virulence regulatory protein PrfA in Listeria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
113:14733–14738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5187702</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27930316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Portman JL, Huang Q, Reniere ML, lavarone AT, Portnoy DA. 2017. 
Activity of the Pore-Forming Virulence Factor Listeriolysin O Is Reversibly Inhibited by Naturally Occurring S-Glutathionylation. Infect Immun
85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5364301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28138025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stritzker J, Janda J, Schoen C, Taupp M, Pilgrim S, Gentschev I, Schreier P, Geginat G, Goebel W. 2004. 
Growth, virulence, and immunogenicity of Listeria monocytogenes aro mutants. Infect Immun
72:5622–5629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC517589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385459</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bueno E, Mesa S, Bedmar EJ, Richardson DJ, Delgado MJ. 2012. 
Bacterial adaptation of respiration from oxic to microoxic and anoxic conditions: redox control. Antioxid Redox Signal
16:819–852.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3283443</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22098259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuffre A, Borisov VB, Arese M, Sarti P, Forte E. 2014. 
Cytochrome bd oxidase and bacterial tolerance to oxidative and nitrosative stress. Biochim Biophys Acta
1837:1178–1187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24486503</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strahl H, Hamoen LW. 2010. 
Membrane potential is important for bacterial cell division. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
107:12281–12286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2901462</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20566861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilstrup M, Hammer K, Ruhdal Jensen P, Martinussen J. 2005. 
Nucleotide metabolism and its control in lactic acid bacteria. FEMS Microbiol Rev
29:555–590.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15935511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meadows JA, Wargo MJ. 2015. 
Carnitine in bacterial physiology and metabolism. Microbiology
161:1161–1174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4635513</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25787873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brubaker SW, Bonham KS, Zanoni I, Kagan JC. 2015. 
Innate immune pattern recognition: a cell biological perspective. Annu Rev Immunol
33:257–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5146691</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25581309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu T, Zhao Y, Xi J. 2016. 
A New Second Messenger: Bacterial c-di-AMP. Crit Rev Eukaryot Gene Expr
26:309–316.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27910745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodward JJ, Iavarone AT, Portnoy DA. 2010. 
c-di-AMP secreted by intracellular Listeria monocytogenes activates a host type I interferon response. Science
328:1703–1705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3156580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20508090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witte CE, Whiteley AT, Burke TP, Sauer JD, Portnoy DA, Woodward JJ. 2013. 
Cyclic di-AMP is critical for Listeria monocytogenes growth, cell wall homeostasis, and establishment of infection. MBio
4:e00282–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3663569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23716572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sauer JD, Sotelo-Troha K, von Moltke J, Monroe KM, Rae CS, Brubaker SW, Hyodo M, Hayakawa Y, Woodward JJ, Portnoy DA, Vance RE. 2011. 
The N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea-induced Goldenticket mouse mutant reveals an essential function of Sting in the in vivo interferon response to Listeria monocytogenes and cyclic dinucleotides. Infect Immun
79:688–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3028833</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21098106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whiteley AT, Eaglesham JB, de Oliveira Mann CC, Morehouse BR, Lowey B, Nieminen EA, Danilchanka O, King DS, Lee ASY, Mekalanos JJ, Kranzusch PJ. 2019. 
Bacterial cGAS-like enzymes synthesize diverse nucleotide signals. Nature.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6544370</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30787435</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaudet RG, Sintsova A, Buckwalter CM, Leung N, Cochrane A, Li J, Cox AD, Moffat J, Gray-Owen SD. 2015. 
INNATE IMMUNITY. Cytosolic detection of the bacterial metabolite HBP activates TIFA-dependent innate immunity. Science
348:1251–1255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26068852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou P, She Y, Dong N, Li P, He H, Borio A, Wu Q, Lu S, Ding X, Cao Y, Xu Y, Gao W, Dong M, Ding J, Wang D-C, Zamyatina A, Shao F. 2018. 
Alpha-kinase 1 is a cytosolic innate immune receptor for bacterial ADP-heptose. Nature
561:122–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30111836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
