<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31536191</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK546582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424">Body Image Distortion</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosseini</LastName><ForeName>Seyed Alireza</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kern Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Padhy</LastName><ForeName>Ranjit K.</ForeName><Initials>RK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UCLA - Kern Medical</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Body image is the subjective picture of individuals of their own body, irrespective of how their body actually looks. Body image is a complex construct comprising thoughts, feelings, evaluations, and behaviors related to one’s body. Body image misperception is common in the general population and is also a core component of several serious diseases, including body dysmorphic disorder, anorexia nervosa, and bulimia nervosa. Distortions in body image are unpleasant and can have tragic results. Poor body image can affect physical and psychological health and can influence self-esteem, mood, competence, social functioning, and occupational functioning. The understanding of the neurotypical distortions in healthy cognition and perceptual distortions in clinical conditions is essential to address body image concerns and enable suffering individuals to lead more contented and productive lives. In this activity, we outline the role of body image in psychological and physical functioning and describe features of various body image-related conditions and disorders. <b>Historical Perspective</b> Early in the 1900s, there were considerable efforts by neurologists to understand unusual forms of body perception reported by patients with brain injury, or phantom limb experience in amputees. The early concepts of body image indeed were rooted in neuropathology. Head, in 1920, first defined body image as a unity of past experiences created in the cerebral sensory cortex. Schilder, who was a neurologist, proposed a biopsychosocial approach to body image, highlighting the need to examine its neurological, psychological, and sociocultural components. Newell noted that body image is dynamic and changes with age, mood, or even clothing. Krueger suggested that body image is the representation of identity derived from both external and internal body experiences. <b>Definition</b> What is body image, and why is it important? Body image is one of the components of personal identity. Body image is the figure that one has on their anthropometric measurements, contours, and shape of the body; and also the feelings correlated to these factors that affect the satisfaction with the body or specific parts of the body. Indeed, body image represents how we think, feel, perceive, and behave regarding our bodies. Body image is a multidimensional concept. The complexity of body image can be appreciated by looking at its components. These components apply to people with healthy and unhealthy perceptions of their bodies and include: Cognitive: thoughts and beliefs about the body. Perceptual: how people perceive the size and shape of their body and body parts. Affective: feelings about the body. Behavioral: the actions that people perform to check on, tend to, alter, or conceal their body. Related but different terms are often used interchangeably in the literature concerning the state of consciousness in which there is an altered body image perception, including body image distortion, body image misperception, body image disturbance, negative body image, altered body image, and body dissatisfaction. The problem of variable terms is intensified by the fact that some studies focus on psychiatric or medical patients, some deal with nonpatients, and others deal with both groups. Body image distortion is a multidimensional symptom, comprising various components of body image. Components that most widely accepted are the cognitive, the perceptive, and the affective. The cognitive component is from thoughts and beliefs concerning body shape and appearance, and the mental representation of the body. The perceptive component involves the identification and estimation of the body, and it indicates the accuracy of the individuals' evaluation of their body size, shape, and weight compared to their actual proportions. Finally, the affective component includes feelings that individuals develop towards their body and satisfaction or dissatisfaction of individuals about their body. Thereupon, body image disturbance can manifest as disturbance of percept (i.e., distortion) and concept (i.e., body dissatisfaction). Perceptual disturbance involves the failure to evaluate the size of one’s body accurately. Body dissatisfaction includes attitudinal or affective perception of one’s body and negative feelings and cognitions. Body image disturbances are thought to also manifest on a behavioral level, such as body avoidance, body checking, or dieting. Negative body image characteristically demonstrates a dissatisfaction of body or body parts, preoccupation with appearance, and engaging in behaviors such as frequent mirror checking, self-weighing, or avoidance of public situations. Negative body image often gets measured as body dissatisfaction. Body dissatisfaction is attributable to a discrepancy between the perception of body image and its idealized image. <b>Body Image Development </b> There are some debates as to when body image development begins. Price believes that primitive sense of body image originates in the uterus with spontaneous movements of the fetus and corresponding feedback from sensory and proprioceptive input. Body image is a learned phenomenon from experiences during both pre-natal and post-natal development in which cross-cortical connections and mirror neurons play prominent roles. Complex interactions between neurophysiological, socio-cultural, and cognitive factors contribute to body image development and maintenance. Different factors such as gender, fashion, peer groups, educational and familial influences, evolving socialization, and physical alterations (hair growth, acne, breast development, menstruation) put children into unknown territory with vulnerable body images. Primary socialization takes place early in life, and a sense of self-recognition is assumed to develop by the age of two. Children in the toddler years become aware of their gender. They also discover social norms, such as competitiveness and athleticism for men (strong legs, muscles, large arms), and beauty or smallness for females (glossy hair, perfect skin, tiny waist, no hips). When children become aware of their body appearance, they attempt to manipulate their parents to receive admiration and approval. This need for approval grows upon starting school, exhibiting a need for social acceptance. Cash assumes body image as a learned behavior. Smolak proposes that children mainly focus on appearance in the context of the toys they play with, such as Barbie dolls. As children grow and socialize, they begin comparing themselves with other children, especially concerning appearance (e.g., little children desire to be bigger). By the age of 6, body shape becomes increasingly prominent consideration (especially muscle and weight). Smolak reported that among school children aged 6 to 12 years old, 40–50% demonstrated dissatisfaction with some part of their body size or shape. Adolescence indicates the transition from childhood to adulthood and is associated with physical and social changes. Adolescence is a critical period in body image development. Body image in adolescents is also under the influence of parents. The parent-adolescent relationship has a significant impact on the development of adolescents’ body dissatisfaction. Parents send sociocultural or critical messages and messages about body appearance ideals to their children. When Individuals feel secure regarding their relationships, they are more satisfied with their body and less likely to think in ways that they have to adhere to appearance ideals to receive others’ acceptance. Researches have shown that adolescents with better parent-adolescent relationships are less likely to experience body dissatisfaction. Although in younger children, the influence of families on body image development is more significant than friends, the role of parents decreases as children get older and peer responses become more important than families. Body image in people aged 14 to 27 is greatly affected by their peers. A critical event or series of events such as teasing and rejection may lead to body image misperception. Studies have found that the more frequent being teased about body size and weight while growing up, the more likely to experience body image distortion and body dissatisfaction during adulthood.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s5">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s6">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s7">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s8">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s9">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s10">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s11">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s12">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s13">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-18424" sec="article-18424.s14">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shoraka H, Amirkafi A, Garrusi B. Review of Body Image and some of Contributing Factors in Iranian Population. Int J Prev Med. 2019;10:19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30820306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alleva JM, Sheeran P, Webb TL, Martijn C, Miles E. A Meta-Analytic Review of Stand-Alone Interventions to Improve Body Image. PLoS One. 2015;10(9):e0139177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4587797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26418470</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spreckelsen PV, Glashouwer KA, Bennik EC, Wessel I, de Jong PJ. Negative body image: Relationships with heightened disgust propensity, disgust sensitivity, and self-directed disgust. PLoS One. 2018;13(6):e0198532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5988313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29870558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadibolova R, Ferrè ER, Linkenauger SA, Longo MR. Distortions of perceived volume and length of body parts. Cortex. 2019 Feb;111:74-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30471452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaudio S, Brooks SJ, Riva G. Nonvisual multisensory impairment of body perception in anorexia nervosa: a systematic review of neuropsychological studies. PLoS One. 2014;9(10):e110087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4193894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irvine KR, McCarty K, McKenzie KJ, Pollet TV, Cornelissen KK, Tovée MJ, Cornelissen PL. Distorted body image influences body schema in individuals with negative bodily attitudes. Neuropsychologia. 2019 Jan;122:38-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30500663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King ICC. Body image in paediatric burns: a review. Burns Trauma. 2018;6:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29744373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva D, Ferriani L, Viana MC. Depression, anthropometric parameters, and body image in adults: a systematic review. Rev Assoc Med Bras (1992) 2019 Jun 03;65(5):731-738.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamotova A, Bulant J, Bocek V, Papezova H. Dissatisfaction with own body makes patients with eating disorders more sensitive to pain. J Pain Res. 2017;10:1667-1675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5522677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28761371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewer M, Bauer A, Hartmann AS, Vocks S. Different Facets of Body Image Disturbance in Binge Eating Disorder: A Review. Nutrients. 2017 Nov 28;9(12)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5748745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29182531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price EH. A critical review of congenital phantom limb cases and a developmental theory for the basis of body image. Conscious Cogn. 2006 Jun;15(2):310-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16182566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bearman SK, Martinez E, Stice E, Presnell K. The Skinny on Body Dissatisfaction: A Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Girls and Boys. J Youth Adolesc. 2006 Apr;35(2):217-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1540456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16912810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grilo CM, Wilfley DE, Brownell KD, Rodin J. Teasing, body image, and self-esteem in a clinical sample of obese women. Addict Behav. 1994 Jul-Aug;19(4):443-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7992678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keizer A, van Elburg A, Helms R, Dijkerman HC. A Virtual Reality Full Body Illusion Improves Body Image Disturbance in Anorexia Nervosa. PLoS One. 2016;11(10):e0163921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27711234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang HY, Ahn JW, Jeon MK. Factors Affecting Body Image Discordance Amongst Korean Adults Aged 19-39 Years. Osong Public Health Res Perspect. 2018 Aug;9(4):197-206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6110325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30159226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahadzadeh AS, Rafik-Galea S, Alavi M, Amini M. Relationship between body mass index, body image, and fear of negative evaluation: Moderating role of self-esteem. Health Psychol Open. 2018 Jan-Jun;5(1):2055102918774251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6024295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29977587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damiano SR, Hart LM, Paxton SJ. Development and validation of parenting measures for body image and eating patterns in childhood. J Eat Disord. 2015;3:5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25774298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Mellor D, Kiehne M, Ricciardelli LA, McCabe MP, Xu Y. Body dissatisfaction, engagement in body change behaviors and sociocultural influences on body image among Chinese adolescents. Body Image. 2010 Mar;7(2):156-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaewpradub N, Kiatrungrit K, Hongsanguansri S, Pavasuthipaisit C. Association Among Internet Usage, Body Image and Eating Behaviors of Secondary School Students. Shanghai Arch Psychiatry. 2017 Aug 25;29(4):208-217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28955140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths S, Murray SB, Krug I, McLean SA. The Contribution of Social Media to Body Dissatisfaction, Eating Disorder Symptoms, and Anabolic Steroid Use Among Sexual Minority Men. Cyberpsychol Behav Soc Netw. 2018 Mar;21(3):149-156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5865626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29363993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Vries DA, Vossen HGM, van der Kolk-van der Boom P. Social Media and Body Dissatisfaction: Investigating the Attenuating Role of Positive Parent-Adolescent Relationships. J Youth Adolesc. 2019 Mar;48(3):527-536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6394528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30478819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Berg PA, Mond J, Eisenberg M, Ackard D, Neumark-Sztainer D. The link between body dissatisfaction and self-esteem in adolescents: similarities across gender, age, weight status, race/ethnicity, and socioeconomic status. J Adolesc Health. 2010 Sep;47(3):290-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2923488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20708569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolton MA, Lobben I, Stern TA. The impact of body image on patient care. Prim Care Companion J Clin Psychiatry. 2010;12(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2911009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20694111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kremer I, Orbach I, Rosenbloom T. Body image among victims of sexual and physical abuse. Violence Vict. 2013;28(2):259-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23763111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson M, Duffy F, Newman E, Prieto Bravo C, Ates HH, Sharpe H. Exploring changes in body image, eating and exercise during the COVID-19 lockdown: A UK survey. Appetite. 2021 Apr 01;159:105062.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7711175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moehlecke M, Blume CA, Cureau FV, Kieling C, Schaan BD. Self-perceived body image, dissatisfaction with body weight and nutritional status of Brazilian adolescents: a nationwide study. J Pediatr (Rio J) 2020 Jan - Feb;96(1):76-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30098939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Sabbah H, Vereecken CA, Elgar FJ, Nansel T, Aasvee K, Abdeen Z, Ojala K, Ahluwalia N, Maes L. Body weight dissatisfaction and communication with parents among adolescents in 24 countries: international cross-sectional survey. BMC Public Health. 2009 Feb 06;9:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2645388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19200369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones WR, Saeidi S, Morgan JF. Knowledge and attitudes of psychiatrists towards eating disorders. Eur Eat Disord Rev. 2013 Jan;21(1):84-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23350077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surgenor LJ, Maguire S. Assessment of anorexia nervosa: an overview of universal issues and contextual challenges. J Eat Disord. 2013;1:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4081667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24999408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips KA. The Presentation of Body Dysmorphic Disorder in Medical Settings. Prim psychiatry. 2006 Jul;13(7):51-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1712667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17183412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlgren CL, Stedal K. Cognitive Remediation Therapy for Adolescents with Anorexia Nervosa-Treatment Satisfaction and the Perception of Change. Behav Sci (Basel) 2017 Apr 18;7(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5485453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs G, Fernández de la Cruz L, Mataix-Cols D. Recent advances in understanding and managing body dysmorphic disorder. Evid Based Ment Health. 2017 Aug;20(3):71-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5566091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28729345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis H, Attia E. Pharmacotherapy of eating disorders. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2017 Nov;30(6):452-457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8221404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28806268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambrou C, Veale D, Wilson G. Appearance concerns comparisons among persons with body dysmorphic disorder and nonclinical controls with and without aesthetic training. Body Image. 2012 Jan;9(1):86-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21893438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keating C, Thomas N, Stephens J, Castle DJ, Rossell SL. Dysmorphic concern is related to delusional proneness and negative affect in a community sample. Psychiatry Res. 2016 Jun 30;240:76-79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27085667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarenga Mdos S, Scagliusi FB, Philippi ST. Development and validity of the Disordered Eating Attitude Scale (DEAS). Percept Mot Skills. 2010 Apr;110(2):379-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20499550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindvall Dahlgren C, Wisting L, Rø Ø. Feeding and eating disorders in the DSM-5 era: a systematic review of prevalence rates in non-clinical male and female samples. J Eat Disord. 2017;5:56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voelker DK, Reel JJ, Greenleaf C. Weight status and body image perceptions in adolescents: current perspectives. Adolesc Health Med Ther. 2015;6:149-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4554432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26347007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacchetti S, Robinson P, Bogaardt A, Clare A, Ouellet-Courtois C, Luyten P, Bateman A, Fonagy P. Reduced mentalizing in patients with bulimia nervosa and features of borderline personality disorder: A case-control study. BMC Psychiatry. 2019 May 06;19(1):134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6501333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31060534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh AR, Veale D. Understanding and treating body dysmorphic disorder. Indian J Psychiatry. 2019 Jan;61(Suppl 1):S131-S135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6343413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bjornsson AS, Didie ER, Phillips KA. Body dysmorphic disorder. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2010;12(2):221-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20623926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tod D, Edwards C, Cranswick I. Muscle dysmorphia: current insights. Psychol Res Behav Manag. 2016;9:179-88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4977020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27536165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aderka IM, Gutner CA, Lazarov A, Hermesh H, Hofmann SG, Marom S. Body image in social anxiety disorder, obsessive-compulsive disorder, and panic disorder. Body Image. 2014 Jan;11(1):51-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24095651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher M. The course and outcome of eating disorders in adults and in adolescents: a review. Adolesc Med. 2003 Feb;14(1):149-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12529198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinhausen HC. Outcome of eating disorders. Child Adolesc Psychiatr Clin N Am. 2009 Jan;18(1):225-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19014869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frank GKW, Shott ME, DeGuzman MC. Recent advances in understanding anorexia nervosa. F1000Res. 2019;8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6480957</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31069054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong K, Nezgovorova V, Hollander E. New perspectives in the treatment of body dysmorphic disorder. F1000Res. 2018;7:361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29636904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Dea JA, Abraham S. Improving the body image, eating attitudes, and behaviors of young male and female adolescents: a new educational approach that focuses on self-esteem. Int J Eat Disord. 2000 Jul;28(1):43-57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10800013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pettersen G, Rosenvinge JH, Thune-Larsen KB, Wynn R. Clinical confidence following an interprofessional educational program on eating disorders for health care professionals: a qualitative analysis. J Multidiscip Healthc. 2012;5:201-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3426273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22936849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vust S, Cook-Darzens S, Lier F, Ambresin AE. [Adolescents suffering from anorexia nervosa: an evidence-based approach of the parent's role in 2018]. Rev Med Suisse. 2018 Apr 18;14(603):835-838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29668146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Collaborating Centre for Mental Health (UK) Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder: Core Interventions in the Treatment of Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder and Body Dysmorphic Disorder. British Psychological Society (UK); Leicester (UK): 2006. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21834191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31536191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
