<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">31599798</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6963</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>32</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in rheumatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>One year in review: Kawasaki disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>15</StartPage>
          <EndPage>20</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>15-20</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000671</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Kawasaki disease is a childhood vasculitis of unknown origin, whose major complication is the development of coronary artery aneurysms (CAA). The purpose of this review is to provide an overview on the most recent evidence on the pathogenesis, diagnosis and treatment options of Kawasaki disease summarizing the most relevant studies published in the last year.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Several genetic polymorphisms leading to Kawasaki disease susceptibility have been identified, mostly related to immune system regulation; potential external triggers are being investigated by environmental epidemiology studies. A new diagnostic test based on trascriptomics has been tested with promising preliminary results. With regards to first-line treatments, the real effectiveness of high-dose aspirin remains a matter of debate. For refractory cases, the ones at the highest risk for developing CAA, promising results come from the use of biologic agents, especially TNF and IL-1 blockers.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Recent literature has provided interesting insights on the various factors involved in the complex scenario behind the pathogenesis of Kawasaki disease, especially genetic ones. Novel diagnostic tests and new evidence on the use of biologic agents in Kawasaki disease are emerging, but further evidence is needed to permit early diagnosis and effective treatment of this condition.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tirelli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francesca</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Anna Meyer, Florence.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marrani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Edoardo</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Anna Meyer, Florence.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Giani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Teresa</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Anna Meyer, Florence.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Biotechnology, University of Siena, Siena.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cimaz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rolando</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences and Community Health, University of Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9000851</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1040-8711</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001688">Biological Products</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005343">Fibrinolytic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016756">Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>R16CO5Y76E</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001241">Aspirin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001241" MajorTopicYN="N">Aspirin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001688" MajorTopicYN="N">Biological Products</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003323" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Aneurysm</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D042241" MajorTopicYN="N">Early Diagnosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005343" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrinolytic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016756" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009080" MajorTopicYN="N">Mucocutaneous Lymph Node Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="Y">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011110" MajorTopicYN="N">Polymorphism, Genetic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31599798</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000671</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00002281-202001000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burns JC, Glodé MP. Kawasaki syndrome. Lancet 2004; 364:533–544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki A, Kamiya T, Kuwahara N, et al. Coronary arterial lesions of Kawasaki disease: cardiac catheterization findings of 1100 cases. Pediatr Cardiol 1986; 7:3–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen E, Sundel R. Kawasaki disease at 50 years. JAMA Pediatr 2016; 170:1093–1099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marrani E, Burns JC, Cimaz R. How should we classify kawasaki disease? Front Immunol 2018; 9:2974.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makino N, Nakamura Y, Yashiro M, et al. Epidemiological observations of Kawasaki disease in Japan, 2013–2014. Pediatr Int 2018; 60:581–587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cimaz R, Fanti E, Mauro A, et al. Epidemiology of Kawasaki disease in Italy: surveillance from national hospitalization records. Eur J Pediatr 2017; 176:1061–1065.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie X, Shi X, Liu M. The roles of genetic factors in Kawasaki disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of genetic association studies. Pediatr Cardiol 2018; 39:207–225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onouchi Y, Ozaki K, Burns JC, et al. Japan Kawasaki Disease Genome Consortium; US Kawasaki Disease Genetics Consortium. A genome-wide association study identifies three new risk loci for Kawasaki disease. Nat Genet 2012; 44:517–521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagelkerke SQ, Tacke CE, Breunis WB, et al. International Kawasaki Disease Genetics Consortium. Extensive ethnic variation and linkage disequilibrium at the FCGR2/3 locus: different genetic associations revealed in kawasaki disease. Front Immunol 2019; 10:185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elluru S, Negi V, Ephrem A, Sibe S. Intravenous immunoglobulin in autoimmune and inflammatory diseases: more than mere transfer of antibodies. Transfus Apher Sci 2007; 37:103–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowley AH. Is Kawasaki disease an infectious disorder? Int J Rheum Dis 2018; 21:20–25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura Y, Yashiro M, Uehara R, et al. Epidemiologic features of Kawasaki disease in Japan: results of the 2009–2010 nationwide survey. J Epidemiol 2012; 22:216–221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uehara R, Yashiro M, Nakamura Y, Yanagawa H. Kawasaki disease in parents and children. Pediatr Infect Dis J 2003; 92:694–697.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagata S. Causes of Kawasaki disease-from past to present. Front Pediatr 2019; 7:18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodo X, Curcoll R, Robinson M, et al. Tropospheric winds from northeastern China carry the etiologic agent of Kawasaki disease from its source to Japan. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2014; 111:7952–7957.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manlhiot C, Mueller B, O'Shea S, et al. Environmental epidemiology of Kawasaki disease: linking disease etiology, pathogenesis and global distribution. PLoS One 2018; 13:e0191087.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCrindle BW, Rowley AH, Newburger JW, et al. American Heart Association Rheumatic Fever, Endocarditis, and Kawasaki Disease Committee of the Council on Cardiovascular Disease in the Young; Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing; Council on Cardiovascular Surgery and Anesthesia; and Council on Epidemiology and Prevention. Diagnosis, treatment, and long-term management of kawasaki disease: a scientific statement for health professionals from the American Heart Association. Circulation 2017; 135:e927–e999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoang LT, Shimizu C, Ling L, et al. Global gene expression profiling identifies new therapeutic targets in acute Kawasaki disease. Genome Med 2014; 6:541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright VJ, Herberg JA, Kaforou M, et al. Immunopathology of Respiratory, Inflammatory and Infectious Disease Study (IRIS) Consortium and the Pediatric Emergency Medicine Kawasaki Disease Research Group (PEMKDRG). Diagnosis of Kawasaki disease using a minimal whole-blood gene expression signature. JAMA Pediatr 2018; 172:e182293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanoshima R, Hashimoto R, Suzuki T, et al. Effectiveness of antiplatelet therapy for Kawasaki disease: a systematic review. Eur J Pediatr 2019; 178:947–955.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng X, Yue P, Liu L, et al. Efficacy between low and high dose aspirin for the initial treatment of Kawasaki disease: current evidence based on a meta-analysis. PLoS One 2019; 14:e0217274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang T-J, Lin M-T, Lu C-Y, et al. The prevention of coronary arterial abnormalities in Kawasaki disease: a meta-analysis of the corticosteroid effectiveness. J Microbiol Immunol Infect 2018; 51:321–331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bar-Meir M, Kalisky I, Schwartz A, et al. Israeli Kawasaki Group. Prediction of resistance to intravenous immunoglobulin in children with Kawasaki disease. J Pediatric Infect Dis Soc 2018; 7:25–29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phuong LK, Curtis N, Gowdie P, et al. Treatment options for resistant Kawasaki disease. Pediatr Drugs 2018; 20:59–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stock AT, Jama HA, Hansen JA, Wicks P. TNF and IL-1 play essential but temporally distinct roles in driving cardiac inflammation in a murine model of Kawasaki disease. J Immunol 2019; 202:3151–3160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koizumi K, Hoshiai M, Katsumata N, et al. Infliximab regulates monocytes and regulatory T cells in Kawasaki disease. Pediatr Int 2018; 60:796–802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masuda H, Kobayashi T, Hachiya A, et al. Committee of Survey on Infliximab use for Kawasaki disease. Infliximab for the treatment of refractory Kawasaki disease: a nationwide survey in Japan. J Pediatr 2018; 195:115.e3–120.e3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori M, Hara T, Kikuchi M, et al. I Infliximab versus intravenous immunoglobulin for refractory Kawasaki disease: a phase 3, randomized, open-label, active-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter trial. Sci Rep 2018; 8:1994.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts SC, Jain S, Tremoulet AH, et al. The Kawasaki Disease Comparative Effectiveness (KIDCARE) trial: a phase III, randomized trial of second intravenous immunoglobulin versus infliximab for resistant Kawasaki disease. Contemp Clin Trials 2019; 79:98–103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Portman MA, Dahdah NS, Slee A, et al. EATAK Investigators. Etanercept with IVIg for acute Kawasaki disease: a randomized controlled trial. Pediatrics 2019; 143: pii: e20183675.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakita D, Kurashima Y, Crother TR, et al. Role of interleukin-1 signaling in a mouse model of Kawasaki disease–associated abdominal aortic aneurysm. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 2016; 36:886–897.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armaroli G, Verweyen E, Pretzer C, et al. Monocyte-derived interleukin-1β as the driver of S100A12-induced sterile inflammatory activation of human coronary artery endothelial cells: implications for the pathogenesis of Kawasaki disease. Arthritis Rheumatol (Hoboken, NJ) 2019; 71:792–804.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorelik M, Lee Y, Abe M, et al. IL-1 receptor antagonist, anakinra, prevents myocardial dysfunction in a mouse model of Kawasaki disease vasculitis and myocarditis. Clin Exp Immunol 2019; 98:101–110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kone-Paut I, Cimaz R, Herberg J, et al. The use of interleukin 1 receptor antagonist (anakinra) in Kawasaki disease: a retrospective cases series. Autoimmun Rev 2018; 17:768–774.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onouchi Y, Suzuki Y, Suzuki H, et al. ITPKC and CASP3 polymorphisms and risks for IVIG unresponsiveness and coronary artery lesion formation in Kawasaki disease. Pharmacogenomics J 2013; 13:52–59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamada H, Suzuki H, Onouchi Y, et al. Efficacy of primary treatment with immunoglobulin plus ciclosporin for prevention of coronary artery abnormalities in patients with Kawasaki disease predicted to be at increased risk of nonresponse to intravenous immunoglobulin (KAICA): a randomised controlled, open-label, blinded-endpoints, phase 3 trial. Lancet 2019; 393:1128–1137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X, Chen Y, Tang Y, et al. Predictors of intravenous immunoglobulin-resistant Kawasaki disease in children: a meta-analysis of 4442 cases. Eur J Pediatr 2018; 177:1279–1292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miura M, Kobayashi T, Kaneko T, et al. Association of severity of coronary artery aneurysms in patients with Kawasaki disease and risk of later coronary events. JAMA Pediatr 2018; 172: e180030.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
