<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31603846</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1669-9106</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>79 Suppl 3</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medicina</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Medicina (B Aires)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Neuromyelitis optica].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>60</StartPage>
          <EndPage>65</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>60-65</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Neuromyelitis optica (NMO) is an autoimmune, inflammatory and de myelinat ing disorder of the central nervous system with a predilection for the optic nerves and spinal cord. In 2004 the association of NMO with an antibody against the water channel aquaporin 4 (anti-AQP4) was published as a different pathology from multiple sclerosis (MS). Currently the term NMO spectrum disorders (NMOSD) is proposed, because the manifestations of the disease can be more extensive, affecting in addition to the optic nerve and spinal cord, the area postrema of the dorsal medulla, brainstem, diencephalon and typical brain areas (periependymal, corpus callosum, internal capsule and subcortical white matter). NMOSD is also applied to patients who meet the NMO criteria and are negative for AQP4-IgG. Within the latter group, the presence of another antibody, anti-MOG, has been detected in 20%, with a different physiopathological mechanism, but with a similar clinic and a better prognosis. The immunosuppressive treatment in the attack, as well as the long-term treatment in the cases that are indicated, is fundamental to avoid sequelaes and recurrences. The correct diagnosis of this entity is essential since it can be aggravated with the use of drugs useful in the treatment of MS. In this publication we will review the pathophysiology, clinical and diagnostic criteria of NMOSD, and discuss the different therapeutic options.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ferrán</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ceila</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centro Hospitalario Pereira Rossell, Facultad de Medicina, Universidad de la República, Montevideo, Uruguay.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pedemonte</LastName>
            <ForeName>Virginia</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centro Hospitalario Pereira Rossell, Facultad de Medicina, Universidad de la República, Montevideo, Uruguay.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Turcatti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emilio</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centro Hospitalario Pereira Rossell, Facultad de Medicina, Universidad de la República, Montevideo, Uruguay.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>González</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centro Hospitalario Pereira Rossell, Facultad de Medicina, Universidad de la República, Montevideo, Uruguay. E-mail: viciogon@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>spa</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Neuromielitis óptica.</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Argentina</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Medicina (B Aires)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0204271</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0025-7680</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="N">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009471" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromyelitis Optica</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
        <AbstractText>La neuromielitis óptica (NMO) es un trastorno autoinmune, inflamatorio y desmielinizante del sistema nervioso central con predilección por los nervios ópticos y médula espinal. En el año 2004 se publicó la asociación de NMO con un anticuerpo contra el canal de agua acuaporina 4 (anti-AQP4), como una enfermedad diferente de la esclerosis múltiple (EM). Actualmente se propone el término trastornos del espectro NMO (NMOSD), debido a que las manifestaciones de la enfermedad pueden ser más extensas, afectando además del nervio óptico y médula espinal, al área postrema del bulbo raquídeo, tronco encefálico, diencéfalo y áreas cerebrales típicas (periependimarias, cuerpo calloso, cápsula interna y sustancia blanca subcortical). NMOSD se aplica también a pacientes que cumplen los criterios de NMO y son negativos para anti-AQP4. Dentro de este último grupo se ha detectado en un 20% la presencia de otro anticuerpo, anti-MOG (Glicoproteína oligodendrocítica de mielina) con un mecanismo fisiopatológico diferente pero con una clínica, en algunos casos, similar, y en general con mejor pronóstico. El tratamiento inmunosupresor en la crisis, así como el tratamiento a largo plazo en los casos que esté indicado, es fundamental para evitar secuelas y recidivas. El diagnóstico correcto de esta entidad es fundamental ya que puede ser agravado con el uso de fármacos útiles en el tratamiento de EM. En esta publicación haremos una revisión de la fisiopatología, clínica y criterios diagnósticos de NMOSD, y discutiremos las distintas opciones terapéuticas.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aquaporin-4</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunoglobulin G</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromyelitis optica</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31603846</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
