<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31621907</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>528</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The reniform body: An integrative lateral protocerebral neuropil complex of Eumalacostraca identified in Stomatopoda and Brachyura.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1079</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1094</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1079-1094</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.24788</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Mantis shrimps (Stomatopoda) possess in common with other crustaceans, and with Hexapoda, specific neuroanatomical attributes of the protocerebrum, the most anterior part of the arthropod brain. These attributes include assemblages of interconnected centers called the central body complex and in the lateral protocerebra, situated in the eyestalks, paired mushroom bodies. The phenotypic homologues of these centers across Panarthropoda support the view that ancestral integrative circuits crucial to action selection and memory have persisted since the early Cambrian or late Ediacaran. However, the discovery of another prominent integrative neuropil in the stomatopod lateral protocerebrum raises the question whether it is unique to Stomatopoda or at least most developed in this lineage, which may have originated in the upper Ordovician or early Devonian. Here, we describe the neuroanatomical structure of this center, called the reniform body. Using confocal microscopy and classical silver staining, we demonstrate that the reniform body receives inputs from multiple sources, including the optic lobe's lobula. Although the mushroom body also receives projections from the lobula, it is entirely distinct from the reniform body, albeit connected to it by discrete tracts. We discuss the implications of their coexistence in Stomatopoda, the occurrence of the reniform body in another eumalacostracan lineage and what this may mean for our understanding of brain functionality in Pancrustacea.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2019 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thoen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hanne Halkinrud</ForeName>
            <Initials>HH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8695-9578</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sensory Neurobiology Group, Queensland Brain Institute, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wolff</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriella Hannah</ForeName>
            <Initials>GH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0075-4975</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biology, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marshall</LastName>
            <ForeName>Justin</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9006-6713</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sensory Neurobiology Group, Queensland Brain Institute, University of Queensland, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sayre</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcel E</ForeName>
            <Initials>ME</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2667-4228</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Lund Vision Group, Department of Biology, Lund University, Lund, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Strausfeld</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas James</ForeName>
            <Initials>NJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1115-1774</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, School of Mind, Brain and Behavior, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003386" MajorTopicYN="N">Brachyura</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="Y">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="Y">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019581" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropil</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Eumalacostraca</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">RRID AB_ 477019</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">RRID AB_1157911</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">RRID AB_301787</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">RRID AB_528479</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">RRID AB_572263</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">RRID AB_572268</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">brain</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">evolution</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">homology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">sensory integration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31621907</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.24788</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrew, D. R., Brown, S. M., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2012). The minute brain of the copepod Tigriopus californicus supports a complex ancestral ground pattern of the tetraconate cerebral nervous systems. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 520, 3446-3470. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.2309</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonsen, B. L., &amp; Paul, D. H. (2001). Serotonergic and octopaminergic systems in the squat lobster Munida quadrispina (Anomura, Galatheidae). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 439, 450-468. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.1362</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellonci, G. (1882). Nuove ricerche sulla struttura del ganglio ottico della Squilla mantis. Memorie della Accademia delle Scienze dell'Istituto di Bologna, Serie 4, 3, 419-426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaustein, D. N., Derby, C. D., Simmons, R. B., &amp; Beall, A. C. (1988). Structure of the brain and medulla terminalis of the spiny lobster Panulirus argus and the crayfish Procambarus clarkii, with an emphasis on olfactory centers. Journal of Crustacean Biology, 8, 493-519. https://doi.org/10.2307/1548686</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bodian, D. (1936). A new method for staining nerve fibers and nerve endings in mounted paraffin sections. Anatomical Record, 69, 153-162. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.1090650110</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brauchle, M., Kiontke, K., MacMenamin, P., Fitch, D. H. A., &amp; Piano, F. (2009). Evolution of early embryogenesis in rhabditid nematodes. Developmental Biology, 335, 253-262. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2009.07.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiou, T.-H., Kleinlogel, S., Cronin, T. W., Caldwell, R., Loeffler, B., Siddiqi, A., &amp; Marshall, N. J. (2008). Circular polarization vision in a stomatopod crustacean. Current Biology, 18, 429-434. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2008.02.066</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohn, R., Morantte, J., &amp; Ruta, V. (2015). Coordinated and compartmentalized neuromodulation shapes sensory processing in Drosophila. Cell, 163, 1742-1755. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2015.11.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cournil, I., Helluy, S. M., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (1994). Dopamine in the lobster Homarus gammarus. I. Comparative analysis of dopamine and tyrosine hydroxylase immunoreactivities in the nervous system of the juvenile. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 334, 455-469. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903440308</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crisp, K. M., Klukas, K. A., Gilchrist, L. S., Nartey, A. J., &amp; Mesce, K. A. (2001). Distribution and development of dopamine- and octopamine-synthesizing neurons in the medicinal leech. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 442, 115-129. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10077</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cronin, T. W., &amp; Marshall, N. J. (1989). A retina with at least ten spectral types of photoreceptors in a mantis shrimp. Nature, 339, 137-140. https://doi.org/10.1038/339137a0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolan, M.-J., Frechter, A., Bates, A. S., Dan, C., Huoviala, P., Roberts, R. J. V., … Jefferis, G. S. X. E. (2019). Neurogenetic dissection of the Drosophila lateral horn reveals major outputs, diverse behavioural functions, and interactions with the mushroom body. eLife, 2019(8), e43079. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.43079</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ehmer, B., &amp; Gronenberg, W. (2002). Segregation of visual input to the mushroom bodies in the honeybee (Apis mellifera). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 451, 362-373. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10355</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Facchini, C. (1890). Biografia di Guiseppe Bellonci e Indice de'suoi lavori. Bologna: Società Tipografica Azzoguidi.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia, G., &amp; Rössler, W. (2010). Parallel olfactory systems in insects: Anatomy and function. Annual Review of Entomology, 55, 399-420. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-ento-112408-085442</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamanaka, Y., Minoura, R., Nishino, H., Miura, T., &amp; Mizunami, M. (2016). Dopamine- and tyrosine hydroxylase-immunoreactive neurons in the brain of the American cockroach, Periplaneta americana. PLoS One, 11, e0160531. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0160531</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanström, B. (1931). Neue Untersuchungen über Sinnesorgane und Nervensystem der Crustaceen I. Zeitschrift für Morphologie und Oekologie der Tiere, 23, 80-236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., Anger, K., &amp; Dawirs, R. R. (1997). Immunocytochemical detection of acetylated α-tubulin and Drosophila synapsin in the embryonic crustacean nervous system. International Journal of Developmental Biology, 41, 477-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2008). Brain architecture in the terrestrial hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomura, Coenobitidae), a crustacean with a good aerial sense of smell. BMC Neuroscience, 9, 58. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2202-9-58</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klagges, B. R., Heimbeck, G., Godenschwege, T. A., Hofbauer, A., Pflugfelder, G. O., Reifegerste, R., … Buchner, E. (1996). Invertebrate synapsins: A single gene codes for several isoforms in Drosophila. The Journal of Neuroscience, 16, 3154-3165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Braun, P., Rivera, N. T., Schubart, C. D., Müller, C. H. G., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2015). Comparative analyses of olfactory systems in terrestrial crabs (Brachyura): Evidence for aerial olfaction? PeerJ, 3, e1433. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.1433</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Y.-S., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (1997). Morphology and sensory modality of mushroom body extrinsic neurons in the brain of the cockroach, Periplaneta americana. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 387, 631-650. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19971103)387:4&lt;631::AID-CNE9&gt;3.0.CO;2-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, C., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2012). Visual inputs to the mushroom body calyces of the whirligig beetle Dineutus sublineatus: Modality switching in an insect. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 520, 2562-2574. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23092</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall, N. J. (1988). A unique colour and polarization vision system in mantis shrimps. Nature, 333, 557-560. https://doi.org/10.1038/333557a0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall, N. J., Cronin, T. W., &amp; Kleinlogel, S. (2007). Stomatopod eye structure and function: A review. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 36, 420-448. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2007.01.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maza, F. J., Sztarker, J., Shkedy, A., Peszano, V. N., Locatelli, F. F., &amp; Delorenzi, A. (2016). Context-dependent memory traces in the crab's mushroom bodies: Functional support for a common origin of high-order memory centers. Proceedings of the National Academy of Science of the United States of America, 113, E7957-E7965. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1612418113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nässel, D. R. (1988). Serotonin and serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in the nervous system of insects. Progress in Neurobiology, 30, 1-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/0301-0082(88)90002-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paulk, A. C., &amp; Gronenberg, W. (2008). Higher order visual input to the mushroom bodies in the bee, Bombus impatiens. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 37, 443-458. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2008.03.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Orive, J., Mazor, O., Turner, G. C., Cassenaer, S., Wilson, R. I., &amp; Laurent, G. (2002). Oscillations and sparsening of odor representations in the mushroom body. Science, 297, 359-365. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1070502</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sayre, M. E., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2019). Mushroom bodies in crustaceans: Insect-like organization in the caridean shrimp Lebbeus groenlandicus. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 2019, 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24678</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schildberger, K. (1984). Multimodal interneurons in the cricket brain: Properties of identified extrinsic mushroom body cells. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 154, 71-79. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00605392</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindelin, J., Arganda-Carreras, I., Frise, E., Kaynig, V., Longair, M., Pietzsch, T., … Cardona, A. (2012). Fiji: An open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nature Methods, 9, 676-682. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skoulakis, E. M., Kalderon, D., &amp; Davis, R. L. (1993). Preferential expression in mushroom bodies of the catalytic subunit of protein kinase A and its role in learning and memory. Neuron, 11, 197-208. https://doi.org/10.1016/0896-6273(93)90178-T</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stemme, T., Iliffe, T. M., &amp; Bicker, G. (2016). Olfactory pathway in Xibalbanus tulumensis: Remipedian hemiellipsoid body as homologue of hexapod mushroom body. Cell and Tissue Research, 363, 635-648.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stern, M. (2009). The PM1 neurons, movement sensitive centrifugal visual brain neurons in the locust: Anatomy, physiology, and modulation by identified octopaminergic neurons. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 195, 123-137. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-008-0392-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (1976). Atlas of an insect brain. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer Verlag.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (2012). Arthropod brains: Evolution, functional elegance, and historical significance. Boston, MA: Harvard Belknap Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Li, Y. (1999). Organization of olfactory and multimodal afferent neurons supplying the calyx and pedunculus of the cockroach mushroom bodies. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 409, 603-625.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Sayre, M. E. (2019). Mushroom bodies in Reptantia reflect a major transition in crustacean brain evolution. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 2019, 1-22. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24752</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., Sinakevitch, I., Brown, S. M., &amp; Farris, S. M. (2009). Ground plan of the insect mushroom body: Functional and evolutionary implications. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 513, 265-291. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21948</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., Sinakevitch, I., &amp; Okamura, J.-Y. (2007). Organization of local interneurons in optic glomeruli of the dipterous visual system and comparisons with the antennal lobes. Developmental Neurobiology, 67, 1267-1288.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thazhath, R., Liu, C., &amp; Gaertig, J. (2002). Polyglycylation domain of β-tubulin maintains axonemal architecture and affects cytokinesis in Tetrahymena. Nature Cell Biology, 4, 256-259. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1038/ncb764</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thoen, H. H., Marshall, J., Wolff, G. H., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2017). Insect-like organization of the stomatopod central complex: Functional and phylogenetic implications. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience, 11, 12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnbeh.2017.00012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thoen, H. H., Sayre, M. E., Marshall, J., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2018). Representation of the stomatopod's retinal midband in the optic lobes: Putative neural substrates for integrating chromatic, achromatic and polarization information. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 526, 1148-1165. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24398</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thoen, H. H., Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Marshall, J. (2017). Neural organization of afferent pathways from the stomatopod compound eye. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525, 3010-3030. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogt, K., Aso, Y., Hige, T., Knapek, S., Ichinose, T., Friedrich, A. B., … Tanimoto, H. (2016). Direct neural pathways convey distinct visual information to Drosophila mushroom bodies. eLife, 5, e14009. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.14009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf, H., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2012). Serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in scorpion pectine neuropils: Similarities to insect and crustacean primary olfactory centres? Zoology, 115, 151-159. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.zool.2011.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe, J. M., Breinholt, J. W., Crandall, K. A., Lemmon, A. R., Lemmon, E. M., Timm, L. E., … Bracken-Grissom, H. D. (2019). A phylogenomic framework, evolutionary timeline and genomic resources for comparative studies of decapod crustaceans. Proceedings of the Royal Society London B, 286, 20190079. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2019.0079</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolff, G., Thoen, H. H., Marshall, N. J., Sayre, M. E., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2017). An insect-like mushroom body in a crustacean brain. eLife, 6, e29889. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.29889</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolff, G. H., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2015). Genealogical correspondence of mushroom bodies across invertebrate phyla. Current Biology, 25, 38-44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2014.10.049</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamazaki, Y., Nishikawa, N., &amp; Mizunami, M. (1998). Three classes of GABA-like immunoreactive neurons in the mushroom body of the cockroach. Brain Research, 788, 80-86. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0006-8993(97)01515-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
