<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31697762</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>PloS one</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Can adoption of pollution prevention techniques reduce pollution substitution?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0224868</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0224868</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0224868</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0224868</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pollution prevention (P2) has become an integral part of the U.S. environmental policy that emphasizes the benefits of preventing pollution generation at the source over treatment or recycling after the generation of wastes. This study extends the existing literature on the effect of voluntary adoption of P2 in reducing toxic wastes by examining the extent to which it reduces pollution substitution. We use facility panel data from the Toxics Release Inventory from 1991 to 2011 to examine the effect of the adoption of P2 techniques on the ratios of water releases to air releases, amounts of treatment to total releases, and amounts of recycling to total releases while controlling for endogeneity of the adoption of P2 techniques and facility fixed effects. We find that the adoption of P2 techniques reduces toxic air and water releases equally, but it is associated with increases in treated and recycled wastes over total releases to the environment.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sangyoul</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Food and Resource Economics Department, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, United States of America.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiang</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8671-487X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Food and Resource Economics Department, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, United States of America.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000397" MajorTopicYN="N">Air Pollution</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004787" MajorTopicYN="N">Environmental Pollution</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014876" MajorTopicYN="N">Water Pollution</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31697762</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6837384</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0224868</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-19-12500</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bi X. ‘Cleansing the air at the expense of waterways?’ Empirical evidence from the toxic releases of coal-fired power plants in the United States. J Regul Econ. 2017;51(1):18–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson M. Regulation-induced pollution substitution. Rev Econ Stat. 2019;forthcoming. Available from: 10.1162/rest_a_00797.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/rest_a_00797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenstone M. Estimating regulation-induced substitution: The effect of the Clean Air Act on water and ground pollution. Am Econ Rev. 2003;93(2):442–48. Available from: 10.1257/000282803321947498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1257/000282803321947498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King AA, Lenox MJ. Lean and green? An empirical examination of the relationship between lean production and environmental performance. Prod Oper Manage. 2001;10(3):244–56</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Pollution prevention law and policies
United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, DC; 2018a.  Available from: https://www.epa.gov/p2/pollution-prevention-law-and-policies#define.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranson M, Cox B, Keenan C, Teitelbaum D. The impact of pollution prevention on toxic environmental releases from U.S. manufacturing facilities. Environ Sci Technol. 2015;49(21):12951–57. 10.1021/acs.est.5b02367
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.5b02367</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora S, Gangopadhyay S. Toward a theoretical model of voluntary overcompliance. J Econ Behav Organ. 1995;28(3):289–309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delmas M, Montes-Sancho MJ, Shimshack JP. Information disclosure polices: Evidence from the electricity industry. Econ Inquiry. 2010;48(2):483–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamilton JT. Pollution as news: Media and stock market reactions to the toxics release inventory data. J Environ Econ Manage. 1995;28(1):98–113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khanna M. Non-mandatory approaches to environmental protection. J Econ Surveys; 2001;15(3):291–324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khanna M, Anton WRQ. Corporate environmental management: Regulatory and market-based incentives. Land Econ. 2002;78(4):539–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konar S, Cohen MA. Does the market value environmental performance?
Rev Econ Stat. 2001;83(2):281–89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harrington DR, Deltas G, Khanna M. Does pollution prevention reduce toxic releases? A dynamic panel data model. Land Econ. 2014;90(2):199–221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alberini A. Environmental regulation and substitution between sources of pollution: An empirical analysis of Florida’s storage tanks. J Regul Econ. 2001;19(1):55–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berchicci L.
Towards an Open R&amp;D System: Internal R&amp;D Investment, External Knowledge Acquisition and Innovative Performance. Res Policy. 2013; 42 (1): 117–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman H, Harten T, Springer J, Randall P, Curran MA, Stone K. Industrial pollution prevention! A critical review. J Air Waste Manage Assoc. 1992;42(5):618–56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cagno E, Trucco P, Tardini L. Cleaner production and profitability: Analysis of 134 industrial pollution prevention (P2) project reports. J Cleaner Prod. 2005;13(6):593–605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khanna M, Deltas G, Harrington DR. Adoption of pollution prevention techniques: The role of management systems, demand-side factors, and complementary assets. Environ Res Econ. 2007;44(1):85–106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dahab MF, Montag DL, Parr JM. Pollution prevention and waste minimization at a galvanizing and electroplating facility. Water Sci Technol. 1994;30(5):243–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajagopalan N, Boddu VM, Mishra S, Kraybill D. Pollution prevention in an aluminum grinding facility. Metal Finishing. 1998;96(11):18–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florida R, Davison D. Gaining from green management: Environmental management systems inside and outside the factory. California Manage Rev. 2001;43(3):64–84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sam AG. Impact of government-sponsored pollution prevention practices on environmental compliance and enforcement: Evidence from a sample of U.S. manufacturing facilities. J Regul Econ. 2010;37(3):266–86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bui LTM, Kapon S. The impact of voluntary programs on polluting behavior: Evidence from pollution prevention programs and toxic releases. J Environ Econ Manage. 2012;64(1):31–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennear LS. Are management-based regulations effective? Evidence from state pollution prevention programs. J Policy Anal Manage. 2007;26(2):327–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigman H. Cross-media pollution: Responses to restrictions on chlorinated solvent releases. Land Econ. 1996;72(3):298–312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fullerton D, Karney DH. Multiple pollutants, co-benefits, and suboptimal environmental policies. J Environ Econ Manage. 2018;87:52–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holland SP. Taxes and trading versus intensity standards: Second-best environmental policies with incomplete regulation (leakage) or market power
National Bureau of Economic Research, Cambridge, MA: 
2009;NBER 15262. Available from: https://www.nber.org/papers/w15262</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Learn about the toxics release inventory
United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, DC; 2018b.  Available from: https://www.epa.gov/toxics-release-inventory-tri-program/learn-about-toxics-release-inventory.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Correia S. A feasible estimator for linear models with multi-way fixed effects; 2016.  Available from: http://scorreia.com/research/hdfe.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burbidge JB, Magee L, Robb AL. Alternative transformations to handle extreme values of the dependent variable. J Am Stat Assoc. 1988;83(401):123–27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanna RN, Oliva P. The impact of inspections on plant-level air emissions. J Econ Anal Policy. 2010;10(1):Article-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). NAAQS table
United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, DC; 2018c.  Available from: https://www.epa.gov/criteria-air-pollutants/naaqs-table.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). Nonattainment areas for criteria pollutants (green book)
United States Environmental Protection Agency, Washington, DC; 2018d.  Available from: https://www.epa.gov/green-book.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walls &amp; Associates. National establishment time-series (NETS) database: Database description; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS). Local area unemployment statistics
United States Bureau of Labor Statistics, Washington, DC; 2011.  Available from: https://www.bls.gov/lau/#tables.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harrington DR. Two-stage adoption of different types of pollution prevention (P2) activities. Res Energy Econ. 2012;34(3):349–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang C, Sam AG. Corporate environmentalism and environmental innovation. J Environ Manage. 2015;153:84–92. 10.1016/j.jenvman.2015.01.010
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jenvman.2015.01.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baum CF, Stillman S, Schaffer ME. Enhanced routines for instrumental variables/GMM estimation and testing. Stata J. 2007;7(4):465–506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutt N, King AA. The judgment of garbage: End-of-pipe treatment and waste reduction. Manage Sci. 2014;60(7):1812–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King A. Retrieving and transferring embodied data: Implications for the management of interdependence within organizations. Manage Sci. 1999;45(7):918–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothenberg S. Knowledge content and worker participation in environmental management at NUMMI. J Manage Studies. 2003;40(7):1783–1802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doshi AR, Dowell GW, Toffel MW. How firms respond to mandatory information disclosure. Strategic Manage J. 2013;34(10):1209–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koutalakis C, Buzogany A, Börzel TA. When soft regulation is not enough: The integrated pollution prevention and control directive of the European Union. Regul Gov. 2010;4(3):329–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD). Recommendation of the council on integrated pollution prevention and control
Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development, Paris, France; 2018a;OECD/LEGAL/0256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD). Best available techniques for preventing and controlling industrial pollution
Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development, Paris, France; 2018b.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaona SD. The utility of the toxic release inventory (TRI) in tracking implementation and environmental impact of industrial green chemistry practices in the United States. Green Chemistry; 2018.  Available from: 10.5772/intechopen.70716</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5772/intechopen.70716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
