<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31751055</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK549865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430">X-linked Agammaglobulinemia</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lackey</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra E.</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AdventHealth Orlando</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Faran</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Creighton University Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>X-linked agammaglobulinemia or XLA is one of the most common pediatric primary immunodeficiencies that prevent affected individuals from making antibodies and requires lifelong immunoglobulin replacement therapy for survival. The molecular basis for XLA is a disruption in B cell development due to mutation in Bruton's tyrosine kinase (Btk). Affected individuals inherit a defect that prevents precursor B cells in the bone marrow from forming mature, circulating B-lymphocytes that would otherwise be capable of proliferating and differentiating into antibody-producing plasma cells in secondary lymphoid organs like the tonsils and lymph nodes. This dysfunction results in dangerously low, clinically undetectable levels of all immunoglobulin isotypes in the serum. Without immunoglobulins (or antibodies), XLA patients are rendered vulnerable to invasive infections from encapsulated bacteria (such as <i>Streptococcus pneumoniae</i>, <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i>, and <i>Haemophilus influenzae</i>), have an increased incidence of enterovirus infections (e.g., poliovirus, coxsackievirus, echovirus), and chronic diarrhea (from <i>Giardia lamblia</i>). XLA patients commonly present with a history of recurrent upper respiratory tract infections, including sinusitis and otitis media, beginning after 6 to 9 months when most of the maternal antibodies have been exhausted.  However, hospitalization for bacterial pneumonia, requiring intravenous antibiotics for resolution, is usually what prompts the diagnostic work-up for immune deficiency disease. The average age of diagnosis is 2.5 years, and almost all cases of XLA get diagnosed before 5 years of age. Notably, late-onset forms of XLA also exist. There is currently no cure for XLA; however, early management with immunoglobulin replacement therapy and antibiotics to prevent and treat infections. Although this lifelong avenue is costly, it has been the mainstay of treatment for the past fifty years. Any significant delay in diagnosis poses the danger of developing chronic, treatment-resistant infections, and end-organ damage that cannot be corrected.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s11">Pertinent Studies and Ongoing Trials</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s12">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s13">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s14">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s15">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s16">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s17">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31430" sec="article-31430.s18">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Suri D, Rawat A, Singh S. X-linked Agammaglobulinemia. Indian J Pediatr. 2016 Apr;83(4):331-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26909497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan WN. Regulation of B lymphocyte development and activation by Bruton's tyrosine kinase. Immunol Res. 2001;23(2-3):147-56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11444380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shillitoe B, Gennery A. X-Linked Agammaglobulinaemia: Outcomes in the modern era. Clin Immunol. 2017 Oct;183:54-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28729230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal Singh S, Dammeijer F, Hendriks RW. Role of Bruton's tyrosine kinase in B cells and malignancies. Mol Cancer. 2018 Feb 19;17(1):57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5817726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29455639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pac M, Bernatowska EA, Kierkuś J, Ryżko JP, Cielecka-Kuszyk J, Jackowska T, Mikołuć B. Gastrointestinal disorders next to respiratory infections as leading symptoms of X-linked agammaglobulinemia in children - 34-year experience of a single center. Arch Med Sci. 2017 Mar 01;13(2):412-417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5332446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28261296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim W, Kim E, Min H, Kim MG, Eisenbeis VB, Dutta AK, Pavlovic I, Jessen HJ, Kim S, Seong RH. Inositol polyphosphates promote T cell-independent humoral immunity via the regulation of Bruton's tyrosine kinase. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019 Jun 25;116(26):12952-12957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6600927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31189594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazregari S, Azizi G, Tavakol M, Asgardoon MH, Kiaee F, Tavakolinia N, Valizadeh A, Abolhassani H, Aghamohammadi A. Evaluation of infectious and non-infectious complications in patients with primary immunodeficiency. Cent Eur J Immunol. 2017;42(4):336-341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5820987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29479289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corneth OBJ, Klein Wolterink RGJ, Hendriks RW. BTK Signaling in B Cell Differentiation and Autoimmunity. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol. 2016;393:67-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26341110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viti R, Marcellusi A, Capone A, Matucci A, Vultaggio A, Pignata C, Spadaro G, Vacca A, Marasco C, Agostini C, Mennini FS. Direct and Indirect Costs of Immunoglobulin Replacement Therapy in Patients with Common Variable Immunodeficiency (CVID) and X-Linked Agammaglobulinemia (XLA) in Italy. Clin Drug Investig. 2018 Oct;38(10):955-965.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30191508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abolhassani H, Vitali M, Lougaris V, Giliani S, Parvaneh N, Parvaneh L, Mirminachi B, Cheraghi T, Khazaei H, Mahdaviani SA, Kiaei F, Tavakolinia N, Mohammadi J, Negahdari B, Rezaei N, Hammarstrom L, Plebani A, Aghamohammadi A. Cohort of Iranian Patients with Congenital Agammaglobulinemia: Mutation Analysis and Novel Gene Defects. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2016;12(4):479-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26910880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Y, Qing Q, Liu X, Chen S, Chen Z, Niu X, Tan Y, He W, Liu X, Li Y, Chen R, Chen L. Bruton's agammaglobulinemia in an adult male due to a novel mutation: a case report. J Thorac Dis. 2016 Oct;8(10):E1207-E1212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5107543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27867589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar S, Dhar A, Varanasi V, Mukherjee T, Boppana R, Basak S, Bal V, George A, Rath S. Mediation of transitional B cell maturation in the absence of functional Bruton's tyrosine kinase. Sci Rep. 2017 Apr 05;7:46029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28378771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva P, Justicia A, Regueiro A, Fariña S, Couselo JM, Loidi L. Autosomal recessive agammaglobulinemia due to defect in μ heavy chain caused by a novel mutation in the IGHM gene. Genes Immun. 2017 Sep;18(3):197-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28769069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lougaris V, Ferrari S, Plebani A. Ig beta deficiency in humans. Curr Opin Allergy Clin Immunol. 2008 Dec;8(6):515-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18978465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikegame K, Imai K, Yamashita M, Hoshino A, Kanegane H, Morio T, Kaida K, Inoue T, Soma T, Tamaki H, Okada M, Ogawa H. Allogeneic stem cell transplantation for X-linked agammaglobulinemia using reduced intensity conditioning as a model of the reconstitution of humoral immunity. J Hematol Oncol. 2016 Feb 13;9:9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4752762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26873735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard V, Myers LA, Williams DA, Wheeler G, Turner EV, Cunningham JM, Conley ME. Stem cell transplants for patients with X-linked agammaglobulinemia. Clin Immunol. 2003 May;107(2):98-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12763478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed ZA, Abramova I, Aldave JC, Al-Herz W, Bezrodnik L, Boukari R, Bousfiha AA, Cancrini C, Condino-Neto A, Dbaibo G, Derfalvi B, Dogu F, Edgar JDM, Eley B, El-Owaidy RH, Espinosa-Padilla SE, Galal N, Haerynck F, Hanna-Wakim R, Hossny E, Ikinciogullari A, Kamal E, Kanegane H, Kechout N, Lau YL, Morio T, Moschese V, Neves JF, Ouederni M, Paganelli R, Paris K, Pignata C, Plebani A, Qamar FN, Qureshi S, Radhakrishnan N, Rezaei N, Rosario N, Routes J, Sanchez B, Sediva A, Seppanen MR, Serrano EG, Shcherbina A, Singh S, Siniah S, Spadaro G, Tang M, Vinet AM, Volokha A, Sullivan KE. X-linked agammaglobulinemia (XLA):Phenotype, diagnosis, and therapeutic challenges around the world. World Allergy Organ J. 2019;12(3):100018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30937141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parvaneh L, Sharifi N, Azizi G, Abolhassani H, Sharifi L, Mohebbi A, Bahraminia E, Delavari S, Alebouyeh M, Tajeddin E, Mohebbi SR, Yazdani R, Behniafard N, Aghamohammadi A. Infectious etiology of chronic diarrhea in patients with primary immunodeficiency diseases. Eur Ann Allergy Clin Immunol. 2019 Jan;51(1):32-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30417635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrillo-Tapia E, García-García E, Herrera-González NE, Yamazaki-Nakashimada MA, Staines-Boone AT, Segura-Mendez NH, Scheffler-Mendoza SC, O Farrill-Romanillos P, Gonzalez-Serrano ME, Rodriguez-Alba JC, Santos-Argumedo L, Berron-Ruiz L, Sanchez-Flores A, López-Herrera G. Delayed diagnosis in X-linked agammaglobulinemia and its relationship to the occurrence of mutations in BTK non-kinase domains. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2018 Jan;14(1):83-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29202590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>García-García E, Staines-Boone AT, Vargas-Hernández A, González-Serrano ME, Carrillo-Tapia E, Mogica-Martínez D, Berrón-Ruíz L, Segura-Mendez NH, Espinosa-Rosales FJ, Yamazaki-Nakashimada MA, Santos-Argumedo L, López-Herrera G. Clinical and mutational features of X-linked agammaglobulinemia in Mexico. Clin Immunol. 2016 Apr;165:38-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26960951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong PL, Boyle J, Ballow M, Boyle M, Berger M, Bleesing J, Bonilla FA, Chinen J, Cunninghamm-Rundles C, Fuleihan R, Nelson L, Wasserman RL, Williams KC, Orange JS. Use of intravenous immunoglobulin and adjunctive therapies in the treatment of primary immunodeficiencies: A working group report of and study by the Primary Immunodeficiency Committee of the American Academy of Allergy Asthma and Immunology. Clin Immunol. 2010 May;135(2):255-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19914873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milito C, Pulvirenti F, Cinetto F, Lougaris V, Soresina A, Pecoraro A, Vultaggio A, Carrabba M, Lassandro G, Plebani A, Spadaro G, Matucci A, Fabio G, Dellepiane RM, Martire B, Agostini C, Abeni D, Tabolli S, Quinti I. Double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized trial on low-dose azithromycin prophylaxis in patients with primary antibody deficiencies. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2019 Aug;144(2):584-593.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30910492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkelstein JA, Marino MC, Lederman HM, Jones SM, Sullivan K, Burks AW, Conley ME, Cunningham-Rundles C, Ochs HD. X-linked agammaglobulinemia: report on a United States registry of 201 patients. Medicine (Baltimore) 2006 Jul;85(4):193-202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16862044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobh A, Bonilla FA. Vaccination in Primary Immunodeficiency Disorders. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2016 Nov - Dec;4(6):1066-1075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27836056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr J, Quinti I, Eibl M, Chapel H, Späth PJ, Sewell WA, Salama A, van Schaik IN, Kuijpers TW, Peter HH. Is dosing of therapeutic immunoglobulins optimal? A review of a three-decade long debate in europe. Front Immunol. 2014;5:629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4263903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25566244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Notarangelo LD. Primary immunodeficiencies. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2010 Feb;125(2 Suppl 2):S182-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20042228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger M. Subcutaneous administration of IgG. Immunol Allergy Clin North Am. 2008 Nov;28(4):779-802, viii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18940574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anaya JM, Shoenfeld Y, Rojas-Villarraga A, Levy RA, Cervera R, editors. Autoimmunity: From Bench to Bedside [Internet] El Rosario University Press; Bogota (Colombia): 2013. Jul 18, </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29087650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu-Arja RF, Chernin LR, Abusin G, Auletta J, Cabral L, Egler R, Ochs HD, Torgerson TR, Lopez-Guisa J, Hostoffer RW, Tcheurekdjian H, Cooke KR. Successful hematopoietic cell transplantation in a patient with X-linked agammaglobulinemia and acute myeloid leukemia. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2015 Sep;62(9):1674-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkelstein JA, Conley ME, James C, Howard V, Boyle J. Adults with X-linked agammaglobulinemia: impact of disease on daily lives, quality of life, educational and socioeconomic status, knowledge of inheritance, and reproductive attitudes. Medicine (Baltimore) 2008 Sep;87(5):253-258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2831411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18794707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barahona Afonso AF, João CM. The Production Processes and Biological Effects of Intravenous Immunoglobulin. Biomolecules. 2016 Mar 09;6(1):15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4808809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27005671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez EE, Orange JS, Bonilla F, Chinen J, Chinn IK, Dorsey M, El-Gamal Y, Harville TO, Hossny E, Mazer B, Nelson R, Secord E, Jordan SC, Stiehm ER, Vo AA, Ballow M. Update on the use of immunoglobulin in human disease: A review of evidence. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2017 Mar;139(3S):S1-S46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28041678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonagura VR, Marchlewski R, Cox A, Rosenthal DW. Biologic IgG level in primary immunodeficiency disease: the IgG level that protects against recurrent infection. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2008 Jul;122(1):210-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18602574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce LR, Jain N. Risks associated with the use of intravenous immunoglobulin. Transfus Med Rev. 2003 Oct;17(4):241-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14571392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31751055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
