<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">31774579</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1754-4505</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>40</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Special care in dentistry : official publication of the American Association of Hospital Dentists, the Academy of Dentistry for the Handicapped, and the American Society for Geriatric Dentistry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Spec Care Dentist</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Oral health and nutritional status of children with cerebral palsy in northeastern peninsular Malaysia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>62</StartPage>
          <EndPage>70</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>62-70</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/scd.12436</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the oral health and nutritional status of children with cerebral palsy (CP).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Oral health assessment included dental caries and dental plaque maturity scores (DPMS) while the nutritional assessment included children's height-for-age Z-score (HAZ), body mass index-for-age Z-score (BAZ), mid-upper-arm circumference (MUAC), nutrient intake, cariogenic food frequency (CFF) and daily sugar exposure (DSE). Ninety-three CP children were recruited. The prevalence of caries was 81.7% (95% CI: 72.7%-88.3%). The median (IQR) of the DMFT and dft scores were 0.5(4.0) and 3.0(8.0), respectively. Most of the participants had acid-producing plaque (90.3%), severely stunted (81.4%), and 45% were severely thin with acute malnutrition. Intakes of calcium, iron, zinc, vitamin A, vitamin D and total fat were below 77% of the Recommended Nutrient Intakes for Malaysian children (RNI 2017). Nine types of cariogenic foods/drinks were consumed moderately, and DSE indicated that 45% of the children were at moderate risk of dental caries.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Untreated dental caries, severe stunting and thinness were prevalent, and cariogenic foods/drinks were consumed moderately suggesting a moderate risk of caries. Therefore, controlling cariogenic food intake is crucial, but monitoring daily nutrient intake is needed for the optimum growth of children with CP.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2019 Special Care Dentistry Association and Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ahmad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rathmawati</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dental Public Health Unit, School of Dental Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cerebral Palsy Research Cluster, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rahman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Normastura Abd</ForeName>
            <Initials>NA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1008-9913</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dental Public Health Unit, School of Dental Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cerebral Palsy Research Cluster, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hasan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ruhaya</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dental Public Health Unit, School of Dental Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cerebral Palsy Research Cluster, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yaacob</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nik Soriani</ForeName>
            <Initials>NS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cerebral Palsy Research Cluster, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medical Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ali</LastName>
            <ForeName>Siti Hawa</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cerebral Palsy Research Cluster, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, Universiti Sains Malaysia, Kelantan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Spec Care Dentist</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8103755</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0275-1879</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002547" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebral Palsy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003731" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dental Caries</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008296" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Malaysia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009909" MajorTopicYN="N">Oral Health</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children with cerebral palsy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional status</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral health</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31774579</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/scd.12436</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krigger KW. Cerebral palsy: an overview. Am Fam Physician. 2006;73(1):91-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinha N, Singh B, Chhabra KG, Patil S. Comparison of oral health status between children with cerebral palsy and normal children in India: a case-control study. J Indian Soc Periodontol. 2015;19(1):78-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso AMR, Gomes LN, Silva CRD, et al. Dental caries and periodontal disease in Brazilian children and adolescents with cerebral palsy. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2015;12:335-353.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos MTBR, Masiero D, Novo NF, Simionato MRL. Oral conditions in children with cerebral palsy. J Dent Child. 2003;70(1):40-46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsh LJ, Tsang AK. Chairside testing for cariogenic bacteria: current concepts and clinical strategies. J Minim Interv Dent. 2008;10(2):26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephen RM, Miller BF. A quantitative method for evaluating physical and chemical agents which modify production of acids in bacterial plaques on human teeth. J Dent Res. 1943;22:45-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilpinen-Loisa P, Pihko H, Vesander U, Paganus A, Ritanen U, Makitie O. Insufficient energy and nutrient intake in children with motor disability. Acta Paediatr. 2009;98(8):1329-1333.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuzun EH, Guven DK, Eker L, Elbasan B, Bulbul SF. Nutritional status of children with cerebral palsy in Turkey. Disabil Rehabil. 2013;35(5):413-417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zainah S, Ong L, Sofiah A, Poh B, Hussain I. Determinants of linear growth in Malaysian children with cerebral palsy. J Paediatr Child H. 2001;37:376-381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camargo MAF, Antunes JLF. Untreated dental caries in children with cerebral palsy in the Brazilian context. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2007;18(2):131-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos MTBR, Guare RO, Celiberti P, Siqueira WL. Caries experience in individuals with cerebral palsy in relation to oromotor dysfunction and dietary consistency. Spec Care Dentist. 2009;29(5):198-203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams MS, Khan NZ, Begum SA, Wirz SL, Hesketh T, Pring TR. Feeding difficulties in children with cerebral palsy: low-cost caregiver training in Dhaka, Bangladesh. Child Care Health Dev. 2012;38(6):878-888.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haliza T, Normastura AR, Azizah Y, Mohd-Khairi MD. Oral health knowledge, practice and dental plaque maturity status of hearing-impaired children. Sains Malays. 2016;45(5):761-768.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>GC America Inc [homepage on the internet]. GC Tri Plaque ID Gel™ [Cited 2019 February 6]. Available from: http://www.gcamerica.com/products/preventive/GC_Tri_Plaque_ID. Accessed January 28, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Oral Health Surveys: Basic Methods. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevenson RD. Use of segmental measures to estimate stature in children with cerebral palsy. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 1995;149(6):658-662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araujo LA, Silva LR. Anthropometric assessment of patients with cerebral palsy: which curves are more appropriate? J Pediatr (Rio J). 2013;89(3):307-314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee RD, Nieman DC. Nutritional Assessment. Boston: McGraw Hill; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Guidelines for an Intergrated Approach to Nutritional care of HIV-infected Children (6 months-14 years). Geneva: World Health Organization; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson GH, Peterson RD, Beaton GH. Estimating nutrient deficiencies in a population from dietary records: the use of probability analyses. Nutr Res. 1982;2(4):409-415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health Malaysia. Recommended Nutrient Intakes for Malaysia 2017. Malaysia: Ministry of Health; 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosnani N, Ruhaya H, Normastura AR. Linguistic Validity and Reliability of Cariogenic Food Frequency and oral Health Knowledge, Attitude and Practice Questionnaires for Parents of 6-11 Years Old Children in Kota Bharu, Kelantan. Malaysia: Universiti Sains Malaysia; 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chee SS, Zawiah H, Ismail MN, Ng KK. Anthropometry, dietary patterns and nutrient intakes of Malaysian estate workers. Malays J Nutr. 1996;2:112-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palmer CA. Diet and Nutrition in Oral Health. Prentice Hall; 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laws of Malaysia. Child Act 2001. Malaysia; 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitsea A, Karidis A, Donta-Bakoyianni C, Spyropoulos N. Oral health status in Greek children and teenagers, with disabilities. J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2001;26(1):111-118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health Malaysia. National Oral Health Survey of School Children 2007 (NOHSS 2007). Putrajaya: Oral Health Division, Ministry of Health Malaysia; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Hashmi H, Mawlood-Kowash AH, Al-Halabi M. Oral health status among children with cerebral palsy in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. J Int Soc Prev Commun Dent. 2017;7(Suppl 3):S149-S154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chandna P, Adlakha VK, Joshi JL. Oral status of a group of cerebral palsy children. J Dent Oral Hyg. 2011;3(2):8-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grzic R, Bakarcic D, Prpic I, et al. Dental health and dental care in children with cerebral palsy. Coll Antropol. 2011;3:761-764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsh LJ. Dental plaque fermentation and its role in caries risk assessment. Int Dent SA. 2006;8(5):34-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry. Guideline on caries-risk assessment and management for infants, children, and adolescents. Pediatr Dent. 2014;37(6):132-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hogan SE. Energy requirements of children with cerebral palsy. Can J Diet Pract Res. 2004;65(3):124-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verschuren O, Peterson MD, Leferink S, Darrah J. Muscle activation and energy-requirements for varying postures in children and adolescents with cerebral palsy. J Pediatr. 2014;165(5):1011-1016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan PB, Juszczak E, Lambert BR, Rose M, Ford-Adams ME, Johnson A. Impact of feeding problems on nutritional intake and growth: oxford Feeding Study II. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2002;44(7):461-467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohd-Shariff Z, Lin KG, Sariman S, et al. The relationship between household income and dietary intakes of 1-10 year old urban Malaysian. Nutr ResPract. 2015;9(3):278-287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glickman I. Acute vitamin C deficiency and periodontal disease: i. the periodontal tissues of the guinea pig in acute vitamin C deficiency. J Dent Res. 1948;27(1):9-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pihlstrom BL, Michalowicz BS, Johnson NW. Periodontal diseases. Lancet. 2005;366(9499):1809-1820.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallberg L, Hulten L. Iron requirements, iron balance and iron deficiency in menstruating pregnant women. In: Hallberg L, Asp N-G, eds. Iron Nutrition in Health and Disease. London: John Libbey &amp; Company; 1996:165-182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semba RD. Vitamin A, immunity, and infection. Clin Infect Dis. 1994;19(3):489-499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toder DS. Respiratory problems in the adolescent with developmental delay. Adolesc Med. 2000;11(3):617-631.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finbraten AK, Syversen U, Skranes J, Andersen GL, Stevenson RD, Vik T. Bone mineral density and vitamin D status in ambulatory and non-ambulatory children with cerebral palsy. OsteoporosInt. 2015;26(1):141-150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathmawati A, Normastura AR, Ruhaya H, Azizah Y. Oral health knowledge, attitude and practice of parents, and frequency of cariogenic food intake among their non syndromic cleft lip with or without cleft palate children in north-east Peninsular Malaysia. Malays J Nutr. 2017;23(2):239-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marya C. A Textbook of Public Health Dentistry. New Delhi: Jaypee Brothers Medical Publishers (P) LTD; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinto VV, Alves LAC, Mendes FM, Ciamponi AL. The nutritional state of children and adolescents with cerebral palsy is associated with oral motor dysfunction and social conditions: a cross sectional study. BMC Neurol. 2016;16(55).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephensen CB. Vitamin A, infection, and immune function. Annu Rev Nutr. 2001;21(1):167-192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young NL, McCormick AM, Gilbert T, et al. Reasons for hospital admissions among youth and young adults with cerebral palsy. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011;92(1):46-50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira LB, Sheiham A, Bonecker M. Exploring the association of dental caries with social factors and nutritional status in Brazilian preschool children. Eur J Oral Sci. 2008;116(1):37-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheiham A. Dental caries affects body weight, growth and quality of life in pre-school children. Br Dent J. 2006;201:625-626.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheah WL, Wan AMW, Mohd ZAH, Chang CT. Factors associated with undernutrition among children in a rural district of Kelantan, Malaysia. Asia Pac J Public Health. 2012;24(2):330-342.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ward KA, Jarjou L, Prentice A. Long-term effects of maternal calcium supplementation on childhood growth differ between males and females in a population accustomed to a low calcium intake. Bone. 2017;103:31-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonjour JP, Carrie AL, Ferrari S, et al. Calcium-enriched foods and bone mass growth in prepubertal girls: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Invest. 1997;99(6):1287-1294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
