<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">31823354</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2133</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>182</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The British journal of dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Br J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Revisiting pachyonychia congenita: a case-cohort study of 815 patients.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>738</StartPage>
          <EndPage>746</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>738-746</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bjd.18794</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Pachyonychia congenita (PC) is a group of autosomal dominant disorders caused by mutations in one of five keratin genes (KRT6A, KRT6B, KRT6C, KRT16, KRT17). The establishment of an international registry containing clinical and molecular data led to the development of a disease classification based on the mutant gene and associated features.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To harness the same resource to clarify the prevalence of PC-associated clinical features, delineate phenotype-genotype correlations and identify prognostic features for disease severity.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">In total, 815 individuals with confirmed keratin mutations registered in the International Pachyonychia Congenita Research Registry were surveyed for clinical findings associated with PC. Data were analysed using various statistical methods, including the Student's t-test, χ<sup>2</sup> -test and anova tests for differences in means/proportions. Spearman correlation and logistic regression were used for phenotype-genotype correlations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">KRT6A mutations were associated with oral leucokeratosis, hoarseness, youngest age or highest number of fingernails/toenails involved, and use of walking aids. KRT17 mutations were most commonly associated with cysts and natal teeth. Using logistic regression, we found that oral leucokeratosis was correlated with earlier toenail involvement, walking aids, nursing difficulties and hoarseness. Cysts were correlated with oral leucokeratosis, natal teeth and ear wax. Natal teeth predicted earlier toenail involvement, walking difficulties and cyst formation. Hoarseness was correlated with an increased number of involved fingernails.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Here, we establish phenotype-genotype correlations in the largest cohort of patients with PC described to date and reveal novel and clinically useful predictors of disease course and manifestations. What's already known about this topic? Pachyonychia congenita (PC) is a group of autosomal dominant disorders caused by mutations in one of five keratin genes (KRT6A, KRT6B, KRT6C, KRT16, KRT17). The main clinical features are nail dystrophy, palmoplantar keratoderma, oral leucokeratosis and cysts. The establishment of an international registry containing the clinical and molecular data of patients with PC led to the development of a disease classification based on the mutant gene and associated features. What does this study add? Data were collected via an international registry to clarify the prevalence of PC-associated clinical features, delineate phenotype-genotype correlations and identify prognostic features for disease severity. This is the largest cohort of patients with PC described to date. The earliest clinical manifestations of PC are nail dystrophy and palmoplantar keratoderma. Diagnosis can be suspected and confirmed in preschool years. Painful plantar keratoderma has the most profound and debilitating effect on quality of life and daily function. Linked Editorial: Steele and O'Toole. Br J Dermatol 2020; 182:521-522. Linked Comment: Mordaunt. Br J Dermatol 2020; 182:537.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2019 British Association of Dermatologists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Samuelov</LastName>
            <ForeName>L</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5387-5490</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Tel-Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Smith</LastName>
            <ForeName>F J D</ForeName>
            <Initials>FJD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pachyonychia Congenita Project, Holladay, UT, U.S.A.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hansen</LastName>
            <ForeName>C D</ForeName>
            <Initials>CD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT, U.S.A.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sprecher</LastName>
            <ForeName>E</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Tel-Aviv Sourasky Medical Center, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sackler Faculty of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Br J Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0004041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0007-0963</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D053553">Keratin-6</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn">
          <RefSource>Br J Dermatol. 2020 Mar;182(3):537</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">31960408</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053553" MajorTopicYN="N">Keratin-6</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007645" MajorTopicYN="Y">Keratoderma, Palmoplantar</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053549" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pachyonychia Congenita</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823354</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.18794</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLean WH, Rugg EL, Lunny DP et al. Keratin 16 and keratin 17 mutations cause pachyonychia congenita. Nat Genet 1995; 9:273-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliason MJ, Leachman SA, Feng BJ et al. A review of the clinical phenotype of 254 patients with genetically confirmed pachyonychia congenita. J Am Acad Dermatol 2012; 67:680-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowden PE, Haley JL, Kansky A et al. Mutation of a type II keratin gene (K6a) in pachyonychia congenita. Nat Genet 1995; 10:363-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJ, Liao H, Cassidy AJ et al. The genetic basis of pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol Symp Proc 2005; 10:21-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJD, Hansen CD, Hull PR et al. Pachyonychia congenita. GeneReviews. Available at: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK1280/ (last accessed 10 December 2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson NJ, Messenger AG, Leachman SA et al. Keratin K6c mutations cause focal palmoplantar keratoderma. J Invest Dermatol 2010; 130:425-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaspar RL. Challenges in developing therapies for rare diseases including pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol Symp Proc 2005; 10:62-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallis T, Poole CD, Hoggart B. Can skin disease cause neuropathic pain? A study in pachyonychia congenita. Clin Exp Dermatol 2016; 41:26-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson AG. Three cases of hereditary hyperkeratosis of the nail-bed. Br J Dermatol 1904; 17:13-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jadassohn J, Lewandowski P. Pachyonychia Congenita: Keratosis Disseminata Circumscripts (Follicularis). Ikonographia Dermatologica. Berlin: Urban and Schwarzenberg, 1906.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feinstein A, Friedman J, Schewach-Millet M. Pachyonychia congenita. J Am Acad Dermatol 1988; 19:705-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paller AS, Moore JA, Scher R. Pachyonychia congenita tarda. A late-onset form of pachyonychia congenita. Arch Dermatol 1991; 127:701-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stieglitz JB, Centerwall WR. Pachyonychia congenita (Jadassohn-Lewandowsky syndrome): a seventeen-member, four-generation pedigree with unusual respiratory and dental involvement. Am J Med Genet 1983; 14:21-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su WP, Chun SI, Hammond DE et al. Pachyonychia congenita: a clinical study of 12 cases and review of the literature. Pediatr Dermatol 1990; 7:33-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLean WH, Hansen CD, Eliason MJ et al. The phenotypic and molecular genetic features of pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol 2011; 131:1015-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng YG, Xiao SX, Ren XR et al. Keratin 17 mutation in pachyonychia congenita type 2 with early onset sebaceous cysts. Br J Dermatol 2003; 148:452-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shamsher MK, Navsaria HA, Stevens HP et al. Novel mutations in keratin 16 gene underly focal non-epidermolytic palmoplantar keratoderma (NEPPK) in two families. Hum Mol Genet 1995; 4:1875-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao H, Sayers JM, Wilson NJ et al. A spectrum of mutations in keratins K6a, K16 and K17 causing pachyonychia congenita. J Dermatol Sci 2007; 48:199-205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paris F, Hurtado C, Azon A et al. A new KRT16 mutation associated with a phenotype of pachyonychia congenita. Exp Dermatol 2013; 22:838-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJ, Fisher MP, Healy E et al. Novel keratin 16 mutations and protein expression studies in pachyonychia congenita type 1 and focal palmoplantar keratoderma. Exp Dermatol 2000; 9:170-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spaunhurst KM, Hogendorf AM, Smith FJ et al. Pachyonychia congenita patients with mutations in KRT6A have more extensive disease compared with patients who have mutations in KRT16. Br J Dermatol 2012; 166:875-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo H, Liu D, Wu J et al. Pachyonychia congenita with corneal dystrophy. J Dermatol 2013; 40:681-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kovacevic M, Goren A, Shapiro J et al. Prevalence of hair shedding among women. Dermatol Ther 2017; 30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malkud S. A hospital-based study to determine causes of diffuse hair loss in women. J Clin Diagn Res 2015; 9:WC01-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pirastu N, Joshi PK, de Vries PS et al. GWAS for male-pattern baldness identifies 71 susceptibility loci explaining 38% of the risk. Nat Commun 2017; 8:1584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah S, Boen M, Kenner-Bell B et al. Pachyonychia congenita in pediatric patients: natural history, features, and impact. JAMA Dermatol 2014; 150:146-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moldenhauer E, Ernst K. [The Jadassohn-Lewandowsky syndrome]. Der Hautarzt 1968; 19:441-7 (in German).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu T, Leachman SA, Wilson NJ et al. Genotype-phenotype correlations among pachyonychia congenita patients with K16 mutations. J Invest Dermatol 2011; 131:1025-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moll R, Franke WW, Schiller DL et al. The catalog of human cytokeratins: patterns of expression in normal epithelia, tumors and cultured cells. Cell 1982; 31:11-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurokawa I, Takahashi K, Moll I et al. Expression of keratins in cutaneous epithelial tumors and related disorders-distribution and clinical significance. Exp Dermatol 2011; 20:217-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L, Zhang S, Wang G. Keratin 17 in disease pathogenesis: from cancer to dermatoses. J Pathol 2019; 247:158-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGowan KM, Coulombe PA. Keratin 17 expression in the hard epithelial context of the hair and nail, and its relevance for the pachyonychia congenita phenotype. J Invest Dermatol 2000; 114:1101-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouhayoun JP, Gosselin F, Forest N et al. Cytokeratin patterns of human oral epithelia: differences in cytokeratin synthesis in gingival epithelium and the adjacent alveolar mucosa. Differentiation 1985; 30:123-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lessard JC, Pina-Paz S, Rotty JD et al. Keratin 16 regulates innate immunity in response to epidermal barrier breach. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2013; 110:19537-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim S, Wong P, Coulombe PA. A keratin cytoskeletal protein regulates protein synthesis and epithelial cell growth. Nature 2006; 441:362-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duverger O, Carlson JC, Karacz CM et al. Genetic variants in pachyonychia congenita-associated keratins increase susceptibility to tooth decay. PLOS Genet 2018; 14:e1007168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGowan KM, Coulombe PA. Onset of keratin 17 expression coincides with the definition of major epithelial lineages during skin development. J Cell Biol 1998; 143:469-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldberg I, Fruchter D, Meilick A et al. Best treatment practices for pachyonychia congenita. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2014; 28:279-85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koren A, Sprecher E, Reider E et al. A treatment protocol for botulinum toxin injections in the treatment of pachyonychia congenita-associated keratoderma. Br J Dermatol 2019; DOI: 10.1111/bjd.18169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
