<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31850928</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-7056</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in gastroenterology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Cholangiocarcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>77</StartPage>
          <EndPage>84</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>77-84</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MOG.0000000000000616</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC) is a rare cholestatic liver disease characterized by progressive fibroinflammatory destruction of the intrahepatic and/or extrahepatic bile ducts. It is associated with a significantly increased risk of malignancy, particularly cholangiocarcinoma (CCA). In this review, we discuss what is currently known about the epidemiology of and risk factors for CCA in PSC as well as recent advances in its prevention, diagnosis, and surveillance.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">An area of major focus has been finding novel biomarkers (in serum, bile, and urine) for CCA. With the advancement of computing power, metabolomic and proteomic approaches, among other methods, may provide enhanced capability for differentiating between benign and malignant bile duct disease. Another area of focus has been the approach to CCA surveillance in PSC; a recent study has found that CCA surveillance in patients with PSC is associated with improved outcomes, including increased survival, thus advocating for its importance.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Despite ongoing advancements in the study of PSC-associated CCA, early diagnosis of CCA remains difficult, treatment options are limited, and prognosis is often consequently poor. Continued research in the development of high-accuracy diagnostic tools, novel biomarkers, and surveillance techniques may help to increase the likelihood of diagnosing CCA at earlier stages, when therapeutic options have the highest likelihood of resulting in cure.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brian M</ForeName>
            <Initials>BM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>UCLA-Olive View Internal Medicine Residency Program.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tabibian</LastName>
            <ForeName>James H</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Olive View-UCLA Medical Center, Sylmar, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Gastroenterol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8506887</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0267-1379</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001650" MajorTopicYN="N">Bile Duct Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018281" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholangiocarcinoma</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015209" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholangitis, Sclerosing</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31850928</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOG.0000000000000616</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00001574-202003000-00006</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lazaridis KN, LaRusso NF. Primary sclerosing cholangitis. N Engl J Med 2016; 375:1161–1170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabibian JH, Lindor KD. Primary sclerosing cholangitis: a review and update on therapeutic developments. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2013; 7:103–114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Hara SP, Tabibian JH, Splinter PL, et al. The dynamic biliary epithelia: molecules, pathways, and disease. J Hepatol 2013; 58:575–582.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyson JK, Beuers U, Jones DEJ, et al. Primary sclerosing cholangitis. Lancet 2018; 391:2547–2559.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boonstra K, Beuers U, Ponsioen CY. Epidemiology of primary sclerosing cholangitis and primary biliary cirrhosis: a systematic review. J Hepatol 2012; 56:1181–1188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boonstra K, Weersma RK, van Erpecum KJ, et al. EpiPSCPBC Study Group. Population-based epidemiology, malignancy risk, and outcome of primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology 2013; 58:2045–2055.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takakura WR, Tabibian JH, Bowlus CL. The evolution of natural history of primary sclerosing cholangitis. Curr Opin Gastroenterol 2016; 33:71–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Folseraas T, Boberg KM. Cancer risk and surveillance in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Clin Liver Dis 2016; 20:79–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gulamhusein AF, Eaton JE, Tabibian JH, et al. Duration of inflammatory bowel disease is associated with increased risk of cholangiocarcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis and IBD. Am J Gastroenterol 2016; 111:705–711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergquist A, Ekbom A, Olsson R, et al. Hepatic and extrahepatic malignancies in primary sclerosing cholangitis. J Hepatol 2002; 36:321–327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Claessen MMH, Vleggaar FP, Tytgat KMAJ, et al. High lifetime risk of cancer in primary sclerosing cholangitis. J Hepatol 2009; 50:158–164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng H-H, Jiang X-L. Increased risk of colorectal neoplasia in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis and inflammatory bowel disease: a meta-analysis of 16 observational studies. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2016; 28:383–390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Said K, Glaumann H, Bergquist A. Gallbladder disease in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis. J Hepatol 2008; 48:598–605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Razumilava N, Gores GJ. Cholangiocarcinoma. Lancet 2014; 383:2168–2179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fevery J, Verslype C, Lai G, et al. Incidence, diagnosis, and therapy of cholangiocarcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis. Dig Dis Sci 2007; 52:3123–3135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang H, Manne S, Shick J, et al. Incidence, prevalence, and natural history of primary sclerosing cholangitis in the United Kingdom. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017; 96:e7116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burak K, Angulo P, Pasha TM, et al. Incidence and risk factors for cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Am J Gastroenterol 2004; 99:523–526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fevery J, Henckaerts L, Oirbeek RV, et al. Malignancies and mortality in 200 patients with primary sclerosering cholangitis: a long-term single-centre study. Liver Int 2012; 32:214–222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zenouzi R, Weismüller TJ, Hübener P, et al. Low risk of hepatocellular carcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis with cirrhosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2014; 12:1733–1738.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weismüller TJ, Trivedi PJ, Bergquist A, et al. International PSC Study Group. Patient age, sex, and inflammatory bowel disease phenotype associate with course of primary sclerosing cholangitis. Gastroenterology 2017; 152:1975.e8–1984.e8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan SA, Tavolari S, Brandi G. Cholangiocarcinoma: epidemiology and risk factors. Liver Int 2019; 39:19–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahrendt S, Lillemoe KD. Diagnosis and management of cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Gastrointest Surg 1999; 3:12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steenstraten IC, Korkmaz KS, Trivedi PJ, et al. Systematic review with meta-analysis: risk factors for recurrent primary sclerosing cholangitis after liver transplantation. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2019; 49:636–643.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mouchli MA, Singh S, Loftus EV, et al. Risk factors and outcomes of de novo cancers (excluding nonmelanoma skin cancer) after liver transplantation for primary sclerosing cholangitis. Transplantation 2017; 101:1859–1866.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khorsandi SE, Salvans S, Zen Y, et al. Cholangiocarcinoma complicating recurrent primary sclerosing cholangitis after liver transplantation. Transpl Int 2011; 24:e93–e96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watt KD, Pedersen RA, Kremers WK, et al. Long-term probability of and mortality from de-novo malignancy after liver transplantation. Gastroenterology 2009; 137:2010–2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landaverde C, Ng V, Sato A, et al. De-novo cholangiocarcinoma in native common bile duct remnant following OLT for primary sclerosing cholangitis. Ann Hepatol 2009; 8:379–383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman E, Majeed A, Kemp W, et al. Long-term outcomes of primary sclerosing cholangitis: an Australian nontransplant tertiary hospital perspective. Intern Med J 2019; 49:323–327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizvi S, Eaton JE, Gores GJ. Primary Sclerosing Cholangitis as a Premalignant Biliary Tract Disease: Surveillance and Management. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol Off Clin Pract J Am Gastroenterol Assoc 2015; 13:2152–2165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adike A, Carey EJ, Lindor KD. Primary sclerosing cholangitis in children versus adults: lessons for the clinic. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2018; 12:1025–1032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Mamari S, Djordjevic J, Halliday JS, Chapman RW. Improvement of serum alkaline phosphatase to &lt;1.5 upper limit of normal predicts better outcome and reduced risk of cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. J Hepatol 2013; 58:329–334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilscher M, Enders FB, Carey EJ, et al. Alkaline phosphatase normalization is a biomarker of improved survival in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Ann Hepatol 2016; 15:246–253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rupp C, Rössler A, Halibasic E, et al. Reduction in alkaline phosphatase is associated with longer survival in primary sclerosing cholangitis, independent of dominant stenosis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2014; 40:1292–1301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jendrek ST, Gotthardt D, Nitzsche T, et al. Anti-GP2 IgA autoantibodies are associated with poor survival and cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Gut 2017; 66:137–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ponsioen CY, Lindor KD, Mehta R, Dimick-Santos L. Design and endpoints for clinical trials in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology 2018; 68:1174–1188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindor KD, Kowdley KV, Harrison ME. ACG clinical guideline: primary sclerosing cholangitis. Am J Gastroenterol 2015; 110:646–659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pardi DS, Loftus EV, Kremers WK, et al. Ursodeoxycholic acid as a chemopreventive agent in patients with ulcerative colitis and primary sclerosing cholangitis. Gastroenterology 2003; 124:889–893.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu RW, Carey EJ, Lindor KD, et al. Curcumin in hepatobiliary disease: pharmacotherapeutic properties and emerging potential clinical applications. Ann Hepatol 2017; 16:835–841.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eaton JE, Nelson KM, Gossard AA, et al. Efficacy and safety of curcumin in primary sclerosing cholangitis: an open label pilot study. Scand J Gastroenterol 2019; 54:633–639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu T, Yang H, Fan W, et al. Mechanisms of MAFG dysregulation in cholestatic liver injury and development of liver cancer. Gastroenterology 2018; 155:557.e14–571.e14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maldonado LY, Arsene D, Mato JM, et al. Methionine adenosyltransferases in cancers: mechanisms of dysregulation and implications for therapy. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2018; 243:107–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan TR, Osann K, Bottiglieri T, et al. A phase II randomized, controlled trial of S-adenosylmethionine in reducing serum α-fetoprotein in patients with hepatitis C cirrhosis and elevated AFP. Cancer Prev Res 2015; 8:864–872.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chalasani N, Baluyut A, Ismail A, et al. Cholangiocarcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis: a multicenter case-control study. Hepatology 2000; 31:7–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergquist A, Glaumann H, Persson B, et al. Risk factors and clinical presentation of hepatobiliary carcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis: a case-control study. Hepatology 1998; 27:311–316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlsen TH, Folseraas T, Thorburn D, Vesterhus M. Primary sclerosing cholangitis - a comprehensive review. J Hepatol 2017; 67:1298–1323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilscher MB, Tabibian JH, Carey EJ, et al. Dominant strictures in primary sclerosing cholangitis: a multicenter survey of clinical definitions and practices. Hepatol Commun 2018; 2:836–844.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lazaridis KN, Gores GJ. Primary sclerosing cholangitis and cholangiocarcinoma. Semin Liver Dis 2006; 26:42–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aabakken L, Karlsen TH, Albert J, et al. Role of endoscopy in primary sclerosing cholangitis: European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) and European Association for the Study of the Liver (EASL) Clinical Guideline. Endoscopy 2017; 49:588–608.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charatcharoenwitthaya P, Enders FB, Halling KC, et al. Utility of serum tumor markers, imaging, and biliary cytology for detecting cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology 2008; 48:1106–1117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman MH, Webster GJ, Bannoo S, et al. Cholangiocarcinoma and dominant strictures in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis; a 25 year single centre experience. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2012; 24:1051–1058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zenouzi R, Liwinski T, Yamamura J, et al. Follow-up magnetic resonance imaging/3D-magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis: challenging for experts to interpret. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2018; 48:169–178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JJ, Schindera ST, Jang H-J, et al. Cholangiocarcinoma and its mimickers in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Abdom Radiol (NY) 2017; 42:2898–2908.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trikudanathan G, Navaneethan U, Njei B, et al. Diagnostic yield of bile duct brushings for cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastrointest Endosc 2014; 79:783–789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonda TA, Glick MP, Sethi A, et al. Polysomy and p16 deletion by fluorescence in situ hybridization in the diagnosis of indeterminate biliary strictures. Gastrointest Endosc 2012; 75:74–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kipp BR, Stadheim LM, Halling SA, et al. A comparison of routine cytology and fluorescence in situ hybridization for the detection of malignant bile duct strictures. Am J Gastroenterol 2004; 99:1675–1681.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boldorini R, Paganotti A, Andorno S, et al. A multistep cytological approach for patients with jaundice and biliary strictures of indeterminate origin. J Clin Pathol 2015; 68:283–287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quinn KP, Tabibian JH, Lindor KD. Clinical implications of serial versus isolated biliary fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH) polysomy in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Scand J Gastroenterol 2017; 52:377–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eaton JE, Barr Fritcher EG, Gores GJ, et al. Biliary multifocal chromosomal polysomy and cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Am J Gastroenterol 2015; 110:299–309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Njei B, McCarty TR, Varadarajulu S, et al. Systematic review with meta-analysis: endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography-based modalities for the diagnosis of cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2016; 44:1139–1151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deprez PH, Duran RG, Moreels T, et al. The economic impact of using single-operator cholangioscopy for the treatment of difficult bile duct stones and diagnosis of indeterminate bile duct strictures. Endoscopy 2018; 50:109–118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derdeyn J, Laleman W. Current role of endoscopic cholangioscopy. Curr Opin Gastroenterol 2018; 34:301–308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fung BM, Tabibian JH. Biliary endoscopy in the management of primary sclerosing cholangitis and its complications. Liver Res 2019; 3:106–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wannhoff A, Gotthardt DN. Recent developments in the research on biomarkers of cholangiocarcinoma in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Clin Res Hepatol Gastroenterol 2019; 43:236–243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinakos E, Saenger AK, Keach J, et al. Many patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis and increased serum levels of carbohydrate antigen 19-9 do not have cholangiocarcinoma. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2011; 9:434.e1–439.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wannhoff A, Hov JR, Folseraas T, et al. FUT2 and FUT3 genotype determines CA19-9 cut-off values for detection of cholangiocarcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis. J Hepatol 2013; 59:1278–1284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman MH, Sandanayake NS, Andreola F, et al. Circulating CYFRA 21-1 is a specific diagnostic and prognostic biomarker in biliary tract cancer. J Clin Exp Hepatol 2011; 1:6–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voigtländer T, David S, Thamm K, et al. Angiopoietin-2 and biliary diseases: elevated serum, but not bile levels are associated with cholangiocarcinoma. PLos One 2014; 9:e97046.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuenco J, Wehnert N, Blyuss O, et al. Identification of a serum biomarker panel for the differential diagnosis of cholangiocarcinoma and primary sclerosing cholangitis. Oncotarget 2018; 9:17430–17442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arbelaiz A, Azkargorta M, Krawczyk M, et al. Serum extracellular vesicles contain protein biomarkers for primary sclerosing cholangitis and cholangiocarcinoma. Hepatology 2017; 66:1125–1143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banales JM, Iñarrairaegui M, Arbelaiz A, et al. Serum metabolites as diagnostic biomarkers for cholangiocarcinoma, hepatocellular carcinoma and primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology 2019; 70:547–562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olaizola P, Lee-Law PY, Arbelaiz A, et al. MicroRNAs and extracellular vesicles in cholangiopathies. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis 2018; 1864:1293–1307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernuzzi F, Marabita F, Lleo A, et al. Serum microRNAs as novel biomarkers for primary sclerosing cholangitis and cholangiocarcinoma. Clin Exp Immunol 2016; 185:61–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Masica D, Ishida M, et al. Human bile contains MicroRNA-laden extracellular vesicles that can be used for cholangiocarcinoma diagnosis. Hepatology 2014; 60:896–907.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira P, Aho V, Arola J, et al. Bile microbiota in primary sclerosing cholangitis: impact on disease progression and development of biliary dysplasia. PLos One 2017; 12:e0182924.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rupp C, Bode KA, Chahoud F, et al. Risk factors and outcome in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis with persistent biliary candidiasis. BMC Infect Dis 2014; 14:562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rupp C, Bode KA, Leopold Y, et al. Pathological features of primary sclerosing cholangitis identified by bile proteomic analysis. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis 2018; 1864:1380–1389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metzger J, Negm AA, Plentz RR, et al. Urine proteomic analysis differentiates cholangiocarcinoma from primary sclerosing cholangitis and other benign biliary disorders. Gut 2013; 62:122–130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navaneethan U, Lourdusamy V, Gk Venkatesh P, et al. Bile proteomics for differentiation of malignant from benign biliary strictures: a pilot study. Gastroenterol Rep 2015; 3:136–143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navaneethan U, Parsi MA, Lourdusamy V, et al. Volatile organic compounds in bile for early diagnosis of cholangiocarcinoma in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis: a pilot study. Gastrointest Endosc 2015; 81:943e1–949.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fung BM, Lindor KD, Tabibian JH. Cancer risk in primary sclerosing cholangitis: epidemiology, prevention, and surveillance strategies. World J Gastroenterol 2019; 25:659–671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schramm C, Eaton J, Ringe KI, et al. MRI working group of the IPSCSG. Recommendations on the use of magnetic resonance imaging in PSC-a position statement from the International PSC Study Group. Hepatology 2017; 66:1675–1688.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zenouzi R, Welle CL, Venkatesh SK, et al. Magnetic resonance imaging in primary sclerosing cholangitis—current state and future directions. Semin Liver Dis 2019; 39:369–380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali AH, Tabibian JH, Nasser-Ghodsi N, et al. Surveillance for hepatobiliary cancers in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology 2018; 67:2338–2351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bangarulingam SY, Gossard AA, Petersen BT, et al. Complications of endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Am J Gastroenterol 2009; 104:855–860.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman R, Fevery J, Kalloo A, et al. Diagnosis and management of primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology 2010; 51:660–678.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamora-Valdes D, Heimbach JK. Liver transplant for cholangiocarcinoma. Gastroenterol Clin North Am 2018; 47:267–280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stremitzer S, Jones RP, Quinn LM, et al. Clinical outcome after resection of early-stage hilar cholangiocarcinoma. Eur J Surg Oncol 2019; 45:213–217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
