<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31860180</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2590-7379</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>39</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Biomedica : revista del Instituto Nacional de Salud</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Biomedica</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Vagino-rectal colonization prevalence by Streptococcus agalactiae and its susceptibility profile in pregnant women attending a third-level hospital.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>689</StartPage>
          <EndPage>698</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>689-698</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7705/biomedica.4514</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Introduction: Streptococcus agalactiae is the main etiological agent causing invasive infection of the newborn with symptoms that may be associated with septicemia, pneumonia or meningitis and prevalences up to 50% worldwide where there is an increase in antibiotic resistance. Objective: To estimate the prevalence of vagino-rectal colonization by S. agalactiae and its sensitivity profile in pregnant women attending a third-level hospital. Materials and methods: One hundred and twenty one pregnant women were sampled by vaginal and rectal swabs. The cultures were carried out following the methodology recommended by the CDC, and chromID Strepto B agar was added. The suggestive colonies were identified biochemically and the sensitivity profiles according to CLSI were determined. As control, S. pneumoniae ATCC 49619 and S. agalactiae ATCC 12403 were used. Results: Pregnant colonization prevalence by S. agalactiae was 20.66%, with a total of 40 isolates of which 12.5% were non-sensitivity to penicillin. Sensitivity to levofloxacin, clindamycin and erythromycin was 100%, 92.5% y 87.5%, respectively, with the phenotypes iMLSB (3/40) and M (2/40). No sensitivity to tetracycline was found. Conclusions: The prevalence of vagino-rectal colonization by S. agalactiae in the study population was 20.66%, obtaining isolates not sensitive to penicillin and resistance to macrolides and lincosamidas by the Kirby-Bauer technique, so the importance of carrying out active active in pregnant women colonized by Streptococcus agalactiae and to perform constant epidemiological surveillance to detect changes in the sensitivity profiles of the isolates.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Campo</LastName>
            <ForeName>César Hernán</ForeName>
            <Initials>CH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departamento de Ginecología y Obstetricia, Hospital Universitario de Santander, Bucaramanga, Colombia. camposuarez@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martínez</LastName>
            <ForeName>María Fernanda</ForeName>
            <Initials>MF</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Otero</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan Carlos</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rincón</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giovanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <Language>spa</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Prevalencia de colonización vaginorrectal por Streptococcus agalactiae y su perfil de sensibilidad en mujeres embarazadas atendidas en un hospital de tercer nivel.</VernacularTitle>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Biomedica</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8205605</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0120-4157</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003105" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Colombia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D024881" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Resistance, Bacterial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010502" MajorTopicYN="N">Perineum</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011263" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy Trimester, Third</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012007" MajorTopicYN="N">Rectum</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013292" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus agalactiae</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062606" MajorTopicYN="N">Tertiary Care Centers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014621" MajorTopicYN="N">Vagina</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
        <AbstractText>Introducción. Streptococcus agalactiae es el principal agente etiológico causante de infección invasiva del recién nacido con cuadros clínicos que pueden cursar con septicemia, neumonía o meningitis con prevalencias hasta del 50 % a nivel mundial, donde se viene presentando un incremento en su resistencia antibiótica. Objetivo. Estimar la prevalencia de colonización vaginorrectal por S. agalactiae y su perfil de sensibilidad, en mujeres embarazadas atendidas en un hospital de tercer nivel. Materiales y métodos. Se muestrearon 121 mujeres gestantes mediante hisopado vaginal y rectal. Los cultivos se desarrollaron siguiendo la metodología recomendada por los Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) y se agregó el agar chromID Strepto B. Las colonias sugestivas se identificaron bioquímicamente y se determinaron los perfiles de sensibilidad según el Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute (CLSI). Resultados. La prevalencia de colonización por S. agalactiae en las mujeres gestantes fue del 20,66 %. Se obtuvieron 40 aislamientos del total de muestras analizadas, de los cuales, el 12,5 % no presentó sensibilidad a la penicilina. La sensibilidad a la levofloxacina, la clindamicina y la eritromicina fue de 100 %, 92,5 % y 87,5 %, respectivamente; no se encontró sensibilidad a la tetraciclina. El fenotipo iMLSB se encontró en tres y, el M, en dos de los 40 aislamientos. Conclusiones. La prevalencia de colonización vaginorrectal por S. agalactiae en la población de estudio, fue de 20,66 %. Se obtuvieron aislamientos no sensibles a la penicilina, y con resistencia a los macrólidos y las lincosamidas mediante el método de Kirby-Bauer. Por ello, es importante la búsqueda activa en las mujeres gestantes colonizadas por estreptococos del grupo B y la vigilancia epidemiológica constante para detectar cambios en los perfiles de sensibilidad de los aislamientos.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="eng">
        <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION:">Streptococcus agalactiae is the main etiological agent causing invasive infection of the newborn with symptoms that may be associated with septicemia, pneumonia or meningitis and prevalences up to 50% worldwide where there is an increase in antibiotic resistance.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE:">To estimate the prevalence of vagino-rectal colonization by S. agalactiae and its sensitivity profile in pregnant women attending a third-level hospital.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS:">One hundred and twenty one pregnant women were sampled by vaginal and rectal swabs. The cultures were carried out following the methodology recommended by the CDC, and chromID Strepto B agar was added. The suggestive colonies were identified biochemically and the sensitivity profiles according to CLSI were determined. As control, S. pneumoniae ATCC 49619 and S. agalactiae ATCC 12403 were used.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="RESULTS:">Pregnant colonization prevalence by S. agalactiae was 20.66%, with a total of 40 isolates of which 12.5% were non-sensitivity to penicillin. Sensitivity to levofloxacin, clindamycin and erythromycin was 100%, 92.5% y 87.5%, respectively, with the phenotypes iMLSB (3/40) and M (2/40). No sensitivity to tetracycline was found.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS:">The prevalence of vagino-rectal colonization by S. agalactiae in the study population was 20.66%, obtaining isolates not sensitive to penicillin and resistance to macrolides and lincosamidas by the Kirby-Bauer technique, so the importance of carrying out active active in pregnant women colonized by Streptococcus agalactiae and to perform constant epidemiological surveillance to detect changes in the sensitivity profiles of the isolates.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Streptococcus agalactiae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pregnant women</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">neonatal sepsis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">prophylaxis antibiotic</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflicto de intereses:</b> Los autores declaran no tener conflicto de intereses.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31860180</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7363344</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7705/biomedica.4514</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ceballos C, Loaiza N, Romero J, Ospina M, Vásquez EM. Caracterización de las gestantes tamizadas para Streptococcus agalactiae y su relación con sepsis neonatal temprana, en la Clínica del Prado de Medellín (Colombia), año 2010. Infectio. 2014;18:66–71. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.infect.2013.12.002 14</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.infect.2013.12.00214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duque CM, Gómez B, Uribe OI, Gutiérrez M, Ruiz E, Leudo GA, et al.  Comparación de métodos para la recuperación y determinación de la prevalencia de Streptococcus agalactiae en mujeres gestantes de Medellín. Infectio. 2010;14:105–111. doi: 10.1016/S0123-9392(10)70098-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0123-9392(10)70098-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García DA, Mojica ME, Méndez IA, Pachón DP, Prieto AC, Santamaría EV, et al.  Prevalencia del Streptococcus agalactiae en maternas usuarias del Hospital Militar Central, Bogotá (Colombia) año 2010. Rev Colomb Obstet Ginecol. 2011;62:302–307. doi: 10.18597/issn.0034-7434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18597/issn.0034-7434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verani JR, McGee L, Schrag SJ. Prevention of perinatal group B streptococcal Disease Revised Guidelines from CDC, 2010. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2010;59:1–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21088663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Restrepo N, Alarcón C, Reveiz L, Morales O, Martínez O, Isaza M, et al.  Prevalencia de la colonización vaginal y rectovaginal por estreptococo del grupo B en gestantes usuarias de la Clínica Universitaria Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia. Rev Medica Sanitas. 2009;12:8–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alós JI, Domingo A, Arribas L, Cabero L, Cueto M, López J, et al.  Prevención de la infección perinatal por estreptococo del grupo B. Recomendaciones españolas. Actualización 2012. Documento de consenso SEIMC/SEGO/SEN/SEQ/ SEMFYC. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin. 2013;31:159–172. doi: 10.1016/j.eimc.2012.03.013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eimc.2012.03.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22658283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Restrepo A, Serna L, Vanegas C, Sarria C, Durango H, Zapata C, et al.  Prevalencia de Streptococcus agalactiae en gestantes con factores de riesgo y sus recién nacidos. Hospital Universitario San Vicente de Paúl. 2002. Infectio. 2003;7:147–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valdés E, Pastene C, Morales A, Gutiérrez B, Canales A, Martínez P, et al.  Prevalencia de colonización por Streptococcus agalactiae (grupo B) durante el embarazo pesquisado en medio de cultivo selectivo. Rev Chil Obstet Ginecol. 2004;69:132–135. https://doi.org/10.4067/S0717-75262004000200008 15</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0717-7526200400020000815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojas JL, Pérez MP, Otálora EP. Prevalencia del Streptococcus B en el tracto genital inferior en embarazadas entre 35 y 37 semanas. Hospital San José. Repert Med Cir. 2010;19:141–146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amaya JP, Bello AM, Mendivil C, Correa O, Reyes N. Prevalencia de colonización vaginal y rectal por Streptococcus agalactiae en gestantes con trabajo de parto pretérmino en clínica maternidad Rafael calvo entre agosto 2011 y enero 2012. Rev Cienc Biomed. 2013;4:20–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crespo MP, Henao EA, Espitia LM, Herrera MH. Colonización por Streptococcus agalactiae en mujeres gestantes de los centros de atención de la ESE Norte en Cali. Ciencia y Salud. 2012;1:23–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beitune P, Duarte G, Leite CM. Colonization by Streptococcus agalactiae during pregnancy: maternal and perinatal prognosis. Braz J Infect Dis. 2005;9:276–282. doi: 10.1590/S1413-86702005000400002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1413-86702005000400002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16270118</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winn H. Group B Streptococcus infection in pregnancy. Clin Perinatol. 2007;34:387–392. doi: 10.1016/j.clp.2007.03.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clp.2007.03.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17765489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag SJ, Zell ER, Lynfield R, Roome A, Arnold KE, Craig AS, et al.  A populationbased comparison of strategies to prevent early-onset group B streptococcal disease in neonates. N Engl J Med. 2002;347:233–239. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa020205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa020205</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12140298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller-Vranjes A, Puntarić D, Curzik D, Sijanović S, Topolovec Z, Kasac Z, et al.  Prevalence and significance of vaginal group B streptococcus colonization in pregnant women from Osijek, Croatia. Coll Antropol. 2011;35:21–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21661350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busetti M, D’Agaro P, Campello C. Group B streptococcus prevalence in pregnant women from North-Eastern Italy: advantages of a screening strategy based on direct plating plus broth enrichment. J Clin Pathol. 2007;60:1140–1143. https://doi.org/10.1136/jcp.2006.043489 16</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jcp.2006.04348916</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2014865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17182659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joachim A, Matee MI, Massawe FA, Lyamuya EF. Maternal and neonatal colonisation of group B streptococcus at Muhimbili National Hospital in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania: prevalence, risk factors and antimicrobial resistance. BMC Public Health. 2009;9:437–437. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-9-437.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-9-437</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2791767</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19948075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rausch A, Gross A, Droz S, Bodmer T, Surbek D. Group B Streptococcus colonization in pregnancy: prevalence and prevention strategies of neonatal sepsis. J Perinat Med. 2009;37:124–129. doi: 10.1515/JPM.2009.020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/JPM.2009.020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19021455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nomura ML, Passini R, Moraes U, Calil R. Group B streptococcus maternal and neonatal colonization in preterm rupture of membranes and preterm labor. Rev Bras Ginecol Obstet. 2009;31:397–403. doi: 10.1590/S0100-72032009000800005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0100-72032009000800005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19838588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reyna J, Ortiz FJ, Arredondo JL, Beltrán M. Asociación entre la colonización materna de Streptococcus del grupo B serotipo III y la rotura prematura de membranas. Clin Invest Ginecol Obstet. 2006;33:140–145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abarzúa F, Argomedo C, Meissner A, Díaz T, Garrido P, Fariña S, et al.  Prevalencia de portación vaginal-anal de Streptococcus agalactiae en el tercer trimestre de gestación y susceptibilidad a macrólidos y lincosamidas, en mujeres embarazadas de Clínica Alemana Temuco, Chile. Rev Chilena Infectol. 2014;31:305–308. https://doi.org/10.4067/S0716- 10182014000300009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0716-10182014000300009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25146205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laufer J, Scasso S, Sosa C, Rodriguez-Cuns G, Justo A, Pons J. Group B streptococcus colonization among pregnant women in Uruguay. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2009;104:242–243. doi: 10.1016/j.ijgo.2008.10.020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijgo.2008.10.020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667712</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19059591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larcher JS, Capellino F, Giusto R, Travella C, Gómez F, Kreiker G, et al.  Colonización por estreptococo beta hemolítico del grupo B durante el embarazo y prevención de enfermedad neonatal. Medicina (Buenos Aires). 2005;65:201–6 17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16042129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marconi C, Rocchetti TT, Rall VL, Carvalho LR, Borges VT, Silva MG. Detection of Streptococcus agalactiae colonization in pregnant women by using combined swab cultures: cross-sectional prevalence study. Sao Paulo Med J. 2010;128:60–62. doi: 10.1590/S1516-31802010000200003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1516-31802010000200003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20676570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa A, Lamy F, Da Costa MB, Oliveira LM, Carvalho Z, Lima K. Prevalence of colonization by group B Streptococcus in pregnant women from a public maternity of Northwest region of Brazil. Rev Bras Ginecol Obstet. 2008;30:274–280. doi: 10.1590/S0100-72032008000600002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0100-72032008000600002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19142504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman A, Baltimore R, Fonseca S. Prevalence of maternal group B Streptococcal colonization and related risk factors in a Brazilian population. Braz J Infect Dis. 2006;10:242–2 6. doi: 10.1590/S1413-86702006000400005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1413-86702006000400005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17293904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamariz JH, Obregón M, Jara JC, Díaz J, Cortez J, Guerra H. Vaginal and anorectal colonization by Streptococcus agalactiae among pregnant patients from Cayetano Heredia and Arzobispo Loayza Hospitals. Rev Medica Hered. 2004;15:144–150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Díaz de R, Nieves B, Vegas L. Rectovaginal colonization by group B streptococcus in pregnant women with gynecobstetrics complications. Revista de la Sociedad Venezolana de Microbiología. 2002:22–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amesty JG, Lares de Acevedo A, Sandrea L, Piña-Reyes E, Rojas P, Salas A, et al.  Colonización de Streptococcus beta hemolítico del grupo B en gestantes en trabajo de parto y sus neonatos. Acta Cient Soc Venez Bioanalistas Esp. 2007;10:27–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosch-Mestres J, Martín-Fernández RM, Jiménez de Anta-Losada MT. Estudio comparativo de tres medios de cultivo para detectar la colonización por estreptococo del grupo B en la mujer embarazada. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin. 2003;21:346–349. doi: 10.1016/S0213-005X(03)72961-918.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0213-005X(03)72961-918</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14525690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura K. Series of studies concerning group B streptococci with reduced penicillin susceptibility (PRGBS) Nihon Saikingaku Zasshi. 2014;69:547–555. doi: 10.3412/jsb.69.547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3412/jsb.69.547</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25447980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura K, Suzuki S, Wachino J, et al.  First molecular characterization of group B streptococci with reduced penicillin susceptibility. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2008;52:2890–2897. doi: 10.1128/aac.00185-08.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aac.00185-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18490507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Betriu C, Gomez M, Sanchez A, Cruceyra A, Romero J, Picazo JJ. Antibiotic resistance and penicillin tolerance in clinical isolates of group B streptococci. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 1994;38:2183–2186. doi: 10.1128/AAC.38.9.2183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.38.9.2183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC284707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7811042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gizachew M, Tiruneh M, Moges F, Adefris M, Tigabu Z, Tessema B. Newborn colonization and antibiotic susceptibility patterns of Streptococcus agalactiae at the University of Gondar Referral Hospital, Northwest Ethiopia. BMC Pediatr. 2018;18:378–378. doi: 10.1186/s12887-018-1350-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12887-018-1350-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6271408</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30501616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamariz JH, Cruz J, Al Atencia, Figueroa J, Horna G, Guerra H. Resistencia a clindamicina inducida por eritromicina en Staphylococcus aureus aislados de tres hospitales de Lima, Perú. Acta Médica Peruana. 2009;26:12–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leclercq R. Mechanisms of resistance to macrolides and lincosamides: Nature of the resistance elements and their clinical implications. Clin Infect Dis. 2002;34:482–492. doi: 10.1086/324626.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/324626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11797175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ardanuy C, Cercenado E, Morosini MI, Torres C. Detección fenotípica de mecanismos de resistencia en grampositivos. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clin. 2012;30:325–332. doi: 10.1016/j.eimc.2011.09.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eimc.2011.09.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
