<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31869167</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK551703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31724">EMS Flight Safety Decisions</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clemente Fuentes</LastName><ForeName>Roselyn W.</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USUHS</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vargas</LastName><ForeName>Matthew J.</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Salzman</LastName><ForeName>Sandra M.</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USAF</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>According to the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB), 85% of flight-related accidents in the last 20 years have been due to “pilot error”, despite the aviation culture having the motto of “Safety First.” This is thought to be attributable to the training focused primarily on flight skill and proficiency and less so on risk identification strategies, disclosure, and mitigation of identified risks. The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) requires all aviators to complete a preflight risk assessment checklist, evaluating the individual risk factors affecting the safety of flight as they relate to the environment, the airframe, mission complexity, external pressures on the crew (mission, supervisor, home, etc) and the pilot. This activity will focus on the human factors relating to flight safety decisions, mitigation strategies, and the GO-NO GO decision.  I-M-S-A-F-E is a common mnemonic to help review these factors.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31724" sec="article-31724.s1">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31724" sec="article-31724.s2">Issues of Concern</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31724" sec="article-31724.s3">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31724" sec="article-31724.s4">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31724" sec="article-31724.s5">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hübner NO, Hübner C, Wodny M, Kampf G, Kramer A. Effectiveness of alcohol-based hand disinfectants in a public administration: impact on health and work performance related to acute respiratory symptoms and diarrhoea. BMC Infect Dis. 2010 Aug 24;10:250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20735818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell-Dunford N, Bushby A. Management of Sea Sickness in Susceptible Flight Crews. Mil Med. 2017 Nov;182(11):e1846-e1850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29087851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhabhar FS. The short-term stress response - Mother nature's mechanism for enhancing protection and performance under conditions of threat, challenge, and opportunity. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2018 Apr;49:175-192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakeman D, Langham MR. Creating a safer operating room: Groups, team dynamics and crew resource management principles. Semin Pediatr Surg. 2018 Apr;27(2):107-113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29548351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selby JB, Thompson A. Aviation and Procedural Medicine. Tech Vasc Interv Radiol. 2018 Dec;21(4):295-304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuček M, Škerjanc A. Alcohol, drugs and psychotropic medication at work: guidelines for medical fitness. Cent Eur J Public Health. 2019 Sep;27(3):195-197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31580553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brumback T, Cao D, McNamara P, King A. Alcohol-induced performance impairment: a 5-year re-examination study in heavy and light drinkers. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 2017 Jun;234(11):1749-1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28280882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JA. Fatigue in aviation. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2005 May;3(2):85-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17292011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Y, Fu G. A modified accident analysis and investigation model for the general aviation industry: Emphasizing on human and organizational factors. J Safety Res. 2018 Dec;67:1-15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30553410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly D, Efthymiou M. An analysis of human factors in fifty controlled flight into terrain aviation accidents from 2007 to 2017. J Safety Res. 2019 Jun;69:155-165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31235226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laws J. FAA takes aim at pilots' fatigue. Occup Health Saf. 2012 Mar;81(3):36-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22474904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Missoni E, Nikolić N, Missoni I. Civil aviation rules on crew flight time, flight duty, and rest: comparison of 10 ICAO member states. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2009 Feb;80(2):135-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19198200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cingi C, Emre IE, Muluk NB. Jetlag related sleep problems and their management: A review. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2018 Jul - Aug;24:59-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29787851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roach GD, Sargent C. Interventions to Minimize Jet Lag After Westward and Eastward Flight. Front Physiol. 2019;10:927.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6684967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31417411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore RK, Webb TS, Hermes ED. Fatigue and stimulant use in military fighter aircrew during combat operations. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2010 Aug;81(8):719-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20681231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen Kew G, See B. Zolpidem as a Sleep Aid for Military Aviators. Aerosp Med Hum Perform. 2018 Apr 01;89(4):406-408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estrada A, Kelley AM, Webb CM, Athy JR, Crowley JS. Modafinil as a replacement for dextroamphetamine for sustaining alertness in military helicopter pilots. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2012 Jun;83(6):556-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22764609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JA, Caldwell JL. Fatigue in military aviation: an overview of US military-approved pharmacological countermeasures. Aviat Space Environ Med. 2005 Jul;76(7 Suppl):C39-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16018329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31869167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
