<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31975553</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4547</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>98</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neuroscience research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neurosci Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Mirror neurons and their relationship with neurodegenerative disorders.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1070</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1094</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1070-1094</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jnr.24579</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The finding of mirror neurons (MNs) has provided a biological substrate to a new concept of cognition, relating data on actions and perceptions not only to integrate perception in action planning and execution but also as a neural mechanism supporting a wide range of cognitive functions. Here we first summarize data on MN localization and role in primates, then we report findings in normal human subjects: functional magnetic resonance imaging and neurophysiological studies sustain that MNs have a role in motor learning and recognizing actions and intentions of others, and they also support an embodied view of language, empathy, and memory. Then, we detail the results of literature searching on MNs and embodied cognition in Parkinson's disease (PD), frontotemporal dementia (FTD)/amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), and in mild cognitive impairment (MCI)/Alzheimer's disease (AD). In PD the network of MN could be altered, but its hyperactivation might support motor and cognitive performances at least in early stages. In the ALS/FTD continuum, preliminary evidence points out to an involvement of the MN network, which could explain language and inter-subjectivity deficits shown in patients affected by these clinical entities. In the MCI/AD spectrum, a few recent studies suggest a possible progressive involvement from posterior to anterior areas of the MN network, with the brain putting in place compensatory mechanisms in early stages. Reinterpreting neurodegenerative diseases at the light of the new views about brain organization stemming from the discovery of MN could help to better comprehend clinical manifestations and open new pathways to rehabilitation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Farina</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elisabetta</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9160-0356</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Borgnis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francesca</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>IRCCS Fondazione Don Carlo Gnocchi, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pozzo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thierry</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>INSERM UMR1093-CAPS, Université Bourgogne Franche-Comté, Dijon, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>IT@UniFe Center for Translational Neurophysiology, Istituto Italiano di Tecnologia, Ferrara, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Neurosci Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7600111</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0360-4012</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059167" MajorTopicYN="N">Mirror Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019636" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegenerative Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer's disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson's disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">embodied cognition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">frontotemporal dementia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">mirror neurons</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31975553</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jnr.24579</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbruzzese, G., Avanzino, L., Marchese, R., &amp; Pelosin, E. (2015). Action observation and motor imagery: Innovative cognitive tools in the rehabilitation of Parkinson’s disease. Parkinson's Disease, 2015, 1-9. https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/124214</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbruzzese, G., Trompetto, C., &amp; Schieppati, M. (1996). The excitability of the human motor cortex increases during execution and mental imagination of sequential but not repetitive finger movements. Experimental Brain Research, 111(3), 465-472. https://doi.org/10.1007/bf00228736</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrevaya, S., Sedeño, L., Fitipaldi, S., Pineda, D., Lopera, F., Buritica, O., … García, A. M. (2016). The road less traveled: Alternative pathways for action-verb processing in Parkinson’s disease. Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 55(4), 1429-1435. https://doi.org/10.3233/jad-160737</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnew, Z. K., Bhakoo, K. K., &amp; Puri, B. K. (2007). The human mirror system: A motor resonance theory of mind-reading. Brain Research Reviews, 54(2), 286-293. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainresrev.2007.04.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agosta, F., Gatti, R., Sarasso, E., Volonté, M. A., Canu, E., Meani, A., … Filippi, M. (2016). Brain plasticity in Parkinson’s disease with freezing of gait induced by action observation training. Journal of Neurology, 264(1), 88-101. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-016-8309-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alaerts, K., Swinnen, S. P., &amp; Wenderoth, N. (2009). Is the human primary motor cortex activated by muscular or direction-dependent features of observed movements? Cortex, 45(10), 1148-1155. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2008.10.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albert, N. B., Peiris, Y., Cohen, G., Miall, R. C., &amp; Praamstra, P. (2010). Interference effects from observed movement in Parkinson's disease. Journal of Motor Behavior, 42(2), 145-149. https://doi.org/10.1080/00222891003612805</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alegre, M., Guridi, J., &amp; Artieda, J. (2011). The mirror system, theory of mind and Parkinson's disease. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 310, 194-196. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2011.07.030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alegre, M., Rodríguez-Oroz, M. C., Valencia, M., Pérez-Alcázar, M., Guridi, J., Iriarte, J., … Artieda, J. (2010). Changes in subthalamic activity during movement observation in Parkinson’s disease: Is the mirror system mirrored in the basal ganglia? Clinical Neurophysiology, 121(3), 414-425. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2009.11.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander, G. E., Crutcher, M. D., &amp; DeLong, M. R. (1990). Basal ganglia-thalamocortical circuits: Parallel substrates for motor, oculomotor, “prefrontal” and “limbic” functions. Progress in Brain Research, 85, 119-146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allison, T., Puce, A., &amp; McCarthy, G. (2000). Social perception from visual cues: Role of the STS region. Trends of Cognitive Science, 4, 267-278. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1364-6613(00)01501-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anders, S., Sack, B., Pohl, A., Munte, T., Pramstaller, P., Klein, C., &amp; Binkofski, F. (2012). Compensatory premotor activity during affective face processing in subclinical carriers of a single mutant Parkin allele. Brain, 135(4), 1128-1140. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aws040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arbib, M. (2008). From grasp to language: Embodied concepts and the challenge of abstraction. Journal of Physiology, 102(1-3), 4-20. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphysparis.2008.03.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ariatti, A., Benuzzi, F., &amp; Nichelli, P. (2008). Recognition of emotions from visual and prosodic cues in Parkinson’s disease. Neurological Sciences, 29(4), 219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnstein, D., Cui, F., Keysers, C., Maurits, N. M., &amp; Gazzola, V. (2011). Suppression during action observation and execution correlates with BOLD in dorsal premotor, inferior parietal, and SI cortices. Journal of Neuroscience, 31(40), 14243-14249. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0963-11.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziz-Zadeh, L., Iacobon, M., Zaidel, E., Wilson, S., &amp; Mazziotta, J. (2004). Left hemisphere motor facilitation in response to manual action sounds. European Journal of Neuroscience, 19(9), 2609-2612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziz-Zadeh, L., Wilson, S. M., Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Iacoboni, M. (2006). Congruent embodied representations for visually presented actions and linguistic phrases describing actions. Current Biology, 16(18), 1818-1823. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2006.07.060</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babiloni, C., Babiloni, F., Carducci, F., Cincotti, F., Cocozza, G., Del Percio, C., … Rossini, P. M. (2002). Human cortical electroencephalography (EEG) rhythms during the observation of simple aimless movements: A high-resolution EEG study. NeuroImage, 17(2), 559-572. https://doi.org/10.1006/nimg.2002.1192</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bacigalupe, M. L., &amp; Pujol, S. (2014). Movement from the social cognitive neuroscience: The case of Parkinson's disease. Vertex, 25(118), 429-436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baez, S., Manes, F., Huepe, D., Torralva, T., Fiorentino, N., Richter, F., … Ibanez, A. (2014). Primary empathy deficits in frontotemporal dementia. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 6, 262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baglio, F., Castelli, I., Alberoni, M., Blasi, V., Griffanti, L., Falini, A., … Marchetti, A. (2012). Theory of mind in amnestic mild cognitive impairment: An FMRI study. Journal of Alzheimer's Disease, 29(1), 25-37. https://doi.org/10.3233/JAD-2011-111256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bak, T. H. (2013). The neuroscience of action semantics in neurodegenerative brain diseases. Current Opinion in Neurology, 26(6), 671-677. https://doi.org/10.1097/wco.0000000000000039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bak, T. H., &amp; Chandran, S. (2012). What wires together dies together: Verbs, actions and neurodegeneration in motor neuron disease. Cortex, 48(7), 936-944. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2011.07.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bak, T., &amp; Hodges, J. R. (1997). Noun-verb dissociation in three patients with motor neuron disease and aphasia. Brain and Language, 60, 38-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bak, T. H., O’Donovan, D. G., Xuereb, J. H., Boniface, S., &amp; Hodges, J. R. (2001). Selective impairment of verb processing associated with pathological changes in Brodmann areas 44 and 45 in the motor neuron disease-dementia-aphasia syndrome. Brain, 124, 103-120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baron-Cohen, S., Wheelwright, S., Hill, J., Raste, Y., &amp; Plumb, I. (2001). The “reading the mind in the eyes” test revised version: A study with normal adults, and adults with Asperger syndrome or high-functioning autism. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 42(2), 241-251. https://doi.org/10.1111/1469-7610.00715</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barsalou, L. W. (1999). Perceptual symbol systems. The Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 22(4), 577-660. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X99002149</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barsalou, L. W. (2008). Grounded cognition. Annual Review of Psychology, 59, 617-645. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.59.103006.093639</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barsalou, L. W., Simmons, W. K., Barbey, A., &amp; Wilson, C. D. (2003). Grounding conceptual knowledge in modality-specific systems. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 7, 84-91. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1364-6613(02)00029-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bassolino, M., Sandini, G., &amp; Pozzo, T. (2015). Activating the motor system through action observation: Is this an efficient approach in adults and children? Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology, 57, 42-45. https://doi.org/10.1111/dmcn.12686</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bediou, B., Ryff, I., Mercier, B., Milliery, M., Hénaff, M.-A., D’Amato, T., … Krolak-Salmon, P. (2009). Impaired social cognition in mild Alzheimer disease. Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry and Neurology, 22(2), 130-140. https://doi.org/10.1177/0891988709332939</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bieńkiewicz, M. M., Rodger, M. W., Young, W. R., &amp; Craig, C. M. (2013). Time to get a move on: Overcoming bradykinetic movement in Parkinson's disease with artificial sensory guidance generated from biological motion. Behavioural Brain Research, 253, 113-120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birba, A., García-Cordero, I., Kozono, G., Legaz, A., Ibáñez, A., Sedeño, L., &amp; García, A. M. (2017). Losing ground: Frontostriatal atrophy disrupts language embodiment in Parkinson’s and Huntington’s disease. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 80, 673-687. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2017.07.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bisio, A., Casteran, M., Ballay, Y., Manckoundia, P., Mourey, F., &amp; Pozzo, T. (2012). Motor resonance mechanisms are preserved in Alzheimer's disease patients. Neuroscience, 222, 58-68. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2012.07.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bisio, A., Casteran, M., Ballay, Y., Manckoundia, P., Mourey, F., &amp; Pozzo, T. (2016). Voluntary imitation in Alzheimer’s disease patients. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 8, 48. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2016.00048</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonassi, G., Pelosin, E., Ogliastro, C., Cerulli, C., Abbruzzese, G., &amp; Avanzino, L. (2016). Mirror visual feedback to improve bradykinesia in Parkinson’s disease. Neural Plasticity, 2016, 1-11. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/8764238</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonini, L. (2016). The extended mirror neuron network. Neuroscientist, 23(1), 56-67. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073858415626400</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonini, L., Rozzi, S., Serventi, F. U., Simone, L., Ferrari, P. F., &amp; Fogassi, L. (2010). Ventral premotor and inferior parietal cortices make distinct contribution to action organization and intention understanding. Cerebral Cortex, 20(6), 1372-1385. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhp200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borra, E., Gerbella, M., Rozzi, S., &amp; Luppino, G. (2011). Anatomical evidence for the involvement of the macaque ventrolateral prefrontal area 12r in controlling goal-directed actions. Journal of Neuroscience, 31(34), 12351-12363. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.1745-11.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braadbaart, L., Williams, J. H. G., &amp; Waiter, G. D. (2013). Do mirror neuron areas mediate mu rhythm suppression during imitation and action observation? International Journal of Psychophysiology, 89(1), 99-105. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2013.05.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brioschi Guevara, A., Knutson, K. M., Wassermann, E. M., Pulaski, S., Grafman, J., &amp; Krueger, F. (2015). Theory of mind impairment in patients with behavioural variant fronto-temporal dementia (bv-FTD) increases caregiver burden. Age and Ageing, 44(5), 891-895. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afv059</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buccino, G. (2014). Action observation treatment: A novel tool in neurorehabilitation. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 369(1644), 20130185. https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2013.0185</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buccino, G., Arisi, D., Gough, P., Aprile, D., Ferri, C., Serotti, L., … Fazzi, E. (2012). Improving upper limb motor functions through action observation treatment: A pilot study in children with cerebral palsy. Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology, 54(9), 822-828. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8749.2012.04334.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buccino, G., Binkofski, F., Fink, G. R., Fadiga, L., Fogassi, L., Gallese, V., … Freund, H. J. (2001). Action observation activates premotor and parietal areas in a somatotopic manner: An fMRI study. European Journal of Neuroscience, 13(2), 400-404. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.2001.01385.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buccino, G., Binkofski, F., &amp; Riggio, L. (2004). The mirror neuron system and action recognition. Brain and Language, 89(2), 370-376. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0093-934X(03)00356-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buccino, G., Gatti, R., Giusti, M. C., Negrotti, A., Rossi, A., Calzetti, S., &amp; Cappa, S. F. (2011). Action observation treatment improves autonomy in daily activities in Parkinson's disease patients: Results from a pilot study. Movement Disorders, 26(10), 1963-1964. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.23745</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buccino, G., Solodkin, A., &amp; Small, S. L. (2006). Functions of the mirror neuron system: Implications for neurorehabilitation. Cognitive and Behavioral Neurology, 19(1), 55-63. https://doi.org/10.1097/00146965-200603000-00007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budell, L., Jackson, P., &amp; Rainville, P. (2010). Brain responses to facial expressions of pain: Emotional or motor mirroring? NeuroImage, 53(1), 355-363. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2010.05.037</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busse, A., Bischkopf, J., Riedel-Heller, S. G., &amp; Angermeyer, M. C. (2003). Mild cognitive impairment: Prevalence and incidence according to different diagnostic criteria. Results of the Leipzig Longitudinal Study of the Aged (LEILA75+). British Journal of Psychiatry, 182, 449-454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caffarra, P., Perini, M., Reda, V., Barocco, F., Michelini, G., Spallazzi, M., … Camanini, G. (2016). The effectiveness of action observation treatment (Aot) in Alzheimer's disease: Benefit on temporal orientation and visuo-prassic abilities. Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia: The Journal of the Alzheimer's Association, 12(7), P615.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caggiano, V., Fogassi, L., Rizzolatti, G., Pomper, J. K., Thier, P., Giese, M. A., &amp; Casile, A. (2011). View-based encoding of actions in mirror neurons of area F5 in macaque premotor cortex. Current Biology, 21(2), 144-148. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2010.12.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caggiano, V., Fogassi, L., Rizzolatti, G., Thier, P., &amp; Casile, A. (2009). Mirror neurons differentially encode the peripersonal and extrapersonal space of monkeys. Science, 324(5925), 403-406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caligiore, D., Mustile, M., Fineschi, A., Romano, L., Piras, F., Assogna, F., … Baldassarre, G. (2019). Action observation with dual task for improving cognitive abilities in Parkinson’s disease: A pilot study. Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience, 13, 7. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2019.00007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caligiore, D., Mustile, M., Spalletta, G., &amp; Baldassarre, G. (2017). Action observation and motor imagery for rehabilitation in Parkinson's disease: A systematic review and an integrative hypothesis. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 72, 210-222. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2016.11.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cappa, S. F., Binetti, G., Pezzini, A., Padovani, A., Rozzini, L., &amp; Trabucchi, M. (1998). Object and action naming in Alzheimer’s disease and frontotemporal dementia. Neurology, 50, 351-355. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.50.2.351</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caramazza, A., Anzellotti, S., Strnad, L., &amp; Lingnau, A. (2014). Embodied cognition and mirror neurons: A critical assessment. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 37, 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-071013-013950</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona, J. F., Gershanik, O., Gelormini-Lezama, C., Houck, A. L., Cardona, S., Kargieman, L., … Ibáñez, A. (2013). Action-verb processing in Parkinson’s disease: New pathways for motor-language coupling. Brain Structure and Function, 218(6), 1355-1373. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-013-0510-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carr, L., Iacoboni, M., Dubeau, M. C., Mazziotta, J. C., &amp; Lenzi, G. L. (2003). Neural mechanisms of empathy in humans: A relay from neural systems for imitation to limbic areas. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 100(9), 5497-5502. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0935845100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho, D., Teixeira, S., Lucas, M., Yuan, T.-F., Chaves, F., Peressutti, C., … Arias-Carrión, O. (2013). The mirror neuron system in post-stroke rehabilitation. International Archives of Medicine, 6(1), 41. https://doi.org/10.1186/1755-7682-6-41</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castiello, U., Ansuini, C., Bulgheroni, M., Scaravilli, T., &amp; Nicoletti, R. (2009). Visuomotor priming effects in Parkinson's disease patients depend on the match between the observed and the executed action. Neuropsychologia, 47(3), 835-842. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2008.12.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerami, C., Dodich, A., Canessa, N., Crespi, C., Iannaccone, S., Corbo, M., … Cappa, S. F. (2014). Emotional empathy in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: A behavioural and voxel-based morphometry study. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration, 15(1-2), 21-29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerri, G., Cabinio, M., Blasi, V., Borroni, P., Iadanza, A., Fava, E., … Bello, L. (2015). The mirror neuron system and the strange case of Broca’s area: Broca is not part of mirror neuron system. Human Brain Mapping, 36(3), 1010-1027. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.22682</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chong, T.- T.-J., Cunnington, R., Williams, M. A., Kanwisher, N., &amp; Mattingley, J. B. (2008). fMRI adaptation reveals mirror neurons in human inferior parietal cortex. Current Biology, 18(20), 1576-1580. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2008.08.068</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chwilla, D. J., Virgillito, D., &amp; Vissers, C. T. V. (2011). The relationship of language and emotion: N400 support for an embodied view of language comprehension. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 23(9), 2400-2414. https://doi.org/10.1162/jocn.2010.21578</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark, U. S., Neargarder, S., &amp; Cronin-Golomb, A. (2008). Specific impairments in the recognition of emotional facial expressions in Parkinson's disease. Neuropsychologia, 46(9), 2300-2309. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2008.03.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cochin, S., Barthelemy, C., Roux, S., &amp; Martineau, J. (1999). Observation and execution of movement: Similarities demonstrated by quantified electroencephalography. European Journal of Neuroscience, 11(5), 1839-1842. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.1999.00598.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coll, M. P., Bird, G., Catmur, C., &amp; Press, C. (2015). Cross-modal repetition effects in the mu rhythm indicate tactile mirroring during action observation. Cortex, 63, 121-131. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2014.08.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conson, M., Trojano, L., Vitale, C., Mazzarella, E., Allocca, R., Barone, P., … Santangelo, G. (2014). The role of embodied simulation in mental transformation of whole-body images: Evidence from Parkinson’s disease. Human Movement Science, 33, 343-353.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, R., Bird, G., Catmur, C., Press, C., &amp; Heyes, C. (2014). Mirror neurons: From origin to function. Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 37(2), 177-192. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X13000903</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corradini, A., &amp; Antonietti, A. (2013). Mirror neurons and their function in cognitively understood empathy. Consciousness and Cognition, 22(3), 1152-1161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cotelli, M., Manenti, R., Cappa, S. F., Geroldi, C., Zanetti, O., Rossini, P. M., &amp; Miniussi, C. (2006). Effect of transcranial magnetic stimulation on action naming in patients with Alzheimer disease. Archives of Neurology, 63(11), 1602. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.63.11.160</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cotelli, M., Manenti, R., Cappa, S. F., Zanetti, O., &amp; Miniussi, C. (2008). Transcranial magnetic stimulation improves naming in Alzheimer disease patients at different stages of cognitive decline. European Journal of Neurology, 15(12), 1286-1292. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02202.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunnington, R., Egan, G. F., O'Sullivan, J. D., Hughes, A. J., Bradshaw, J. L., &amp; Colebatch, J. G. (2001). Motor imagery in Parkinson's disease: A PET study. Movement Disorders, 16(5), 849-857. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.1181</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>da Silva, H. S., Machado, J., Cravo, A., Parente, M. A. P., &amp; Carthery-Goulart, M. T. (2014). Action/verb processing: Debates in neuroimaging and the contribution of studies in patients with Parkinson's disease. Dementia &amp; Neuropsychologia, 8(1), 3-13. https://doi.org/10.1590/S1980-57642014DN81000002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dapretto, M., Davies, M. S., Pfeifer, J. H., Scott, A. A., Sigman, M., Bookheimer, S., &amp; Iacoboni, M. (2006). Understanding emotions in others: Mirror neuron dysfunction in children with autism spectrum disorders. Nature Neuroscience, 9(1), 28-30. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1611</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Scalzi, M., Rusted, J., &amp; Oakhill, J. (2015). Embodiment effects and language comprehension in Alzheimer's disease. Cognitive Science, 39(5), 890-917. https://doi.org/10.1111/cogs.12187</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decety, J. (1996). Do imagined and executed actions share the same neural substrate? Cognitive Brain Research, 3(2), 87-93. https://doi.org/10.1016/0926-6410(95)00033-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deconinck, F. J. A., Smorenburg, A. R. P., Benham, A., Ledebt, A., Feltham, M. G., &amp; Savelsbergh, G. J. P. (2014). Reflections on mirror therapy. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair, 29(4), 349-361. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968314546134</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>del Olmo, M. F., &amp; Cudeiro, J. (2005). Temporal variability of gait in Parkinson disease: Effects of a rehabilitation programme based on rhythmic sound cues. Parkinsonism &amp; Related Disorders, 11, 25-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Iorio, W., Ciarimboli, A., Ferriero, G., Feleppa, M., Baratto, L., Matarazzo, G., … Sale, P. (2018). Action observation in people with Parkinson’s disease. A motor-cognitive combined approach for motor rehabilitation. A preliminary report. Diseases, 6(3), 58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>di Pellegrino, G., Fadiga, L., Fogassi, L., Gallese, V., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (1992). Understanding motor events: A neurophysiological study. Experimental Brain Research, 91(1), 176-180. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00230027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dijkstra, K., Kaschak, M. P., &amp; Zwaan, R. A. (2007). Body posture facilitates retrieval of autobiographical memories. Cognition, 102(1), 139-149. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cognition.2005.12.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Druks, J., Masterson, J., Kopelman, M., Clare, L., Rose, A., &amp; Rai, G. (2006). Is action naming better preserved (than object naming) in Alzheimer’s disease and why should we ask? Brain and Language, 98(3), 332-340. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bandl.2006.06.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eggermont, L. H. P., Swaab, D. F., Hol, E. M., &amp; Scherder, E. J. A. (2009). Observation of hand movements by older persons with dementia: Effects on cognition: A pilot study. Dementia and Geriatric Cognitive Disorders, 27(4), 366-374. https://doi.org/10.1159/000209311</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisen, A., Turner, M. R., &amp; Lemon, R. (2013). Tools and talk: An evolutionary perspective on the functional deficits associated with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Muscle and Nerve, 49(4), 469-477. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.24132</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enticott, P. G., Hoy, K. E., Herring, S. E., Johnston, P. J., Daskalakis, Z. J., &amp; Fitzgerald, P. B. (2008). Reduced motor facilitation during action observation in schizophrenia: A mirror neuron deficit? Schizophrenia Research, 102(1-3), 116-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.schres.2008.04.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ertelt, D., &amp; Binkofski, F. (2012). Action observation as a tool for neurorehabilitation to moderate motor deficits and aphasia following stroke. Neural Regeneration Research, 7(26), 2063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fadiga, L., Craighero, L., &amp; Olivier, E. (2005). Human motor cortex excitability during the perception of others’ action. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 15(2), 213-218. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2005.03.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fadiga, L., Fogassi, L., Pavesi, G., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (1995). Motor facilitation during action observation: A magnetic stimulation study. Journal of Neurophysiology, 73(6), 2608-2611. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.1995.73.6.2608</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farina, E., Baglio, F., Pomati, S., D’Amico, A., Campini, I. C., Di Tella, S., … Pozzo, T. (2017). The mirror neurons network in aging, mild cognitive impairment, and Alzheimer disease: A functional MRI study. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 9, 371. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2017.00371</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez-Duque, D., Hodges, S. D., Baird, J. A., &amp; Black, S. E. (2009). Empathy in frontotemporal dementia and Alzheimer's disease. Journal of Clinical and Experimental Neuropsychology, 32(3), 289-298. https://doi.org/10.1080/13803390903002191</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrari, P. F., Gallese, V., Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Fogassi, L. (2003). Mirror neurons responding to the observation of ingestive and communicative mouth actionsin the monkey ventral premotor cortex. European Journal of Neuroscience, 17(8), 1703-1714. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.2003.02601.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrari, P. F., Gerbella, M., Coudé, G., &amp; Rozzi, S. (2017). Two different mirror neuron networks: The sensorimotor (hand) and limbic (face) pathways. Neuroscience, 358, 300-315. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2017.06.052</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrari, P. F., Rozzi, S., &amp; Fogassi, L. (2005). Mirror neurons responding to observation of actions made with tools in monkey ventral premotor cortex. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 17(2), 212-226. https://doi.org/10.1162/0898929053124910</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferri, S., Peeters, R., Nelissen, K., Vanduffel, W., Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Orban, G. A. (2015). A human homologue of monkey F5c. NeuroImage, 111, 251-266. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2015.02.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fiori, F., Sedda, A., Ferrè, E. R., Toraldo, A., Querzola, M., Pasotti, F., … Bottini, G. (2013). Exploring motor and visual imagery in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Experimental Brain Research, 226(4), 537-547. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00221-013-3465-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fischer, M. H., &amp; Zwaan, R. A. (2008). Embodied language: A review of the role of the motor system in language comprehension. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, 61(6), 825-850. https://doi.org/10.1080/17470210701623605</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fishman, I., Keown, C. L., Lincoln, A. J., Pineda, J. A., &amp; Müller, R. A. (2014). Atypical cross talk between mentalizing and mirror neuron networks in autism spectrum disorder. JAMA Psychiatry, 71(7), 751-760. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2014.83</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fogassi, L., Ferrari, P. F., Gesierich, B., Rozzi, S., Chersi, F., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (2005). Parietal lobe: From action organization to intention understanding. Science, 308(5722), 662-667. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1106138</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox, N. A., Bakermans-Kranenburg, M. J., Yoo, K. H., Bowman, L. C., Cannon, E. N., Vanderwert, R. E., … van IJzendoorn, M. H. (2016). Assessing human mirror activity with EEG mu rhythm: A meta-analysis. Psychological Bulletin, 142, 291-313. https://doi.org/10.1037/bul0000031</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher, S. (2005). How the body shapes the mind. Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallese, V. (2003). The roots of empathy: The shared manifold hypothesis and the neural basis of intersubjectivity. Psychopathology, 36(4), 171-180. https://doi.org/10.1159/000072786</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallese, V., Fadiga, L., Fogassi, L., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (1996). Action recognition in the premotor cortex. Brain, 119, 593-609. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/119.2.593</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallese, V., Keysers, C., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (2004). A unifying view of the basis of social cognition. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 8(9), 396-403. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2004.07.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García, A., &amp; Ibáñez, A. (2014). Words in motion: Motor-language coupling in Parkinson’s disease. Translational Neuroscience, 5(2), 152-159. https://doi.org/10.2478/s13380-014-0218-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gatti, R., Tettamanti, A., Gough, P. M., Riboldi, E., Marinoni, L., &amp; Buccino, G. (2013). Action observation versus motor imagery in learning a complex motor task: A short review of literature and a kinematics study. Neuroscience Letters, 540, 37-42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2012.11.039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gavazzi, G., Bisio, A., &amp; Pozzo, T. (2013). Time perception of visual motion is tuned by the motor representation of human actions. Scientific Reports, 3(1), 1168. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep01168</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gazzola, V., Aziz-Zadeh, L., &amp; Keysers, C. (2006). Empathy and the somatotopic auditory mirror system in humans. Current Biology, 16(18), 1824-1829. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2006.07.072</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gazzola, V., van der Worp, H., Mulder, T., Wicker, B., Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Keysers, C. (2007). Aplasics born without hands mirror the goal of hand actions with their feet. Current Biology, 17(14), 1235-1240. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2007.06.045</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gelbard-Sagiv, H., Mukamel, R., Harel, M., Malach, R., &amp; Fried, I. (2008). Internally generated reactivation of single neurons in human hippocampus during free recall. Science, 322(5898), 96-101. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1164685</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerbella, M., Borra, E., Mangiaracina, C., Rozzi, S., &amp; Luppino, G. (2015). Corticostriate projections from areas of the “lateral grasping network”: Evidence for multiple hand-related input channels. Cerebral Cortex, 26(7), 3096-3115. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhv135</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerbella, M., Borra, E., Tonelli, S., Rozzi, S., &amp; Luppino, G. (2012). Connectional heterogeneity of the ventral part of the macaque area 46. Cerebral Cortex, 23(4), 967-987. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhs096</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghilardi, M. F., Alberoni, M., Marelli, S., Rossi, M., Franceschi, M., Ghez, C., &amp; Fazio, F. (1999). Impaired movement control in Alzheimer's disease. Neuroscience Letters, 260, 45-48. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0304-3940(98)00957-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girardi, A., MacPherson, S. E., &amp; Abrahams, S. (2011). Deficits in emotional and social cognition in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neuropsychology, 25(1), 53-65. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0020357</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giret, N., Kornfeld, J., Ganguli, S., &amp; Hahnloser, R. H. R. (2014). Evidence for a causal inverse model in an avian cortico-basal ganglia circuit. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 111(16), 6063-6068. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1317087111</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glenberg, A., Sato, M., Cattaneo, L., Riggio, L., Palumbo, D., &amp; Buccino, G. (2008). Processing abstract language modulates motor system activity. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, 61(6), 905-919. https://doi.org/10.1080/17470210701625550</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greene, S., Killiany, R. J., &amp; Alzheimer's Disease Neuroimaging Initiative. (2010). Subregions of the inferior parietal lobule are affected in the progression to AD. Neurobiology of Aging, 31(8), 1304-1311. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2010.04.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grèzes, J., Armony, J. L., Rowe, J., &amp; Passingham, R. E. (2003). Activations related to “mirror” and “canonical” neurons in the human brain: An fMRI study. NeuroImage, 18(4), 928-937.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grosbras, M. H., &amp; Paus, T. (2006). Brain networks involved in viewing angry hands or faces. Cerebral Cortex, 8, 1087-1096. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhj050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grossman, M., Anderson, C., Khan, A., Avants, B., Elman, L., &amp; McCluskey, L. (2008). Impaired action knowledge in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Neurology, 71(18), 1396-1401. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000319701.50168.8c</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guaita, A., Malnati, M., Vaccaro, R., Pezzati, R., Marcionetti, J., Vitali, S. F., &amp; Colombo, M. (2009). Impaired facial emotion recognition and preserved reactivity to facial expressions in people with severe dementia. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 49, 135-146. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2009.09.023</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hardwick, R. M., Caspers, S., Eickhoff, S. B., &amp; Swinnen, S. P. (2018). Neural correlates of action: Comparing meta-analyses of imagery, observation, and execution. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 94, 31-44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2018.08.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauk, O., Johnsrude, I., &amp; Pulvermüller, F. (2004). Somatotopic representation of action words in human motor and premotor cortex. Neuron, 41(2), 301-307. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0896-6273(03)00838-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heida, T., Poppe, N. R., de Vos, C. C., van Putten, M. J. A. M., &amp; van Vugt, J. P. P. (2014). Event-related mu-rhythm desynchronization during movement observation is impaired in Parkinson’s disease. Clinical Neurophysiology, 125(9), 1819-1825. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinph.2014.01.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heiser, M., Iacoboni, M., Maeda, F., Marcus, J., &amp; Mazziotta, J. C. (2003). The essential role of Broca’s area in imitation. European Journal of Neuroscience, 17(5), 1123-1128. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.2003.02530.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helmich, R. C., de Lange, F. P., Bloem, B. R., &amp; Toni, I. (2007). Cerebral compensation during motor imagery in Parkinson's disease. Neuropsychologia, 45(10), 2201-2215. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2007.02.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hennenlotter, A., Schroeder, U., Erhard, P., Castrop, F., Haslinger, B., Stoecker, D., … Ceballosbaumann, A. (2005). A common neural basis for receptive and expressive communication of pleasant facial affect. Neuroimage, 26(2), 581-591. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2005.01.057</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heremans, E., Feys, P., Nieuwboer, A., Vercruysse, S., Vandenberghe, W., Sharma, N., &amp; Helsen, W. (2011). Motor imagery ability in patients with early- and mid-stage Parkinson disease. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair, 25(2), 168-177. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968310370750</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herrera, E., Cuetos, F., &amp; Rodríguez-Ferreiro, J. (2011). Emotion recognition impairment in Parkinson's disease patients without dementia. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 310(1-2), 237-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill, N. T. M., Mowszowski, L., Naismith, S. L., Chadwick, V. L., Valenzuela, M., &amp; Lampit, A. (2017). Computerized cognitive training in older adults with mild cognitive impairment or dementia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. American Journal of Psychiatry, 174(4), 329-340. https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16030360</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillis, A. E., Oh, S., &amp; Ken, L. (2004). Deterioration of naming nouns versus verbs in primary progressive aphasia. Annals of Neurology, 55(2), 268-275. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.10812</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hobson, H. M., &amp; Bishop, D. V. M. (2016). Mu suppression-A good measure of the human mirror neuron system? Cortex, 82, 290-310. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2016.03.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iacoboni, M. (2009). Imitation, empathy, and mirror neurons. Annual Review of Psychology, 60, 653-670. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.60.110707.163604</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iacoboni, M., Molnar-Szakacs, I., Gallese, V., Buccino, G., Mazziotta, J. C., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (2005). Grasping the intentions of others with one’s own mirror neuron system. PLoS Biology, 3(3), 529-535.e79. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.0030079</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iacoboni, M., Woods, R. P., Brass, M., Bekkering, H., Mazziotta, J. C., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (1999). Cortical mechanisms of human imitation. Science, 286(5449), 2526-2528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs, D. H., Shuren, J., Bowers, D., &amp; Heilman, K. M. (1995). Emotional facial imagery, perception, and expression in Parkinsons-disease. Neurology, 45(9), 1696-1702. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.45.9.1696</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jastorff, J., De Winter, F.-L., Van den Stock, J., Vandenberghe, R., Giese, M. A., &amp; Vandenbulcke, M. (2016). Functional dissociation between anterior temporal lobe and inferior frontal gyrus in the processing of dynamic body expressions: Insights from behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia. Human Brain Mapping, 37(12), 4472-4486. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.23322</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaywant, A., Ellis, T. D., Roy, S., Lin, C.-C., Neargarder, S., &amp; Cronin-Golomb, A. (2016). Randomized controlled trial of a home-based action observation intervention to improve walking in Parkinson disease. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, 97(5), 665-673. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2015.12.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaywant, A., Shiffrar, M., Roy, S., &amp; Cronin-Golomb, A. (2016). Impaired perception of biological motion in Parkinson’s disease. Neuropsychology, 30(6), 720-730. https://doi.org/10.1037/neu0000276</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeannerod, M. (2001). Neural simulation of action: A unifying mechanism for motor cognition. NeuroImage, 14(1), S103-S109. https://doi.org/10.1006/nimg.2001.0832</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeannerod, M., &amp; Decety, J. (1995). Mental motor imagery: A window into the representational stages of action. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 5(6), 727-732. https://doi.org/10.1016/0959-4388(95)80099-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeannerod, M., &amp; Frak, V. (1999). Mental imaging of motor activity in humans. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 9(6), 735-739. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0959-4388(99)00038-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelsone-Swain, L., Persad, C., Burkard, D., &amp; Welsh, R. C. (2015). Action processing and mirror neuron function in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: An fMRI study. PLoS ONE, 10(4), e0119862. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0119862</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato, Y., Muramatsu, T., Kato, M., Shibukawa, Y., Shintani, M., &amp; Mimura, M. (2011). Magnetoencephalography study of right parietal lobe dysfunction of the evoked mirror neuron system in antipsychotic-free schizophrenia. PLoS ONE, 6(11), e28087. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0028087</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemmerer, D., Rudrauf, D., Manzel, K., &amp; Tranel, D. (2012). Behavioral patterns and lesion sites associated with impaired processing of lexical and conceptual knowledge of actions. Cortex, 48(7), 826-848. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2010.11.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilner, J. M., Neal, A., Weiskopf, N., Friston, K. J., &amp; Frith, C. D. (2009). Evidence of mirror neurons in human inferior frontal gyrus. Journal of Neuroscience, 29(32), 10153-10159. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2668-09.2009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, M., &amp; Thompson, C. K. (2004). Verb deficits in Alzheimer’s disease and agrammatism: Implications for lexical organization. Brain and Language, 88(1), 1-20. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0093-934x(03)00147-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohler, C. G., Anselmo-Gallagher, G., Bilker, W., Karlawish, J., Gur, R. E., &amp; Clark, C. M. (2005). Emotion-discrimination deficits in mild Alzheimer disease. American Journal of Geriatric Psychiatry, 13(11), 926-933. https://doi.org/10.1097/00019442-200511000-00002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohler, E., Keysers, C., Umiltà, M. A., Fogassi, L., Gallese, V., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (2002). Hearing sounds, understanding actions: Action representation in mirror neurons. Science, 297(5582), 846-848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kraskov, A., Dancause, N., Quallo, M. M., Shepherd, S., &amp; Lemon, R. N. (2009). Corticospinal neurons in macaque ventral premotor cortex with mirror properties: A potential mechanism for action suppression? Neuron, 64(6), 922-930. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2009.12.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krubitzer, L. (2007). The magnificent compromise: Cortical field evolution in mammals. Neuron, 56(2), 201-208. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2007.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kühn, S., &amp; Brass, M. (2008). Testing the connection of the mirror system and speech: How articulation affects imitation in a simple response task. Neuropsychologia, 46(5), 1513-1521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laforce, R., Jr. (2013). Behavioral and language variants of frontotemporal dementia: A review of key symptoms. Clinical Neurology and Neurosurgery, 115(12), 2405-2410. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clineuro.2013.09.031</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanzilotto, M., Gerbella, M., Perciavalle, V., &amp; Lucchetti, C. (2017). Neuronal encoding of self and others’ head rotation in the macaque dorsal prefrontal cortex. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 8571. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-08936-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, T. M., Sun, D., Leung, M. K., Chu, L. W., &amp; Keysers, C. (2013). Neural activities during affective processing in people with Alzheimer's disease. Neurobiol Aging, 34(3), 706-715. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2012.06.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lepage, J. F., &amp; Théoret, H. (2006). EEG evidence for the presence of an action observation-execution matching system in children. European Journal of Neuroscience, 21, 2505-2510. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2006.04769.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leslie, K. R., Johnson-Frey, S. H., &amp; Grafton, S. T. (2004). Functional imaging of face and hand imitation: Towards a motor theory of empathy. Neuroimage, 21(2), 601-607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy, J., &amp; Feldman, R. (2019). Synchronous interactions foster empathy. Journal of Experimental Neuroscience, 13, 1179069519865799.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, H., Chen, Y., Li, Y., Yin, B., Tang, W., Yu, X., … Zhang, B. (2015). Altered cortical activation during action observation in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients: A parametric functional MRI study. European Radiology, 25(9), 2584-2592. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00330-015-3671-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linkovski, O., Katzin, N., &amp; Salti, M. (2017). Mirror neurons and mirror-touch synesthesia. The Neuroscientist, 23(2), 103-108. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073858416652079</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Livingstone, S. R., Vezer, E., McGarry, L. M., Lang, A. E., &amp; Russo, F. A. (2016). Deficits in the mimicry of facial expressions in Parkinson’s disease. Frontiers in Psychology, 7, 230. 7:780.10.3389/fpsyg.2016.00780</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macedonia, M. (2014). Bringing back the body into the mind: Gestures enhance word learning in foreign language. Frontiers in Psychology, 5, 1467. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.01467.eCollection2014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maillet, A., Thobois, S., Fraix, V., Redouté, J., Bars, D., Lavenne, F., … Debû, B. (2015). Neural substrates of levodopa responsive gait disorders and freezing in advanced Parkinson’s disease: A kinesthetic imagery approach. Human Brain Mapping, 36, 959-980. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.22679</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manera, V., Ben-Sadoun, G., Aalbers, T., Agopyan, H., Askenazy, F., Benoit, M., … Robert, P. (2017). Recommendations for the use of serious games in neurodegenerative disorders: 2016 Delphi Panel. Frontiers in Psychology, 8, 1243. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01243</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marceglia, S., Fiorio, M., Foffani, G., Mrakic-Sposta, S., Tiriticco, M., Locatelli, M., … Priori, A. (2009). Modulation of beta oscillations in the subthalamic area during action observation in Parkinson's disease. Neuroscience, 161(4), 1027-1036. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2009.04.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marneweck, M., Palermo, R., &amp; Hammond, G. (2014). Discrimination and recognition of facial expressions of emotion and their links with voluntary control of facial musculature in Parkinson’s disease. Neuropsychology, 28(6), 917-928. https://doi.org/10.1037/neu0000106</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall, C., Hardy, C., Russell, L., Clark, C., Dick, K., Brotherhood, E., … Warren, J. (2016). Embodied cognition of dynamic emotion in frontotemporal lobar degeneration. 10th International Conference on Frontotemporal Dementias.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinez, M., Multani, N., Anor, C. J., Misquitta, K., Tang-Wai, D. F., Keren, R., … Tartaglia, M. C. (2018). Emotion detection deficits and decreased empathy in patients with Alzheimer’s disease and Parkinson’s disease affect caregiver mood and Burden. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 10, 120. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2018.00120</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masterson, J., Druks, J., Kopelman, M., Clare, L., Garley, C., &amp; Hayes, M. (2007). Selective naming (and comprehension) deficits in Alzheimer’s disease? Cortex, 43(7), 921-934. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0010-9452(08)70691-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattar, A. A. G., &amp; Gribble, P. L. (2005). Motor learning by observing. Neuron, 46(1), 153-160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2005.02.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCormick, L. M., Brumm, M. C., Beadle, J. N., Paradiso, S., Yamada, T., &amp; Andreasen, N. (2012). Mirror neuron function, psychosis, and empathy in schizophrenia. Psychiatry Research: Neuroimaging, 201(3), 233-239. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pscychresns.2012.01.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKeith, I. G., Boeve, B. F., Dickson, D. W., Halliday, G., Taylor, J. P., Weintraub, D., … Kosaka, K. (2017). Diagnosis and management of dementia with Lewy bodies: Fourth consensus report of the DLB Consortium. Neurology, 89(1), 88-100. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000004058</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLellan, T., Johnston, L., Dalrymple-Alford, J., &amp; Porter, R. (2008). The recognition of facial expressions of emotion in Alzheimer’s disease: A review of findings. Acta Neuropsychiatrica, 20(5), 236-250. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1601-5215.2008.00315.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meteyard, L., Zokaei, N., Bahrami, B., &amp; Vigliocco, G. (2008). Visual motion interferes with lexical decision on motion words. Current Biology, 18(17), R732-R733. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2008.07.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meteyard, L., Cuadrado, S. R., Bahrami, B., &amp; Vigliocco, G. (2012). Coming of age: A review of embodiment and the neuroscience of semantics. Cortex, 48(7), 788-804. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2010.11.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molenberghs, P., Brander, C., Mattingley, J. B., &amp; Cunnington, R. (2010). The role of the superior temporal sulcus and the mirror neuron system in imitation. Human Brain Mapping, 31(9), 1316-1326. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.20938</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molenberghs, P., Cunnington, R., &amp; Mattingley, J. B. (2012). Brain regions with mirror properties: A meta-analysis of 125 human fMRI studies. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 36(1), 341-349. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2011.07.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molnar-Szakacs, I., Iacoboni, M., Koski, L., &amp; Mazziotta, J. C. (2005). Functional segregation within pars opercularis of the inferior frontal gyrus: Evidence from fMRI studies of imitation and action observation. Cerebral Cortex, 15(7), 986-994. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhh199</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montgomery, K. J., Isenberg, N., &amp; Haxby, J. V. (2007). Communicative hand gestures and object-directed hand movements activated the mirror neuron system. Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience, 2(2), 114-122. https://doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsm004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moretti, D. V. (2016). Involvement of mirror neuron system in prodromal Alzheimer’s disease. BBA Clinical, 5, 46-53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbacli.2015.12.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moretti, D. V., Frisoni, G. B., Fracassi, C., Pievani, M., Geroldi, C., Binetti, G., … Zanetti, O. (2011). MCI patients’ EEGs show group differences between those who progress and those who do not progress to AD. Neurobiology of Aging, 32(4), 563-571. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2009.04.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrish, P. K., Sawle, G. V., &amp; Brooks, D. J. (1996). Regional changes in [18F]dopa metabolism in the striatum in Parkinson’s disease. Brain, 119(Pt 6), 2097-2103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moustafa, A. A., &amp; Poletti, M. (2013). Neural and behavioral substrates of subtypes of Parkinson’s disease. Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience, 7, 117. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2013.00117</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mukamel, R., Ekstrom, A. D., Kaplan, J., Iacoboni, M., &amp; Fried, I. (2010). Single-neuron responses in humans during execution and observation of actions. Current Biology, 20(8), 750-756. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2010.02.045</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muthukumaraswamy, S., &amp; Johnson, B. (2004). Changes in rolandic mu rhythm during observation of a precision grip. Psychophysiology, 41, 152-156. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1469-8986.2003.00129.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muthukumaraswamy, S., Johnson, B., &amp; McNair, N. (2004). Mu rhythm modulation during observation of an object-directed grasp. Cognitive Brain Research, 19, 195-201. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cogbrainres.2003.12.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nambu, A. (2004). A new dynamic model of the cortico-basal ganglia loop. In Progress in Brain Research (Vol. 143, pp. 461-466). Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelissen, K., Borra, E., Gerbella, M., Rozzi, M., Luppino, G., Vanduffel, W., … Orban, G. A. (2011). Action observation circuits in the macaque monkey cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 31(10), 3743-3756. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.4803-10.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niedermeyer, E., &amp; da Silva, F. (2005). Electroencephalography: Basic principles, clinical applications, and related fields (5th ed.). Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noe, A. (2004). Action in perception. Cambridge, MA: MIT press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nobis, L., Schindlbeck, K., Ehlen, F., Tiedt, H., Rewitzer, C., Duits, A. A., &amp; Klostermann, F. (2017). Theory of mind performance in Parkinson’s disease is associated with motor and cognitive functions, but not with symptom lateralization. Journal of Neural Transmission, 124(9), 1067-1072.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Northcutt, R. G. (2002). Understanding vertebrate brain evolution. Integrative and Comparative Biology, 42(4), 743-756. https://doi.org/10.1093/icb/42.4.743</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oztop, E., Kawato, M., &amp; Arbib, M. A. (2013). Mirror neurons: Functions, mechanisms and models. Neuroscience Letters, 540, 43-55. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2012.10.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel, M. (2017). Action observation in the modification of postural sway and gait: Theory and use in rehabilitation. Gait &amp; Posture, 58, 115-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gaitpost.2017.07.113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peelle, J. E., Powers, J., Cook, P. A., Smith, E. E., &amp; Grossman, M. (2014). Frontotemporal neural systems supporting semantic processing in Alzheimer’s disease. Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioural Neuroscience, 14(1), 37-48. https://doi.org/10.3758/s13415-013-0239-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peeters, R., Simone, L., Nelissen, K., Fabbri-Destro, M., Vanduffel, W., Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Orban, G. A. (2009). The representation of tool use in humans and monkeys: Common and uniquely human features. Journal of Neuroscience, 29, 11523-11539. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2040-09.2009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelosin, E., Avanzino, L., Bove, M., Stramesi, P., Nieuwboer, A., &amp; Abbruzzese, G. (2010). Action observation improves freezing of gait in patients with Parkinson’s disease. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair, 24(8), 746-752. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968310368685</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelosin, E., Bisio, A., Pozzo, T., Lagravinese, G., Crisafulli, O., Marchese, R., … Avanzino, L. (2018). Postural stabilization strategies to motor contagion induced by action observation are impaired in Parkinson’s disease. Frontiers in Neurology, 9, 105. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2018.00105</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelosin, E., Bove, M., Ruggeri, P., Avanzino, L., &amp; Abbruzzese, G. (2013). Reduction of bradykinesia of finger movements by a single session of action observation in Parkinson disease. Neurorehabilitation and Neural Repair, 27(6), 552-560. https://doi.org/10.1177/1545968312471905</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Péran, P., Cardebat, D., Cherubini, A., Piras, F., Luccichenti, G., Peppe, A., … Sabatini, U. (2009). Object naming and action-verb generation in Parkinson’s disease: A fMRI study. Cortex, 45, 960-971. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2009.02.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Péron, J., Dondaine, T., Le Jeune, F., Grandjean, D., &amp; Vérin, M. (2012). Emotional processing in Parkinson's disease: A systematic review. Movement Disorders, 27(2), 186-199. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.24025. Epub 2011 Dec 9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen, R. C., Doody, R., Kurz, A., Mohs, R. C., Morris, J. C., Rabins, P. V., … Winblad, B. (2001). Current concepts in mild cognitive impairment. Archives of Neurology, 58(12), 1985-1992. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.58.12.1985</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen, R. C., Lopez, O., Armstrong, M. J., Getchius, T. S. D., Ganguli, M., Gloss, D., … Rae-Grant, A. (2017). Practice guideline update summary: Mild cognitive impairment. Neurology, 90(3), 126-135. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000004826</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen, R. C., Smith, G. E., Waring, S. C., Ivnik, R. J., Tangalos, E. G., &amp; Kokmen, E. (1999). Mild cognitive impairment: Clinical characterization and outcome. Archives of Neurology, 56(3), 303-308. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.56.3.303</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson, D. S., Pickett, K. A., &amp; Earhart, G. M. (2012). Effects of levodopa on vividness of motor imagery in Parkinson disease. Journal of Parkinson's Disease, 2(2), 127-133. https://doi.org/10.3233/JPD-2012-12077</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfeifer, J. H., Iacoboni, M., Mazziotta, J. C., &amp; Dapretto, M. (2008). Mirroring others' emotions relates to empathy and interpersonal competence in children. NeuroImage, 39(4), 2076-2085. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.10.032</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pineda, J. A. (2005). EEG evidence for mirror neuron dysfunction in autism spectrum disorders. Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience, 24(2), 190-198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pineda, J. A., &amp; Hecht, E. (2009). Mirroring and mu rhythm involvement in social cognition: Are there dissociable subcomponents of theory of mind? Biological Psychology, 80(3), 306-314. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsycho.2008.11.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pohl, A., Anders, S., Chen, H., Patel, H. J., Heller, J., Reetz, K., … Binkofski, F. (2017). Impaired emotional mirroring in Parkinson’s disease-A study on brain activation during processing of facial expressions. Frontiers in Neurology, 8, 682. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2017.00682</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poliakoff, E., Galpin, A., Dick, J., Moore, P., &amp; Tipper, S. P. (2007). The effect of viewing graspable objects and actions in Parkinson’s disease. NeuroReport, 18(5), 483-487. https://doi.org/10.1097/wnr.0b013e32805867a1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pozzo, T., Inuggi, A., Keuroghlanian, A., Panzeri, S., Saunier, G., &amp; Campus, C. (2017). Natural translating locomotion modulates cortical activity at action observation. Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience, 11, 83. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsys.2017.0008300000000</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pulvermüller, F., Moseley, R. L., Egorova, N., Shebani, Z., &amp; Boulenger, V. (2014). Motor cognition-motor semantics: Action perception theory of cognition and communication. Neuropsychologia, 55, 71-84. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2013.12.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raina, P., Santaguida, P., Ismaila, A., Patterson, C., Cowan, D., Levine, M., … Oremus, M. (2008). Effectiveness of cholinesterase inhibitors and memantine for treating dementia: Evidence review for a clinical practice guideline. Annals of Internal Medicine, 148(5), 379-397. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-148-5-200803040-00009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramachandran, V. S., &amp; Altschuler, E. L. (2009). The use of visual feedback, in particular mirror visual feedback, in restoring brain function. Brain, 132(7), 1693-1710. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awp135</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rascovsky, K., Hodges, J. R., Knopman, D., Mendez, M. F., Kramer, J. H., Neuhaus, J., … Miller, B. L. (2011). Sensitivity of revised diagnostic criteria for the behavioural variant of frontotemporal dementia. Brain, 134(9), 2456-2477. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awr179</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rattanachayoto, P., Tritanon, O., Laothamatas, J., &amp; Sungkarat, W. (2012). Comparison of a mirror neuron system among elders with mild cognitive impairment, Alzheimer's disease, and no disease. In 6th Annual Scientific Meeting on Challenges of Quality Assurance in Radiation Medicine Abstracts (p. 122). Thailand.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricciardi, L., Visco-Comandini, F., Erro, R., Morgante, F., Bologna, M., Fasano, A., … Kilner, J. (2017). Facial emotion recognition and expression in Parkinson’s disease: An emotional mirror mechanism? PLoS ONE, 12(1), e0169110. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0169110</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G. (2005). The mirror neuron system and its function in humans. Anatomy and Embryology, 210(5-6), 419-421. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-005-0039-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Arbib, M. A. (1998). Language within our grasp. Trends in Neurosciences, 21(5), 188-194. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0166-2236(98)01260-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Craighero, L. (2004). The mirror-neuron system. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 27, 169-192. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.neuro.27.070203.144230</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G., Fadiga, L., Gallese, V., &amp; Fogassi, L. (1996). Premotor cortex and the recognition of motor actions. Cognitive Brain Research, 3, 131-141. https://doi.org/10.1016/0926-6410(95)00038-0)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Fogassi, L. (2014). The mirror mechanism: Recent findings and perspectives. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London. Series B, Biological Sciences, 369, 20130420. https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2013.0420</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G., Fogassi, L., &amp; Gallese, V. (2001). Neurophysiological mechanisms underlying the understanding and imitation of action. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 2(9), 661-670. https://doi.org/10.1038/35090060</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, K. M., Grossman, M., White-Devine, T., &amp; D'Esposito, M. (1996). Category-specific difficulty naming with verbs in Alzheimer's disease. Neurology, 47(1), 178-182. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.47.1.178</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodríguez-Ferreiro, J., Davies, R. A. I., González-Nosti, M., Barbón, A., &amp; Cuetos, F. (2009). Name agreement, frequency and age of acquisition, but not grammatical class, affect object and action naming in Spanish speaking participants with Alzheimer’s disease. Journal of Neurolinguistics, 22(1), 37-54. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroling.2008.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossor, M. (1992). Alzheimer's disease. Postgraduate Medical Journal, 68(801), 528-532. https://doi.org/10.1136/pgmj.68.801.528</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saimpont, A., Mourey, F., Manckoundia, P., Pfitzenmeyer, P., &amp; Pozzo, T. (2010). Aging affects the mental simulation/planning of the “rising from the floor” sequence. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 51(3), e41-e45. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2009.11.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saimpont, A., Pozzo, T., &amp; Papaxanthis, C. (2009). Aging affects the mental rotation of left and right hands. PLoS ONE, 4(8), e6714. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0006714</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saito, Y., Kubicki, M., Koerte, I., Otsuka, T., Rathi, Y., Pasternak, O., … Niznikiewicz, M. A. (2017). Impaired white matter connectivity between regions containing mirror neurons, and relationship to negative symptoms and social cognition, in patients with first-episode schizophrenia. Brain Imaging and Behavior, 12(1), 229-237. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11682-017-9685-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santamato, A., Ranieri, M., Cinone, N., Stuppiello, L. A., Valeno, G., De Sanctis, J. L., … Panza, F. (2015). Postural and balance disorders in patients with Parkinson’s disease: A prospective open-label feasibility study with two months of action observation treatment. Parkinson’s Disease, 2015, 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1155/2015/902738</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiavio, A., &amp; Altenmüller, E. (2015). Exploring music-based rehabilitation for Parkinsonism through embodied cognitive science. Frontiers in Neurology, 6, 2017. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2015.00217</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schilbach, L., Derntl, B., Aleman, A., Caspers, S., Clos, M., Diederen, K. M., … Eickhoff, S. B. (2016). Differential patterns of dysconnectivity in mirror neuron and mentalizing networks in schizophrenia. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 42(5), 1135-11148. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbw015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeter, M. L., Pawelke, S., Bisenius, S., Kynast, J., Schuemberg, K., Polyakova, M., … Jessen, F. (2018). A modified reading the mind in the eyes test predicts behavioral variant frontotemporal dementia better than executive function tests. Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience, 10, 11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sgandurra, G., Ferrari, A., Cossu, G., Guzzetta, A., Biagi, L., Tosetti, M., … Cioni, G. (2011). Upper limb children action-observation training (UP-CAT): A randomised controlled trial in Hemiplegic Cerebral Palsy. BMC Neurology, 11(1), 80. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2377-11-80</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shih, T.-Y., Wu, C.-Y., Lin, K.-C., Cheng, C.-H., Hsieh, Y.-W., Chen, C.-L., … Chen, C.-C. (2017). Effects of action observation therapy and mirror therapy after stroke on rehabilitation outcomes and neural mechanisms by MEG: Study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials, 18(1), 459. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-017-2205-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spada, G. (2012). La stimolazione del sistema mirror nei pazienti Alzheimer: effetti sul linguaggio (Dissertation). Università degli Studi di Modena e Reggio Emilia, Reggio Emilia (I).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sprengelmeyer, R., Young, A. W., Calder, A. J., Karnat, A., Lange, H., Hömberg, V., … Rowland, D. (1996). Loss of disgust: Perception of faces and emotions in Huntington's disease. Brain, 119(5), 1647-1665. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/119.5.1647</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefan, K., Cohen, L. G., Duque, J., Mazzocchio, R., Celnik, P., Sawaki, L., … Classen, J. (2005). Formation of a motor memory by action observation. Journal of Neuroscience, 25(41), 9339-9346. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.2282-05.2005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka, S., &amp; Inui, T. (2002). Cortical involvement for action imitation of hand/arm postures versus finger configurations: An fMRI study. NeuroReport, 13(13), 1599-1602. https://doi.org/10.1097/00001756-200209160-00005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teng, E., Lu, P. H., &amp; Cummings, J. L. (2007). Deficits in facial emotion processing in mild cognitive impairment. Dementia and Geriatric Cognitive Disorders, 23(4), 271-279. https://doi.org/10.1159/000100829</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tettamanti, M., Buccino, G., Saccuman, M. C., Gallese, V., Danna, M., Scifo, P., … Perani, D. (2005). Listening to action-related sentences activates fronto-parietal motor circuits. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 17, 273-281.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Theoret, H., &amp; Pascual-Leone, A. (2002). Language acquisition: Do as you hear. Current Biology, 12(21):R736-R737.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tremblay, F., Léonard, G., &amp; Tremblay, L. (2007). Corticomotor facilitation associated with observation and imagery of hand actions is impaired in Parkinson’s disease. Experimental Brain Research, 185(2), 249-257. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00221-007-1150-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trinkler, I., Devignevielle, S., Achaibou, A., Ligneul, R. V., Brugières, P., Cleret de Langavant, L., … Bachoud-Lévi, A. C. (2017). Embodied emotion impairment in Huntington's disease. Cortex, 92, 44-56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cortex.2017.02.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Umiltà, M. A., Kohler, E., Gallese, V., Fogassi, L., Fadiga, L., Keysers, C., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (2001). I know what you are doing: A neurophysiological study. Neuron, 31(1), 155-165. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(01)00337-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallet, G. T. (2015). Embodied cognition of aging. Frontiers in Psychology, 6, 463. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2015.00463</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallet, G. T., Hudon, C., Bier, N., Macoir, J., Versace, R., &amp; Simard, M. (2017). A semantic and episodic memory test (SEMEP) developed within the embodied cognition framework: Application to normal aging, Alzheimer's disease and semantic dementia. Frontiers in Psychology, 8, 1493. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.01493.eCollection</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vannuscorps, G., Dricot, L., &amp; Pillon, A. (2016). Persistent sparing of action conceptual processing in spite of increasing disorders of action production: A case against motor embodiment of action concepts. Cognitive Neuropsychology, 33(3-4), 191-219. https://doi.org/10.1080/02643294.2016.1186615</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verstraete, E., Veldink, J. H., van den Berg, L. H., &amp; van den Heuvel, M. P. (2013). Structural brain network imaging shows expanding disconnection of the motor system in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Human Brain Mapping, 35(4), 1351-1361. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.22258</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogt, S., Buccino, G., Wohlschläger, A. M., Canessa, N., Shah, N. J., Zilles, K., … Fink, G. R. (2007). Prefrontal involvement in imitation learning of hand actions: Effects of practice and expertise. NeuroImage, 37(4), 1371-1383. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2007.07.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, L., Larson, E. B., Bowen, J. D., &amp; van Belle, G. (2006). Performance-based physical function and future dementia in older people. Archives of Internal Medicine, 166(10), 1115. https://doi.org/10.1001/archinte.166.10.1115</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheeler, M. (2005). Reconstructing the cognitive world. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wicker, B., Keysers, C., Plailly, J., Royet, J.-P., Gallese, V., &amp; Rizzolatti, G. (2003). Both of us disgusted in my insula. Neuron, 40(3), 655-664. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0896-6273(03)00679-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamson, D. J., Adair, J. C., Raymer, A. M., &amp; Heilman, K. M. (1998). Object and action naming in Alzheimer's disease. Cortex, 34(4), 601-610. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0010-9452(08)70517-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, M. (2002). Six views of embodied cognition. Psychonomic Bulletin &amp; Review, 9(4), 625-636. https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03196322</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods, B., Aguirre, E., Spector, A. E., &amp; Orrell, M. (2012). Cognitive stimulation to improve cognitive functioning in people with dementia. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, (2). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.cd005562.pub2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan, J. H., Rountree, S., Massman, P., Doody, R. S., &amp; Li, H. (2008). Alzheimer's disease and mild cognitive impairment deteriorate fine movement control. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 42(14), 1203-1212. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2008.01.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yee, E., Chrysikou, E. G., Hoffman, E., &amp; Thompson-Schill, S. L. (2013). Manual experience shapes object representations. Psychological Science, 24(6), 909-919. https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797612464658</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>York, C., Olm, C., Boller, A., McCluskey, L., Elman, L., Haley, J., … Grossman, M. (2014). Action verb comprehension in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and Parkinson’s disease. Journal of Neurology, 261(6), 1073-1079. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-014-7314-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
