<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31985956</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK553163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339">Otoscope Exam</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mankowski</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas L.</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tulane University School of Medicine</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raggio</LastName><ForeName>Blake S.</ForeName><Initials>BS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Toronto</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Clinicians perform an otoscope exam to assess the condition of the external auditory canal (EAC), tympanic membrane (TM), and the middle ear.  Steps of the otoscope exam include inspecting the EAC and the TM with its identifying landmarks as outlined below. A pneumatic attachment is available to apply pressure to assess the mobility (i.e., compliance) of the tympanic membrane. Mastering the otoscope exam leads to accurate diagnoses, allowing for targeted treatment and prevention of complications. Early stages of otologic diseases can be present in the absence of complaints such as ear pain, ear fullness, and hearing loss; therefore, the otoscope should be part of all routine exams performed by primary care clinicians and not specific to otolaryngologists.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339" sec="article-27339.s1">Definition/Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339" sec="article-27339.s2">Issues of Concern</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339" sec="article-27339.s3">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339" sec="article-27339.s4">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Interventions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339" sec="article-27339.s5">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-27339" sec="article-27339.s6">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Niermeyer WL, Philips RHW, Essig GF, Moberly AC. Diagnostic accuracy and confidence for otoscopy: Are medical students receiving sufficient training? Laryngoscope. 2019 Aug;129(8):1891-1897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30329157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demir E, Topal S, Atsal G, Erdil M, Coskun ZO, Dursun E. Otologic Findings Based on no Complaints in a Pediatric Examination. Int Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2019 Jan;23(1):36-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6331296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30647782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang P, Pedler K. Ear examination--a practical guide. Aust Fam Physician. 2005 Oct;34(10):857-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16217573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szymanski A, Geiger Z.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Jul 26, Anatomy, Head and Neck, Ear.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eavey RD, Stool SE, Peckham GJ, Mitchell LR. How to examine the ear of the neonate. "Careful monitoring can recognize problems early". Clin Pediatr (Phila) 1976 Apr;15(4):338-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1253513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahid FI, Nagra SR. Incidence and characteristics of Traumatic Tympanic Membrane perforation. Pak J Med Sci. 2018 Sep-Oct;34(5):1099-1103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6191782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30344557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adegbiji WA, Olajide GT, Olajuyin OA, Olatoke F, Nwawolo CC. Pattern of tympanic membrane perforation in a tertiary hospital in Nigeria. Niger J Clin Pract. 2018 Aug;21(8):1044-1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30074009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins Joyce A, Raman M, Beaumont JL, Heiman H, Adler M, Schmidt SM. A survey comparison of educational interventions for teaching pneumatic otoscopy to medical students. BMC Med Educ. 2019 Mar 12;19(1):79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30866922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponka D, Baddar F. Pneumatic otoscopy. Can Fam Physician. 2013 Sep;59(9):962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3771724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24029512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbott P, Rosenkranz S, Hu W, Gunasekera H, Reath J. The effect and acceptability of tympanometry and pneumatic otoscopy in general practitioner diagnosis and management of childhood ear disease. BMC Fam Pract. 2014 Dec 12;15:181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4308896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25522872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onusko E. Tympanometry. Am Fam Physician. 2004 Nov 01;70(9):1713-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15554489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichichero ME. Acute otitis media: Part I. Improving diagnostic accuracy. Am Fam Physician. 2000 Apr 01;61(7):2051-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10779248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor JF. Otoscope fogging: examination finding for perforated tympanic membrane. BMJ Case Rep. 2014 May 30;2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24879720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michaudet C, Malaty J. Cerumen Impaction: Diagnosis and Management. Am Fam Physician. 2018 Oct 15;98(8):525-529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30277727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz SR, Magit AE, Rosenfeld RM, Ballachanda BB, Hackell JM, Krouse HJ, Lawlor CM, Lin K, Parham K, Stutz DR, Walsh S, Woodson EA, Yanagisawa K, Cunningham ER. Clinical Practice Guideline (Update): Earwax (Cerumen Impaction) Executive Summary. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2017 Jan;156(1):14-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28045632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danishyar A, Ashurst JV.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Mar 16, Acute Otitis Media.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barriga F, Schwartz RH, Hayden GF. Adequate illumination for otoscopy. Variations due to power source, bulb, and head and speculum design. Am J Dis Child. 1986 Dec;140(12):1237-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3776938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh N, Hoberman A, Kaleida PH, Ploof DL, Paradise JL. Videos in clinical medicine. Diagnosing otitis media--otoscopy and cerumen removal. N Engl J Med. 2010 May 20;362(20):e62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20484393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaikh N, Hoberman A, Rockette HE, Kurs-Lasky M. Development of an algorithm for the diagnosis of otitis media. Acad Pediatr. 2012 May-Jun;12(3):214-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22459064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pontefract B, Nevers M, Fleming-Dutra KE, Hersh A, Samore M, Madaras-Kelly K. Diagnosis and Antibiotic Management of Otitis Media and Otitis Externa in United States Veterans. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2019 Nov;6(11):ofz432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6837836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31723568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmes KM, Blackwood RA, Burrows HL, Cooke JM, Harrison RV, Passamani PP. Otitis media: diagnosis and treatment. Am Fam Physician. 2013 Oct 01;88(7):435-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24134083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emmett SD, Kokesh J, Kaylie D. Chronic Ear Disease. Med Clin North Am. 2018 Nov;102(6):1063-1079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30342609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifian MR, Mahmoudi M, Pourmomenarabi B, Keramati MR. Correlation between Allergic Rhinitis and Otitis Media with Effusion. Iran J Otorhinolaryngol. 2019 Jul;31(105):209-215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6666939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31384586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searight FT, Singh R, Peterson DC.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Aug 11, Otitis Media With Effusion.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osguthorpe JD, Nielsen DR. Otitis externa: Review and clinical update. Am Fam Physician. 2006 Nov 01;74(9):1510-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17111889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beers SL, Abramo TJ. Otitis externa review. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2004 Apr;20(4):250-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15057182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiegand S, Berner R, Schneider A, Lundershausen E, Dietz A. Otitis Externa. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2019 Mar 29;116(13):224-234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31064650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carfrae MJ, Kesser BW. Malignant otitis externa. Otolaryngol Clin North Am. 2008 Jun;41(3):537-49, viii-ix.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18435997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handzel O, Halperin D. Necrotizing (malignant) external otitis. Am Fam Physician. 2003 Jul 15;68(2):309-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12892351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy KL, Singh AK.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Jul 10, Middle Ear Cholesteatoma.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaacson G. Diagnosis of pediatric cholesteatoma. Pediatrics. 2007 Sep;120(3):603-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17766534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang P, Kim S. Cholesteatoma--diagnosing the unsafe ear. Aust Fam Physician. 2008 Aug;37(8):631-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18704212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plouin-Gaudon I, Bossard D, Ayari-Khalfallah S, Froehlich P. Fusion of MRIs and CT scans for surgical treatment of cholesteatoma of the middle ear in children. Arch Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2010 Sep;136(9):878-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20855680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coman M, Coman A, Gheorghe DC. All about Imagistic Exploration in Cholesteatoma. Maedica (Bucur) 2015 Jun;10(2):178-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5327812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28275415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott MC, Lundy LB. Tympanic membrane perforation in adults. How to manage, when to refer. Postgrad Med. 2001 Nov;110(5):81-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11727654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyewumi M, Brandt MG, Carrillo B, Atkinson A, Iglar K, Forte V, Campisi P. Objective Evaluation of Otoscopy Skills Among Family and Community Medicine, Pediatric, and Otolaryngology Residents. J Surg Educ. 2016 Jan-Feb;73(1):129-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26364889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly MJ, Quraishi MS, McShane DP. ENT and general practice: a study of paediatric ENT problems seen in general practice and recommendations for general practitioner training in ENT in Ireland. Ir J Med Sci. 1995 Jul-Sep;164(3):209-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7672936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu V, Sattar J, Cheon S, Beyea JA. Ear Disease Knowledge and Otoscopy Skills Transfer to Real Patients: A Randomized Controlled Trial. J Surg Educ. 2018 Jul - Aug;75(4):1062-1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29371080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>You P, Chahine S, Husein M. Improving learning and confidence through small group, structured otoscopy teaching: a prospective interventional study. J Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2017 Dec 28;46(1):68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29282128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31985956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
