<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">31985936</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK553143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530">Streptococcus Group B</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanna</LastName><ForeName>Morcos</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NYU-Winthrop University Hospital</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Noor</LastName><ForeName>Asif</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Winthrop University Hospital</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>The pathogen <i>Streptococcus agalactiae</i> represents group B <i>Streptococcus</i> (GBS)<i>.</i> The commonly used term of group B streptococcus or GBS is based on Lancefield grouping that takes into account specific cell wall carbohydrate antigen. It is a common colonizer of the genital and gastrointestinal tracts. GBS colonization in pregnant women is a major risk factor for neonatal and infant infection.  The widespread screening of pregnant women for this organism in the third trimester and subsequent antibiotic prophylaxis for maternal colonization has dramatically reduced the incidence of early-onset neonatal disease from 1.7 cases per 1000 live births in the early 1990s to 0.22 cases per 1000 live births in 2017. Direct medical costs of neonatal disease before prevention were $294 million annually. This chapter will discuss different aspects of GBS infection in neonates and infants and pregnant women and the elderly. <i>History:</i> Edmond Nocard first recognized this pathogen in 1887 as a source of bovine mastitis that resulted in agalactia or lack of milk production. Decades later, <i>S. agalactiae </i>gained recognition as a human pathogen responsible for infections, most commonly in pregnant women and newborns.<b> </b>However, the significance of this organism was not discovered until 1938, when Fry described three fatal cases of postpartum sepsis. Numerous reports continued to ascribe neonatal infections to this pathogen until the 1970s, when GBS emerged as the predominant organism causing bacteremia and meningitis in newborns and young infants less than three months old.<i> </i>GBS is also an occasional cause of infections in postpartum women (endometritis) and individuals with impaired immune systems, in whom the organism may cause septicemia or pneumonia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s10">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s11">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s12">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s13">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s14">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29530" sec="article-29530.s20">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Burcham LR, Spencer BL, Keeler LR, Runft DL, Patras KA, Neely MN, Doran KS. Determinants of Group B streptococcal virulence potential amongst vaginal clinical isolates from pregnant women. PLoS One. 2019;14(12):e0226699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6919605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31851721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng L, Xu FL, Niu M, Li WL, Xia L, Zhang YH, Xing JY. [Pathogens and clinical features of preterm infants with sepsis]. Zhongguo Dang Dai Er Ke Za Zhi. 2019 Sep;21(9):881-885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tevdorashvili G, Tevdorashvili D, Andghuladze M, Tevdorashvili M. Prevention and treatment strategy in pregnant women with group B streptococcal infection. Georgian Med News. 2015 Apr;(241):15-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25953932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Six A, Firon A, Plainvert C, Caplain C, Bouaboud A, Touak G, Dmytruk N, Longo M, Letourneur F, Fouet A, Trieu-Cuot P, Poyart C. Molecular Characterization of Nonhemolytic and Nonpigmented Group B Streptococci Responsible for Human Invasive Infections. J Clin Microbiol. 2016 Jan;54(1):75-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4702713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26491182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paoletti LC, Kasper DL. Surface Structures of Group B Streptococcus Important in Human Immunity. Microbiol Spectr. 2019 Mar;7(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30873933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi S, Aoyagi Y, Adderson EE, Okuwaki Y, Bohnsack JF. Capsular sialic acid limits C5a production on type III group B streptococci. Infect Immun. 1999 Apr;67(4):1866-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC96539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10085029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morinis J, Shah J, Murthy P, Fulford M. Horizontal transmission of group B streptococcus in a neonatal intensive care unit. Paediatr Child Health. 2011 Jun;16(6):e48-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3328229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22654550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardi A, Rossi C, Creti R, China M, Gherardi G, Venturelli C, Rumpianesi F, Ferrari F. Group B streptococcal colonization in 160 mother-baby pairs: a prospective cohort study. J Pediatr. 2013 Oct;163(4):1099-104.e1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23866714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berardi A, Spada C, Vaccina E, Boncompagni A, Bedetti L, Lucaccioni L. Intrapartum beta-lactam antibiotics for preventing group B streptococcal early-onset disease: can we abandon the concept of 'inadequate' intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis? Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2020 Jan;18(1):37-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31762370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristeva M, Tillman C, Goordeen A. Immunization Against Group B Streptococci vs. Intrapartum Antibiotic Prophylaxis in Peripartum Pregnant Women and their Neonates: A Review. Cureus. 2017 Oct 13;9(10):e1775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6017184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Francois Watkins LK, McGee L, Schrag SJ, Beall B, Jain JH, Pondo T, Farley MM, Harrison LH, Zansky SM, Baumbach J, Lynfield R, Snippes Vagnone P, Miller LA, Schaffner W, Thomas AR, Watt JP, Petit S, Langley GE. Epidemiology of Invasive Group B Streptococcal Infections Among Nonpregnant Adults in the United States, 2008-2016. JAMA Intern Med. 2019 Apr 01;179(4):479-488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30776079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nanduri SA, Petit S, Smelser C, Apostol M, Alden NB, Harrison LH, Lynfield R, Vagnone PS, Burzlaff K, Spina NL, Dufort EM, Schaffner W, Thomas AR, Farley MM, Jain JH, Pondo T, McGee L, Beall BW, Schrag SJ. Epidemiology of Invasive Early-Onset and Late-Onset Group B Streptococcal Disease in the United States, 2006 to 2015: Multistate Laboratory and Population-Based Surveillance. JAMA Pediatr. 2019 Mar 01;173(3):224-233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30640366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong SW, Barkham T, Kyaw WM, Ho HJ, Chan M. Characterisation of bone and joint infections due to Group B Streptococcus serotype III sequence type 283. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2018 Jul;37(7):1313-1317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Procianoy RS, Silveira RC. The challenges of neonatal sepsis management. J Pediatr (Rio J) 2020 Mar - Apr;96 Suppl 1:80-86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31747556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez M, Rench MA, Albanyan EA, Edwards MS, Baker CJ. Failure of rifampin to eradicate group B streptococcal colonization in infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2001 Apr;20(4):371-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11332660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prevention of Group B Streptococcal Early-Onset Disease in Newborns: ACOG Committee Opinion Summary, Number 782. Obstet Gynecol. 2019 Jul;134(1):1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31241596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31985936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
