<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">31994284</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-6984</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>55</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of language &amp; communication disorders</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Lang Commun Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Language, literacy and cognitive skills of young adults with developmental language disorder (DLD).</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>255</StartPage>
          <EndPage>265</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>255-265</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1460-6984.12518</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">There is limited evidence concerning the longer term language, literacy and cognitive skills of young adults with developmental language disorder (DLD). Studies that exist suggest continuing difficulties with language and reading, but abilities may change over time.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS">This study aimed to examine the language, literacy and cognitive skills of young adults with and without DLD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS &amp; PROCEDURES">Data were used from the Manchester Language Study data set which was collected from a group of young adults with DLD (recruited originally at 7 years of age from language units-specialist educational resource bases). Participants were assessed on their language, literacy and cognitive functioning when they were aged 24. A comparison group of age-matched peers (AMPs; also 24 years old) were also assessed. For language and cognition, change in scores between 16 and 24 years was also available for analysis. Finally, self-rated measures of literacy difficulties were taken at 24 years for functional reading and writing.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OUTCOME &amp; RESULTS">The results indicate that the young people with DLD in this sample continue to perform more poorly as a group on formal oral and written language tests. A small but significant minority of young adults with DLD also report functional reading and writing difficulties compared with AMPs despite reporting reading as often as their peer group. Compared with scores at 16 years of age, this subsample now appears to show slightly less risk of non-verbal IQ difficulties, showing small but significant 'catch-up' to AMPs.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS &amp; IMPLICATIONS">These preliminary data suggest that at least some individuals with DLD experience marked linguistic difficulties in adulthood, and that the pathways of language, literacy and cognition are not entirely parallel for this group. Continued support and awareness of challenges for young adults with DLD may be useful. What this paper adds What is already known on the subject It is known that DLD is long term and persists into adulthood. There has recently been a body of work reporting on the well-being of this population, as well as their employment, financial status and driving ability. However, there is very little information about language, literacy and cognitive skills beyond school age. What this paper adds to existing knowledge This study presents data on language, literacy and cognition from a large cohort of young adults with DLD and their AMPs. In this sample, a large proportion of participants score low on language, with fewer scoring as impaired on literacy and cognition. A significant minority reports difficulties in functional reading. Preliminary analysis appears to suggest that while language development remains depressed, non-verbal cognitive skills show some catch up over time. What are the potential or actual clinical implications of this work? Increased awareness and continued support for language, literacy and cognition may be useful for young adults with DLD.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Botting</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicola</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1082-9501</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Language and Communication Science Research, City University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Lang Commun Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9803709</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1368-2822</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007804" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Development</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007805" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Development Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000067010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Literacy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009483" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Developmental Language Disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">adults</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cognition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">literacy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">outcomes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31994284</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1460-6984.12518</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adlof, S. M. and Hogan, T. P., 2018, Understanding dyslexia in the context of developmental language disorders. Language, Speech, and Hearing Services in Schools, 49(4), 762-773.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkinson, L., Beitchman, J., Gonzalez, A., Young, A., Wilson, B., Escobar, M., Chisholm, V., Brownlie, E., Khoury, J. E., Ludmer, J. and Villani, V., 2015, Cumulative risk, cumulative outcome: A 20-year longitudinal study. PloS One, 10(6), e0127650.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bavin, E. L., Wilson, P. H., Maruff, P. and Sleeman, F., 2005, Spatio-visual memory of children with specific language impairment: evidence for generalized processing problems. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 40(3), 319-332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop, D. V., 2014, Ten questions about terminology for children with unexplained language problems. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 49(4), 381-415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop, D. V., Snowling, M. J., Thompson, P. A., Greenhalgh, T. and CATALISE-2 Consortium, 2017, Phase 2 of CATALISE: A multinational and multidisciplinary Delphi Consensus Study of problems with language development: Terminology. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 58(10), 1068-1080.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop, D. V. M. and Edmundson, A., 1987, Language-impaired 4-year-olds: Distinguishing transient from persistent impairment. Journal of Speech and Hearing Disorders, 52(2), 156-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N., 2005, Non-verbal cognitive development and language impairment. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 46(3), 317-326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N., Beauchamp-Whitworth, R., Chandwani, A., Gilbert, N., Holmes, A., Kranios, A., de Lemos, C., Pender, A. and Whitehouse, C., in preparation, Developmental Language Disorder in the workplace: A survey of general managers’ awareness (forthcoming).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2001, Non-word repetition and language development in children with specific language impairment (SLI). International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 36(4), 421-432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N., Durkin, K., Toseeb, U., Pickles, A. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2016b, Emotional health, support, and self-efficacy in young adults with a history of language impairment. British Journal of Developmental Psychology, 34(4), 538-554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N., Psarou, P., Caplin, T. and Nevin, L., 2013, Short-term memory skills in children with specific language impairment: The effect of verbal and nonverbal task content. Topics in Language Disorders, 33(4), 313-327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N., Simkin, Z. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2006, Associated reading skills in children with a history of specific language impairment (SLI). Reading and Writing, 19(1), 77-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botting, N., Toseeb, U., Pickles, A., Durkin, K. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2016a, Depression and anxiety change from adolescence to adulthood in individuals with and without language impairment. PloS One, 11(7), e0156678.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carroll, C. and Dockrell, J., 2012, Enablers and challenges of post-16 education and employment outcomes: the perspectives of young adults with a history of SLI. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 47(5), 567-577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catts, H. W., Fey, M. E., Tomblin, J. B. and Zhang, X., 2002, A longitudinal investigation of reading outcomes in children with language impairments. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 45(6), 1142-1157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clegg, J., Hollis, C., Mawhood, L. and Rutter, M., 2005, Developmental language disorders-a follow-up in later adult life. Cognitive, language and psychosocial outcomes. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 46(2), 128-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen, J., 1988, Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences, 2nd edn (Hillsdale, NJ: Lawrence Earlbaum Associates).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G., Botting, N. and Faragher, B., 2001a, Psycholinguistic markers for SLI. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 42(6), 741-748.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G., Botting, N. Simkin, Z. and Knox, E., 2001a, Follow-up of children attending infant language units: Outcomes at 11 years of age. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 36(2), 207-219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G., Durkin, K., Mok, P. L., Toseeb, U. and Botting, N., 2016, Health, employment and relationships: Correlates of personal wellbeing in young adults with and without a history of childhood language impairment. Social Science and Medicine, 160, 20-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G., Durkin, K. and Simkin, Z., 2010, Language and social factors in the use of cell phone technology by adolescents with and without specific language impairment (SLI). Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 53(1), 196-208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G., Durkin, K., Toseeb, U., Botting, N. and Pickles, A., 2018, Education and employment outcomes of young adults with a history of developmental language disorder. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 53(2), 237-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G., St Clair, M. C., Pickles, A. and Durkin, K., 2012, Developmental trajectories of verbal and nonverbal skills in individuals with a history of specific language impairment: From childhood to adolescence. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 55(6), 1716-1735.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Bree, E., Wijnen, F. and Gerrits, E., 2010, Non-word repetition and literacy in Dutch children at-risk of dyslexia and children with SLI: Results of the follow-up study. Dyslexia, 16(1), 36-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durkin, K., Conti-Ramsden, G. and Walker, A. J., 2011, Txt lang: Texting, textism use and literacy abilities in adolescents with and without specific language impairment. Journal of Computer Assisted Learning, 27(1), 49-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fidler, L. J., Plante, E. and Vance, R., 2011, Identification of adults with developmental language impairments. American Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 20(1), 2-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freed, J., Adams, C. and Lockton, E., 2011, Literacy skills in primary school-aged children with pragmatic language impairment: a comparison with children with specific language impairment. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 46(3), 334-347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry, L. A. and Botting, N., 2017, Working memory and developmental language impairments. Child Language Teaching and Therapy, 33(1), 19-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry, L. A., Messer, D. J. and Nash, G., 2012, Executive functioning in children with specific language impairment. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 53(1), 37-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hick, R. F., Botting, N. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2005, Short-term memory and vocabulary development in children with Down syndrome and children with specific language impairment. Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology, 47(8), 532-538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson, C. J., Beitchman, J. H. and Brownlie, E. B., 2010, Twenty-year follow-up of children with and without speech-language impairments: Family, educational, occupational, and quality of life outcomes. American Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 19(1), 51-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Just, M. A. and Carpenter, P. A., 1992, A capacity theory of comprehension: Individual differences in working memory. Psychological Review, 99, 122-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klem, M., Melby-Lervåg, M., Hagtvet, B., Lyster, S. A., Gustafsson, J. E. and Hulme, C., 2015, Sentence repetition is a measure of children's language skills rather than working memory limitations. Developmental Science, 18(1), 146-154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lancaster, H. S. and Camarata, S., 2019, Reconceptualizing developmental language disorder as a spectrum disorder: issues and evidence. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 54(1), 79-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Law, J., Rush, R., Schoon, I. and Parsons, S., 2009, Modelling developmental language difficulties from school entry into adulthood: Literacy, mental health, and employment outcomes. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 52, 1401-1416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loucas, T., Baird, G., Simonoff, E. and Slonims, V., 2016, Phonological processing in children with specific language impairment with and without reading difficulties. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 51(5), 581-588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lum, J. A., Conti-Ramsden, G., Page, D. and Ullman, M. T., 2012, Working, declarative and procedural memory in specific language impairment. Cortex, 48, 1138-1154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McClure, S. M., Botvinick, M. M., Yeung, N., Greene, J. D. and Cohen, J. D., 2007, Conflict monitoring in cognition-emotion competition. In J. Gross (ed.), Handbook of Emotion Regulation (New York: Guilford Press), pp. 204-226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marton, K., 2008, Visuo-spatial processing and executive functions in children with specific language impairment. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 43(2), 181-200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murray, L. L., Holland, A. L. and Beeson, P. M., 1997, Accuracy monitoring and task demand evaluation in aphasia. Aphasiology, 11(4-5), 401-414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myers, L. and Botting, N., 2008, Literacy in the mainstream inner-city school: Its relationship to spoken language. Child Language Teaching and Therapy, 24(1), 95-114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pickles, A., Durkin, K., Mok, P. L., Toseeb, U. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2016, Conduct problems co-occur with hyperactivity in children with language impairment: A longitudinal study from childhood to adolescence. Autism and Developmental Language Impairments, 1, 1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly, S., Tomblin, B., Law, J., McKean, C., Mensah, F. K., Morgan, A., Goldfeld, S., Nicholson, J. M. and Wake, M., 2014, Specific language impairment: A convenient label for whom? International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 49(4), 416-451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly, S., Wake, M., Ukoumunne, O. C., Bavin, E., Prior, M., Cini, E., Conway, L., Eadie, P. and Bretherton, L., 2010, Predicting language outcomes at 4 years of age: Findings from Early Language in Victoria study. Pediatrics, 126(6), e1530-e1537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott, W. C., Austin, D. W. and Reid, D. S., 2007, Investigation of the WISC-III and WASI in clinical child populations: A framework for further exploration. Canadian Journal of School Psychology, 22(2), 249-254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semel, E. M., Wiig, E. H. and Secord, W., 2006, CELF 4: Clinical Evaluation of Language Fundamentals-4 (London: PsychCorp).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snowling, M., Bishop, D. V. M. and Stothard, S. E., 2000, Is preschool language impairment a risk factor for dyslexia in adolescence? Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry and Allied Disciplines, 41(5), 587-600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snowling, M. J., Adams, J. W., Bishop, D. V. and Stothard, S. E., 2001, Educational attainments of school leavers with a preschool history of speech-language impairments. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 36(2), 173-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stothard, S. E., Snowling, M. J., Bishop, D. V., Chipchase, B. B. and Kaplan, C. A., 1998, Language-impaired preschoolers: A follow-up into adolescence. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 41(2), 407-418.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torgesen, J. K., Wagner, R. K. and Rashotte, C. A., 2012, TOWRE-2 Examiner's Manual (Austin, TX: PRO-ED).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullman, M. T. and Pierpont, E. I., 2005, Specific language impairment is not specific to language: The procedural deficit hypothesis. Cortex, 41(3), 399-433.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Washington, K. N., 2013, The association between expressive grammar intervention and social and emergent literacy outcomes for preschoolers with SLI. American Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 22(1), 113-125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wechsler, D., 1999, Manual for the Wechsler Abbreviated Intelligence Scale (WASI) (San Antonio, TX: Psychological Corp.).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitehouse, A. J., Line, E. A., Watt, H. J. and Bishop, D. V., 2009, Qualitative aspects of developmental language impairment relate to language and literacy outcome in adulthood. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 44(4), 489-510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winstanley, M., Webb, R. T. and Conti-Ramsden, G., 2018, More or less likely to offend? Young adults with a history of identified developmental language disorders. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 53(2), 256-270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
