<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32096326</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1545-5017</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>67 Suppl 3</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pediatric blood &amp; cancer</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Blood Cancer</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Assessment of nutritional status in children with cancer: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e28211</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e28211</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/pbc.28211</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>A child's appropriate development stems in large part from proper nutrition. Malnutrition is an adverse prognostic factor in children with cancer, and its prevalence is highly variable. Currently, there is no standardized definition and assessment method of nutritional status in pediatric oncology. A complete nutritional assessment includes anthropometry, biochemical, clinical, and dietary assessments. In this article, we explore these methods and suggest practical approaches for pediatric cancer units depending on the levels of care that these can provide. We also advise on the monitoring and follow-up of children with cancer during and after treatment, and discuss potential areas for future research.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Viani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karina</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9563-7255</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto de Tratamento do Câncer Infantil (ITACI), Instituto da Criança, Hospital das Clínicas, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de São Paulo, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Trehan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Hematology Oncology Unit, Advanced Pediatric Center, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manzoli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bianca</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto de Tratamento do Câncer Infantil (ITACI), Instituto da Criança, Hospital das Clínicas, Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de São Paulo, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schoeman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Judy</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Oncology Unit, Department of Pediatrics, Steve Biko Academic Hospital and University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Blood Cancer</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101186624</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1545-5009</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015362" MajorTopicYN="N">Child Nutrition Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015596" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutrition Assessment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">anthropometry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">levels of care</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">malnutrition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">nutritional assessment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pediatric oncology</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32096326</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pbc.28211</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Galindo C, Friedrich P, Alcasabas P, Antillon F, Banavali S, Castillo L, et al. Toward the cure of all children with cancer through collaborative efforts: pediatric oncology as a global challenge. J Clin Oncol. 2015;33:3065-3073.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antillon F, Rossi E, Molina AL, Sala A, Pencharz P, Valsecchi MG, et al. Nutritional status of children during treatment for acute lymphoblastic leukemia in Guatemala. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2013;60:911-915.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orgel E, Sposto R, Malvar J, Seibel NL, Ladas E, Gaynon PS, et al. Impact on survival and toxicity by duration of weight extremes during treatment for pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia: a report from the Children's Oncology Group. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32:1331-1337.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Israels T, Renner L, Hendricks M, Hesseling P, Howard S, Molyneux E. SIOP PODC: recommendations for supportive care of children with cancer in a low-income setting. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2013;60:899-904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers PC, Ladas EJ. The impact of nutritional status on outcomes: a neglected area of research. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2011;57:902-903.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells JCK. Using body composition assessment to evaluate the double burden of malnutrition. Ann Nutr Metab. 2019;75:103-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brinksma A, Sanderman R, Roodbol PF, Sulkers E, Burgerhof JG, de Bont ES, et al. Malnutrition is associated with worse health-related quality of life in children with cancer. Support Care Cancer. 2015;23:3043-3052.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sala A, Rossi E, Antillon F, Molina AL, de Maselli T, Bonilla M, et al. Nutritional status at diagnosis is related to clinical outcomes in children and adolescents with cancer: a perspective from Central America. Eur J Cancer. 2012;48:243-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joffe L, Dwyer S, Glade Bender JL, Frazier AL, Ladas EJ. Nutritional status and clinical outcomes in pediatric patients with solid tumors: a systematic review of the literature. Semin Oncol. 2019;46:48-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pribnow AK, Ortiz R, Baez LF, Mendieta L, Luna-Fineman S. Effects of malnutrition on treatment-related morbidity and survival of children with cancer in Nicaragua. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2017 Apr 27. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.26590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orgel E, Genkinger JM, Aggarwal D, Sung L, Nieder M, Ladas EJ. Association of body mass index and survival in pediatric leukemia: a meta-analysis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2016;103:808-817.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladas EJ, Sacks N, Meacham L, Henry D, Enriquez L, Lowry G, et al. A multidisciplinary review of nutrition considerations in the pediatric oncology population: a perspective from children's oncology group. Nutr Clin Pract. 2005;20:377-393.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauer J, Jurgens H, Fruhwald MC. Important aspects of nutrition in children with cancer. Adv Nutr. 2011;2:67-77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers PC. Nutritional status as a prognostic indicator for pediatric malignancies. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32:1293-1294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barr RD, Gomez-Almaguer D, Jaime-Perez JC, Ruiz-Arguelles GJ. Importance of nutrition in the treatment of leukemia in children and adolescents. Arch Med Res. 2016;47:585-592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladas EJ, Arora B, Howard SC, Rogers PC, Mosby TT, Barr RD. A framework for adapted nutritional therapy for children with cancer in low- and middle-income countries: a report From the SIOP PODC Nutrition Working Group. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2016;63:1339-1348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Secker DJ, Jeejeebhoy KN. Subjective global nutritional assessment for children. Am J Clin Nutr. 2007;85:1083-1089.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy AJ, White M, Viani K, Mosby TT. Evaluation of the nutrition screening tool for childhood cancer (SCAN). Clin Nutr. 2016;35:219-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO Multicentre Growth Reference Study Group. WHO Child Growth Standards: Length/Height-for-Age, Weight-for-Age, Weight-for-Length, Weight-for-Height and Body Mass Index-for-Age: Methods and Development. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2006. 312 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, World food programme. A Manual: Measuring and Interpreting Malnutrition and Mortality. Rome: World Food Programme Nutrition Service, 2005. 232 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barr RD. Nutritional status in children with cancer: before, during and after therapy. Indian J Cancer. 2015;52:173-175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barr R, Collins L, Nayiager T, Doring N, Kennedy C, Halton J, et al. Nutritional status at diagnosis in children with cancer. 2. An assessment by arm anthropometry. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2011;33:e101-104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lifson LF, Hadley GP, Wiles NL, Pillay K. Nutritional status of children with Wilms' tumour on admission to a South African hospital and its influence on outcome. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2016 Dec 27. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.26382.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF) WHO, International Bank for Reconstruction and Development/The World Bank. Levels and Trends in Child Malnutrition: Key Findings of the 2019 Edition of the Joint Child Malnutrition Estimates. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization &amp; United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF). WHO Child Growth Standards and the Identification of Severe Acute Malnutrition in Infants and Children: Joint Statement by the World Health Organization and the United Nations Children's Fund. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frisancho AR. Anthropometric Standards for the Assessment of Growth and Nutritional Status. Ann Arbor: University of Michigan Press; 1990:189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joffe L, Schadler KL, Shen W, Ladas EJ. Body composition in pediatric solid tumors: state of the science and future directions. J Natl Cancer Inst Monogr. 2019;2019:144-148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy AJ, White M, Davies PS. Body composition of children with cancer. Am J Clin Nutr. 2010;92:55-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kyle UG, Bosaeus I, De Lorenzo AD, Deurenberg P, Elia M, Manuel Gomez J, et al. Bioelectrical impedance analysis-part II: utilization in clinical practice. Clin Nutr. 2004;23:1430-1453.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maqbool A, Olsen I, Stallings V. Clinical assessment of nutritional status. In: Duggan C, ed. Nutrition in Pediatrics. Ontario: Hamilton; 2008:5-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy AJ, White M, Davies PS. The validity of simple methods to detect poor nutritional status in paediatric oncology patients. Br J Nutr. 2009;101:1388-1392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers PC, Schoeman J. Nutritional assessment and intervention. In: Stefan DC, Rodriguez-Gallindo C, eds. Pediatric Hematology-Oncology in Countries with Limited Resources. New York: Springer; 2014:91-112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Management of Severe Malnutrition: a Manual for Physicians and Other Senior Health Workers. Geneva: World Health Organization; 1999. 60 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashworth A, Khanum S, Jackson A, Schofield C. Guidelines for the Inpatient Treatment of Severely Malnourished Children. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyu QY, Kong SK, Wong FK, You LM. Validation of Hospitalization Impact Scale among families with children hospitalized for cancer treatment. J Adv Nurs. 2015;71:1958-1969.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoeman J. Nutritional assessment and intervention in a pediatric oncology unit. Indian J Cancer. 2015;52:186-190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maqbool A, Olsen I, Stallings V. Clinical Assessment of Nutritional Status. Ontario: Hamilton; 2008:5-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trumbo P, Schlicker S, Yates AA, Poos M. Dietary reference intakes for energy, carbohydrate, fiber, fat, fatty acids, cholesterol, protein and amino acids. J Am Diet Assoc. 2002;102:1621-1630.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazak AE, Hocking MC, Ittenbach RF, Meadows AT, Hobbie W, DeRosa BW, et al. A revision of the intensity of treatment rating scale: classifying the intensity of pediatric cancer treatment. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2012;59:96-99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen JE, Wakefield CE, Cohn RJ. Nutritional interventions for survivors of childhood cancer. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016:Cd009678.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang FF, Kelly MJ, Saltzman E, Must A, Roberts SB, Parsons SK. Obesity in pediatric ALL survivors: a meta-analysis. Pediatrics. 2014;133:e704-715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown AL, Lupo PJ, Danysh HE, Okcu MF, Scheurer ME, Kamdar KY. Prevalence and predictors of overweight and obesity among a multiethnic population of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia survivors: a cross-sectional assessment. J Pediatr Hematol Oncol. 2016;38:429-436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pluimakers VG, van Waas M, Neggers S, van den Heuvel-Eibrink MM. Metabolic syndrome as cardiovascular risk factor in childhood cancer survivors. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2019;133:129-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostoufi-Moab S, Ward LM. Skeletal morbidity in children and adolescents during and following cancer therapy. Horm Res Paediatr. 2019;91:137-151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choudhary A, Chou J, Heller G, Sklar C. Prevalence of vitamin D insufficiency in survivors of childhood cancer. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2013;60:1237-1239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosen GP, Beebe KL, Shaibi GQ. Vitamin D levels differ by cancer diagnosis and decline over time in survivors of childhood cancer. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2013;60:949-952.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang FF, Kelly MJ, Must A. Early nutrition and physical activity interventions in childhood cancer survivors. Curr Obes Rep. 2017;6:168-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Waist Circumference and Waist-Hip Ratio: Report of a WHO Expert Consultation. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlage RE, Wilson CL, Zhang N, Kaste S, Green DM, Armstrong GT, et al. Validity of anthropometric measurements for characterizing obesity among adult survivors of childhood cancer: a report from the St. Jude Lifetime Cohort Study. Cancer. 2015;121:2036-2043.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Obesity: Preventing and Managing the Global Epidemic: Report of a WHO Consultation. Geneva: World Health Organization; 2000. 252 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andaki ACR, Quadros TMB, Gordia AP, Mota J, Tinoco ALA, Mendes EL. Skinfold reference curves and their use in predicting metabolic syndrome risk in children. J Pediatr (Rio J). 2017;93:490-496.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens J, Waters R, Sieniawska C, Kassam S, Montoto S, Fitzgibbon J, et al. Serum selenium concentration at diagnosis and outcome in patients with haematological malignancies. Br J Haematol. 2011;154:448-456.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy Moulik N, Kumar A, Agrawal S, Mahdi AA. Folate deficiency in north Indian children undergoing maintenance chemotherapy for acute lymphoblastic leukemia-Implications and outcome. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2017 Aug 2. https://doi.org/10.1002/pbc.26730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sermet-Gaudelus I, Poisson-Salomon AS, Colomb V, Brusset MC, Mosser F, Berrier F, et al. Simple pediatric nutritional risk score to identify children at risk of malnutrition. Am J Clin Nutr. 2000;72:64-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarthy H, Dixon M, Crabtree I, Eaton-Evans MJ, McNulty H. The development and evaluation of the Screening Tool for the Assessment of Malnutrition in Paediatrics (STAMP(c)) for use by healthcare staff. J Hum Nutr Diet. 2012;25:311-318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hulst JM, Zwart H, Hop WC, Joosten KF. Dutch national survey to test the STRONGkids nutritional risk screening tool in hospitalized children. Clin Nutr. 2010;29:106-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kussmann M, Affolter M. Proteomics at the center of nutrigenomics: comprehensive molecular understanding of dietary health effects. Nutrition. 2009;25:1085-1093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sales NM, Pelegrini PB, Goersch MC. Nutrigenomics: definitions and advances of this new science. J Nutr Metab. 2014 Mar 25. https://doi.org/10.1155/2014/202759.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiffon C. The impact of nutrition and environmental epigenetics on human health and disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19:E3425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazzio EA, Soliman KF. Epigenetics and nutritional environmental signals. Integr Comp Biol. 2014;54:21-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McQuade JL, Daniel CR, Helmink BA, Wargo JA. Modulating the microbiome to improve therapeutic response in cancer. Lancet Oncol. 2019;20:e77-e91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Co-Reyes E, Li R, Huh W, Chandra J. Malnutrition and obesity in pediatric oncology patients: causes, consequences, and interventions. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2012;59:1160-1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selwood K, Ward E, Gibson F. Assessment and management of nutritional challenges in children's cancer care: a survey of current practice in the United Kingdom. Eur J Oncol Nurs. 2010;14:439-446.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerasimidis K, Keane O, Macleod I, Flynn DM, Wright CM. A four-stage evaluation of the Paediatric Yorkhill Malnutrition Score in a tertiary paediatric hospital and a district general hospital. Br J Nutr. 2010;104:751-756.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
