<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">32149846</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3708</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>85</Volume>
            <Issue>S1 Suppl 1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of plastic surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Plast Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Submuscular Placement of Baclofen Infusion Pumps: Case Series and Technique.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>S8</StartPage>
          <EndPage>S11</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>S8-S11</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SAP.0000000000002347</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Baclofen pumps provide treatment of symptoms of spasticity for disease processes such as cerebral palsy and traumatic brain injury. These devices provide continuous infusion or periodic dosing of intrathecal baclofen (ITB). Traditionally, these pumps have been placed subcutaneously. Subcutaneous device placement has been associated with infection and extrusion. Baclofen pumps are large and range from 8 to 10 cm in diameter and 4 to 8 cm in width. Patients requiring device placement typically have a paucity of subcutaneous tissue. Cachexia coupled with the size and bulk of these devices leads to increased protusion and friction. Submuscular placement provides a well-vascularized pocket that directs the device inward eliminating protrusion and decreasing the potential for soft tissue breakdown.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective chart review of ITB pump placement in a submuscular plane by a single plastic surgeon at a major academic center in conjunction with a neurosurgeon was performed. Inclusion criteria were cases of primary placement or replacement of ITB pumps and spasticity requiring ITB. Major complications included infection, extrusion, and reoperation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Five patients during a 5-month period were treated with submuscular placement of ITB pumps. Average age of patients included was 18.4 years. Average preoperative body mass index was 18.8 kg/m, with values ranging from 15.8 to 20.1 kg/m. Medical histories of patients included diagnoses of cerebral palsy and traumatic brain injury causing spasticity. The most frequently cited reason for plastic surgical consultation preoperatively was cachexia. Two patients had previous baclofen pumps placed subcutaneously. Average follow-up was 6 months and ranged from 3 to 13 months. There were no major complications. One patient had a small seroma that spontaneously resolved. No patient had wound healing problems, and there were no extrusions of implanted devices or reoperations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Submuscular placement of baclofen pumps provides a well-vascularized and stable environment for device placement that minimizes the dangers of pump extrusion and infection. Patients who require treatment with ITB commonly have severe cachexia, which makes subcutaneous device placement high risk. Submuscular placement should be performed in all patients with body mass index less than 20 kg/m.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bogue</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jarrod T</ForeName>
            <Initials>JT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Surgery, Division of Plastic Surgery.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wald</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gal</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Surgery, Division of Plastic Surgery.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Iosim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sonia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Surgery, Division of Plastic Surgery.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Greenfield</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeffrey P</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurological Surgery, Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, NY.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Otterburn</LastName>
            <ForeName>David M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Surgery, Division of Plastic Surgery.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Plast Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7805336</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-7043</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D009125">Muscle Relaxants, Central</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>H789N3FKE8</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001418">Baclofen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001418" MajorTopicYN="Y">Baclofen</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007260" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusion Pumps</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015918" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusion Pumps, Implantable</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007278" MajorTopicYN="N">Injections, Spinal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009125" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Relaxants, Central</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32149846</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SAP.0000000000002347</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00000637-202007001-00003</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaupmann K, Schuler V, Mosbacher J, et al. Human gamma-aminobutyric acid type B receptors are differentially expressed and regulate inwardly rectifying K+ channels. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1998;95:14991–14996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krach LE. Pharmacotherapy of spasticity: oral medications and intrathecal baclofen. J Child Neurol. 2001;16:31–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCormick ZL, Chu SK, Binler D, et al. Intrathecal versus oral baclofen: a matched cohort study of spasticity, pain, sleep, fatigue, and quality of life. PM R. 2016;8:553–562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilmartin R, Bruce D, Storrs BB, et al. Intrathecal baclofen for management of spastic cerebral palsy: multicenter trial. J Child Neurol. 2000;15:71–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coffey JR, Cahill D, Steers W, et al. Intrathecal baclofen for intractable spasticity of spinal origin: results of a long-term multicenter study. J Neurosurg. 1993;78:226–232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brennan PM, Whittle IR. Intrathecal baclofen therapy for neurological disorders: a sound knowledge base but many challenges remain. Br J Neurosurg. 2008;22:508–519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vender JR, Hester S, Waller JL, et al. Identification and management of intrathecal baclofen pump complications: a comparison of pediatric and adult patients. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2006;104:9–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woolf SM, Baum CR. Baclofen pumps: uses and complications. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2017;33:271–275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh D, Mainali G, Khera J, et al. Complications of intrathecal baclofen pumps in children: experience from a tertiary care center. Pediatr Neurosurg. 2013;49:138–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borowski A, Littleton AG, Borkhuu B, et al. Complications of intrathecal baclofen pump therapy in pediatric patients. J Pediatr Orthop. 2010;30:76–81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albright AL, Turner M, Pattisapu JV. Best-practice surgical techniques for intrathecal baclofen therapy. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2006;104:233–239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopell BH, Sala D, Doyle WK, et al. Subfascial implantation of intrathecal baclofen pumps in children: technical note. Neurosurgery. 2001;49:753–756.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
