<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">32239567</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-3083</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>34</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology : JEADV</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Onychomycosis: a review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1972</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1990</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1972-1990</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jdv.16394</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Onychomycosis is a fungal infection of the nail, causing discoloration and thickening of the affected nail plate, and is the most common nail infection worldwide. Onychomycosis was initially thought to be predominantly caused by dermatophytes; however, new research has revealed that mixed infections and those caused by non-dermatophyte moulds (NDMs) are more prevalent than previously thought, especially in warmer climates. Microscopy and fungal culture are the gold standard techniques for onychomycosis diagnosis, but high false-negative rates have pushed for more accurate methods, such as histology and PCR. As NDMs are skin and laboratory contaminants, their presence as an infectious agent requires multiple confirmations and repeated sampling. There are several treatment options available, including oral antifungals, topicals and devices. Oral antifungals have higher cure rates and shorter treatment periods than topical treatments, but have adverse side effects such as hepatotoxicity and drug interactions. Terbinafine, itraconazole and fluconazole are most commonly used, with new oral antifungals such as fosravuconazole being evaluated. Topical treatments, such as efinaconazole, tavaborole, ciclopirox and amorolfine have less serious side effects, but also have generally lower cure rates and much longer treatment regimens. New topical formulations are being investigated as faster-acting alternatives to the currently available topical treatments. Devices such as lasers have shown promise in improving the cosmetic appearance of the nail, but due to a high variation of study methods and definitions of cure, their effectiveness for onychomycosis has yet to be sufficiently proven. Recurrence rates for onychomycosis are high; once infected, patients should seek medical treatment as soon as possible and sanitize their shoes and socks. Prophylactic application of topicals and avoiding walking barefoot in public places may help prevent recurrence.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gupta</LastName>
            <ForeName>A K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8664-7723</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stec</LastName>
            <ForeName>N</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Summerbell</LastName>
            <ForeName>R C</ForeName>
            <Initials>RC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sporometrics, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dalla Lana School of Public Health, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shear</LastName>
            <ForeName>N H</ForeName>
            <Initials>NH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9151-1145</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Sunnybrook Health Sciences Centre, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Piguet</LastName>
            <ForeName>V</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Women's College Hospital, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tosti</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Cutaneous Surgery, Leonard Miller School of Medicine, University of Miami, Miami, FL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Piraccini</LastName>
            <ForeName>B M</ForeName>
            <Initials>BM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Unit, Department of Experimental, Diagnostic and Specialty Medicine, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9216037</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0926-9959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>304NUG5GF4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017964">Itraconazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>8VZV102JFY</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015725">Fluconazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>G7RIW8S0XP</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077291">Terbinafine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000287" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Topical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015725" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluconazole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017964" MajorTopicYN="N">Itraconazole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014009" MajorTopicYN="Y">Onychomycosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077291" MajorTopicYN="N">Terbinafine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32239567</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.16394</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlahovic TC. Onychomycosis. Clin Podiatr Med Surg 2016; 33: 305-318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Charif MA. Prevalence of onychomycosis in patients attending a dermatology clinic in northeastern Ohio for other conditions. Arch Dermatol 1997; 133: 1172-1173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vasconcellos C, Pereira CQM, Souza MC, Pelegrini A, Freitas RS, Takahashi JP. Identification of fungi species in the onychomycosis of institutionalized elderly. An Bras Dermatol 2013; 88: 377-380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Jain HC, Lynde CW, Watteel GN, Summerbell RC. Prevalence and epidemiology of unsuspected onychomycosis in patients visiting dermatologists' offices in Ontario, Canada-a multicenter survey of 2001 patients. Int J Dermatol 1997; 36: 783-787.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK. Onychomycosis in the elderly. Drugs Aging 2000; 16: 397-407.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Gupta G, Jain HC et al. The prevalence of unsuspected onychomycosis and its causative organisms in a multicentre Canadian sample of 30 000 patients visiting physicians' offices. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol JEADV 2016; 30: 1567-1572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE. Onychomycosis: pathogenesis, diagnosis, and management. Clin Microbiol Rev 1998; 11: 415-429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A, Lynde CW, Jain HC et al. A higher prevalence of onychomycosis in psoriatics compared with non-psoriatics: a multicentre study. Br J Dermatol 1997; 136: 786-789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klaassen KMG, Dulak MG, van de Kerkhof PCM, Pasch MC. The prevalence of onychomycosis in psoriatic patients: a systematic review. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2014; 28: 533-541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piérard G. Onychomycosis and other superficial fungal infections of the foot in the elderly: a pan-European survey. Dermatology 2001; 202: 220-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Konnikov N, MacDonald P et al. Prevalence and epidemiology of toenail onychomycosis in diabetic subjects: a multicentre survey. Br J Dermatol. 1998; 139: 665-671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Gupta MA, Summerbell RC et al. The epidemiology of onychomycosis: possible role of smoking and peripheral arterial disease. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2000; 14: 466-469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Taborda P, Taborda V et al. Epidemiology and prevalence of onychomycosis in HIV-positive individuals. Int J Dermatol 2000; 39: 746-753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams C, Athanasoula E, Lee W, Mahmudova N, Vlahovic TC. Environmental and genetic factors on the development of onychomycosis. J Fungi 2015; 1: 211-216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG, Shear NH. A practical application of onychomycosis cure - combining patient, physician and regulatory body perspectives. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2018; 33: 281-287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faergemann J, Correia O, Nowicki R, Ro B-I. Genetic predisposition-understanding underlying mechanisms of onychomycosis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol JEADV. 2005; 19(Suppl 1): 17-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG, Shear NH, Piguet V, Tosti A, Piraccini BM. A practical guide to curing onychomycosis: how to maximize cure at the patient, organism, treatment, and environmental level. Am J Clin Dermatol 2019; 20: 123-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Augustin M, Radtke MA, Herberger K, Kornek T, Heigel H, Schaefer I. Prevalence and disease burden of hyperhidrosis in the adult population. Dermatology 2013; 227: 10-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum MA, Hajjeh RA, Scher R et al. A large-scale North American study of fungal isolates from nails: the frequency of onychomycosis, fungal distribution, and antifungal susceptibility patterns. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 43: 641-648.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R ed. Baran &amp; Dawber's Diseases of the Nails and their Management, 5th edn. Wiley-Blackwell, Hoboken, NJ, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Svejgaard EL, Nilsson J. Onychomycosis in Denmark: prevalence of fungal nail infection in general practice. Mycoses 2004; 47: 131-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Summerbell RC, Gueidan C, Guarro J et al. The protean Acremonium. A. sclerotigenum/egyptiacum: revision, food contaminant, and human disease. Microorganisms 2018; 6: 88. https://doi.org/10.3390/microorganisms6030088.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sergeev AY, Ivanov OL, Sergeev YV et al. Epidemiology of onychomycosis in modern Russia: incidence is growing. Mycoses 2002; 45(S2): 56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burzykowski T, Molenberghs G, Abeck D et al. High prevalence of foot diseases in Europe: results of the Achilles Project. Mycoses 2003; 46: 496-505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ioannidou DJ, Maraki S, Krasagakis SK, Tosca A, Tselentis Y. The epidemiology of onychomycoses in Crete, Greece, between 1992 and 2001. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2006; 20: 170-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vélez A, Linares MJ, Fenández-Roldán JC, Casal M. Study of onychomycosis in Córdoba, Spain: prevailing fungi and pattern of infection. Mycopathologia 1997; 137: 1-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsh O, Vera-Cabrera L, Welsh E. Onychomycosis. Clin Dermatol 2010; 28: 151-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Mays RR, Versteeg SG et al. Global perspectives for the management of onychomycosis. Int J Dermatol 2019; 58: 1118-1129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranawaka RR, Nagahawatte A, Gunasekara TA, Weerakoon HS, de Silva SHP. Randomized, double-blind, comparative study on efficacy and safety of itraconazole pulse therapy and terbinafine pulse therapy on nondermatophyte mold onychomycosis: a study with 90 patients. J Dermatol Treat 2016; 27: 364-372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghavendra KR, Yadav D, Kumar A, Sharma M, Bhuria J, Chand AE. The nondermatophyte molds: emerging as leading cause of onychomycosis in south-east Rajasthan. Indian Dermatol Online J 2015; 6: 92-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rafat Z, Hashemi SJ, Saboor-Yaraghi A-A et al. A systematic review and meta-analysis on the epidemiology, casual agents and demographic characteristics of onychomycosis in Iran. J Mycol Medicale 2019; 29: 265-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vander Straten MR, Balkis MM, Ghannoum MA. The role of nondermatophyte molds in onychomycosis: diagnosis and treatment. Dermatol Ther 2002; 15: 89-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno G, Arenas R. Other fungi causing onychomycosis. Clin Dermatol 2010; 28: 160-163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salakshna N, Bunyaratavej S, Matthapan L, Lertrujiwanit K, Leeyaphan C. A cohort study of risk factors, clinical presentations and outcomes for dermatophyte, non-dermatophyte and mixed toenail infections. J Am Acad Dermatol 2018; 79: 1145-1146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebihara M, Makimura K, Sato K, Abe S, Tsuboi R. Molecular detection of dermatophytes and nondermatophytes in onychomycosis by nested polymerase chain reaction based on 28S ribosomal RNA gene sequences. Br J Dermatol 2009; 161: 1038-1044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A, Nakrieko K-A. Molecular determination of mixed infections of dermatophytes and nondermatophyte moulds in individuals with onychomycosis. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2014; 104: 330-336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Drummond-Main C, Cooper EA, Brintnell W, Piraccini BM, Tosti A. Systematic review of nondermatophyte mold onychomycosis: diagnosis, clinical types, epidemiology, and treatment. J Am Acad Dermatol 2012; 66: 494-502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Foley KA. Evidence for biofilms in onychomycosis. G Ital Dermatol Venereol 2019; 154: 50-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Daigle D, Carviel JL. The role of biofilms in onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol 2016; 74: 1241-1246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramage G, Mowat E, Jones B, Williams C, Lopez-Ribot J. Our current understanding of fungal biofilms. Crit Rev Microbiol 2009; 35: 340-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kernien JF, Snarr BD, Sheppard DC, Nett JE. The interface between fungal biofilms and innate immunity. Front Immunol 2017; 8: 1968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borghi E, Borgo F, Morace G. Fungal biofilms: update on resistance. Adv Microbiol Infect Dis Public Health 2016; 3: 37-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramage G, Rajendran R, Sherry L, Williams C. Fungal biofilm resistance. Int J Microbiol 2012; 2012: 528521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Onychomycosis: diagnosis and therapy. In Razzaghi-Abyaneh M, M Shams-Ghahfarokhi M, Rai, eds. Medical Mycology: Current Trends and Future Prospects. CRC Press, Boca Raton, FL, 2015; 28-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Onychomycosis: current and investigational therapies. Cutis 2014; 94: E21-E24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Evaluation of nail lines: color and shape hold clues. Cleve Clin J Med 2016; 83: 385-391.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Ryder JE, Baran R, Summerbell RC. Non-dermatophyte onychomycosis. Dermatol Clin 2003; 21: 257-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM, Lorenzi S. Onychomycosis caused by nondermatophytic molds: clinical features and response to treatment of 59 cases. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 42(2 Pt 1): 217-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG, Shear NH. Confirmatory testing prior to initiating onychomycosis therapy is cost-effective. J Cutan Med Surg 2018; 22: 129-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Simpson FC. Diagnosing onychomycosis. Clin Dermatol 2013; 31: 540-543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>English MP. Nails and fungi. Br J Dermatol 1976; 94: 697-701.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Davidovici B, Grunwald MH, Trau H, Amichai B. New criteria for the laboratory diagnosis of nondermatophyte moulds in onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2009; 160: 37-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA, MacDonald P, Summerbell RC. Utility of inoculum counting (Walshe and English criteria) in clinical diagnosis of onychomycosis caused by nondermatophytic filamentous fungi. J Clin Microbiol 2001; 39: 2115-2121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Jain HC, Lynde CW, Macdonald P, Cooper EA, Summerbell RC. Prevalence and epidemiology of onychomycosis in patients visiting physicians' offices: a multicenter canadian survey of 15,000 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 43(2 Pt 1): 244-248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bock M, Maiwald M, Kappe R, Nickel P, Näher H. Polymerase chain reaction-based detection of dermatophyte DNA with a fungus-specific primer system. Mycoses 1994; 37: 79-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verrier J, Monod M. Diagnosis of dermatophytosis using molecular biology. Mycopathologia 2017; 182: 193-202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arrese JE, Piérard-Franchimont C, Greimers R, Piérard GE. Fungi in onychomycosis. A study by immunohistochemistry and dual flow cytometry. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 1995; 4: 123-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Balestri R, Starace M, Rech G. Nail digital dermoscopy (Onychoscopy) in the diagnosis of onychomycosis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2013; 27: 509-513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdallah NA, Said M, Mahmoud MT, Omar MA. Onychomycosis: correlation between the dermoscopic patterns and fungal culture. J Cosmet Dermatol 2019. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocd.13144 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Crignis G, Valgas N, Rezende P, Leverone A, Nakamura R. Dermatoscopy of onychomycosis. Int J Dermatol 2014; 53: e97-e99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maatouk I, Haber R, Benmehidi N. Onychoscopic evaluation of distal and lateral subungual onychomycosis: a cross-sectional study in Lebanon. Curr Med Mycol 2019; 5: 41-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Daniel R, Rigopoulos D, Farhi R, Babaev M. Variability in systemic treatment efficacy for onychomycosis: information that clinical studies do not impart to the office dermatologist. Skin Appendage Disord 2018; 4: 141-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gustafson E, Bakotic W, Bennett L, Page L, McCarthy L. DNA-based detection for onychomycosis correlates better to histopathology than does fungal culture. Dermatol Online J 2019; 25. https://doi.org/13030/qt5bc2z46g</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blake N, Zhu J, Hernandez G, Juliano PJ. A retrospective review of diagnostic testing for onychomycosis of the foot. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2015; 105: 503-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velasquez-Agudelo V, Cardona-Arias JA. Meta-analysis of the utility of culture, biopsy, and direct KOH examination for the diagnosis of onychomycosis. BMC Infect Dis 2017; 17: 166.https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-017-2258-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karaman BFO, Açıkalın A, Ünal İ, Aksungur VL. Diagnostic values of KOH examination, histological examination, and culture for onychomycosis: a latent class analysis. Int J Dermatol 2019; 58: 319-324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Nakrieko K-A. Onychomycosis infections do polymerase chain reaction and culture reports agree? J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2017; 107: 280-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehlig L, Garve C, Ritschel A et al. Clinical evaluation of a novel commercial multiplex-based PCR diagnostic test for differential diagnosis of dermatomycoses. Mycoses 2014; 57: 27-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhib I, Fathallah A, Yaacoub A, Hadj Slama F, Said MB, Zemni R. Multiplex PCR assay for the detection of common dermatophyte nail infections. Mycoses 2014; 57: 19-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spiliopoulou A, Bartzavali C, Jelastopulu E, Anastassiou ED, Christofidou M. Evaluation of a commercial PCR test for the diagnosis of dermatophyte nail infections. J Med Microbiol 2015; 64(Pt 1): 25-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Aly R, Baldwin SL et al. Efficacy and safety of tavaborole topical solution, 5%, a novel boron-based antifungal agent, for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis: results from 2 randomized phase-III studies. J Am Acad Dermatol 2015; 73: 62-69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Rich P, Pollak R et al. Efinaconazole 10% solution in the treatment of toenail onychomycosis: two phase III multicenter, randomized, double-blind studies. J Am Acad Dermatol 2013; 68: 600-608.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Long-standing onychodystrophy in a young woman. JAMA 2016; 316: 1915-1916.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carney C, Tosti A, Daniel R et al. A new classification system for grading the severity of onychomycosis: Onychomycosis Severity Index. Arch Dermatol 2011; 147: 1277-1282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sergeev AY, Gupta AK, Sergeev YV. The Scoring Clinical Index for Onychomycosis (SCIO index). Skin Ther Lett 2002; 7(Suppl 1): 6-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nenoff P, Grunewald S, Paasch U. Laser therapy of onychomycosis. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2014; 12: 33-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Onychomycosis: treatment and prevention of recurrence. J Am Acad Dermatol 2019; 80: 853-867.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foley K, Gupta AK, Versteeg S, Mays R, Villanueva E, John D. Topical and device-based treatments for fungal infections of the Toenails. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020; 1: CD012093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamaguchi H. Potential of ravuconazole and its prodrugs as the new oraltherapeutics for onychomycosis. Med Mycol J 2016; 57: E93-E110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healthdirect Australia. Terbinafine (DRLA). Healthdirect Australia. [WWW document] 2020. URL https://www.healthdirect.gov.au/medicines/brand/amt,920112011000036102/terbinafine-drla (Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healthdirect Australia. Lozanoc Healthdirect Australia. [WWW document] 2020. URL https://www.healthdirect.gov.au/medicines/brand/amt,679991000168108/lozanoc(Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Medicines Agency. Diflucan European Medicines Agency. [WWW document] 2018. URL https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/referrals/diflucan(Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolverton SE, Wu JJ. Comprehensive Dermatologic Drug Therapy E-Book. Elsevier Health Sciences, St. Louis, MO, 2019: 186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryder NS. Terbinafine: mode of action and properties of the squalene epoxidase inhibition. Br J Dermatol 1992; 126(Suppl 39): 2-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Sauder DN, Shear NH. Antifungal agents: an overview. Part II. J Am Acad Dermatol 1994; 30: 911-933; quiz 934-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faergemann J, Zehender H, Denouël J, Millerioux L. Levels of terbinafine in plasma, stratum corneum, dermis-epidermis (without stratum corneum), sebum, hair and nails during and after 250 mg terbinafine orally once per day for four weeks. Acta Derm Venereol 1993; 73: 305-309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schatz F, Bräutigam M, Dobrowolski E et al. Nail incorporation kinetics of terbinafine in onychomycosis patients. Clin Exp Dermatol 1995; 20: 377-383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faergemann J, Zehender H, Millerioux L. Levels of terbinafine in plasma, stratum corneum, dermis-epidermis (without stratum corneum), sebum, hair and nails during and after 250 mg terbinafine orally once daily for 7 and 14 days. Clin Exp Dermatol 1994; 19: 121-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novartis Pharmaceuticals Corporation. LAMISIL (terbinafine hydrochloride) Tablets, 250 mg, for oral use Drugs@FDA: FDA-Approved Drugs. [WWW document] 2017. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2017/020539s029,022071s013lbl.pdf(last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Lipner SR. Retrospective analysis of adverse events with systemic onychomycosis medications reported to the United States Food and Drug Administration. J Dermatol Treat 2020: https://doi.org/10.1080/09546634.2019.1708242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Shear NH. Terbinafine: an update. J Am Acad Dermatol 1997; 37: 979-988.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balfour JA, Faulds D. Terbinafine. A review of its pharmacodynamic and pharmacokinetic properties, and therapeutic potential in superficial mycoses. Drugs 1992; 43: 259-284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korting HC, Schöllmann C. The significance of itraconazole for treatment of fungal infections of skin, nails and mucous membranes. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2009; 7: 11-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies. Sporanox (itraconazole) CapsulesDrugs@FDA: FDA approved drug products. [WWW document]2018 URL https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2018/020083s062lbl.pdf(Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavrijsen AP, Balmus KJ, Nugteren-Huying WM, Roldaan AC, van't Wout JW, Stricker BH. Hepatic injury associated with itraconazole. Lancet Lond Engl 1992; 340: 251-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Peer A, Woestenborghs R, Heykants J, Gasparini R, Gauwenbergh G. The effects of food and dose on the oral systemic availability of itraconazole in healthy subjects. Eur J Clin Pharmacol 1989; 36: 423-426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brammer KW, Farrow PR, Faulkner JK. Pharmacokinetics and tissue penetration of fluconazole in humans. Rev Infect Dis 1990; 12(Suppl 3): S318-S326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muńoz P, Moreno S, Berenguer J, Bernaldo de Quirós JC, Bouza E. Fluconazole-related hepatotoxicity in patients with acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. Arch Intern Med 1991; 151: 1020-1021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scher RK, Breneman D, Rich P et al. Once-weekly fluconazole (150, 300, or 450 mg) in the treatment of distal subungual onychomycosis of the toenail. J Am Acad Dermatol 1998; 38(6 Pt 2): S77-S86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfizer Canada Inc. Diflucan (fluconazole). Pfizer [WWW document] 2018 URL https://www.pfizer.ca/sites/default/files/201806/Diflucan_PM_E_207077_12June2018.pdf (Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faergemann J and Laufen H. Levels of Fluconazole in Normal and Diseased Nails during and after Treatment of Onychomycoses in Toe-nails with Fluconazole 150 mg Once Weekly. Acta Derm Venereol 1996; 76: 219-221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bérard A, Sheehy O, Zhao J-P et al. Associations between low- and high-dose oral fluconazole and pregnancy outcomes: 3 nested case-control studies. CMAJ 2019; 191: E179-E187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Sá DC, Lamas APB, Tosti A. Oral therapy for onychomycosis: an evidence-based review. Am J Clin Dermatol 2014; 15: 17-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Paquet M, Simpson F, Tavakkol A. Terbinafine in the treatment of dermatophyte toenail onychomycosis: a meta-analysis of efficacy for continuous and intermittent regimens. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2013; 27: 267-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigurgeirsson B, Paul C, Curran D, Evans EGV. Prognostic factors of mycological cure following treatment of onychomycosis with oral antifungal agents. Br J Dermatol 2002; 147: 1241-1243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Baran R, Summerbell R. Onychomycosis: strategies to improve efficacy and reduce recurrence. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2002; 16: 579-586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Konnikov N, Lynde CW. Single-blind, randomized, prospective study on terbinafine and itraconazole for treatment of dermatophyte toenail onychomycosis in the elderly. J Am Acad Dermatol 2001; 44: 479-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Del Rosso JQ. An evaluation of intermittent therapies used to treat onychomycosis and other dermatomycoses with the oral antifungal agents. Int J Dermatol 2000; 39: 401-411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski B, Pollak R, Ashton S, Rich P, Schlessinger J, Tavakkol A. A randomized, placebo- and active-controlled, parallel-group, multicentre, investigator-blinded study of four treatment regimens of posaconazole in adults with toenail onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2012; 166: 389-398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigurgeirsson B, van Rossem K, Malahias S, Raterink K. A phase II, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel group, dose-ranging study to investigate the efficacy and safety of 4 dose regimens of oral albaconazole in patients with distal subungual onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol 2013; 69: 416-425.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maddin S, Quiring J, Bulger L. Randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 3 study of itraconazole for the treatment of onychomycosis. J Drugs Dermatol 2013; 12: 758-763.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitenbach J. Melt extrusion: from process to drug delivery technology. Eur J Pharm Biopharm 2002; 54: 107-117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Leonadri C, Pierce P, Conetta B. A phase I/II randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-ranging study evaluating the efficacy, safety and pharmacokinetics of ravuconazole in the treatment of onychomycosis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2005; 19: 437-443.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe S, Tsubouchi I, Okubo A. Efficacy and safety of fosravuconazole L-lysine ethanolate, a novel oral triazole antifungal agent, for the treatment of onychomycosis: a multicenter, double-blind, randomized phase III study. J Dermatol 2018; 45: 1151-1159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski B, Kempers S, Bhatia N et al. Efficacy and Safety of VT-1161 in a Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study of Four Oral VT-1161 Regimens in the Treatment of Patients with Moderate-to-Severe Distal-Lateral Subungual Onychomycosis (DLSO), 4th edn. International Summit for Nail Diseases, Athens, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaul S, Yadav S, Dogra S. Treatment of dermatophytosis in elderly, children, and pregnant women. Indian Dermatol Online J 2017; 8: 310-318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Chang P, Del Rosso JQ, Adam P, Hofstader SL. Onychomycosis in children: prevalence and management. Pediatr Dermatol 1998; 15: 464-471.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, De Rosso JQ. Management of onychomycosis in children. Postgrad Med 1999; Spec No: 31-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Mays RR, Versteeg SG, Shear NH, Friedlander SF. Onychomycosis in children: safety and efficacy of antifungal agents. Pediatr Dermatol 2018; 35: 552-559.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ameen M, Lear JT, Madan V, Mohd Mustapa MF, Richardson M. British Association of Dermatologists' guidelines for the management of onychomycosis 2014. Br J Dermatol 2014; 171: 937-958.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anacor Pharmaceuticals Inc.Kerydin (tavaborole) topical solution, 5% 5%. Drugs@FDA: FDA approved drug products. [WWW document] 2014. URL https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2014/204427s000lbl.pdf (last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valeant Canada LP. Jublia Efinaconazole Topical Solution, 10% [WWW document] 2017URL https://pdf.hres.ca/dpd_pm/00040037.PDF(Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aventis Pharma. Penlac (Ciclopirox Topical Solution, 8% w/w) Nail Lacquer. [WWW document] 2012 URL https://pdf.hres.ca/dpd_pm/00015736.PDF(Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galderma (U.K) Ltd. Curanail 5% w/v Medicated Nail Lacquer. emc. [WWW document] 2020. URL https://www.medicines.org.uk/emc/product/9436/smpc (Last accessed: 13 April 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauharanta J. Comparative efficacy and safety of amorolfine nail lacquer 2% versus 5% once weekly. Clin Exp Dermatol 1992; 17(Suppl 1): 41-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pilmis B, Jullien V, Sobel J, Lecuit M, Lortholary O, Charlier C. Antifungal drugs during pregnancy: an updated review. J Antimicrob Chemother 2014; 70: 14-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Lynch LE. Onychomycosis: review of recurrence rates, poor prognostic factors, and strategies to prevent disease recurrence. Cutis 2004; 74(1 Suppl): 10-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosen T. Evaluation of gender as a clinically relevant outcome variable in the treatment of onychomycosis with efinaconazole topical solution 10. Cutis 2015; 96: 197-201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markinson B, Caldwell B. Efinaconazole topical solution, 10% efficacy in patients with onychomycosis and coexisting tinea pedis. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2015; 105: 407-411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez DA. Efinaconazole topical solution, 10%, for the treatment of mild and moderate toenail onychomycosis. J Clin Aesthetic Dermatol 2015; 8: 24-29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Elewski BE, Sugarman JL et al. The efficacy and safety of efinaconazole 10% solution for treatment of mild to moderate onychomycosis: a pooled analysis of two phase 3 randomized trials. J Drugs Dermatol 2014; 13: 815-820.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Korotzer A. Topical treatment of onychomycosis and clinically meaningful outcomes. J Drugs Dermatol 2016; 15: 1260-1266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK. Long term therapy with daily efinaconazole 10% nail solution for mild to moderate toenail onychomycosis caused by dermatophytes: an investigator-initiated clinical trial. Dermatology Update. Montreal, Canada, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eichenfield LF, Elewski B, Sugarman Jet al. Safety, pharmacokinetics, and efficacy of efinaconazole 10% topical solution for the treatment of onychomycosis in pediatric patients. 2020 Maui Derm for Dermatologists Annual Meeting, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma N, Sharma D. An upcoming drug for onychomycosis: tavaborole. J Pharmacol Pharmacother 2015; 6: 236-239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi Y, Komatsu T, Sumi M et al. In vitro permeation of several drugs through the human nail plate: relationship between physicochemical properties and nail permeability of drugs. Eur J Pharm Sci 2004; 21: 471-477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rich P, Spellman M, Purohit V, Zang C, Crook TJ. Tavaborole 5% topical solution for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis in pediatric patients: results from a Phase 4 Open-Label Study. J Drugs Dermatol 2019; 18: 190-195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee REB, Liu TT, Barker KS, Lee RE, Rogers PD. Genome-wide expression profiling of the response to ciclopirox olamine in Candida albicans. J Antimicrob Chemother 2005; 55: 655-662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belenky P, Camacho D, Collins JJ. Fungicidal drugs induce a common oxidative-damage cellular death pathway. Cell Rep 2013; 3: 350-358.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>del Palacio-Hernanz A, Guarro-Artigas J, Figueras-Salvat MJ, Esteban-Moreno J, Lopez-Gomez S. Changes in fungal ultrastructure after short-course ciclopiroxolamine therapy in pityriasis versicolor. Clin Exp Dermatol 1990; 15: 95-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Fleckman P, Baran R. Ciclopirox nail lacquer topical solution 8% in the treatment of toenail onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 43(4 Suppl): S70-S80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Uro M, Cooper EA. Onychomycosis therapy: past, present, future. J Drugs Dermatol 2010; 9: 1109-1113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haria M, Bryson HM. Amorolfine. A review of its pharmacological properties and therapeutic potential in the treatment of onychomycosis and other superficial fungal infections. Drugs 1995; 49: 103-120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reinel D. Topical treatment of onychomycosis with amorolfine 5% nail lacquer: comparative efficacy and tolerability of once and twice weekly use. Dermatology 1992; 184(Suppl 1): 21-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R, Tosti A, Hartmane I et al. An innovative water-soluble biopolymer improves efficacy of ciclopirox nail lacquer in the management of onychomycosis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2009; 23: 773-781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monti D, Herranz U, Dal Bo L, Subissi A. Nail penetration and predicted mycological efficacy of an innovative hydrosoluble ciclopirox nail lacquer vs. a standard amorolfine lacquer in healthy subjects. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2013; 27: e153-e158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum MA, Long L, Isham N et al. Ability of hydroxypropyl chitosan nail lacquer to protect against dermatophyte nail infection. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2015; 59: 1844-1848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iorizzo M, Hartmane I, Derveniece A, Mikazans I. Ciclopirox 8% HPCH nail lacquer in the treatment of mild-to-moderate onychomycosis: a randomized, double-blind amorolfine controlled study using a blinded evaluator. Skin Appendage Disord 2015; 1: 134-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caserini M. Study to evaluate the efficacy and Safety of P-3058 Nail Solution in the Treatment of Onychomycosis. ClinicalTrials.gov. [WWW document] 2018. URL https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03094468 (Last accessed: 20 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moberg Pharma AB. Moberg Pharma meets primary endpoint for MOB-015 in a Phase 3 study for the treatment of onychomycosis [Internet]. News Powered by Cision. [WWW document] 2019. URL https://news.cision.com/moberg-pharma/r/moberg-pharma-meets-primary-endpoint-for-mob-015-in-a-phase-3-study-for-the-treatment-of-onychomycos,c2984987 (last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Simpson FC. New pharmacotherapy for the treatment of onychomycosis: an update. Expert Opin Pharmacother 2015; 16: 227-236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum M, Isham N, Herbert J, Henry W, Yurdakul S. Activity of TDT 067 (terbinafine in transfersome) against agents of onychomycosis, as determined by minimum inhibitory and fungicidal concentrations. J Clin Microbiol 2011; 49: 1716-1720.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Stec N. Recent advances in therapies for onychomycosis and its management. F1000Research 2019; 8: 968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahata S, Kubota N, Takei-Masuda N et al. Mechanism of action of ME1111, a novel antifungal agent for topical treatment of onychomycosis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2016; 60: 873-880.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Simpson F. Newly approved laser systems for onychomycosis. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2012; 102: 428-430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garrison R. NuvoLase's PinPointe FootLaser Receives Korean Regulatory Approval. NuvoLase Inc. [WWW document] 2013. URL https://www.nuvolase.com/2013/11/nuvolases-pinpointe-footlaser-receives-korean-regulatory-approval-2/ (Last accessed: 7 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsambas AD, Lotti TM, Dessinioti C, D'Erme AM. European Handbook of Dermatological Treatments, 3rd edn. Springer, New York, NY, 2015: 1521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubin AI, Jellinek NJ, Daniel CR III, Scher RK. Scher and Daniel's Nails: Diagnosis, Surgery, Therapy. Springer, New York, NY: 2018: 669.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Paquet M. A retrospective chart review of the clinical efficacy of Nd:YAG 1064-nm laser for toenail onychomycosis. J Dermatol Treat 2015; 26: 376-378.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG. A critical review of improvement rates for laser therapy used to treat toenail onychomycosis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2017; 31: 1111-1118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hay R. Therapy of skin, hair and nail fungal infections. J Fungi 2018; 4: 99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe D, Kawamura C, Masuda Y, Akita Y, Tamada Y, Matsumoto Y. Successful treatment of toenail onychomycosis with photodynamic therapy. Arch Dermatol 2008; 144: 19-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreutz T, de Matos SP, Koester LS. Recent patents containing permeation enhancers for nail delivery. Recent Pat Drug Deliv Formul 2019; 13: 203-218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Napolez A. Nail Penetration device for delivery of anti-fungal treatments. US2018207414A1US2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nair AB, Kim HD, Davis SP et al. An ex vivo toe model used to assess applicators for the iontophoretic ungual delivery of terbinafine. Pharm Res 2009; 26: 2194-2201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Natori N, Takabe H, Ishimaru T, Iseki H, Karasawa K.External preparation for treating trichophytosis unguium. WO2019088005A1, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong Y.Plant extraction formula applied to onychomycosis and tinea pedis, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Baran R. Ciclopirox nail lacquer solution 8% in the 21st century. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 43(4 Suppl): S96-S102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Shear NH. A risk-benefit assessment of the newer oral antifungal agents used to treat onychomycosis. Drug Saf 2000; 22: 33-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terbinafine. In LiverTox: Clinical and Research Information on Drug-Induced Liver Injury [Internet]. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, Bethesda, MD. [WWW document] 2012. URL http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK548617/ (last accessed: 16 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itraconazole. In LiverTox: Clinical and Research Information on Drug-Induced Liver Injury [Internet]. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, Bethesda, MD. [WWW document] 2012. URL http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK548273/ (last accessed: 16 January 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fluconazole. In LiverTox: Clinical and Research Information on Drug-Induced Liver Injury [Internet]. National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, Bethesda, MD. [WWW document] 2012. URL http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK548300/ (last accessed: 16 January 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leyden J. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacology of terbinafine and itraconazole. J Am Acad Dermatol 1998; 38(5, Supplement 2): S42-S47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Chwetzoff E, Del Rosso J, Baran R. Hepatic safety of itraconazole. J Cutan Med Surg 2002; 6: 210-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ripa S, Ferrante L, Prenna M. Pharmacokinetics of fluconazole in normal volunteers. Chemotherapy 1993; 39: 6-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gayam V, Khalid M, Dahal S, Garlapati P, Gill A. Hyperacute liver injury following intravenous fluconazole: a rare case of dose-independent hepatotoxicity. J Fam Med Prim Care 2018; 7: 451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawson C-A, Karlowsky JA. Fluconazole-induced hepatotoxicity: Review of published case reports. Can J Hosp Pharm 1998; 51: 61-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlefman BS. Onychomycosis: a compendium of facts and a clinical experience. J Foot Ankle Surg 1999; 38: 290-302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Doncker P, Decroix J, Piérard GE et al. Antifungal pulse therapy for onychomycosis. A pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic investigation of monthly cycles of 1-week pulse therapy with itraconazole. Arch Dermatol 1996; 132: 34-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willemsen M, De Doncker P, Willems J et al. Posttreatment itraconazole levels in the nail: New implications for treatment in onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol 1992; 26(5, Part 1): 731-735.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blum RA, D’Andrea DT, Florentino BM et al. Increased gastric pH and the bioavailability of fluconazole and ketoconazole. Ann Intern Med 1991; 114: 755-757.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debruyne D, Coquerel A. Pharmacokinetics of antifungal agents in onychomycoses. Clin Pharmacokinet 2001; 40: 441-472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schäfer-Korting M. Pharmacokinetic optimisation of oral antifungal therapy. Clin Pharmacokinet 1993; 25: 329-341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi Y, Miyamoto M, Sugibayashi K, Morimoto Y. Drug permeation through the three layers of the human nail plate. J Pharm Pharmacol 1999; 51: 271-278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Tosti A. Tavaborole for the treatment of onychomycosis. Expert Opin Pharmacother 2014; 15: 1439-1448.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugiura K, Sugimoto N, Hosaka S et al. The low keratin affinity of efinaconazole contributes to its nail penetration and fungicidal activity in topical onychomycosis treatment. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2014; 58: 3837-3842.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogura H, Kobayashi H, Nagai K et al. Synthesis and antifungal activities of (2R,3R)-2-aryl-1-azolyl-3-(substituted amino)-2-butanol derivatives as topical antifungal agents. Chem Pharm Bull (Tokyo) 1999; 47: 1417-1425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kircik LH. Enhancing transungual delivery and spreading of efinaconazole under the nail plate through a unique formulation approach. J Drugs Dermatol 2014; 13: 1457-1461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murdan S. Enhancing the nail permeability of topically applied drugs. Expert Opin Drug Deliv 2008; 5: 1267-1282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murdan S. Drug delivery to the nail following topical application. Int J Pharm 2002; 236: 1-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markinson B, Ghannoum M, Winter T, Rycerz A, Rock F, Gupta AK. Examining the benefits of the boron-based mechanism of action and physicochemical properties of tavaborole in the treatment of onychomycosis. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2018; 108: 12-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coronado D, Merchant T, Chanda S, Zane LT. In vitro nail penetration and antifungal activity of tavaborole, a boron-based pharmaceutical. J Drugs Dermatol 2015; 14: 609-614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Pollak RA, Pillai R, Olin JT. Access of efinaconazole topical solution, 10%, to the infection site by spreading through the subungual space. J Drugs Dermatol 2014; 13: 1394-1398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Simpson FC. Routes of drug delivery into the nail apparatus: Implications for the efficacy of topical nail solutions in onychomycosis. J Dermatol Treat 2016; 27: 2-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarratt M, Siu WJ, Yamakawa E, Kodera N, Pillai R, Smith K. Safety and pharmacokinetics of efinaconazole 10% solution in healthy volunteers and patients with severe onychomycosis. J Drugs Dermatol 2013; 12: 1010-1016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto M, Sugimoto N, Kawabata H et al. Transungual delivery of efinaconazole: its deposition in the nail of onychomycosis patients and in vitro fungicidal activity in human nails. J Drugs Dermatol 2014; 13: 1388-1392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Daigle D., Tavaborole (AN-2690) for the treatment of onychomycosis of the toenail in adults. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther 2014; 12: 735-742.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abastabar M, Haghani I, Shokohi T, et al. Low In Vitro Antifungal Activity of Tavaborole against Yeasts and Molds from Onychomycosis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2018; 62: e01632-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jinna S, Finch J. Spotlight on tavaborole for the treatment of onychomycosis. Drug Des Devel Ther 2015; 9: 6185-6190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohn M, Kraemer KT. Dermatopharmacology of ciclopirox nail lacquer topical solution 8% in the treatment of onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 43(4 Suppl): S57-S69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polak A. Kinetics of amorolfine in human nails. Mycoses 1993; 36: 101-103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cernea M. How effective is efinaconazole in the management of onychomycosis? Expert Opin Pharmacother2016; 17: 611-618.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seebacher C, Brasch J, Abeck D et al. Onychomycosis. Mycoses. 2007; 50: 321-327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schein JR, Gause D, Stier DM, Lubeck DP, Bates MM, Onychomycosis FR. Baseline results of an observational study. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 1997; 87: 512-519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scher RK. Onychomycosis: a significant medical disorder. J Am Acad Dermatol 1996; 35(3 Pt 2): S2-S5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Sisti A, Tosti A. Long-term follow-up of toenail onychomycosis caused by dermatophytes after successful treatment with systemic antifungal agents. J Am Acad Dermatol 2010; 62: 411-414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scher RK, Baran R. Onychomycosis in clinical practice: factors contributing to recurrence. Br J Dermatol 2003; 149(Suppl 65): 5-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingber A. Intermittent low dose itraconazole treatment for onychomycosis-long term follow-up. Med Mycol. 2001; 39: 471-473.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Simpson FC. New therapeutic options for onychomycosis. Expert Opin Pharmacother 2012; 13: 1131-1142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM, Stinchi C, Colombo MD. Relapses of onychomycosis after successful treatment with systemic antifungals: a three-year follow-up. Dermatology 1998; 197: 162-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigurgeirsson B, Olafsson JH, Steinsson JB, Paul C, Billstein S, Evans EGV. Long-term effectiveness of treatment with terbinafine vs itraconazole in onychomycosis: a 5-year blinded prospective follow-up study. Arch Dermatol 2002; 138: 353-357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko JY, Lee HE, Jae H, Oh DH, Kim JS, Yu HJ. Cure rate, duration required for complete cure and recurrence rate of onychomycosis according to clinical factors in Korean patients. Mycoses 2011; 54: e384-e388.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayo T, Cantrell W, Elewksi BE. Can we prevent onychomycosis? J Infect Dis Ther 2014; 2: 4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein E. How often does oral treatment of toenail onychomycosis produce a disease-free nail? An analysis of published data. Arch Dermatol 1998; 134: 1551-1554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Elewski BE, Rosen T et al. Onychomycosis: strategies to minimize recurrence. J Drugs Dermatol 2016; 15:279-282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Daigle D. Potential role of tavaborole for the treatment of onychomycosis. Future Microbiol 2014; 9: 1243-1250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer TR, Mucha H, Hoefer D. Infection risk by dermatophytes during storage and after domestic laundry and their temperature-dependent inactivation. Mycopathologia 2011; 171: 43-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feuilhade de Chauvin M. A study on the decontamination of insoles colonized by Trichophyton rubrum: effect of terbinafine spray powder 1% and terbinafine spray solution 1%. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2012; 26: 875-878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum MA, Isham N, Long L. Optimization of an infected shoe model for the evaluation of an ultraviolet shoe sanitizer device. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2012; 102: 309-313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Brintnell WC. Sanitization of contaminated footwear from onychomycosis patients using ozone gas: a novel adjunct therapy for treating onychomycosis and tinea pedis? J Cutan Med Surg 2013; 17: 243-249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Brintnell W. Ozone gas effectively kills laboratory strains of Trichophyton rubrum and Trichophyton mentagrophytes using an in vitro test system. J Dermatol Treat 2012; 25: 251-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
