<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">32280143</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-1058</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>52</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The journal of extra-corporeal technology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Extra Corpor Technol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Water Condensation and Gas Exchange Correlation in Different Models and Fibers of Blood Oxygenators: "How Can We Improve Performance?".</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>43</StartPage>
          <EndPage>51</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>43-51</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1182/ject-1900028</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Creation of water condensation in blood oxygenators is a phenomenon that is constantly present during cardiopulmonary bypass and in medium- to long-term extracorporeal life support. Clinical observation of condensation at the oxygenator exit is still a common event normally associated with sudden cooling of the gas flow proximal to the outlet cover (after exiting the fiber bundle), where the warming effect of blood is no longer present. Condensation could progressively obstruct a certain number of fibers, reducing the efficiency of gaseous exchange in the membrane of the oxygenator surface. The study included 48 patients divided into four oxygenator groups of 12 each: group 1 used an Inspire 6 F oxygenator from Livanova; group 2, an Affinity Fusion from Medtronic; group 3, an Alone from Eurosets, and group 4, an ECMO Alone from Eurosets; while the last group used an ECMO Alone oxygenator from Eurosets with polymethylpentene fiber. Each group of oxygenators comprising 12 patients were divided into two groups, namely, A and B, with six patients in each group. Group A used mild hypothermia during the procedure, and group B of six patients used normothermia; Groups A and B were further subdivided into four subgroups: A1, A2, B1, and B2, each consists of three patients; subgroups A1 and B1 used negative aspiration (-8 mmHg) measuring humidity (%) and temperature (°C) in the gas oxygenator output; consequently, a measurement system was necessary to be created; Subgroups A2 and B2 did not use negative aspiration in the oxygenator outlet. No statistically significant difference for PaO<sub>2</sub> and humidity values was found in polypropylene and polymethylpentene oxygenators with mild hypothermia management with vacuum and without vacuum in the gas outlet in the first 60 minutes and 60 minutes later during cardiopulmonary bypass. In normothermia, a statistically significant difference in the PaO<sub>2</sub>-humidity relationship was observed with polypropylene and polymethylpentene fiber models. Results of this study show an inversely proportional correlation between gas exchange and condensation in statistically significant values during the use of normothermia and a reduction in oxygenation performance, in polypropylene and polymethylpentene fiber oxygenators.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© Copyright 2020 AMSECT.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Condello</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ignazio</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, Anthea Hospital - GVM Care &amp; Research, Bari, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Extra Corpor Technol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0267637</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-1058</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>S88TT14065</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010100">Oxygen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002315" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiopulmonary Bypass</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004867" MajorTopicYN="N">Equipment Design</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015199" MajorTopicYN="Y">Extracorporeal Membrane Oxygenation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010100" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010106" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygenators</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010107" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oxygenators, Membrane</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32280143</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138120</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/ject-1900028</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">1900028</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang Y, Novak P, Hozalski R, et al. . 
Condensation studies in gas permeable membranes. J Membr Sci. 2004;231:47–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickramasinghe SR, Han B, Garcia JD, et al. . 
Micro- porous membrane blood oxygenators. AIChE J. 2005;51:656–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martınez L.
Characterisation of three hydrophobic porous membranes used in membrane distillation modelling and evaluation of their water vapour permeabilities. J Membr Sci. 2002;203:15–27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiu L, Zheng X, Yue P, et al. . 
Adaptable thermal conductivity characterization of microporous membranes based on freestanding sensor-based 3-omega technique. Int J Therm Sci. 2015;89:185–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomson G.
The antoine equation for vapor-pressure data. Chem Rev. 1946;38:1–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21016992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borges JC, Neto ML, Marinho GS. 
Variation of the thermal properties of a polyurethane-polyethylene composite. J Phys Sci Appl. 2015;5:179–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ANSYS Inc., 2016. 
Fluent User’s Guide version 17.2. PTC: Canonsburg, PA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurashima N, Takeda H. 
Prototyping an automatic oxygen flush unit while using a PCPS. Jpn J Extra Corpor Technol. 2000;27:13–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Incropera FP, Incropera FP. 
Fundamentals of Heat and Mass Transfer. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley, 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamura A, Watanabe M, Yoshida Y, et al. . 
One formulation for a method of preventing a reduction in oxygenizing capability due to oxygenator condensation in long-term use of a PCPS. Jpn J Extra Corpor Technol. 2005;32:50–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anno M, Toda K, Maeda K, et al. . 
About dewfall measures of PCPS. Jpn J Extra Corpor Technol. 2010;37:436–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishigaki T, Fujii J, Yoshida K, et al. . 
Prevention of dew condensation occurring in the oxygenator for extracorporeal life support in vitro model. Puerto Vallarta, Mexico: IEEE, 2012. 
World Automation Congress (WAC). Available at: http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/articleDetails. jsp?arnumber56320892.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Carson JK, North MF, et al. . 
A new approach to modelling the effective thermal conductivity of heterogeneous materials. Int J Heat Mass Tran. 2006;49:3075– 83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lund LW, Hattler BG, Federspiel WJ. 
Is condensation the cause of plasma leakage in microporous hollow fibre membrane oxygenators. J Membr Sci. 1998;147:87–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez Bardón R, Dubini G, Pennati G. 
A computational model of heat loss and water condensation on the gas-side of blood oxygenators. Artif Organs. 2018;42:E380–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6282549</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30155896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
