<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32310488</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK556028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896">Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saunders</LastName><ForeName>Hollie</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanghavi</LastName><ForeName>Devang</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mayo Clinic</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Continuous renal replacement therapy is one of the renal replacement methods that include intermittent hemodialysis and peritoneal dialysis. It is intended to be applied for 24 hours or longer through continuous, slower dialysis. CRRT acts as renal support through blood purification to allow solute and fluid homeostasis. It requires appropriate vascular access, pumps to allow blood circulation, a permeable membrane, and varying solutions to allow fluid balance. There are different techniques of CRRT that are distinguished by their method of solute removal. <b>Continuous Venovenous Hemofiltration (CVVH)</b> This method utilizes convection via a transmembrane pressure gradient to filter solutes. It does not require dialysate fluid; instead, a substitute fluid is used to replace the filtered fluid. <b>Continuous Venovenous Hemodialysis (CVVHD)     </b> This method utilizes diffusion via a transmembrane concentration gradient across the membrane. In this method, dialysate fluid is used. This is effective for solutes will small molecular weights such as potassium, urea, and creatinine. <b>Continuous Venovenous Hemodiafiltration (CVVHDF)</b> This combines both convection and diffusion methods of filtration. The composition of the dialysate or the substitution fluids can be tailored to achieve the desired plasma composition. This is mainly applied in electrolyte derangements and in lactic acidosis, where a bicarbonate buffer may be used. The preferred vascular access site is the right internal jugular vein due to a more direct pathway to the superior vena cava. An alternative to jugular access is femoral. Subclavian is less preferred as it may result in stenosis of the vessel and may cause future issues if the patient requires an arteriovenous (AV) fistula. End-stage renal disease (ESRD) patients who have AV fistulas should not use these if CRRT is needed. Using their established AV fistula increases the risk of needle dislodgment and bleeding. In CRRT, the use of an extracorporeal circuit results in a prothrombotic state. If membrane clotting occurs, it will result in a decrease in the surface area available for diffusion or convection. As such, an anticoagulant is required to prevent clotting. The anticoagulant used can either be systemic or regional. Both systemic and regional anticoagulation have advantages and disadvantages; these are detailed in table 1. The options for systemic anticoagulation include unfractionated heparin or low molecular weight heparin. If a patient has heparin-induced thrombocytopenia (HIT), alternatives such as argatroban or hirudin may be used for systemic anticoagulation. Regional anticoagulation is achieved using citrate. Citrate acts by chelating calcium and thus inhibiting the clotting cascade. If using this method, then serum ionized calcium levels should be monitored frequently. These patients will often require a calcium infusion with rate adjustments made based on the ionized calcium level. One option for if anticoagulation cannot be used is intermittent saline flushes. This is performed every 15 to 30 minutes and helps wash off the fibrin strands. However, filter half-lives are generally reduced.. Table 1. Advantages and disadvantages of anticoagulation methods.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s3">Indications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s4">Contraindications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s5">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s6">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s7">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s8">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Interventions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s9">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Monitoring</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s10">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-90896" sec="article-90896.s14">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Macedo E, Mehta RL. Continuous Dialysis Therapies: Core Curriculum 2016. Am J Kidney Dis. 2016 Oct;68(4):645-657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27241853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manns M, Sigler MH, Teehan BP. Continuous renal replacement therapies: an update. Am J Kidney Dis. 1998 Aug;32(2):185-207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9708602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kes P. Slow continuous renal replacement therapies: an update. Acta Med Croatica. 2000;54(2):69-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11028112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jang SM, Infante S, Abdi Pour A. Drug Dosing Considerations in Critically Ill Patients Receiving Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy. Pharmacy (Basel) 2020 Feb 07;8(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32046092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw AR, Chaijamorn W, Mueller BA. We Underdose Antibiotics in Patients on CRRT. Semin Dial. 2016 Jul;29(4):278-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27082510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibney RT, Bagshaw SM, Kutsogiannis DJ, Johnston C. When should renal replacement therapy for acute kidney injury be initiated and discontinued? Blood Purif. 2008;26(5):473-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18810230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connor MJ, Karakala N. Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy: Reviewing Current Best Practice to Provide High-Quality Extracorporeal Therapy to Critically Ill Patients. Adv Chronic Kidney Dis. 2017 Jul;24(4):213-218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28778360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32310488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
