<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32338374</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0010</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>100</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of the science of food and agriculture</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Sci Food Agric</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Size development of tomatoes growing in trusses: linking time of fruit set to diameter.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>4020</StartPage>
          <EndPage>4028</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>4020-4028</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jsfa.10447</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Size of fruit is an important issue in determining yield at harvest. Even under controlled conditions, variation between fruit and trusses can be considerable. As an easy to measure indication of size, the diameter of tomatoes growing in trusses was assessed in three experiments with different number of tomatoes per truss, as well as cultivars, and also by varying the level of ions in the recirculated drain water.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">By applying the von Bertalanffy growth model, more than 99% of the variation present could be explained by the time of fruit set for all tomatoes growing anywhere in the trusses. A linear relationship between time of fruit set and the biological shift factor, an indication of developmental age, was observed. Integrating this linear relationship in the analysis of the diameter data removed one stochastic variable (biological shift factor), effectively halving the number of parameters to be estimated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of the present study indicate that the major part of the variation present in the diameter of tomatoes growing in trusses is the result of variation in the time of fruit set of individual fruits. The position within the greenhouse (i.e. local differences in assimilates supply) exerted only a minor effect on diameter development. Accordingly, the time of fruit set largely determines fruit size. Likely, growing conditions before fruit set are crucial for final fruit size. The time of fruit set of each tomato in the truss and the local growing conditions within the greenhouse that affect assimilate supply need to be assessed accurately for a reliable size prediction.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 The Authors. Journal of The Science of Food and Agriculture published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tijskens</LastName>
            <ForeName>L M M</ForeName>
            <Initials>LMM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4913-9105</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Horticulture and Product Physiology, Wageningen University and Research, Wageningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>van Mourik</LastName>
            <ForeName>S</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Farm Technology, Wageningen University and Research, Wageningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dieleman</LastName>
            <ForeName>J A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Greenhouse Horticulture, Wageningen University and Research, Wageningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schouten</LastName>
            <ForeName>R E</ForeName>
            <Initials>RE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Horticulture and Product Physiology, Wageningen University and Research, Wageningen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Sci Food Agric</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0376334</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-5142</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018533" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomass</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069599" MajorTopicYN="N">Crop Production</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005638" MajorTopicYN="N">Fruit</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="Y">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018551" MajorTopicYN="N">Lycopersicon esculentum</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="Y">growth &amp; development</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diameter</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">size</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">time of fruit set</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tomato</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">truss</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32338374</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7384071</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jsfa.10447</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bac CW, Henten Van E, Hemming J, Edan Y, Harvesting robots for high‐value crops: state‐of‐the‐art review and challenges ahead. J Field Robotics, 31, pp. 888–911 (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Li B, Ling Y, Zhang H and Zheng S, The design and realization of cherry tomato harvesting robot based on Iot. Int J Online Eng
12:23–23 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zhao Y, Gong L, Liu C and Huang Y, Dual‐arm robot design and testing for harvesting tomato in greenhouse. IFAC‐Papers Online
49:161–165 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lovatt CJ, Timing citrus and avocado foliar nutrient applications to increase fruit set and size. Hort Technol
9:607–612 (1999).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Unuk T, Hrlbar J, Tojnko S, Simčič M, Požrl T, Plestenjak A
et al, Effect of nitrogen application and crop load on external and internal fruit quality parameters of apples. Dtsch Lebensmitt Rundsch
104:127–135 (2008).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Intrigliolo DS and Castel JR, Performance of various water stress indicators for prediction of fruit size response to deficit irrigation in plum. Agric Water Manage
83:173–180 (2006).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Naor A, Peres M, Greenblat Y, Doron I, Gal Y and Stern RA, Irrigation and crop load interactions in relation to pear yield and fruit‐size distribution. J Hortic Sci Biotechnol
75:555–561 (2000).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lötze E and Bergh O, Early prediction of harvest fruit size distribution of an apple and pear cultivar. Sci Hortic
101:281–290 (2004).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tromp J, Maturity of apple cvs 'Cox’s Orange pippin’ and 'Elstar’ as affected by mid‐season and late‐season temperature. Gartenbauwissenschaft
64:145–151 (1999).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Warrington IJ, Fulton TA, Halligan EA and de Silva HN, Apple fruit growth and maturity are affected by early season temperatures. J Am Soc Hort Sci
124:468–477 (1999).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tijskens LMM, Unuk T, Okello RCO, Wubs AM, Šuštar V, Šumak D
et al, From fruitlet to harvest: modelling and predicting size and its distributions for tomato, apple and pepper fruit. Sci Hortic
204:54–64 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Colle M, Weng Y, Kang Y, Ophir R, Sherman A and Grumet R, Variation in cucumber (Cucumis sativus L.) fruit size and shape results from multiple components acting pre‐anthesis and post‐pollination. Planta
246:641–658 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28623561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fanwoua J, De Visser PHB, Heuvelink E, Angenent G, Yin X, Marcelis LFM
et al, Histological and molecular investigation of the basis for variation in tomato fruit size in response to fruit load and genotype. Funct Plant Biol
39:754–763 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32480826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dorey E, Fournier P, Léchaudel M and Tixier P, A statistical model to predict titratable acidity of pineapple during fruit developing period responding to climatic variables. Sci Hortic
210:19–24 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ernesto THM, Moreno DV, Ojeda AJC and Ochoa AM, Prediction of days after anthesis of developing tomato (Solanum lycopersicum) fruit from blossom‐end changes in color. Am J Agric Biol Sci
8:191–198 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Marcelis LFM, Sink strength as a determinant of dry matter partitioning in the whole plant. J Exp Botany
47 (Spec. Iss.):1281–1291 (1996).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21245260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tanksley SD, The genetic, developmental, and molecular bases of fruit size and shape variation in tomato. The Plant Cell
16:S181–S189 (2004).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2643388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15131251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Seginer I and Gent M, Vegetative growth response to light and temperature, interpreted by carbohydrate‐pool dynamics. Acta Hortic
956:231–238 (2012).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hall AJ, Minchin PEH, Clearwater MJ and Génard M, A biophysical model of kiwifruit (Actinidia deliciosa) berry development. J Exp Bot
64:5473–5483 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3871809</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24123250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lechaudel M, Vercambre G, Lescourret F, Normand F and Génard M, An analysis of elastic and plastic fruit growth of mango in response to various assimilate supplies. Tree Physiol
27:219–230 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Austin PT, Hall AJ, Gandar PW, Warrington IJ, Fulton TA and Halligan EA, A compartment model of the effect of early‐season temperatures on potential size and growth of 'Delicious’ apple fruits. Ann Bot
83:129–143 (1999).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
West GB, Brown JH and Enquist BJ, A general model for ontogenetic growth. Nature
413:628–631 (2001).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11675785</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tran DT, MLATM H, TLH T, Quyen NT, Van De Poel B, Mata CI
et al, Population modeling approach to optimize crop harvest strategy. The case of field tomato. Front Plant Sci
8:608 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5397500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28473843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cockshull KE and Ho LC, Regulation of tomato fruit size by plant density and truss thinning. J Hortic Sci
70:395–407 (1995).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bertin N, Gautier H and Roche C, Number of cells in tomato fruit depending on fruit position and source‐sink balance during plant development. Plant Growth Regul
36:105–112 (2002).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Romero‐Aranda R, Soria T and Cuartero J, Tomato plant‐water uptake and plant‐water relationships under saline growth conditions. Plant Sci
160:265–272 (2001).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11164598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kemi Idowu M, E Adote Aduayi, sodium‐potassium interaction on growth, yield and quality of tomato in ultisol. Journal of Plant Interact
2:263–271 (2007).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rouphael Y, Petropoulos SA and Cardarelli M, Colla, salinity as eustressor for enhancing quality of vegetables. Sci Hortic
234:361–369 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
von Bertalanffy L, A quantitative theory of organic growth. Hum Biol
10:181–213 (1938).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
von Bertalanffy L, Das organische Wachstum und seine Gesetzmäßigkeiten. Experientia
4:255–269 (1948).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18875258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tijskens LMM, Heuvelink E, Schouten RE, Lana MM and van Kooten O, The biological shift factor: biological age as a tool for modelling in pre‐ and postharvest horticulture. Acta Hortic
687:39–46 (2005).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tijskens LMM, Schouten RE, Konopacki P and Jongbloed G, Basic principles of analysing biological and technical variation in non‐destructive data. Comput Electron Agric
111:121–126 (2015).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
R Core Team
, R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna:  (2017). http://www.R-project.org/.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Moreda GP, Ortiz‐Cañavate J, García‐Ramos FJ and Ruiz‐Altisent M, Non‐destructive technologies for fruit and vegetable size determination ‐ a review. J Food Eng
92:119–136 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kang M, Hua J, Wang X, de Reffye P, Jaeger M and Akaffou S, Estimating sink parameters of stochastic functional‐structural plant models using organic series‐continuous and rhythmic development. Front Plant Sci
9:1688 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6284058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30555494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Okello RCO, Heuvelink E, de Visser PHB, Lammers M, de Maagd RA, Marcelis LFM
et al, Fruit illumination stimulates cell division but has no detectable effect on fruit size in tomato (Solanum lycopersicum). Physiol Plant
154:114–127 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25220433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Crank J, The Mathematics of Diffusion, 2nd edn
Clarendon Press, Oxford:  (1975).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Heuvelink E and Buiskool RPM, Influence of sink‐source interaction on dry matter production in tomato. Ann Bot
75:381–389 (1995).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
