<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32377124</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1302-7123</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>53</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2019</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Sisli Etfal Hastanesi tip bulteni</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sisli Etfal Hastan Tip Bul</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Importance of Streptococci Infections in Childhood Neuropsychiatric Disorders.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>441</StartPage>
          <EndPage>444</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>441-444</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.14744/SEMB.2017.65487</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Paediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococci (PANDAS) are important neuropsychiatric disorders in childhood. Streptococcus pyogenes infection associated with tics, obsessive-compulsive disorders, and chorea co-occurrence is important. Swedo et al. have increased the awareness of this situation since 1998. How streptococcal infections give rise to this condition is not clear yet, but the severity of the symptoms is reduced by the treatment of streptococcal infections is important. Eight-year- nine-month-old girl presented with complaints of a 2-year history of upper respiratory tract infections and increased severity of blinking of eyes, throat cleaning, tic disorder and obsession with hand cleaning. In addition, choreiform movements were present and fluoxetine did not improve the symptoms. The patient was followed-up and treated with PANDAS pre-diagnosis. Streptococcus treatment and prophylaxis decreased the patient's complaints. A six-year-four months old boy, admitted with abnormal hand and body movements, which increased severity after the school period, and causing deteriorated fine motor skills during infectious periods for two years. There were also complaints with vocal tics and obsessive-compulsive disorder in the form of throat cleaning. Treatment of S. pyogenes was administered in throat culture. After the penicillin prophylaxis, the complaints decreased. In this study, two patients were presented with choreiform movements, obsessive-compulsive disorder and tic disorder due to follow-up PANDAS diagnosis. PANDAS should be considered in children with neuropsychiatric disorders, especially symptoms associated with infection periods.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright: © 2019 by The Medical Bulletin of Sisli Etfal Hospital.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kırık</LastName>
            <ForeName>Serkan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Neurology, Sutcu Imam University Faculty of Medicine, Kahramanmaras, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Güngör</LastName>
            <ForeName>Olcay</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Neurology, Sutcu Imam University Faculty of Medicine, Kahramanmaras, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kırık</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yasemin</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, Necip Fazil State Hospital, Kahramanmaras, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Sisli Etfal Hastan Tip Bul</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9424130</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1302-7123</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychiatric</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PANDAS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">streptococci</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: None declared.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2017</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32377124</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192289</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14744/SEMB.2017.65487</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">MBSEH-53-441</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Garvey M, Mittleman B, Allen AJ, Perlmutter S, et al.  Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections:clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry. 1998;155:264–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Frankovich J, Murphy TK. Overview of Treatment of Pediatric Acute-Onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2017;27:562–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5610386</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona F, Orefici G. Group A streptococcal infections and tic disorders in an Italian pediatric population. J Pediatr. 2001;138:71–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11148515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mell LK, Davis RL, Owens D. Association between streptococcal infection and obsessive-compulsive disorder, Tourette's syndrome, and tic disorder. Pediatrics. 2005;116:56–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tucker DM, Leckman JF, Scahill L, Wilf GE, LaCamera R, Cardona L, et al.  A putative poststreptococcal case of OCD with chronic tic disorder, not otherwise specified. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 1996;35:1684–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8973076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ, Manson WL, Steenhuis MP, Kallenberg CG, Minderaa RB. Association of common cold with exacerbations in pediatric but not adult patients with tic disorder:A prospective longitudinal study. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2005;15:285–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15910212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavone P, Bianchini R, Parano E, Incorpora G, Rizzo R, Mazzone L, et al.  Anti-brain antibodies in PANDAS versus uncomplicated streptococcal infection. Pediatr Neurol. 2004;30:107–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14984902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson DR, Kurlan R, Leckman J, Kaplan EL. The Human Immune Response to Streptococcal Extracellular Antigens:Clinical, Diagnostic, and Potential Pathogenetic Implications. Clin Infect Dis. 2010;50:481–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20067422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham MW. Pathogenesis of group A streptococcal infections and their sequelae. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2008;609:29–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18193655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farhood Z, Ong AA, Discolo CM. PANDAS:A systematic review of treatment options. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2016;89:149–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27619047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
