<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32429451</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>13</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Experimental Analysis of Space Trusses Using Spacers of Concrete with Steel Fiber and Sisal Fiber.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2305</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma13102305</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Space trusses are structural systems, generally made of tubes, used worldwide because of their advantages in covering long-span roofs. In addition to having a low cost, the truss weight is relatively reduced. The load capacity of these structures depends also on the strength of their node connection. Connections made with the superposition of flattened tube ends trespassed by one bolt are, generally, known as typical nodes. They are inexpensive but present eccentricities that reduce significantly the strength of such space trusses. To increase the truss load capacity, this research presents the results of an experimental program to reduce the eccentricities of the typical nodes. This reduction is done with a new type of spacer made of encapsulated concrete with steel fiber or sisal fiber. The experimental tests showed that the trusses with typical nodes collapsed under reduced load by local failure due to high distortions at the nodes. The trusses with encapsulated concrete spacer showed good results, with an increase in collapse load of 36% and failure by buckling bars.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Silva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Welington V</ForeName>
            <Initials>WV</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5200-5995</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Darcy Ribeiro Campus, University of Brasília, SG12 Building, Brasilia 70910-900, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Silva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ramon</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2004-6236</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Darcy Ribeiro Campus, University of Brasília, SG12 Building, Brasilia 70910-900, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bezerra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luciano M</ForeName>
            <Initials>LM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Darcy Ribeiro Campus, University of Brasília, SG12 Building, Brasilia 70910-900, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Freitas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cleirton A S</ForeName>
            <Initials>CAS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Federal University of Cariri - UFCA, Av. Tenente Raimundo Rocha S/N, Juazeiro do Norte, Ceará 63048-080, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bonilla</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jorge</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Group for Numerical Methods in Engineering, University of Ciego de Ávila, Ciego de Ávila 65100, Cuba.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">connection eccentricity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">experimental test</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">full-scale space truss</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sisal fiber concrete</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spacer encapsulated with concrete</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">steel fiber concrete</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32429451</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7287734</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma13102305</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">ma13102305</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makowski Z.S., Ramaswamy G.S., Eekhout M., Suresh G.R. Book Review: Analysis, Design and Construction of Steel Space Frames. Int. J. Space Struct. 2002;17:243. doi: 10.1260/026635102320321905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/026635102320321905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koushky A., Dehdashti G., Fiouz A. Nonlinear Analysis of Double-Layer Grids with Compositive Nodes under Symmetric and Unsymmetrical Gravity Loads. Int. J. Space Struct. 2007;22:133–140. doi: 10.1260/026635107781482622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/026635107781482622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makowski Z.S.  Estructuras Espaciales de Acero. 2nd ed. Editorial Gustavo Gili; Barcelona, Spain: 1972. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gioncu V. Instability Problems in Space Structures. Int. J. Space Struct. 1985;1:169–183. doi: 10.1177/026635118500100306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/026635118500100306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makoswski Z.S. A worldwide review of space structures in sports buildings. Bull. Int. Assoc. Shell Spat. Struct. 1988;29:11–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanaor A. Characteristics of Prefabricated Spatial Frame Systems. Int. J. Space Struct. 1995;10:151–173. doi: 10.1177/026635119501000303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/026635119501000303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chilton J.  Space Grid Structures. Architectural Press; London, UK: 2007. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato S., Kim J.-M., Cheong M.-C. A new proportioning method for member sections of single layer reticulated domes subjected to uniform and non-uniform loads. Eng. Struct. 2003;25:1265–1278. doi: 10.1016/S0141-0296(03)00077-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0141-0296(03)00077-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza A.S.C.  Ph.D. Thesis. Universidade de Sao Paulo; de Sao Paulo, Brazil: 2003. Análise Teórica e Experimental de Treliças Espaciais.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H., Taniguchi Y. Load-carrying capacity of semi-rigid double-layer grid structures with initial crookedness of member. Eng. Struct. 2019;184:421–433. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.01.094.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.01.094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lan T.T. Space Frame Construction in China. Adv. Steel Struct. 1996;4:55–64. doi: 10.1016/b978-008042830-7/50009-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-008042830-7/50009-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makowski Z.S. Development of jointing systems for modular prefabricated steel space structures. Light. Struct. Civ. Eng. 2002;1:24–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bangash M., Bangash T.  Elements of Spatial Structures—Analysis and Design. Thomas Telford Ltd; New York, NY, USA: 2003. pp. 10017–12398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aydincilar Y.  Master’s Thesis. Middle East Technical University; Ankara, Turkey: 2010. Optimum Design of Double-Layer Grid Systems: Comparison with Current Design Practice Using Real-Life Industrial Applications.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arekar V.A., Bhavsar B.B. Analytical Study of MERO Connector in Double Layer Grid Structure. IJLTET. 2013;2:35–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mengeringhausen M.  Mero, SISTEMA KK Nodi Sferici e Aste Tubolari. Würzburg, Germany: 2014. Rohbauwwise.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casanova P.A.A.  Estudo Numérico Experimental de Treliças Espaciais Feitas com Tubos de aço com ponta Amassada e Espaçadores de Madeira para Corrigir as Excentricidades nos nós de Ligação. Biblioteca Central da UNB; Brasilia, Brazil: 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Shami M., Mahmoud S., Elabd M. Effect of floor openings on the capacity of composite space trusses. J. King Saud Univ. Eng. Sci. 2018;30:130–140. doi: 10.1016/j.jksues.2016.03.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jksues.2016.03.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caglayan B.O., Yuksel E. Experimental and finite element investigations on the collapse of a Mero space truss roof structure—A case study. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2008;15:458–470. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2007.05.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2007.05.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebadi M., Davoodi M. Evaluate axial stiffness of the MERO connection, under the effect of hardening the screw. Int. J. Sci. Emerg. Technol. 2012;4:116–122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piroglu F., Ozakgul K. Partial collapses experienced for a steel space truss roof structure induced by ice ponds. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2016;60:155–165. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2015.11.039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2015.11.039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tarczewski R., Motro R. The Beauty of Technical Thought in Architecture—The Lifework of Stéphane Du Chateau. Int. J. Space Struct. 2015;30:203–220. doi: 10.1260/0266-3511.30.3-4.203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/0266-3511.30.3-4.203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dipaola V., Prete G. “PREMIT” System for Space Reticulated Structures Part. I: Geometrical and Structural Definitions of the Construction System. Int. J. Space Struct. 2002;18:31–45. doi: 10.1260/026635103769016618.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/026635103769016618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sampaio T.S.  Ph.D. Thesis. Universidade de Sao Paulo; de Sao Paulo, Brazil: 2004. Análise Numérica, via MEF, de Ligações em Treliças Metálicas Espaciais.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Space Frame Roofs Collapse Hartford Coliseum Following Heavy Snowfalls. ENR; New York, NY, USA: 1978. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zetlin L.  Report of the Engineering Investigation Concerning the Causes of the Collapse of the Hartford Coliseum Space Truss Roof on January 18. Hartford Press; Hartford, CT, USA: 1978. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parke G.A.R.  Ph.D. Thesis. University of Surrey; Guildford, UK: 1988. The Behaviour of Space Trusses Incorporating Novel Compression Members.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan F., Cao Z., Shen S. Elasto-plastic stability of single-layer reticulated shells. Thin-Walled Struct. 2010;48:827–836. doi: 10.1016/j.tws.2010.04.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tws.2010.04.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu F.  Structural Analysis and Design to Prevent Disproportionate Collapse. CRC Press; Boca Raton, FL, USA: 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dizdar Ç., Baran E., Topkaya C. Strength and stiffness of floor trusses fabricated from cold-formed steel lipped channels. Eng. Struct. 2019;181:437–457. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2018.12.041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2018.12.041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abedi K., Parke G. Progressive Collapse of Single-Layer Braced Domes. Int. J. Space Struct. 1996;11:291–306. doi: 10.1177/026635119601100302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/026635119601100302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papadopoulos C.M., Loricco M.T. A Case Study of Symmetry-Adapted Computation: Analysis of the Bucharest Dome; Proceedings of the International Conference on Computing and. Decision Making in Civil and Building Engineering; Montreal, QC, Canada. 14–16 June 2006; pp. 2842–2851.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan J., Qin F., Cao Z., Fan F., Mo Y. Mechanism of coupled instability of single-layer reticulated domes. Eng. Struct. 2016;114:158–170. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2016.02.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2016.02.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang C., Deng C. Static behaviors of buckling-monitoring members. Eng. Struct. 2019;178:55–69. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2018.09.086.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2018.09.086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamid Y.S.  Ph.D. Thesis. University of Surrey; Guildford, UK: 2015. Progressive Collapse of Double Layer Space Trusses.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chishti S. Book Reviews. Int. Stud. 1982;21:164–166. doi: 10.1177/0020881782021002009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0020881782021002009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Precupas V., Ivan A., Ivan M. Dynamic Analysis of the Dome with Arches and Rings from Romexpo Bucharest. Int. J. Civ. Environ. Eng. 2012;6:246–251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fredriksson G., Herrstrom M.  Master’s Thesis. Lund University; Lund, Sweden: 2017. Stability Analysis of a Large Span Timber Dome.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han Q., Liu Y., Xu Y. Study on the Assembled Hub joints in single-layer reticulated domes; Proceedings of the IASS Annual Symposia, International Association for Shell and Spatial Structures (IASS); Beijing, China. 10–14 September 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fellows L.  Coliseum Roof Collapse. Hartford Civic Center; New York, NY, USA: 1978. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petroski H.  To Engineer is Human: The role of failure in successful design. Martin’s Press; New York, NY, USA: 1985. pp. 198–200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaminetzky D., Carper K.L. Design and Construction Failures: Lessons from Forensic Investigations. J. Perform. Constr. Facil. 1992;6:71–72. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)0887-3828(1992)6:1(71).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)0887-3828(1992)6:1(71)</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin R., Delatte N. Another Look at Hartford Civic Center Coliseum Collapse. J. Perform. Constr. Facil. 2001;15:31–36. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)0887-3828(2001)15:1(31).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)0887-3828(2001)15:1(31)</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delatte N.J.J.  Beyond Failure: Forensic Case Studies for Civil. Engineers. American Society of Civil Engineers; New York, NY, USA: 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy M., Salvadori M.  Why Buildings Fall Down: How Structures Fail. Norton and Company; New York, NY, USA: 1992. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sylwester K., Edward H., Zenon Z. Failures of building constructions caused by design errors. J.S.M. Forces. 2015;178:86–99. doi: 10.5604/17318157.1200174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5604/17318157.1200174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhingra A., Bennage W. Topological optimization of truss structures using simulated annealing. Eng. Optim. 1995;24:239–259. doi: 10.1080/03052159508941192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03052159508941192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teknik K.  Master’s Thesis. Bingol University; Bingol, Turkey: 2015. Analyses of compressive elements in the finite element method.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alegre V., Ródenas V., Villalba S. Colapso de la cubierta metálica de un polideportivo; patologías singulares y recurrentes. Rev. ALCONPAT. 2012;2:37–45. doi: 10.21041/ra.v2i1.25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21041/ra.v2i1.25</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michael A.O., Razak A.R. The study of claims arising from building collapses: Case Studies from Malaysia, Nigeria, Singapore and Thailand. Civ. Environ. Res. 2013;3:113–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gul F.A., Ali C.M. Sultan Mizan Zainal Abidin Stadium Roof Collapse, Kuala Terengganu, Malaysia (Lack of Safety Issues) EPH Int. J. Math. Stat. 2016;2:14–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang J.C.L. Quality Engineering Design and Construction in Malaysia: A Fast Disappearing and Endangered Commodity? Jurutera. 2010:34–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson K. Stage Design in Fatal Radiohead Concert Collapse Called for Parts that Didn’t Exist, Witness Says.  [(accessed on 23 August 2019)];2012  Available online:  https://www.spin.com/2013/06/live-nation-charged-radiohead-stage-collapse/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza A.S.C.  Ph.D. Thesis. Universidade de Sao Paulo; de Sao Paulo, Brazil: 2018. Contribuição ao Estudo das Estruturas Metálicas Espaciais.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Magalhães J.R.M., Malite M. Treliças metálicas espaciais: Alguns aspectos relativos ao projeto e à construção. Cad. Eng. Estrut. 1998;9928:30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz-Rojas P.A.  Ph.D. Thesis. Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul Curso; do Rio Grande do Sul Curso, Brazil: 2001. Análise Não-Linear Geométrica e Material de Treliças Espaciais.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosa Y.R.D.S.  Master’s Thesis. Pontifícia Universida de Católica; do Rio de Janeiro, Brazil: 2002. Comportamento De Estruturas Espaciais Metálicas Com Nós De Ligação Do Tipo Ponta Amassada.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza A.S.C. Análise Teórica e Experimental de Treliças Espaciais. Cad. Eng. Estruturas. 2006;8:31–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Freitas C.A.S.  Análise Teórico-Experimental da Conexão Estampada de Treliça Espacial de Aço Sob Carregamentos Estático e Cíclico. Universidade de Brasília; Brasília, Brazil: 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araújo W. Ginásio Castelinho.  [(accessed on 23 August 2019)];2019  Available online:  http://edwilsonaraujo.com/tag/ginasio-castelinho/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cichoń C., Corradi L. Large displacement analysis of elastic-plastic trusses with unstable bars. Eng. Struct. 1981;3:210–218. doi: 10.1016/0141-0296(81)90003-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0141-0296(81)90003-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Sheikh A. Effect of member length imperfections on triple-layer space trusses. Eng. Struct. 1997;19:540–550. doi: 10.1016/S0141-0296(96)00120-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0141-0296(96)00120-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Y.-B., Yang C.-T., Chang T.-P., Chang P.-K. Effects of member buckling and yielding on ultimate strengths of space trusses. Eng. Struct. 1997;19:179–191. doi: 10.1016/S0141-0296(96)00032-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0141-0296(96)00032-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Sheikh A. Failure mode and strength of space truss compression chord members. Eng. Struct. 1999;21:395–405. doi: 10.1016/S0141-0296(97)00223-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0141-0296(97)00223-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murtha-Smith E. Resistance is due to high factors of safety in the design, or due to the portion removed being noncritical to the total structural action. This paper examines the vulnerability of space trusses to progressive collapse. J. Struct. Eng. 1999;114:1978–1999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Sheikh A. New space truss system—From concept to implementation. Eng. Struct. 2000;22:1070–1085. doi: 10.1016/S0141-0296(99)00051-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0141-0296(99)00051-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piroglu F., Ozakgul K., Iskender H., Trabzon L., Kahya C. Site investigation of damages occurred in a steel space truss roof structure due to ponding. Eng. Fail. Anal. 2014;36:301–313. doi: 10.1016/j.engfailanal.2013.10.018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engfailanal.2013.10.018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Augenti N., Parisi F. Buckling Analysis of a Long-Span Roof Structure Collapsed during Construction. J. Perform. Constr. Facil. 2013;27:77–88. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)CF.1943-5509.0000302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)CF.1943-5509.0000302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu R., Xue S., Li X., Mollaert M., Sun G. Preventing disproportionate displacements in an annular crossed cable-truss structure. Int. J. Space Struct. 2017;29:3–10. doi: 10.1177/0266351117694975.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0266351117694975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu F., Parke G.A.R. Assessment of the Progressive Collapse Resistance of Double-Layer Grid Space Structures Using Implicit and Explicit Methods. Int. J. Steel Struct. 2018;18:831–842. doi: 10.1007/s13296-018-0030-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13296-018-0030-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo Y.-L., Zhou P., Wang M.-Z., Pi Y.-L., Bradford M., Tong J.-Z. Experimental and numerical studies of hysteretic response of triple-truss-confined buckling-restrained braces. Eng. Struct. 2017;148:157–174. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2017.06.058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2017.06.058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Sousa W.C.A., Ikeda J.I. Análise Não Linear De Estruturas: Aplicação Do Nonlinear Analysis of Structures: Application to Crisfield’s Arc Length Method. Rev. Eng. Technol. 2017;9:148–163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rashidyan S., Sheidaii M.R. Improving double-layer space trusses collapse behavior by strengthening compression layer and weakening tension layer members. Adv. Struct. Eng. 2017;20:1757–1767. doi: 10.1177/1369433217693631.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1369433217693631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei J.-P., Tian L.-M., Hao J.-P. Improving the progressive collapse resistance of long-span single-layer spatial grid structures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;171:96–108. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.03.126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng Q., Guo X., Huang Z., Zong S. Uniaxial compression bearing capacity of bolted ball-cylinder joint. Eng. Struct. 2019;183:976–986. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.01.064.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2019.01.064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saka M., Ulker M. Optimum design of geometrically nonlinear space trusses. Comput. Struct. 1992;42:289–299. doi: 10.1016/0045-7949(92)90025-U.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0045-7949(92)90025-U</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zingoni A. On the symmetries and vibration modes of layered space grids. Eng. Struct. 2005;27:629–638. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2004.12.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2004.12.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thai H.-T., Kim S.-E. Nonlinear inelastic analysis of space frames. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2011;67:585–592. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2010.12.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2010.12.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanno Y. Worst scenario detection in limit analysis of trusses against deficiency of structural components. Eng. Struct. 2012;42:33–42. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2012.04.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2012.04.012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacerda E.G.M.  Master’s Thesis. Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Norte; Natal, Brazil: 2014. Análise Não Linear de Treliça pelo Método dos Elementos Finitos Posicional.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh J., Ju Y.K., Hwang K.-J., Kim S.-D., Lho S.-H. FREE node for a single layer free-form envelope subjected to bending moment. Eng. Struct. 2016;106:25–35. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2015.09.030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2015.09.030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinelli L.B., Alves E.C.  Um Sistema para Análise Dinâmica de Treliças Espaciais. CILAMCE; Brasília, Brazil: 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Souza A.S.C., Gonçalves R.M., Maiola C.H., Malite M. Theoretical Analysis of the Structural Performance of Space Trusses Commonly Used in Brazil. Int. J. Space Struct. 2003;18:167–179. doi: 10.1260/026635103322437454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1260/026635103322437454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bezerra L.M., De Freitas C.A.S., Matias W.T., Nagato Y. Increasing load capacity of steel space trusses with end-flattened connections. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2009;65:2197–2206. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2009.06.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2009.06.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan S.L., Cho S.H. Second-order P delta analysis and design of angle trusses allowing for imperfections and semi-rigid connections. Adv. Steel Constr. 2005;1:169–183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva W.V., Bezerra L.M., Freitas C.A.S., Silva R.S.Y.R.C. Experimental analysis of steel space trusses with correction of the stamped connection with glass fiber reinforced polymer spacer. Int. J. Eng. Sci. Res. Technol. 2018:1–11. doi: 10.5281/zenodo.1282146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5281/zenodo.1282146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy R., Hanaor A., Rizzuto N. Experimental Investigation of Prestressing in Double-Layer Grids. Int. J. Space Struct. 1994;9:21–26. doi: 10.1177/026635119400900103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/026635119400900103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mastali M., Dalvand A., Sattarifard A., Illikainen M. Development of eco-efficient and cost-effective reinforced self-consolidation concretes with hybrid industrial/recycled steel fibers. Constr. Build. Mater. 2018;166:214–226. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2018.01.147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labib W., Eden N.A.  Investigation into the Use of Fibres in Concrete Industrial Ground-Floor Slabs. Liverpool John Moores University; Liverpool, UK: 2006. pp. 466–477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenhalgh J. 20 Years of Fibre Concrete Linings in the UK, Ireland.  [(accessed on 20 March 2020)];2010  Available online:  https://www.tunneltalk.com/Fibrecrete-Oct10-20-years-of-fibrecrete-in-the-UK.php.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang J., Zhang H., Wang Z., Zhou Y., Zhang H. Structural Behavior of Ultrahigh-Performance Fiber-Reinforced Concrete Thin-Walled Arch Subjected to Asymmetric Load. Adv. Civ. Eng. 2019;2019:1–12. doi: 10.1155/2019/9276839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/9276839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi J., Zi G., Hino S., Yamaguchi K., Kim S. Influence of fiber reinforcement on strength and toughness of all-lightweight concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2014;69:381–389. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.07.074.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2014.07.074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atahan H.N., Pekmezci B., Tuncel E.Y. Behavior of PVA Fiber-Reinforced Cementitious Composites under Static and Impact Flexural Effects. J. Mater. Civ. Eng. 2013;25:1438–1445. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0000691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0000691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zia A., Ali M. Behavior of fiber reinforced concrete for controlling the rate of cracking in canal-lining. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;155:726–739. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.08.078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pang Y., Cai L., Ouyang H., Zhou X. Seismic performance assessment of different fibers reinforced concrete columns using incremental dynamic analysis. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;203:241–257. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.087.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.01.087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simoncello N., Zampieri P., Gonzalez-Libreros J., Pellegrino C. Experimental behaviour of damaged masonry arches strengthened with steel fiber reinforced mortar (SFRM) Compos. Part. B Eng. 2019;177 doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2019.107386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinola G., Meda A., Plizzari G., Rinaldi Z. Strengthening and repair of RC beams with fiber reinforced concrete. Cem. Concr. Compos. 2010;32:731–739. doi: 10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2010.07.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cemconcomp.2010.07.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altun F., Haktanir T., Ari K. Effects of steel fiber addition on mechanical properties of concrete and RC beams. Constr. Build. Mater. 2007;21:654–661. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2005.12.006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2005.12.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rashid M.U. Experimental investigation on durability characteristics of steel and polypropylene fiber reinforced concrete exposed to natural weathering action. Constr. Build. Mater. 2020;250:118910. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118910.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2020.118910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen G., Yang H., Lin C., Chen J., He Y., Zhang H. Fracture behaviour of steel fibre reinforced recycled aggregate concrete after exposure to elevated temperatures. Constr. Build. Mater. 2016;128:272–286. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.10.072.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2016.10.072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sevil T., Baran M., Bilir T., Canbay E. Use of steel fiber reinforced mortar for seismic strengthening. Constr. Build. Mater. 2011;25:892–899. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.06.096.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2010.06.096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castoldi R.D.S., De Souza L.M.S., Silva F.D.A. Comparative study on the mechanical behavior and durability of polypropylene and sisal fiber reinforced concretes. Constr. Build. Mater. 2019;211:617–628. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2019.03.282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mastali M., Dalvand A., Sattarifard A., Abdollahnejad Z., Illikainen M. Characterization and optimization of hardened properties of self-consolidating concrete incorporating recycled steel, industrial steel, polypropylene and hybrid fibers. Compos. Part. B: Eng. 2018;151:186–200. doi: 10.1016/j.compositesb.2018.06.021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.compositesb.2018.06.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H., Wang B., Xie A., Qi Y. Experimental study on dynamic mechanical properties and constitutive model of basalt fiber reinforced concrete. Constr. Build. Mater. 2017;152:154–167. doi: 10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.06.177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conbuildmat.2017.06.177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue J., Lavorato D., Bergami A.V., Nuti C., Briseghella B., Marano G.C., Ji T., Vanzi I., Tarantino A.M., Santini S. Severely Damaged Reinforced Concrete Circular Columns Repaired by Turned Steel Rebar and High-Performance Concrete Jacketing with Steel or Polymer Fibers. Appl. Sci. 2018;8:1671.  doi: 10.3390/app8091671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/app8091671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smarzewski P. Processes of Cracking and Crushing in Hybrid Fibre Reinforced High-Performance Concrete Slabs. Processes. 2019;7:49.  doi: 10.3390/pr7010049.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pr7010049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNI 11039. Steel Fibre Reinforced Concrete—Part I: Definitions, Classification Specification and Conformity—Part II: Test Method for Measuring First Crack Strength and Ductility Indexes. Italian Board for Standardization.  [(accessed on 14 September 2018)];2003  Available online:  http://store.uni.com/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>RILEM TC 162-TDF: Test and Design Methods for Steel Fibre Reinforced Concrete’-Sigma-Epsilon-Design Method-Final Recommendation.  [(accessed on 14 September 2018)]; Available online:  https://www.rilem.net/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NBR 5738, Concrete—Procedure for molding and Curing Concrete Test. Specimens. ABNT; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil: 2015. pp. 1–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NBR 7222, Mortar and Concrete—Determination of the Tension Strength of Cylindrical Specimens Submitted to Diametrical Compression—Method of test Descriptors: Mortar Concrete. ABNT; Rio de Janeiro, Brazil: 1993. pp. 1–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
