<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32462710</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>62</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Update on immune-mediated therapies for myasthenia gravis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>579</StartPage>
          <EndPage>592</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>579-592</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.26919</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>With the exception of thymectomy, immune modulatory treatment strategies and clinical trials in myasthenia gravis over the past 50 y were mainly borrowed from experience in other nonneurologic autoimmune disorders. The current experimental therapy paradigm has significantly changed such that treatments directed against the pathological mechanisms specific to myasthenia gravis are being tested, in some cases as the initial disease indication. Key advances have been made in three areas: (i) the expanded role and long-term benefits of thymectomy, (ii) complement inhibition to prevent antibody-mediated postsynaptic membrane damage, and (iii) neonatal Fc receptor (FcRn) inhibition as in vivo apheresis, removing pathogenic antibodies. Herein, we discuss these advances and the potential for these newer therapies to significantly influence the current treatment paradigms. While these therapies provide exciting new options with rapid efficacy, there are anticipated challenges to their use, especially in terms of a dramatic increase in cost of care for some patients with myasthenia gravis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Habib</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ali Aamer</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, Irvine, California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ahmadi Jazi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ghazaleh</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, Irvine, California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mozaffar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tahseen</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of California, Irvine, California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, University of California, Irvine, California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, University of California, Irvine, California.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007166">Immunosuppressive Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007166" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunosuppressive Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007167" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009157" MajorTopicYN="N">Myasthenia Gravis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013934" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thymectomy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">clinical trials</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">complement inhibition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">immunotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">myasthenia gravis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">thymectomy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32462710</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26919</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes T. The early history of myasthenia gravis. Neuromuscul Disord. 2005;15(12):878-886. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nmd.2005.08.007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Fine BM, Milani M, Kaminski HJ. Myasthenia gravis: past, present, and future. J Clin Invest. 2006;116(11):2843-2854. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI29894.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanders DB, Wolfe GI, Benatar M, et al. International consensus guidance for management of myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2016;87(4):419-425. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000002790.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Triantafyllou NI, Grapsa EI, Kararizou E, Psimenou E, Lagguranis A, Dimopoulos A. Periodic therapeutic plasma exchange in patients with moderate to severe chronic myasthenia gravis non-responsive to immunosuppressive agents: an eight year follow-up. Ther Apher Dial. 2009;13(3):174-178. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1744-9987.2009.00684.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liew WK, Powell CA, Sloan SR, et al. Comparison of plasmapheresis and intravenous immunoglobulin as maintenance therapies for juvenile myasthenia gravis. JAMA Neurol. 2014;71(5):575-580. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aydin Y, Ulas AB, Mutlu V, Colak A, Eroglu A. Thymectomy in myasthenia gravis. Eurasian J Med. 2017;49(1):48-52. https://doi.org/10.5152/eurasianjmed.2017.17009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medscape. Myasthenia gravis treatment &amp; management. Approach considerations. Pharmacologic therapy. Management of neonatal myasthenia gravis. September 2018. https://emedicine.medscape.com/article/1171206-treatment#showall. Accessed December 9, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe GI, Kaminski HJ, Aban IB, et al. Randomized trial of thymectomy in myasthenia gravis. N Engl J Med. 2016;375(6):511-522. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1602489.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhillon S. Eculizumab: a review in generalized myasthenia gravis. Drugs. 2018;78(3):367-376. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40265-018-0875-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muppidi S, Utsugisawa K, Benatar M, et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of eculizumab in generalized myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(1):14-24. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26447.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, Nowak RJ, Wolfe GI, et al. Clinical effects of the self-administered subcutaneous complement inhibitor Zilucoplan in patients with moderate to severe generalized myasthenia gravis: results of a phase 2 randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(5):582-592. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.5125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, Bril V, Burns TM, et al. Randomized phase 2 study of FcRn antagonist efgartigimod in generalized myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2019;92(23):e2661-e2673. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000007600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gronseth GS, Barohn RJ. Practice parameter: thymectomy for autoimmune myasthenia gravis (an evidence-based review): report of the Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2000;55(1):7-15. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.55.1.7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cataneo AJM, Felisberto G Jr, Cataneo DC. Thymectomy in nonthymomatous myasthenia gravis - systematic review and meta-analysis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2018;13:99. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-018-0837-z.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wekerle H, Ketelsen UP. Intrathymic pathogenesis and dual genetic control of myasthenia gravis. Lancet. 1977;1(8013):678-680.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schluep M, Willcox N, Vincent A, Dhoot GK, Newsom-Davis J. Acetylcholine receptors in human thymic myoid cells in situ: an immunohistological study. Ann Neurol. 1987;22(2):212-222. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410220205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alabdali M, Barnett C, Katzberg H, Breiner A, Bril V. Intravenous immunoglobulin as treatment for myasthenia gravis: current evidence and outcomes. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2014;10(12):1659-1665. https://doi.org/10.1586/1744666X.2014.971757.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cavalcante P, Panse RL, Berrih-aknin S, et al. The thymus in myasthenia gravis: site of “innate autoimmunity”? Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(4):467-484. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.22103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okumura M, Ohta M, Takeuchi Y, et al. The immunologic role of thymectomy in the treatment of myasthenia gravis: implication of thymus-associated B-lymphocyte subset in reduction of the anti-acetylcholine receptor antibody titer. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2003;126(6):1922-1928. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill JT, Sanders DB, Evoli A. Anti-musk antibody myasthenia gravis: clinical findings and response to treatment in two large cohorts. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(1):36-40. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.22006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauriola L, Ranelletti F, Maggiano N, et al. Thymus changes in anti-MuSK-positive and -negative myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2005;64(3):536-538. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.WNL.0000150587.71497.B6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leite MI, Ströbel P, Jones M, et al. Fewer thymic changes in MuSK antibody-positive than in MuSK antibody-negative MG: thymus in seronegative MG. Ann Neurol. 2005;57(3):444-448. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.20386.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evoli A, Padua L. Diagnosis and therapy of myasthenia gravis with antibodies to muscle-specific kinase. Autoimmun Rev. 2013;12(9):931-935. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.03.004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clifford KM, Hobson-Webb LD, Benatar M, et al. Thymectomy may not be associated with clinical improvement in MuSK myasthenia gravis: thymectomy in MuSK-MG. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(4):404-410. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.26404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drachman DB. Myasthenia Gravis. N Engl J Med. 1994;330(25):1797-1810. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM199406233302507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider-Gold C, Hagenacker T, Melzer N, Ruck T. Understanding the burden of refractory myasthenia gravis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2019;12:1756286419832242. https://doi.org/10.1177/1756286419832242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'sullivan KE, Kreaden US, Hebert AE, Eaton D, Redmond KC. A systematic review of robotic versus open and video assisted thoracoscopic surgery (VATS) approaches for thymectomy. Ann Cardiothorac Surg. 2019;8(2):174-193. https://doi.org/10.21037/acs.2019.02.04.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mao Z, Hu X, Lu Z, Hackett ML. Prognostic factors of remission in myasthenia gravis after thymectomy. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2015;48(1):18-24. https://doi.org/10.1093/ejcts/ezu309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madenci AL, Li GZ, Weil BR, Zurakowski D, Kang PB, Weldon CB. The role of thymectomy in the treatment of juvenile myasthenia gravis: a systematic review. Pediatr Surg Int. 2017;33(6):683-694. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00383-017-4086-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu K, Li J, Huang X, et al. Thymectomy is a beneficial therapy for patients with non-thymomatous ocular myasthenia gravis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurol Sci. 2017;38(10):1753-1760. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-017-3058-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evoli A, Tonali P, Bartoccioni E, Lo MM. Ocular myasthenia: diagnostic and therapeutic problems. Acta Neurol Scand. 1988;77(1):31-35. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0404.1988.tb06970.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sommer N, Sigg B, Melms A, et al. Ocular myasthenia gravis: response to long-term immunosuppressive treatment. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1997;62(2):156-162. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.62.2.156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Feng H, Yeung SC, et al. Extended transsternal thymectomy for the treatment of ocular myasthenia gravis. Ann Thorac Surg. 2011;92(6):1993-1999. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.athoracsur.2011.08.001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumm F, Wiethölter H, Fateh-Moghadam A, Dichgans J. Thymectomy in myasthenia with pure ocular symptoms. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1985;48(4):332-337. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.48.4.332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts PF, Venuta F, Rendina E, et al. Thymectomy in the treatment of ocular myasthenia gravis. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2001;122(3):562-568. https://doi.org/10.1067/mtc.2001.116191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang DS, Nakahara K, Ohno K, et al. The result of extended thymectomy in patients with myasthenia gravis of pure ocular type. Nihon Kyobu Geka Gakkai Zasshi. 1989;37(2):313-317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kodama H, Yoshida I, Iijima T, et al. Effect of extended thymectomy in myasthenia gravis of pure ocular type. Kyobu Geka. 1993;46(12):1017-1020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mineo TC, Ambrogi V. Outcomes after thymectomy in class I myasthenia gravis. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2013;145(5):1319-1324. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtcvs.2012.12.053.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Haidar M, Benatar M, Kaminski HJ. Ocular myasthenia. Neurol Clin. 2018;36(2):241-251. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ncl.2018.01.003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith SV, Lee AG. Update on ocular myasthenia gravis. Neurol Clin. 2017;35(1):115-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ncl.2016.08.008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawaguchi N, Kuwabara S, Nemoto Y, et al. Treatment and outcome of myasthenia gravis: retrospective multi-center analysis of 470 Japanese patients, 1999-2000. J Neurol Sci. 2004;224(1-2):43-47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2003.09.016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papatestas AE, Genkins G, Kornfeld P, et al. Effects of thymectomy in myasthenia gravis. Ann Surg. 1987;206(1):79-88. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000658-198707000-00013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benatar M, Kaminski H. Medical and surgical treatment for ocular myasthenia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2006;2:CD005081. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD005081.pub2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerty E, Elsais A, Argov Z, Evoli A, Gilhus NE. EFNS/ENS guidelines for the treatment of ocular myasthenia. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21(5):687-693. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.12359.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe GI, Kaminski HJ, Aban IB, et al. Long-term effect of thymectomy plus prednisone versus prednisone alone in patients with non-thymomatous myasthenia gravis: 2-year extension of the MGTX randomised trial. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(3):259-268. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30392-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips WD, Vincent A. Pathogenesis of myasthenia gravis: update on disease types, models, and mechanisms. F1000Research. 2016;5:1513. https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.8206.1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tüzün E, Christadoss P. Complement associated pathogenic mechanisms in myasthenia gravis. Autoimmun Rev. 2013;12(9):904-911. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2013.03.003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilhus NE, Skeie GO, Romi F, Lazaridis K, Zisimopoulou P, Tzartos S. Myasthenia gravis - autoantibody characteristics and their implications for therapy. Nat Rev Neurol. 2016;12(5):259-268. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2016.44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meriggioli MN, Sanders DB. Muscle autoantibodies in myasthenia gravis: beyond diagnosis? Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2012;8(5):427-438. https://doi.org/10.1586/eci.12.34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel AG, Lambert EH, Howard FM. Immune complexes (IgG and C3) at the motor end-plate in myasthenia gravis: ultrastructural and light microscopic localization and electrophysiologic correlations. Mayo Clin Proc. 1977;52(5):267-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakano S, Engel AG. Myasthenia gravis: quantitative immunocytochemical analysis of inflammatory cells and detection of complement membrane attack complex at the end-plate in 30 patients. Neurology. 1993;43(6):1167-1172. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.43.6.1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tüzün E, Huda R, Christadoss P. Complement and cytokine based therapeutic strategies in myasthenia gravis. J Autoimmun. 2011;37(2):136-143. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaut.2011.05.006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christadoss P. C5 gene influences the development of murine myasthenia gravis. J Immunol. 1988;140(8):2589-2592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tüzün E, Scott BG, Goluszko E, Higgs S, Christadoss P. Genetic evidence for involvement of classical complement pathway in induction of experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis. J Immunol. 2003;171(7):3847-3854. https://doi.org/10.4049/jimmunol.171.7.3847.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaminski HJ, Kusner LL, Richmonds C, Medof ME, Lin F. Deficiency of decay accelerating factor and CD59 leads to crisis in experimental myasthenia. Exp Neurol. 2006;202(2):287-293. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.expneurol.2006.06.003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nastuk WL, Plescia OJ, Osserman KE. Changes in serum complement activity in patients with myasthenia gravis. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med. 1960;105:177-184. https://doi.org/10.3181/00379727-105-26050.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romi F, Kristoffersen EK, Aarli JA, Gilhus NE. The role of complement in myasthenia gravis: serological evidence of complement consumption in vivo. J Neuroimmunol. 2005;158(1-2):191-194. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2004.08.002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu A, Lin H, Liu Y, Cao X, Wang X, Li Z. Correlation of C3 level with severity of generalized myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2009;40(5):801-808. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.21398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon VA, Seybold ME, Lindstrom JM, Cochrane C, Ulevitch R. Role of complement in the pathogenesis of experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis. J Exp Med. 1978;147(4):973-983. https://doi.org/10.1084/jem.147.4.973.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soltys J, Kusner LL, Young A, et al. Novel complement inhibitor limits severity of experimentally myasthenia gravis. Ann Neurol. 2009;65(1):67-75. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.21536.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soliris 300 product information. https://www.ema.europa.eu/documents/product-information/soliris-epar-product-information_en.pdf. Accessed December 12, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Inc. Eculizumab for use in AChR+ gMG. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2017/125166s422lbl.pdf. Accessed October 28, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas TC, Rollins SA, Rother RP, et al. Inhibition of complement activity by humanized anti-C5 antibody and single-chain Fv. Mol Immunol. 1996;33(17-18):1389-1401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamara LA, Topaz N, Wang X, Hariri S, Fox L, MacNeil JR. High risk for invasive meningococcal disease among patients receiving eculizumab (Soliris) despite receipt of meningococcal vaccine. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2017;66(27):734-737. https://doi.org/10.1111/ajt.14426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillmen P, Muus P, Röth A, et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of sustained eculizumab treatment in patients with paroxysmal nocturnal haemoglobinuria. Br J Haematol. 2013;162(1):62-73. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjh.12347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, Barohn RJ, Cutter GR, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase II study of eculizumab in patients with refractory generalized myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2013;48(1):76-84. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.23839.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, Utsugisawa K, Benatar M, et al. Safety and efficacy of eculizumab in anti-acetylcholine receptor antibody-positive refractory generalised myasthenia gravis (REGAIN): a phase 3, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicentre study. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16(12):976-986. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(17)30369-1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Inc. Soliris® (Eculizumab) receives marketing authorization in Japan for the treatment of patients with generalized myasthenia gravis (gMG). https://news.alexion.com/press-release/product-news/soliris-eculizumab-receives-marketing-authorization-japan-treatment-patie. Accessed November 21, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersen H, Mantegazza R, Wang JJ, et al. Eculizumab improves fatigue in refractory generalized myasthenia gravis. Qual Life Res. 2019;28(8):2247-2254. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136-019-02148-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheridan D, Yu Z-X, Zhang Y, et al. Design and preclinical characterization of ALXN1210: a novel anti-C5 antibody with extended duration of action. PLoS One. 2018;13(4):e0195909. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0195909.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. FDA approves ravulizumab-cwvz for paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria. FDA. 2019. http://www.fda.gov/drugs/resources-information-approved-drugs/fda-approves-ravulizumab-cwvz-paroxysmal-nocturnal-hemoglobinuria. Accessed September 16, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricardo A, Arata M, DeMarco S, et al. Preclinical evaluation of RA101495, a potent cyclic peptide inhibitor of C5 for the treatment of paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria. Blood. 2015;126(23):939-939. http://www.bloodjournal.org/content/126/23/939. Accessed December 13, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Transforming Complement Therapeutics. https://rapharma.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Ra-Pharma-July-2019-Corporate-Presentation.pdf. Accessed July 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>BioPharma Global. Ra Pharmaceuticals receives orphan drug designation from the U.S. FDA for RA101495 for the Treatment of Paroxysmal Nocturnal Hemoglobinuria. 2017. https://www.biopharmaglobal.com/2017/08/06/ra-pharmaceuticals-receives-orphan-drug-designation-u-s-fda-ra101495-treatment-paroxysmal-nocturnal-hemoglobinuria/. Accessed April 4, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myasthenia Gravis News. FDA grants orphan drug status to Ra Pharma's Zilucoplan as potential MG treatment. 2019. https://myastheniagravisnews.com/2019/09/05/fda-grants-orphan-drug-status-to-ra-pharmas-zilucoplan-for-mg/. Accessed November 22, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simister NE, Mostov KE. An Fc receptor structurally related to MHC class I antigens. Nature. 1989;337(6203):184-187. https://doi.org/10.1038/337184a0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roopenian DC, Christianson GJ, Sproule TJ, et al. The MHC Class I-Like IgG receptor controls perinatal IgG transport, IgG homeostasis, and fate of IgG-Fc-coupled drugs. J Immunol. 2003;170(7):3528-3533. https://doi.org/10.4049/jimmunol.170.7.3528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roopenian DC, Akilesh S. FcRn: the neonatal Fc receptor comes of age. Nat Rev Immunol. 2007;7(9):715-725. https://doi.org/10.1038/nri2155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simister NE, Rees AR. Isolation and characterization of an Fc receptor from neonatal rat small intestine. Eur J Immunol. 1985;15(7):733-738. https://doi.org/10.1002/eji.1830150718.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodewald R. pH-dependent binding of immunoglobulins to intestinal cells of the neonatal rat. J Cell Biol. 1976;71(2):666-669. https://doi.org/10.1083/jcb.71.2.666.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ulrichts P, Guglietta A, Dreier T, et al. Neonatal Fc receptor antagonist efgartigimod safely and sustainably reduces IgGs in humans. J Clin Invest. 2018;128(10):4372-4386. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI97911.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith B, Kiessling A, Lledo-Garcia R, et al. Generation and characterization of a high affinity anti-human FcRn antibody, rozanolixizumab, and the effects of different molecular formats on the reduction of plasma IgG concentration. MAbs. 2018;10:1111-1130. https://doi.org/10.1080/19420862.2018.1505464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christianson GJ, Sun VZ, Akilesh S, Pesavento E, Proetzel G, Roopenian DC. Monoclonal antibodies directed against human FcRn and their applications. MAbs. 2012;4(2):208-216. https://doi.org/10.4161/mabs.4.2.19397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nixon AE, Chen J, Sexton DJ, et al. Fully human monoclonal antibody inhibitors of the neonatal Fc receptor reduce circulating IgG in non-human primates. Front Immunol. 2015;6:176. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2015.00176.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mezo AR, McDonnell KA, Hehir CAT, et al. Reduction of IgG in nonhuman primates by a peptide antagonist of the neonatal Fc receptor FcRn. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2008;105(7):2337-2342. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0708960105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiessling P, Lledo-Garcia R, Watanabe S, et al. The FcRn inhibitor rozanolixizumab reduces human serum IgG concentration: a randomized phase 1 study. Sci Transl Med. 2017;9(414):eaan1208. doi:https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.aan1208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bril V, Benatar M, Brock M, et al. Proof-of-concept and safety of the Anti-FcRn antibody rozanolixizumab in patients with moderate-to-severe generalized myasthenia gravis (GMG): a phase 2a study (S43.001) | Neurology. https://n.neurology.org/content/92/15_Supplement/S43.001. Accessed November 22, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ling LE, Hillson JL, Tiessen RG, et al. M281, an anti-FcRn antibody: pharmacodynamics, pharmacokinetics, and safety across the full range of IgG reduction in a first-in-human study. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2019;105(4):1031-1039. https://doi.org/10.1002/cpt.1276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jolles S, Sewell WA, Misbah SA. Clinical uses of intravenous immunoglobulin. Clin Exp Immunol. 2005;142(1):1-11. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2249.2005.02834.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zinman L, Ng E, Bril V. IV immunoglobulin in patients with myasthenia gravis: a randomized controlled trial. Neurology. 2007;68(11):837-841. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000256698.69121.45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bril V, Barnett-Tapia C, Barth D, Katzberg HD. IVIG and PLEX in the treatment of myasthenia gravis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2012;1275:1-6. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2012.06767.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barth D, Nabavi Nouri M, Ng E, Nwe P, Bril V. Comparison of IVIg and PLEX in patients with myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2011;76(23):2017-2023. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821e5505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shabaninejad H, Asgharzadeh A, Rezaei N, Rezapoor A. A comparative study of intravenous immunoglobulin and subcutaneous immunoglobulin in adult patients with primary immunodeficiency diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2016;12(5):595-602. https://doi.org/10.1586/1744666X.2016.1155452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger M. Subcutaneous administration of IgG. Immunol Allergy Clin North Am. 2008;28(4):779-802, viii. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.iac.2008.07.002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leussink VI, Hartung HP, Kieseier BC, Stettner M. Subcutaneous immunoglobulins in the treatment of chronic immune-mediated neuropathies. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2016;9(4):336-343. https://doi.org/10.1177/1756285616641583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Racosta JM, Sposato LA, Kimpinski K. Subcutaneous versus intravenous immunoglobulin for chronic autoimmune neuropathies: a meta-analysis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55(6):802-809. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajdos P, Tranchant C, Clair B, et al. Treatment of myasthenia gravis exacerbation with intravenous immunoglobulin: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. Arch Neurol. 2005;62(11):1689-1693. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.62.11.1689.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajdos P, Chevret S, Toyka KV. Intravenous immunoglobulin for myasthenia gravis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;12:CD002277. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD002277.pub4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beecher G, Anderson D, Siddiqi ZA. Subcutaneous immunoglobulin in myasthenia gravis exacerbation: a prospective, open-label trial. Neurology. 2017;89(11):1135-1141. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000004365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapel HM, Spickett GP, Ericson D, Engl W, Eibl MM, Bjorkander J. The comparison of the efficacy and safety of intravenous versus subcutaneous immunoglobulin replacement therapy. J Clin Immunol. 2000;20(2):94-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaspar J, Gerritsen B, Jones A. Immunoglobulin replacement treatment by rapid subcutaneous infusion. Arch Dis Child. 1998;79(1):48-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abolhassani H, Sadaghiani MS, Aghamohammadi A, Ochs HD, Rezaei N. Home-based subcutaneous immunoglobulin versus hospital-based intravenous immunoglobulin in treatment of primary antibody deficiencies: systematic review and meta analysis. J Clin Immunol. 2012;32(6):1180-1192. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10875-012-9720-1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourque PR, Pringle CE, Cameron W, Cowan J, Chardon JW. Subcutaneous immunoglobulin therapy in the chronic management of myasthenia gravis: a retrospective cohort study. PLoS One. 2016;11(8):e0159993. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0159993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dimachkie M, Bril V, Levine T, et al. Subcutaneous immunoglobulin in myasthenia gravis: results of a North American open label study (N4.002). Neurology. 2019;92(15 Suppl):N4.002. https://n.neurology.org/content/92/15_Supplement/N4.002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monson NL, Cravens PD, Frohman EM, Hawker K, Racke MK. Effect of rituximab on the peripheral blood and cerebrospinal fluid B cells in patients with primary progressive multiple sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 2005;62(2):258-264. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.62.2.258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. Rituxan prescribing information. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2018/103705s5450lbl.pdf. Accessed November 22, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajra A, Vajpayee N, Grethlein SJ. Response of myasthenia gravis to rituximab in a patient with non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Am J Hematol. 2004;77(2):196-197. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajh.20169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorman C, Leandro M, Isenberg D. B cell depletion in autoimmune disease. Arthritis Res Ther. 2003;5(4):S17. https://doi.org/10.1186/ar1007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards JC, Cambridge G. Sustained improvement in rheumatoid arthritis following a protocol designed to deplete B lymphocytes. Rheumatol Oxf Engl. 2001;40(2):205-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leandro MJ, Edwards JC, Cambridge G. Clinical outcome in 22 patients with rheumatoid arthritis treated with B lymphocyte depletion. Ann Rheum Dis. 2002;61(10):883-888.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill JT, Sanders DB. Update on muscle-specific tyrosine kinase antibody positive myasthenia gravis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2010;23(5):530. https://doi.org/10.1097/WCO.0b013e32833c0982.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Díaz-Manera J, Rojas-García R, Gallardo E, et al. Antibodies to AChR, MuSK and VGKC in a patient with myasthenia gravis and Morvan's syndrome. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2007;3(7):405-410. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncpneuro0526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebrun C, Bourg V, Tieulie N, Thomas P. Successful treatment of refractory generalized myasthenia gravis with rituximab. Eur J Neurol. 2009;16(2):246-250. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02399.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Illa I, Diaz-Manera J, Rojas-Garcia R, et al. Sustained response to Rituximab in anti-AChR and anti-MuSK positive myasthenia gravis patients. J Neuroimmunol. 2008;201-202(C):90-94. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2008.04.039.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blum S, Gillis D, Brown H, et al. Use and monitoring of low dose rituximab in myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2011;82(6):659-663. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2010.220475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Díaz-Manera J, Martínez-Hernández E, Querol L, et al. Long-lasting treatment effect of rituximab in MuSK myasthenia. Neurology. 2012;78(3):189-193. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182407982.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tandan R, Hehir MK, Waheed W, Howard DB. Rituximab treatment of myasthenia gravis: a systematic review. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(2):185-196. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hehir MK, Hobson-Webb LD, Benatar M, et al. Rituximab as treatment for anti-MuSK myasthenia gravis: multicenter blinded prospective review. Neurology. 2017;89(10):1069-1077. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000004341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CuraVac. Myasterix. http://www.curavac.com/myasterix/. Accessed April 4, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araga S, Blalock JE. Use of complementary peptides and their antibodies in B-cell-mediated autoimmune disease: prevention of experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis with a peptide vaccine. ImmunoMethods. 1994;5(2):130-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araga S, LeBoeuf RD, Blalock JE. Prevention of experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis by manipulation of the immune network with a complementary peptide for the acetylcholine receptor. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1993;90(18):8747-8751.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araga S, Xu L, Nakashima K, Villain M, Blalock JE. A peptide vaccine that prevents experimental autoimmune myasthenia gravis by specifically blocking T cell help. FASEB J. 2000;14(1):185-196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galin FS, Chrisman CL, Cook JR, et al. Possible therapeutic vaccines for canine myasthenia gravis: implications for the human disease and associated fatigue. Brain Behav Immun. 2007;21(3):323-331. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2006.10.001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CORDIS European Commission. Final report summary - MYASTERIX (clinical safety, immunogenicity and efficacy of a therapeutic vaccine that combines peptides mimicking antigen receptors on autoimmune B and T cells associated with myasthenia gravis). https://cordis.europa.eu/project/rcn/110173/reporting/en. Accessed November 22, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cordoba F, Wieczorek G, Audet M, et al. A novel, blocking, Fc-silent anti-CD40 monoclonal antibody prolongs nonhuman primate renal allograft survival in the absence of B cell depletion. Am J Transplant. 2015;15(11):2825-2836. https://doi.org/10.1111/ajt.13377.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Im SH, Barchan D, Maiti PK, Fuchs S, Souroujon MC. Blockade of CD40 ligand suppresses chronic experimental myasthenia gravis by down-regulation of Th1 differentiation and up-regulation of CTLA-4. J Immunol. 2001;166(11):6893-6898.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American College of Rheumatology. The novel anti-CD40 monoclonal antibody CFZ533 shows beneficial effects in patients with primary Sjögren's Syndrome: a phase IIa double-blind, placebo-controlled randomized trial. https://acrabstracts.org/abstract/the-novel-anti-cd40-monoclonal-antibody-cfz533-shows-beneficial-effects-in-patients-with-primary-sjogrens-syndrome-a-phase-iia-double-blind-placebo-controlled-randomized-trial/. Accessed April 4, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novartis Pharmaceuticals. displaypdf.pdf. https://www.novctrd.com/CtrdWeb/displaypdf.nov?trialresultid=17276. Accessed April 14, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaveri SV, Mouthon L, Bayry J. Basophils and nephritis in lupus. N Engl J Med. 2010;363(11):1080-1082.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bossen C, Schneider P. BAFF, APRIL and their receptors: structure, function and signaling. Semin Immunol. 2006;18(5):263-275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantegazza R, Antozzi C. When myasthenia gravis is deemed refractory: clinical signposts and treatment strategies. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2018;11:1756285617749134. https://doi.org/10.1177/1756285617749134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>GSK. GSK receives FDA approval for a new self-injectable formulation of Benlysta (belimumab) for systemic lupus erythematosus. https://www.gsk.com/en-gb/media/press-releases/gsk-receives-fda-approval-for-a-new-self-injectable-formulation-of-benlysta-belimumab-for-systemic-lupus-erythematosus/. Accessed April 11, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lisak RP, Ragheb S. The role of B cell-activating factor in autoimmune myasthenia gravis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2012;1274:60-67. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2012.06842.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JY, Yang Y, Moon JS, et al. Serum BAFF expression in patients with myasthenia gravis. J Neuroimmunol. 2008;199(1-2):151-154. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2008.05.010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scuderi F, Alboini PE, Bartoccioni E, Evoli A. BAFF serum levels in myasthenia gravis: effects of therapy. J Neurol. 2011;258(12):2284-2285. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-011-6092-z.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hewett K, Sanders DB, Grove RA, et al. Randomized study of adjunctive belimumab in participants with generalized myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2018;90(16):e1425-e1434. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000005323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen P, Feng H, Deng J, et al. Leflunomide treatment in corticosteroid-dependent myasthenia gravis: an open-label pilot study. J Neurol. 2016;263(1):83-88. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00415-015-7944-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sussman J, Farrugia ME, Maddison P, Hill M, Leite MI, Hilton-Jones D. The Association of British Neurologists’ myasthenia gravis guidelines. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2018;1412(1):166-169. https://doi.org/10.1111/nyas.13503.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murai H. Japanese clinical guidelines for myasthenia gravis: putting into practice. Clin Exp Neuroimmunol. 2015;6(1):21-31. https://doi.org/10.1111/cen3.12180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagane Y, Suzuki S, Suzuki N, Utsugisawa K. Early aggressive treatment strategy against myasthenia gravis. Eur Neurol. 2011;65(1):16-22. https://doi.org/10.1159/000322497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Utsugisawa K, Nagane Y, Akaishi T, et al. Early fast-acting treatment strategy against generalized myasthenia gravis: early treatment for MG. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55(6):794-801. https://doi.org/10.1002/mus.25397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanders DB, Hart IK, Mantegazza R, et al. An international, phase III, randomized trial of mycophenolate mofetil in myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2008;71(6):400-406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pasnoor M, He J, Herbelin L, et al. A randomized controlled trial of methotrexate for patients with generalized myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2016;87(1):57-64. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000002795.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
