<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32491445</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK557513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719">Typhoid Fever</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhandari</LastName><ForeName>Jenish</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Punjab Medical College/University of Health Scienes</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thada</LastName><ForeName>Pawan K.</ForeName><Initials>PK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Punjab Medical College/University of Health Sciences</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeVos</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Florida</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Typhoid fever is also called enteric fever. It is a prospectively, multisystemic illness that has been a public health problem, especially in the developing world. It is caused by <i>Salmonella typhi</i> and <i>Salmonella paratyphi</i>. Enteric fever is a cumulative term that illustrates both typhoid and paratyphoid fever. Paratyphoid is clinically indistinct from typhoid fever; thus, enteric and typhoid fever are used mutually. Typhoid fever is one of the major causes of mortality and morbidity in overcrowded and unhygienic areas though comprehensive research and public health interventions have decreased the occurrence. The disease course ranges from early gastrointestinal distress to nonspecific systemic illness but ultimately may lead to multiple complications. Salmonella is said to spread by the 'four Fs" (flies, fingers, feces, fomites). Fever characteristically comes in a step-wise pattern (i.e., rises and falls alternatively) followed by headache and abdominal pain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s10">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s11">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s12">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s13">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s14">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-30719" sec="article-30719.s17">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Parry CM, Hien TT, Dougan G, White NJ, Farrar JJ. Typhoid fever. N Engl J Med. 2002 Nov 28;347(22):1770-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12456854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alikhan NF, Zhou Z, Sergeant MJ, Achtman M. A genomic overview of the population structure of Salmonella. PLoS Genet. 2018 Apr;14(4):e1007261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5886390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29621240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymans R, Vila A, van Heerwaarden CAM, Jansen CCC, Castelijn GAA, van der Voort M, Biesta-Peters EG. Rapid detection and differentiation of Salmonella species, Salmonella Typhimurium and Salmonella Enteritidis by multiplex quantitative PCR. PLoS One. 2018;13(10):e0206316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6201931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30359449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu D, Wang Z, Tian Y, Kang X, Meng C, Chen X, Pan Z, Jiao X. Prevalence of Salmonella Isolates and Their Distribution Based on Whole-Genome Sequence in a Chicken Slaughterhouse in Jiangsu, China. Front Vet Sci. 2020;7:29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7046563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32154275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moudgil KD, Narang BS. Pathogenesis of typhoid fever. Indian J Pediatr. 1985 Jul-Aug;52(417):371-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4093170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiodini J. The CDC Yellow Book app 2018. Travel Med Infect Dis. 2017 Sep;19:75-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29074406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klotz SA, Jorgensen JH, Buckwold FJ, Craven PC. Typhoid fever. An epidemic with remarkably few clinical signs and symptoms. Arch Intern Med. 1984 Mar;144(3):533-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6703825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta V, Kaur M, Datta P, Chander J. Chronic urinary carrier state due to Salmonella Typhi causing urinary tract infection in an immunocompetent healthy woman. Trop Doct. 2018 Jul;48(3):236-238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29307275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaishnavi C, Kochhar R, Singh G, Kumar S, Singh S, Singh K. Epidemiology of typhoid carriers among blood donors and patients with biliary, gastrointestinal and other related diseases. Microbiol Immunol. 2005;49(2):107-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15722595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lianou A, Nychas GE, Koutsoumanis KP. Variability in the adaptive acid tolerance response phenotype of Salmonella enterica strains. Food Microbiol. 2017 Apr;62:99-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27889173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohbata S, Yokoyama H, Yabuuchi E. Cytopathogenic effect of Salmonella typhi GIFU 10007 on M cells of murine ileal Peyer's patches in ligated ileal loops: an ultrastructural study. Microbiol Immunol. 1986;30(12):1225-37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3553868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van de Vosse E, Ali S, de Visser AW, Surjadi C, Widjaja S, Vollaard AM, van Dissel JT. Susceptibility to typhoid fever is associated with a polymorphism in the cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR). Hum Genet. 2005 Oct;118(1):138-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16078047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornick RB. Pathogenesis of typhoid fever. J Egypt Public Health Assoc. 1970;45(1):247-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5484829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getahun Strobel A, Parry CM, Crump JA, Rosa V, Jenney A, Naidu R, Mulholland K, Strugnell RA. A retrospective study of patients with blood culture-confirmed typhoid fever in Fiji during 2014-2015: epidemiology, clinical features, treatment and outcome. Trans R Soc Trop Med Hyg. 2019 Dec 01;113(12):764-770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6907003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31638153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keddy KH, Sooka A, Smith AM, Musekiwa A, Tau NP, Klugman KP, Angulo FJ, GERMS-SA  Typhoid Fever in South Africa in an Endemic HIV Setting. PLoS One. 2016;11(10):e0164939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5079545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27780232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A, Ahmed B. Jaundice in typhoid patients: differentiation from other common causes of fever and jaundice in the tropics. Ann Afr Med. 2010 Jul-Sep;9(3):135-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20710103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhutta ZA. Current concepts in the diagnosis and treatment of typhoid fever. BMJ. 2006 Jul 08;333(7558):78-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1489205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16825230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogasale V, Ramani E, Mogasale VV, Park J. What proportion of Salmonella Typhi cases are detected by blood culture? A systematic literature review. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2016 May 17;15(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4869319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27188991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilman RH, Terminel M, Levine MM, Hernandez-Mendoza P, Hornick RB. Relative efficacy of blood, urine, rectal swab, bone-marrow, and rose-spot cultures for recovery of Salmonella typhi in typhoid fever. Lancet. 1975 May 31;1(7918):1211-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">48834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Näsström E, Jonsson P, Johansson A, Dongol S, Karkey A, Basnyat B, Tran Vu Thieu N, Trinh Van T, Thwaites GE, Antti H, Baker S. Diagnostic metabolite biomarkers of chronic typhoid carriage. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2018 Jan;12(1):e0006215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5802941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29373578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mawazo A, Bwire GM, Matee MIN. Performance of Widal test and stool culture in the diagnosis of typhoid fever among suspected patients in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. BMC Res Notes. 2019 Jun 05;12(1):316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6551910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31167646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goay YX, Chin KL, Tan CL, Yeoh CY, Ja'afar JN, Zaidah AR, Chinni SV, Phua KK. Identification of Five Novel Salmonella Typhi-Specific Genes as Markers for Diagnosis of Typhoid Fever Using Single-Gene Target PCR Assays. Biomed Res Int. 2016;2016:8905675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5126401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27975062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanata CF, Levine MM, Ristori C, Black RE, Jimenez L, Salcedo M, Garcia J, Sotomayor V. Vi serology in detection of chronic Salmonella typhi carriers in an endemic area. Lancet. 1983 Aug 20;2(8347):441-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6192305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Punjabi NH, Hoffman SL, Edman DC, Sukri N, Laughlin LW, Pulungsih SP, Rivai AR, Sututo, Moechtar A, Woodward TE. Treatment of severe typhoid fever in children with high dose dexamethasone. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 1988 Aug;7(8):598-600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3050856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen SC, Best E, Nourse C. Non-typhoidal Salmonella infections in children: Review of literature and recommendations for management. J Paediatr Child Health. 2017 Oct;53(10):936-941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28556448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiwaskar M. Cefixime-ofloxacin Combination in the Management of Uncomplicated Typhoid Fever in the Indian Community Setting. J Assoc Physicians India. 2019 Mar;67(3):75-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson BR, Iqbal S, Mahon B, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)  Updated recommendations for the use of typhoid vaccine--Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, United States, 2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2015 Mar 27;64(11):305-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4584884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25811680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burki T. Typhoid conjugate vaccine gets WHO prequalification. Lancet Infect Dis. 2018 Mar;18(3):258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7129039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29485093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appiah GD, Chung A, Bentsi-Enchill AD, Kim S, Crump JA, Mogasale V, Pellegrino R, Slayton RB, Mintz ED. Typhoid Outbreaks, 1989-2018: Implications for Prevention and Control. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2020 Jun;102(6):1296-1305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7253085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32228795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qamar FN, Yousafzai MT, Khaliq A, Karim S, Memon H, Junejo A, Baig I, Rahman N, Bhurgry S, Afroz H, Sami U. Adverse events following immunization with typhoid conjugate vaccine in an outbreak setting in Hyderabad, Pakistan. Vaccine. 2020 Apr 23;38(19):3518-3523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32201138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization Typhoid vaccines: WHO position paper, March 2018 - Recommendations. Vaccine. 2019 Jan 07;37(2):214-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29661581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellon G, Eme AL, Rohaut B, Brossier F, Epelboin L, Caumes E. Encephalitis in a traveller with typhoid fever: efficacy of corticosteroids. J Travel Med. 2017 Sep 01;24(6)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29088483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EY, Park JY, Kim DR, Song M, Sahastrabuddhe S, Kim H, Chon Y, Yang JS. Comparison of anti-Vi IgG responses between two clinical studies of typhoid Vi conjugate vaccines (Vi-DT vs Vi-TT). PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2020 Mar;14(3):e0008171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32203521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambire JL, Ouedraogo S, Ouedraogo S, Ouangre E, Traore SS. [Results after surgical management of ileal perforation due to typhoid fever, about 29 cases in Ouahigouya (Burkina Faso)]. Bull Soc Pathol Exot. 2017 Dec;110(5):298-299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29127649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>STUART BM, PULLEN RL. Typhoid; clinical analysis of 360 cases. Arch Intern Med (Chic) 1946 Dec;78(6):629-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20278487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr RW. Leptospirosis. Clin Infect Dis. 1995 Jul;21(1):1-6; quiz 7-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7578715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derrick EH. "Q" fever, a new fever entity: clinical features, diagnosis and laboratory investigation. Rev Infect Dis. 1983 Jul-Aug;5(4):790-800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6622891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura K, Fujita H, Miura T, Igata Y, Narita M, Monma N, Hara Y, Saito K, Matsumoto A, Kanemitsu K. A case of typhoidal tularemia in a male Japanese farmer. Int J Infect Dis. 2018 Jun;71:56-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29635071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Annamalai AK, Padmini K. Melioidosis. Indian J Med Res. 2019 Apr;149(4):561-562.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6676822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31411183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen R, Babushkin F, Shapiro M, Uda M, Atiya-Nasagi Y, Finn T. Case Report: Typhoid Fever and Spotted Fever Group Rickettsiosis Presenting Concomitantly in an Indian Immigrant. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2018 Oct;99(4):864-866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6159590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30062981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banerjee B, Madiyal M, Madhava PK, Agarwal M, Mukhopadhyay C. Typhoid spondylodiscitis mimicking tuberculosis in a teenage girl. J Infect Public Health. 2018 Jan - Feb;11(1):136-137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28602673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zerfu B, Medhin G, Mamo G, Getahun G, Tschopp R, Legesse M. Community-based prevalence of typhoid fever, typhus, brucellosis and malaria among symptomatic individuals in Afar Region, Ethiopia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2018 Oct;12(10):e0006749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6191156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waddington CS, Darton TC, Woodward WE, Angus B, Levine MM, Pollard AJ. Advancing the management and control of typhoid fever: a review of the historical role of human challenge studies. J Infect. 2014 May;68(5):405-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24491597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cruz Espinoza LM, McCreedy E, Holm M, Im J, Mogeni OD, Parajulee P, Panzner U, Park SE, Toy T, Haselbeck A, Seo HJ, Jeon HJ, Kim JH, Kwon SY, Kim JH, Parry CM, Marks F. Occurrence of Typhoid Fever Complications and Their Relation to Duration of Illness Preceding Hospitalization: A Systematic Literature Review and Meta-analysis. Clin Infect Dis. 2019 Oct 30;69(Suppl 6):S435-S448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6821330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumwenda M, Iroh Tam PY. An adolescent with multi-organ involvement from typhoid fever. Malawi Med J. 2019 Jun;31(2):159-160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6698619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31452851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esmailpour N, Rasoolinejad M, Abdolbaghi MH. Cardiopulmonary manifestations of typhoid fever: a prospective analysis of 65 cases in Iran. Trop Doct. 2006 Apr;36(2):118-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16611453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman SL, Punjabi NH, Kumala S, Moechtar MA, Pulungsih SP, Rivai AR, Rockhill RC, Woodward TE, Loedin AA. Reduction of mortality in chloramphenicol-treated severe typhoid fever by high-dose dexamethasone. N Engl J Med. 1984 Jan 12;310(2):82-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6361558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majid A, Bin Waqar SH, Rehan A, Kumar S. From Gut to Heart: Havoc in a Young Patient with Typhoid-associated Cardiomyopathy. Cureus. 2019 Jul 01;11(7):e5049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6716968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31511802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohilla R, Bhatia M, Gupta P, Singh A, Shankar R, Omar BJ. Salmonella osteomyelitis: A rare extraintestinal manifestation of an endemic pathogen. J Lab Physicians. 2019 Apr-Jun;11(2):164-170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31160858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koshiol J, Wozniak A, Cook P, Adaniel C, Acevedo J, Azócar L, Hsing AW, Roa JC, Pasetti MF, Miquel JF, Levine MM, Ferreccio C, Gallbladder Cancer Chile Working Group  Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi and gallbladder cancer: a case-control study and meta-analysis. Cancer Med. 2016 Nov;5(11):3310-3235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5119987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27726295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunn JS, Marshall JM, Baker S, Dongol S, Charles RC, Ryan ET. Salmonella chronic carriage: epidemiology, diagnosis, and gallbladder persistence. Trends Microbiol. 2014 Nov;22(11):648-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4252485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25065707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32491445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
