<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32491378</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK557446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496">Myotonic Dystrophy</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vydra</LastName><ForeName>Darrell G.</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UT Health San Antonio</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rayi</LastName><ForeName>Appaji</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Charleston Area Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Myotonic dystrophy (DM) is considered a subgroup of myopathy and the most common type of muscular dystrophy that begins in adulthood. There are two major forms recognized based on clinical and molecular presentation: Myotonic dystrophy type I (DM1), known as Steinert disease, and myotonic dystrophy type II (DM2), or proximal myotonic myopathy which is a milder variety of DMI. These are progressive, multisystem genetic disorders. Clinical presentation is diverse and can range from asymptomatic electrical myotonia to severe weakness and disability, including cardiac conduction defects, infertility, cataracts, and insulin resistance. A congenital form of DM type 1 is associated with an apparent developmental disability. Myotonia is characterized by impaired relaxation of muscles after voluntary contraction due to repetitive depolarization of the muscle membrane. Myotonia, due to myotonic dystrophy, improves with repeated exercise and is worsened by exposure to cold.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s13">Consultations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s14">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s15">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s16">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-25496" sec="article-25496.s17">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hahn C, Salajegheh MK. Myotonic disorders: A review article. Iran J Neurol. 2016 Jan 05;15(1):46-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4852070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27141276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook JD, McCurrach ME, Harley HG, Buckler AJ, Church D, Aburatani H, Hunter K, Stanton VP, Thirion JP, Hudson T. Molecular basis of myotonic dystrophy: expansion of a trinucleotide (CTG) repeat at the 3' end of a transcript encoding a protein kinase family member. Cell. 1992 Feb 21;68(4):799-808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1310900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranum LP, Rasmussen PF, Benzow KA, Koob MD, Day JW. Genetic mapping of a second myotonic dystrophy locus. Nat Genet. 1998 Jun;19(2):196-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thornton CA. Myotonic dystrophy. Neurol Clin. 2014 Aug;32(3):705-19, viii.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4105852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25037086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahadevan M, Tsilfidis C, Sabourin L, Shutler G, Amemiya C, Jansen G, Neville C, Narang M, Barceló J, O'Hoy K. Myotonic dystrophy mutation: an unstable CTG repeat in the 3' untranslated region of the gene. Science. 1992 Mar 06;255(5049):1253-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1546325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner C, Hilton-Jones D. The myotonic dystrophies: diagnosis and management. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2010 Apr;81(4):358-67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20176601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yotova V, Labuda D, Zietkiewicz E, Gehl D, Lovell A, Lefebvre JF, Bourgeois S, Lemieux-Blanchard E, Labuda M, Vézina H, Houde L, Tremblay M, Toupance B, Heyer E, Hudson TJ, Laberge C. Anatomy of a founder effect: myotonic dystrophy in Northeastern Quebec. Hum Genet. 2005 Jul;117(2-3):177-87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15883838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoser B, Montagnese F, Bassez G, Fossati B, Gamez J, Heatwole C, Hilbert J, Kornblum C, Kostera-Pruszczyk A, Krahe R, Lusakowska A, Meola G, Moxley R, Thornton C, Udd B, Formaker P, Myotonic Dystrophy Foundation  Consensus-based care recommendations for adults with myotonic dystrophy type 2. Neurol Clin Pract. 2019 Aug;9(4):343-353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31583190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaki M, Boyd PA, Impey L, Roberts A, Chamberlain P. Congenital myotonic dystrophy: prenatal ultrasound findings and pregnancy outcome. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2007 Mar;29(3):284-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17238150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Echenne B, Bassez G. Congenital and infantile myotonic dystrophy. Handb Clin Neurol. 2013;113:1387-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23622362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logigian EL, Blood CL, Dilek N, Martens WB, Moxley RT, Wiegner AW, Thornton CA, Moxley RT. Quantitative analysis of the "warm-up" phenomenon in myotonic dystrophy type 1. Muscle Nerve. 2005 Jul;32(1):35-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15880468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wenninger S, Montagnese F, Schoser B. Core Clinical Phenotypes in Myotonic Dystrophies. Front Neurol. 2018;9:303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29770119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callus E, Bertoldo EG, Beretta M, Boveri S, Cardani R, Fossati B, Brigonzi E, Meola G. Neuropsychological and Psychological Functioning Aspects in Myotonic Dystrophy Type 1 Patients in Italy. Front Neurol. 2018;9:751.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6160752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30298045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meola G, Cardani R. Myotonic Dystrophy Type 2: An Update on Clinical Aspects, Genetic and Pathomolecular Mechanism. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2015 Jul 22;2(s2):S59-S71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5240594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27858759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricker K, Koch MC, Lehmann-Horn F, Pongratz D, Otto M, Heine R, Moxley RT. Proximal myotonic myopathy: a new dominant disorder with myotonia, muscle weakness, and cataracts. Neurology. 1994 Aug;44(8):1448-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8058147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auvinen S, Suominen T, Hannonen P, Bachinski LL, Krahe R, Udd B. Myotonic dystrophy type 2 found in two of sixty-three persons diagnosed as having fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 2008 Nov;58(11):3627-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2585600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18975316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoser B.  Myotonic Dystrophy Type 2. In: Adam MP, Ardinger HH, Pagon RA, Wallace SE, Bean LJH, Gripp KW, Mirzaa GM, Amemiya A, editors. GeneReviews® [Internet] University of Washington, Seattle; Seattle (WA): 2006. Sep 21, </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Achiron A, Barak Y, Magal N, Shohat M, Cohen M, Barar R, Gadoth N. Abnormal liver test results in myotonic dystrophy. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1998 Jun;26(4):292-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9649014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khoshbakht R, Soltanzadeh A, Zamani B, Abdi S, Gharagozli K, Kahrizi K, Khoshbakht R, Nafissi S. Correlation between distribution of muscle weakness, electrophysiological findings and CTG expansion in myotonic dystrophy. J Clin Neurosci. 2014 Jul;21(7):1123-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24417793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nojszewska M, Lusakowska A, Gawel M, Sierdzinski J, Sulek A, Krysa W, Elert-Dobkowska E, Seroka A, Kaminska AM, Kostera-Pruszczyk A. The needle EMG findings in myotonia congenita. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2019 Dec;49:102362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31610484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burakgazi AZ. Electrodiagnostic findings in myotonic dystrophy: A study on 12 patients. Neurol Int. 2019 Nov 29;11(4):8205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31871599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pongratz D, Schultz D, Koppenwallner C, Hübner G. [Diagnostic value of muscle biopsy findings in myotonic dystrophy (Curschmann-Steinert) (author's transl)]. Klin Wochenschr. 1979 Mar 01;57(5):215-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">431031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally EM, Mann DL, Pinto Y, Bhakta D, Tomaselli G, Nazarian S, Groh WJ, Tamura T, Duboc D, Itoh H, Hellerstein L, Mammen PPA. Clinical Care Recommendations for Cardiologists Treating Adults With Myotonic Dystrophy. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020 Feb 18;9(4):e014006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7070199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32067592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashizawa T, Gagnon C, Groh WJ, Gutmann L, Johnson NE, Meola G, Moxley R, Pandya S, Rogers MT, Simpson E, Angeard N, Bassez G, Berggren KN, Bhakta D, Bozzali M, Broderick A, Byrne JLB, Campbell C, Cup E, Day JW, De Mattia E, Duboc D, Duong T, Eichinger K, Ekstrom AB, van Engelen B, Esparis B, Eymard B, Ferschl M, Gadalla SM, Gallais B, Goodglick T, Heatwole C, Hilbert J, Holland V, Kierkegaard M, Koopman WJ, Lane K, Maas D, Mankodi A, Mathews KD, Monckton DG, Moser D, Nazarian S, Nguyen L, Nopoulos P, Petty R, Phetteplace J, Puymirat J, Raman S, Richer L, Roma E, Sampson J, Sansone V, Schoser B, Sterling L, Statland J, Subramony SH, Tian C, Trujillo C, Tomaselli G, Turner C, Venance S, Verma A, White M, Winblad S. Consensus-based care recommendations for adults with myotonic dystrophy type 1. Neurol Clin Pract. 2018 Dec;8(6):507-520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6294540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arikawa-Hirasawa E, Le AH, Nishino I, Nonaka I, Ho NC, Francomano CA, Govindraj P, Hassell JR, Devaney JM, Spranger J, Stevenson RE, Iannaccone S, Dalakas MC, Yamada Y. Structural and functional mutations of the perlecan gene cause Schwartz-Jampel syndrome, with myotonic myopathy and chondrodysplasia. Am J Hum Genet. 2002 May;70(5):1368-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC447613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11941538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charles G, Zheng C, Lehmann-Horn F, Jurkat-Rott K, Levitt J. Characterization of hyperkalemic periodic paralysis: a survey of genetically diagnosed individuals. J Neurol. 2013 Oct;260(10):2606-13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3824221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23884711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller TM. Differential diagnosis of myotonic disorders. Muscle Nerve. 2008 Mar;37(3):293-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18067134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke D, Skuse NF, Lethlean AK. An analysis of myotonia in paramyotonia congenita. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1974 Aug;37(8):900-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC494804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4422263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ørstavik K, Wallace SC, Torbergsen T, Abicht A, Erik Tangsrud S, Kerty E, Rasmussen M. A de novo Mutation in the SCN4A Gene Causing Sodium Channel Myotonia. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2015 Jun 04;2(2):181-184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5240542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27858731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu XL, Huang XJ, Shen JY, Zhou HY, Luan XH, Wang T, Chen SD, Wang Y, Tang HD, Cao L. Myotonia congenita: novel mutations in CLCN1 gene. Channels (Austin) 2015;9(5):292-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4826137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26260254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groh WJ, Groh MR, Shen C, Monckton DG, Bodkin CL, Pascuzzi RM. Survival and CTG repeat expansion in adults with myotonic dystrophy type 1. Muscle Nerve. 2011 May;43(5):648-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21484823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Die-Smulders CE, Höweler CJ, Thijs C, Mirandolle JF, Anten HB, Smeets HJ, Chandler KE, Geraedts JP. Age and causes of death in adult-onset myotonic dystrophy. Brain. 1998 Aug;121 ( Pt 8):1557-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9712016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benhayon D, Lugo R, Patel R, Carballeira L, Elman L, Cooper JM. Long-term arrhythmia follow-up of patients with myotonic dystrophy. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2015 Mar;26(3):305-10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25546341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhry SP, Frishman WH. Myotonic dystrophies and the heart. Cardiol Rev. 2012 Jan-Feb;20(1):1-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22143278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petri H, Ahtarovski KA, Vejlstrup N, Vissing J, Witting N, Køber L, Bundgaard H. Myocardial fibrosis in patients with myotonic dystrophy type 1: a cardiovascular magnetic resonance study. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2014 Aug 01;16:59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25086734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta N, N Saxena K, Kumar Panda A, Anand R, Mishra A. Myotonic dystrophy: an anaesthetic dilemma. Indian J Anaesth. 2009 Dec;53(6):688-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2900080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20640098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Pfeiffer RM, Alsaggaf R, Meeraus W, Gage JC, Anderson LA, Bremer RC, Nikolenko N, Lochmuller H, Greene MH, Gadalla SM. Risk of skin cancer among patients with myotonic dystrophy type 1 based on primary care physician data from the U.K. Clinical Practice Research Datalink. Int J Cancer. 2018 Mar 15;142(6):1174-1181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5773358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29114849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32491378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
