<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32504376</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1950</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>80</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Drugs</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Drugs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Edoxaban and the Issue of Drug-Drug Interactions: From Pharmacology to Clinical Practice.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1065</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1083</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1065-1083</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40265-020-01328-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Edoxaban, a direct factor Xa inhibitor, is the latest of the non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants (NOACs). Despite being marketed later than other NOACs, its use is now spreading in current clinical practice, being indicated for both thromboprophylaxis in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation (NVAF) and for the treatment and prevention of venous thromboembolism (VTE). In patients with multiple conditions, the contemporary administration of several drugs can cause relevant drug-drug interactions (DDIs), which can affect drugs' pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics. Usually, all the NOACs are considered to have significantly fewer DDIs than vitamin K antagonists; notwithstanding, this is actually not true, all of them are affected by DDIs with drugs that can influence the activity (induction or inhibition) of P-glycoprotein (P-gp) and cytochrome P450 3A4, both responsible for the disposition and metabolism of NOACs to a different extent. In this review/expert opinion, we focused on an extensive report of edoxaban DDIs. All the relevant drugs categories have been examined to report on significant DDIs, discussing the impact on edoxaban pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics, and the evidence for dose adjustment. Our analysis found that, despite a restrained number of interactions, some strong inhibitors/inducers of P-gp and drug-metabolising enzymes can affect edoxaban concentration, just as it happens with other NOACs, implying the need for a dose adjustment. However, our analysis of edoxaban DDIs suggests that given the small propensity for interactions of this agent, its use represents an acceptable clinical decision. Still, DDIs can be significant in certain clinical situations and a careful evaluation is always needed when prescribing NOACs.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Corsini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alberto</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacological and Biomolecular Sciences, University of Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Multimedica IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ferri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicola</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical and Pharmacological Sciences, University of Padua, Padua, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Proietti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marco</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1452-2478</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences and Community Health, University of Milan, Via della Commenda 19, 20122, Milan, Italy. marco.proietti@unimi.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Unit, Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico, Milan, Italy. marco.proietti@unimi.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Liverpool Centre for Cardiovascular Science, University of Liverpool and Liverpool Heart &amp; Chest Hospital, Liverpool, UK. marco.proietti@unimi.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boriani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giuseppe</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Division, Department of Biomedical, Metabolic and Neural Sciences, University of Modena and Reggio Emilia, Policlinico di Modena, Modena, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>New Zealand</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Drugs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7600076</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0012-6667</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D020168">ATP Binding Cassette Transporter, Subfamily B, Member 1</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D065692">Cytochrome P-450 CYP3A Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D065427">Factor Xa Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011725">Pyridines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013844">Thiazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>NDU3J18APO</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C552171">edoxaban</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020168" MajorTopicYN="Y">ATP Binding Cassette Transporter, Subfamily B, Member 1</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000819" MajorTopicYN="N">agonists</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D065692" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytochrome P-450 CYP3A Inhibitors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004347" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Interactions</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D065427" MajorTopicYN="N">Factor Xa Inhibitors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054539" MajorTopicYN="N">Medication Therapy Management</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011725" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyridines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013844" MajorTopicYN="N">Thiazoles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013923" MajorTopicYN="N">Thromboembolism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32504376</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-020-01328-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40265-020-01328-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boriani G, Diemberger I, Martignani C, Biffi M, Branzi A. The epidemiological burden of atrial fibrillation: a challenge for clinicians and health care systems. Eur Heart J. 2006;27:893–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16543253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lip GY, Laroche C, Ioachim PM, Rasmussen LH, Vitali-Serdoz L, Petrescu L, et al. Prognosis and treatment of atrial fibrillation patients by European cardiologists: one year follow-up of the EURObservational Research Programme-Atrial Fibrillation General Registry Pilot Phase (EORP-AF Pilot registry). Eur Heart J. 2014;35(47):3365–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25176940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boriani G, Proietti M, Laroche C, Fauchier L, Marin F, Nabauer M, et al. Contemporary stroke prevention strategies in 11 096 European patients with atrial fibrillation: a report from the EURObservational Research Programme on Atrial Fibrillation (EORP-AF) Long-Term General Registry. Europace. 2018;20(5):747–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boriani G, et al. Asymptomatic atrial fibrillation: clinical correlates, management and outcomes in the EORP-AF Pilot General Registry. Am J Med. 2014;128:509–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25534423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Timp JF, Braekkan SK, Versteeg HH, Cannegieter SC. Epidemiology of cancer-associated venous thrombosis. Blood. 2013;122(10):1712–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23908465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steffel J, Verhamme P, Potpara TS, Albaladejo P, Antz M, Desteghe L, et al. The 2018 European Heart Rhythm Association Practical Guide on the use of non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants in patients with atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J. 2018;39(16):1330–933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lip GYH, Banerjee A, Boriani G, Chiang CE, Fargo R, Freedman B, et al. Antithrombotic therapy for atrial fibrillation: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2018;154(5):1121–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30144419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Go AS, Hylek EM, Phillips KA, Chang Y, Henault LE, Selby JV, et al. Prevalence of diagnosed atrial fibrillation in adults: national implications for rhythm management and stroke prevention: the AnTicoagulation and Risk Factors in Atrial Fibrillation (ATRIA) Study. JAMA. 2001;285(18):2370–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11343485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Wang TJ, Leip EP, Larson MG, Levy D, Vasan RS, et al. Lifetime risk for development of atrial fibrillation: the Framingham Heart Study. Circulation. 2004;110(9):1042–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyasaka Y, Barnes ME, Gersh BJ, Cha SS, Bailey KR, Abhayaratna WP, et al. Secular trends in incidence of atrial fibrillation in Olmsted County, Minnesota, 1980 to 2000, and implications on the projections for future prevalence. Circulation. 2006;114(2):119–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16818816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Go AS, Mozaffarian D, Roger VL, Benjamin EJ, Berry JD, Blaha MJ, et al. Heart disease and stroke statistics–2014 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2014;129(3):e28–e292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24352519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppens M, Eikelboom JW, Hart RG, Yusuf S, Lip GY, Dorian P, et al. The CHA2DS2-VASc score identifies those patients with atrial fibrillation and a CHADS2 score of 1 who are unlikely to benefit from oral anticoagulant therapy. Eur Heart J. 2013;34(3):170–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23018151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nutescu EA, Shapiro NL, Ibrahim S, West P. Warfarin and its interactions with foods, herbs and other dietary supplements. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2006;5(3):433–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16610971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teklay G, Shiferaw N, Legesse B, Bekele ML. Drug-drug interactions and risk of bleeding among inpatients on warfarin therapy: a prospective observational study. Thromb J. 2014;12:20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249791</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4171718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>[Internet] Sde. Lixiana 60mg Film-Coated Tablets. Summary of Product Characteristics (SPC)d(eMC) [Internet]. Last Updated on eMC 31 July 2017. https://www.medicinesorguk/emc/product/6905 . Accessed 4 Jan 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LIXIANA. 2018. https://www.emaeuropaeu/docs/en_GB/document_library/EPAR_-_Product_Information/human/002629/WC500189045.pdf .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ay C, Pabinger I, Cohen AT. Cancer-associated venous thromboembolism: burden, mechanisms, and management. Thromb Haemost. 2017;117(2):219–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27882374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firkins R, Eisfeld H, Keinki C, Buentzel J, Hochhaus A, Schmidt T, et al. The use of complementary and alternative medicine by patients in routine care and the risk of interactions. J Cancer Res Clin Oncol. 2018;144(3):551–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29356888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis EL, Oh B, Butow PN, Mullan BA, Clarke S. Cancer patient disclosure and patient-doctor communication of complementary and alternative medicine use: a systematic review. Oncologist. 2012;17(11):1475–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22933591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3500370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosher DF. Blood coagulation and fibrinolysis: an overview. Clin Cardiol. 1990;13(4 Suppl 6):VI5–VI11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2191814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eriksson BI, Quinlan DJ, Weitz JI. Comparative pharmacodynamics and pharmacokinetics of oral direct thrombin and factor xa inhibitors in development. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2009;48(1):1–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19071881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furugohri T, Isobe K, Honda Y, Kamisato-Matsumoto C, Sugiyama N, Nagahara T, et al. DU-176b, a potent and orally active factor Xa inhibitor: in vitro and in vivo pharmacological profiles. J Thromb Haemost. 2008;6(9):1542–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18624979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsushima N, Lee F, Sato T, Weiss D, Mendell J. Bioavailability and safety of the factor Xa inhibitor edoxaban and the effects of quinidine in healthy subjects. Clin Pharmacol Drug Dev. 2013;2(4):358–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27121940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogata K, Mendell-Harary J, Tachibana M, Masumoto H, Oguma T, Kojima M, et al. Clinical safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics of the novel factor Xa inhibitor edoxaban in healthy volunteers. J Clin Pharmacol. 2010;50(7):743–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20081065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parasrampuria DA, Kanamaru T, Connor A, Wilding I, Ogata K, Shimoto Y, et al. Evaluation of regional gastrointestinal absorption of edoxaban using the enterion capsule. J Clin Pharmacol. 2015;55(11):1286–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969414</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4755158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakeam HA, Al-Sanea N. Effect of major gastrointestinal tract surgery on the absorption and efficacy of direct acting oral anticoagulants (DOACs). J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2017;43(3):343–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28050755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendell J, Tachibana M, Shi M, Kunitada S. Effects of food on the pharmacokinetics of edoxaban, an oral direct factor Xa inhibitor, in healthy volunteers. J Clin Pharmacol. 2011;51(5):687–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20534818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Logrippo S, Ricci G, Sestili M, Cespi M, Ferrara L, Palmieri GF, et al. Oral drug therapy in elderly with dysphagia: between a rock and a hard place! Clin Interv Aging. 2017;12:241–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28203065</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5293185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coluzzi PH, Fairbairn BS. The management of pain in terminally ill cancer patients with difficulty swallowing. Am J Hosp Palliat Care. 1999;16(6):731–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11094910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreira Silva R, Novaes MRCG. Interactions between drugs and drug-nutrient in enteral nutrition: a review based on evidences. Nutr Hosp. 2014;30(3):514–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25238825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">25238825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duchin K, Duggal A, Atiee GJ, Kidokoro M, Takatani T, Shipitofsky NL, et al. An Open-label crossover study of the pharmacokinetics of the 60-mg edoxaban tablet crushed and administered either by a nasogastric tube or in apple puree in healthy adults. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2018;57(2):221–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28512699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikkaichi T, Yoshigae Y, Masumoto H, Imaoka T, Rozehnal V, Fischer T, et al. Edoxaban transport via P-glycoprotein is a key factor for the drug's disposition. Drug Metab Dispos. 2014;42(4):520–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24459178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aller SG, Yu J, Ward A, Weng Y, Chittaboina S, Zhuo R, et al. Structure of P-glycoprotein reveals a molecular basis for poly-specific drug binding. Science. 2009;323(5922):1718–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2720052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parasrampuria DA, Truitt KE. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of edoxaban, a non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulant that inhibits clotting factor Xa. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2016;55(6):641–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26620048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steffel J, Giugliano RP, Braunwald E, Murphy SA, Mercuri M, Choi Y, et al. Edoxaban versus warfarin in atrial fibrillation patients at risk of falling: ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 analysis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2016;68(11):1169–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27609678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toda Kato E, Giugliano RP, Ruff CT. Efficacy and safety of edoxaban for the management of elderly patients with atrial fibrillation: engage AF-TIMI 48. Circulation. 2014;130:A16612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato ET, Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, Koretsune Y, Yamashita T, Kiss RG, et al. Efficacy and safety of edoxaban in elderly patients with atrial fibrillation in the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5(5):e003432.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27207971</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4889207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruff CT, Giugliano RP, Braunwald E, Hoffman EB, Deenadayalu N, Ezekowitz MD, et al. Comparison of the efficacy and safety of new oral anticoagulants with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: a meta-analysis of randomised trials. Lancet. 2014;383(9921):955–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24315724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohula EA, Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, Kuder JF, Murphy SA, Antman EM, et al. Impact of renal function on outcomes with edoxaban in the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Circulation. 2016;134(1):24–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27358434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krekels EH, Niebecker R, Karlsson MO, Miller R, Shimizu T, Karlsson KE, et al. Population pharmacokinetics of edoxaban in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation in the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 study, a phase III clinical trial. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2016;55(9):1079–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26951208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grundvold I, et al. Body weight and risk of atrial fibrillation in 7,169 patients with newly diagnosed type 2 diabetes; an observational study. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2015;14:5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25589001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4299152</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adeli K, Taghibiglou C, Van Iderstine SC, Lewis GF. Mechanisms of hepatic very low-density lipoprotein overproduction in insulin resistance. Trends Cardiovasc Med. 2001;11(5):170–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11597827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindner SM, Fordyce CB, Hellkamp AS, Lokhnygina Y, Piccini JP, Breithardt G, et al. Treatment consistency across levels of baseline renal function with rivaroxaban or warfarin: a ROCKET AF (rivaroxaban once-daily, oral, direct factor Xa Inhibition Compared With Vitamin K antagonism for prevention of stroke and embolism trial in atrial fibrillation) analysis. Circulation. 2017;135(10):1001–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28264892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bathala MS, Masumoto H, Oguma T, He L, Lowrie C, Mendell J. Pharmacokinetics, biotransformation, and mass balance of edoxaban, a selective, direct factor Xa inhibitor, in humans. Drug Metab Dispos. 2012;40(12):2250–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22936313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jonsson S, Simonsson US, Miller R, Karlsson MO. Population pharmacokinetics of edoxaban and its main metabolite in a dedicated renal impairment study. J Clin Pharmacol. 2015;55(11):1268–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25966665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heidbuchel H, Verhamme P, Alings M, Antz M, Diener HC, Hacke W, et al. Updated European Heart Rhythm Association Practical Guide on the use of non-vitamin K antagonist anticoagulants in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation. Europace. 2015;17(10):1467–507.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26324838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gnoth MJ, Buetehorn U, Muenster U, Schwarz T, Sandmann S. In vitro and in vivo P-glycoprotein transport characteristics of rivaroxaban. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2011;338(1):372–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21515813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gosselin RC, Adcock DM, Bates SM, Douxfils J, Favaloro EJ, Gouin-Thibault I, et al. International Council for Standardization in Haematology (ICSH) recommendations for laboratory measurement of direct oral anticoagulants. Thromb Haemost. 2018;118(3):437–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29433148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Testa S, Tripodi A, Legnani C, Pengo V, Abbate R, Dellanoce C, et al. Plasma levels of direct oral anticoagulants in real life patients with atrial fibrillation: results observed in four anticoagulation clinics. Thromb Res. 2016;137:178–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26672898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsh Raccah B, Rottenstreich A, Zacks N, Muszkat M, Matok I, Perlman A, et al. Drug interaction as a predictor of direct oral anticoagulant drug levels in atrial fibrillation patients. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2018;46(4):521–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stöllberger C. Drug interactions with new oral anticoagulants in elderly patients. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2017;10(11):1191–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28825849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, Braunwald E, Murphy SA, Wiviott SD, Halperin JL, et al. Edoxaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2013;369(22):2093–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24251359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>GaBHaPMaSAaSMaSLavKRaMM R. Edoxaban for the long-term treatment of venous thromboembolism: rationale and design of the Hokusai-venous thromboembolism study–methodological implications for clinical trials. J Thromb Haemost. 2013;11(7):1287–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendell J, Zahir H, Matsushima N, Noveck R, Lee F, Chen S, et al. Drug-drug interaction studies of cardiovascular drugs involving P-glycoprotein, an efflux transporter, on the pharmacokinetics of edoxaban, an oral factor Xa inhibitor. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2013;13(5):331–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23784266</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3781304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holtzman CW, Wiggins BS, Spinler SA. Role of P-glycoprotein in statin drug interactions. Pharmacotherapy. 2006;26(11):1601–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17064205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steffel J, Giugliano RP, Braunwald E, Murphy SA, Atar D, Heidbuchel H, et al. Edoxaban vs. warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation on amiodarone: a subgroup analysis of the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Eur Heart J. 2015;36(33):2239–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25971288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SAVAYSA FDA SmPC. 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salazar DE, Mendell J, Kastrissios H, Green M, Carrothers TJ, Song S, et al. Modelling and simulation of edoxaban exposure and response relationships in patients with atrial fibrillation. Thromb Haemost. 2012;107(5):925–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22398655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>[Internet] Sde. Lixiana 60mg Film-Coated Tablets. Summary of Product Characteristics (SPC)d(eMC) [Internet]. Last updated on eMC: 10 Aug 2018. https://www.medicinesorguk/emc/product/6905/smpc . Accessed 22 Oct 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aisenberg J, Chatterjee-Murphy P, Friedman Flack K, Weitz JI, Ruff CT, Nordio F, et al. Gastrointestinal bleeding with edoxaban versus warfarin: results from the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial (effective anticoagulation with factor Xa next generation in atrial fibrillation-thrombolysis in myocardial infarction). Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2018;11(5):e003998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29748353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansen ML, Sorensen R, Clausen MT, Fog-Petersen ML, Raunso J, Gadsboll N, et al. Risk of bleeding with single, dual, or triple therapy with warfarin, aspirin, and clopidogrel in patients with atrial fibrillation. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170(16):1433–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20837828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendell J, Lee F, Chen S, Worland V, Shi M, Samama MM. The effects of the antiplatelet agents, aspirin and naproxen, on pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of the anticoagulant edoxaban, a direct factor Xa inhibitor. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol. 2013;62(2):212–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23615159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu H, Ruff CT, Giugliano RP, Murphy SA, Nordio F, Patel I, et al. Concomitant use of single antiplatelet therapy with edoxaban or warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: analysis from the ENGAGE AF-TIMI48 trial. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5(2):e002587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26908401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4802446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wessler JD, Grip LT, Mendell J, Giugliano RP. The P-glycoprotein transport system and cardiovascular drugs. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013;61(25):2495–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23563132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh J, Shin D, Lim KS, Lee S, Jung KH, Chu K, et al. Aspirin decreases systemic exposure to clopidogrel through modulation of P-glycoprotein but does not alter its antithrombotic activity. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2014;95(6):608–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24566733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teng R, Butler K. A pharmacokinetic interaction study of ticagrelor and digoxin in healthy volunteers. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;69(10):1801–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23748750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teng R, Mitchell P, Butler K. Effect of rifampicin on the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of ticagrelor in healthy subjects. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;69(4):877–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23093043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mega JL, Close SL, Wiviott SD, Shen L, Walker JR, Simon T, et al. Genetic variants in ABCB1 and CYP2C19 and cardiovascular outcomes after treatment with clopidogrel and prasugrel in the TRITON-TIMI 38 trial: a pharmacogenetic analysis. Lancet. 2010;376(9749):1312–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20801494</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3036672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gelosa P, Castiglioni L, Tenconi M, Baldessin L, Racagni G, Corsini A, et al. Pharmacokinetic drug interactions of the non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants (NOACs). Pharmacol Res. 2018;135:60–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30040996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiggins BS, Saseen JJ, Page RL 2nd, Reed BN, Sneed K, Kostis JB, et al. Recommendations for management of clinically significant drug-drug interactions with statins and select agents used in patients with cardiovascular disease: a scientific statement from the American heart association. Circulation. 2016;134(21):e468–e495495.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27754879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antoniou T, Macdonald EM, Yao Z, Hollands S, Gomes T, Tadrous M, et al. Association between statin use and ischemic stroke or major hemorrhage in patients taking dabigatran for atrial fibrillation. CMAJ Can Med Assoc J. 2017;189(1):E4–E10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd RA, Stern RH, Stewart BH, Wu X, Reyner EL, Zegarac EA, et al. Atorvastatin coadministration may increase digoxin concentrations by inhibition of intestinal P-glycoprotein-mediated secretion. J Clin Pharmacol. 2000;40(1):91–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10631627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schelleman H, Bilker WB, Brensinger CM, Wan F, Yang YX, Hennessy S. Fibrate/Statin initiation in warfarin users and gastrointestinal bleeding risk. Am J Med. 2010;123(2):151–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20103024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2813204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corsini A, Bellosta S, Davidson MH. Pharmacokinetic interactions between statins and fibrates. Am J Cardiol. 2005;96(9A):44K–K49 (discussion 34K–5K).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16291014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prueksaritanont T, Tang C, Qiu Y, Mu L, Subramanian R, Lin JH. Effects of fibrates on metabolism of statins in human hepatocytes. Drug Metab Dispos. 2002;30(11):1280–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12386136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ehrhardt M, Lindenmaier H, Burhenne J, Haefeli WE, Weiss J. Influence of lipid lowering fibrates on P-glycoprotein activity in vitro. Biochem Pharmacol. 2004;67(2):285–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14698041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamazaki M, Li B, Louie SW, Pudvah NT, Stocco R, Wong W, et al. Effects of fibrates on human organic anion-transporting polypeptide 1B1-, multidrug resistance protein 2- and P-glycoprotein-mediated transport. Xenobiotica. 2005;35(7):737–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16316932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry CA, Lyon RA, Ling H. Clinical efficacy and safety of evolocumab for low-density lipoprotein cholesterol reduction. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2016;12:163–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27143910</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">27143910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gouin-Thibault I, Delavenne X, Blanchard A, Siguret V, Salem JE, Narjoz C, et al. Interindividual variability in dabigatran and rivaroxaban exposure: contribution of ABCB1 genetic polymorphisms and interaction with clarithromycin. J Thromb Haemost. 2017;15(2):273–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27893182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes J, Crowe A. Inhibition of P-glycoprotein-mediated efflux of digoxin and its metabolites by macrolide antibiotics. J Pharmacol Sci. 2010;113(4):315–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20724802</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parasrampuria DA, Mendell J, Shi M, Matsushima N, Zahir H, Truitt K. Edoxaban drug-drug interactions with ketoconazole, erythromycin, and cyclosporine. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2016;82(6):1591–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27530188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5099547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greiner B, Eichelbaum M, Fritz P, Kreichgauer HP, von Richter O, Zundler J, et al. The role of intestinal P-glycoprotein in the interaction of digoxin and rifampin. J Clin Investig. 1999;104(2):147–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10411543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuetz EG, Schinkel AH, Relling MV, Schuetz JD. P-glycoprotein: a major determinant of rifampicin-inducible expression of cytochrome P4503A in mice and humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1996;93(9):4001–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8633005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendell J, Chen S, He L, Desai M, Parasramupria DA. The effect of rifampin on the pharmacokinetics of edoxaban in healthy adults. Clin Drug Investig. 2015;35(7):447–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26068927</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4488474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roedler R, Neuhauser MM, Penzak SR. Does metronidazole interact with CYP3A substrates by inhibiting their metabolism through this metabolic pathway? Or should other mechanisms be considered? Ann Pharmacother. 2007;41(4):653–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17374625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalets EL, Williams CR. Drug interactions with cisapride: clinical implications. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2000;39(1):49–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10926350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim KA, Park JY. Effect of metronidazole on the pharmacokinetics of fexofenadine, a P-glycoprotein substrate, in healthy male volunteers. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2010;66(7):721–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20306185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heit JA, Silverstein MD, Mohr DN, Petterson TM, O'Fallon WM, Melton LJ 3rd. Risk factors for deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism: a population-based case-control study. Arch Intern Med. 2000;160(6):809–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10737280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raskob GE, van Es N, Verhamme P, Carrier M, Di Nisio M, Garcia D, et al. Edoxaban for the treatment of cancer-associated venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(7):615–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29231094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiczer TE, Levine LB, Brumbaugh J, Coggins J, Zhao Q, Ruppert AS, et al. Cumulative incidence, risk factors, and management of atrial fibrillation in patients receiving ibrutinib. Blood Adv. 2017;1(20):1739–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29296820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5728342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorp BC, Badoux X. Atrial fibrillation as a complication of ibrutinib therapy: clinical features and challenges of management. Leukemia Lymphoma. 2018;59(2):311–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28629235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boriani G, Corradini P, Cuneo A, Falanga A, Foa R, Gaidano G, et al. Practical management of ibrutinib in the real life: focus on atrial fibrillation and bleeding. Hematol Oncol. 2018;36:624–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29512173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilad R. Management of seizures following a stroke: what are the options? Drugs Aging. 2012;29(7):533–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22540349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stollberger C, Finsterer J. Interactions between non-vitamin K oral anticoagulants and antiepileptic drugs. Epilepsy Res. 2016;126:98–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27450623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giessmann T, May K, Modess C, Wegner D, Hecker U, Zschiesche M, et al. Carbamazepine regulates intestinal P-glycoprotein and multidrug resistance protein MRP2 and influences disposition of talinolol in humans. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2004;76(3):192–200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15371980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moerman L, Wyffels L, Slaets D, Raedt R, Boon P, De Vos F. Antiepileptic drugs modulate P-glycoproteins in the brain: a mice study with (11)C-desmethylloperamide. Epilepsy Res. 2011;94(1–2):18–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21277169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jing X, Liu X, Wen T, Xie S, Yao D, Liu X, et al. Combined effects of epileptic seizure and phenobarbital induced overexpression of P-glycoprotein in brain of chemically kindled rats. Br J Pharmacol. 2010;159(7):1511–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20233212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2850407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvariza S, Fagiolino P, Vazquez M, Feria-Romero I, Orozco-Suarez S. Chronic administration of phenytoin induces efflux transporter overexpression in rats. Pharmacol Rep. 2014;66(6):946–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25443719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eyal S, Lamb JG, Smith-Yockman M, Yagen B, Fibach E, Altschuler Y, et al. The antiepileptic and anticancer agent, valproic acid, induces P-glycoprotein in human tumour cell lines and in rat liver. Br J Pharmacol. 2006;149(3):250–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16894351</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2014277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang R, Faussat AM, Majdak P, Perrot JY, Chaoui D, Legrand O, et al. Valproic acid inhibits proliferation and induces apoptosis in acute myeloid leukemia cells expressing P-gp and MRP1. Leukemia. 2004;18(7):1246–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15116123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang-Tilz Y, Tilz C, Wang B, Tilz GP, Stefan H. Influence of lamotrigine and topiramate on MDR1 expression in difficult-to-treat temporal lobe epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2006;47(2):233–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16499746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewer D, O'Reilly C, Mojtabai R, Evans-Lacko S. Antidepressant use in 27 European countries: associations with sociodemographic, cultural and economic factors. Br J Psychiatry. 2015;207(3):221–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26159603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurer-Spurej E, Pittendreigh C, Solomons K. The influence of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors on human platelet serotonin. Thromb Haemost. 2004;91(1):119–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14691577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schalekamp T, Klungel OH, Souverein PC, de Boer A. Increased bleeding risk with concurrent use of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors and coumarins. Arch Intern Med. 2008;168(2):180–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18227365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>[Internet] Sde. Pradaxa 150 mg hard capsules. Summary of Product Characteristics (SPC)d(eMC) [Internet]. Last Updated on eMC 30-Jan-2015. Last Updated on eMC 30-Jan-2015. https://www.medicinesorguk/emc/medicine/24839 . Accessed 18 May 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xarelto 20mg film-coated tablets—Summary of Product Characteristics (SmPC)—(eMC). Date of first authorisation: 30 September 2008. Date of latest renewal: 22 May 2018. https://www.medicines.org.uk/emc/product/2793/smpc .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss J, Dormann SM, Martin-Facklam M, Kerpen CJ, Ketabi-Kiyanvash N, Haefeli WE. Inhibition of P-glycoprotein by newer antidepressants. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2003;305(1):197–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12649369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapoor A, Iqbal M, Petropoulos S, Ho HL, Gibb W, Matthews SG. Effects of sertraline and fluoxetine on p-glycoprotein at barrier sites: in vivo and in vitro approaches. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(2):e56525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468867</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3585317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sansone RA, Sansone LA. Warfarin and antidepressants: happiness without hemorrhaging. Psychiatry. 2009;6(7):24–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19724766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spina E, de Leon J. Metabolic drug interactions with newer antipsychotics: a comparative review. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol. 2007;100(1):4–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17214606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang JS, Zhu HJ, Markowitz JS, Donovan JL, DeVane CL. Evaluation of antipsychotic drugs as inhibitors of multidrug resistance transporter P-glycoprotein. Psychopharmacology. 2006;187(4):415–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16810505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moons T, de Roo M, Claes S, Dom G. Relationship between P-glycoprotein and second-generation antipsychotics. Pharmacogenomics. 2011;12(8):1193–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21843066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wyss-Coray T. Ageing, neurodegeneration and brain rejuvenation. Nature. 2016;539(7628):180–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27830812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5172605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niccoli T, Partridge L. Ageing as a risk factor for disease. Curr Biol. 2012;22(17):R741–R752752.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22975005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tysnes OB, Storstein A. Epidemiology of Parkinson's disease. J Neural Transm. 2017;124(8):901–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150045</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayeux R, Stern Y. Epidemiology of Alzheimer disease. Cold Spring Harbor Perspect Med. 2012;2(8):a006239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mittur A, Gupta S, Modi NB. Pharmacokinetics of Rytary((R)), an extended-release capsule formulation of carbidopa-levodopa. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2017;56(9):999–1014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28236251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5563351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vautier S, Milane A, Fernandez C, Buyse M, Chacun H, Farinotti R. Interactions between antiparkinsonian drugs and ABCB1/P-glycoprotein at the blood-brain barrier in a rat brain endothelial cell model. Neurosci Lett. 2008;442(1):19–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18598736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wynalda MA, Wienkers LC. Assessment of potential interactions between dopamine receptor agonists and various human cytochrome P450 enzymes using a simple in vitro inhibition screen. Drug Metab Dispos. 1997;25(10):1211–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9321526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller T. ABCB1: is there a role in the drug treatment of Parkinson's disease? Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2018;14(2):127–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29224383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pingili R, Vemulapalli S, Mullapudi SS, Nuthakki S, Pendyala S, Kilaru N. Pharmacokinetic interaction study between flavanones (hesperetin, naringenin) and rasagiline mesylate in wistar rats. Drug Dev Ind Pharm. 2016;42(7):1110–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26530401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller T. Pharmacokinetic drug evaluation of safinamide mesylate for the treatment of mid-to-late stage Parkinson's disease. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2017;13(6):693–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28537214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Csoti I, Storch A, Müller W, Jost WH. Drug interactions with selegiline versus rasagiline. Basal Ganglia. 2012;2:S27–S31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bicker J, Fortuna A, Alves G, Soares-da-Silva P, Falcao A. Elucidation of the Impact of P-glycoprotein and breast cancer resistance protein on the brain distribution of catechol-O-methyltransferase inhibitors. Drug Metab Dispos. 2017;45(12):1282–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dingemanse J, Meyerhoff C, Schadrack J. Effect of the catechol-O-methyltransferase inhibitor entacapone on the steady-state pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of warfarin. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2002;53(5):485–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1874359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeong HJ, Lee HS, Kim KS, Kim YK, Yoon D, Park SW. Sterol-dependent regulation of proprotein convertase subtilisin/kexin type 9 expression by sterol-regulatory element binding protein-2. J Lipid Res. 2008;49(2):399–409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17921436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki T, Fukami T, Tomono K. Possible involvement of cationic-drug sensitive transport systems in the blood-to-brain influx and brain-to-blood efflux of amantadine across the blood-brain barrier. Biopharm Drug Dispos. 2015;36(2):126–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mceneny-King A, Eginton AN, Rao PP. Investigating the binding interactions of the anti-Alzheimer's drug donepezil with CYP3A4 and P-glycoprotein. Bioorg Med Chem Lett. 2015;25(2):297–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25499431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang F, Fu Y. A review of clinical pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of galantamine, a reversible acetylcholinesterase inhibitor for the treatment of Alzheimer's disease, in healthy subjects and patients. Curr Clin Pharmacol. 2010;5(2):115–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20156150</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kraus W, et al. The national physical activity plan: a call to action from the American heart association: a science advisory from the American heart association. Circulation. 2015;131(21):1932–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25918126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polinsky RJ. Clinical pharmacology of rivastigmine: a new-generation acetylcholinesterase inhibitor for the treatment of Alzheimer's disease. Clin Ther. 1998;20(4):634–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9737824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohamed LA, Keller JN, Kaddoumi A. Role of P-glycoprotein in mediating rivastigmine effect on amyloid-beta brain load and related pathology in Alzheimer's disease mouse model. Biochem Biophys Acta. 2016;1862(4):778–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West TA, Perram J, Holloway CJ. Use of direct oral anticoagulants for treatment of atrial fibrillation in patients with HIV: a review. Curr Opin HIV AIDS. 2017;12(6):554–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28799998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caplan MR, Daar ES, Corado KC. Next generation fixed dose combination pharmacotherapies for treating HIV. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2018;19(6):589–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29557204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clumeck N, Pozniak A, Raffi F. European AIDS Clinical Society (EACS) guidelines for the clinical management and treatment of HIV-infected adults. HIV Med. 2008;9(2):65–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18257769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tseng A, Foisy M. Important drug-drug interactions in HIV-infected persons on antiretroviral therapy: an update on new interactions between HIV and Non-HIV drugs. Curr Infect Dis Rep. 2012;14(1):67–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22125049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathias AA, German P, Murray BP, Wei L, Jain A, West S, et al. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of GS-9350: a novel pharmacokinetic enhancer without anti-HIV activity. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2010;87(3):322–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20043009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar P, Gordon LA, Brooks KM, George JM, Kellogg A, McManus M, et al. Differential influence of the antiretroviral pharmacokinetic enhancers ritonavir and cobicistat on intestinal P-glycoprotein transport and the pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic disposition of dabigatran. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2017;61(11):e01201-17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5655101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koff RS. Review article: the efficacy and safety of sofosbuvir, a novel, oral nucleotide NS5B polymerase inhibitor, in the treatment of chronic hepatitis C virus infection. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2014;39(5):478–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24387618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garimella T, You X, Wang R, Huang SP, Kandoussi H, Bifano M, et al. A review of daclatasvir drug-drug interactions. Adv Ther. 2016;33(11):1867–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27664109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5083780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertz R. Bristol-Myers Squibb HCV full development portfolio overview. In: Plenary presentation presented at the 14th International Workshop on Clinical Pharmacology, April 22–24, 2014, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodin S, Basset T, Jacqueroux E, Delezay O, Clotagatide A, Perek N, et al. In vitro comparison of the role of P-glycoprotein and breast cancer resistance protein on direct oral anticoagulants disposition. Eur J Drug Metab Pharmacokinet. 2018;43(2):183–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28895074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garrison KL, German P, Mogalian E, Mathias A. The drug-drug interaction potential of antiviral agents for the treatment of chronic hepatitis C infection. Drug Metab Dispos. 2018;46:1212–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
