<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">32603495</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0579</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>24</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European journal of dental education : official journal of the Association for Dental Education in Europe</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Dent Educ</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Rubber Dam Isolation Survey (RDIS) for adhesive restorative treatments.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>724</StartPage>
          <EndPage>733</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>724-733</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/eje.12562</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Rubber dam isolation is considered as an essential component of modern adhesive dentistry. However, dental students do not always use it due to several barriers they face on their clinical practice. The aim of this study was to design and validate a questionnaire based on the COM-B model to measure students' implementation of rubber dam isolation in restorative treatments with adhesive materials.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 7-item questionnaire was developed based on the COM-B model, with questions measuring the Capability, Opportunity (Relevance and Resources), and Motivation to perform rubber dam isolation (Behaviour). Content validation of the questionnaire was conducted by experts in aesthetic/restorative dentistry that assessed the clarity, coherence and relevance of the questions. The final survey was administered to a dental student population from three large private universities in the Dominican Republic. Descriptive analysis, t tests, polychoric correlations and a path analysis were carried out to establish the validity of the instrument.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 382 students from three universities completed the questionnaire. According to the COM-B path model, the significant predictors of the implementation of rubber dam isolation were Capability and Motivation for University A, Motivation and Opportunity-Resources for University B, and Opportunity-Relevance and Capability for University C.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The RDIS is a very short, easy to administer and valid questionnaire that can be applied by the universities to determine where they need to focus their interventions to achieve better rubber dam isolation implementation by their students.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abreu-Placeres</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ninoska</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1742-8102</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Biomaterials and Dentistry Research Center (CIBO-UNIBE), Academic Research Department, Universidad Iberoamericana, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yunes Fragoso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paula</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6155-3595</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Biomaterials and Dentistry Research Center (CIBO-UNIBE), Academic Research Department, Universidad Iberoamericana, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cruz Aponte</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paola</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Dentistry, Universidad Tecnológica de Santiago, Santiago, Dominican Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Garrido</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luis Eduardo</ForeName>
            <Initials>LE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8932-6063</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Pontificia Universidad Católica Madre y Maestra, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Dent Educ</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9712132</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1396-5883</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003738">Dental Cements</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003738" MajorTopicYN="N">Dental Cements</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004497" MajorTopicYN="N">Education, Dental</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019239" MajorTopicYN="Y">Practice Patterns, Dentists'</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016733" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rubber Dams</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental education</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental students</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rubber dam</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">survey</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603495</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/eje.12562</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ammann P, Kolb A, Lussi A, Seemann R. Influence of rubber dam on objective and subjective parameters of stress during dental treatment of children and adolescents - a randomized controlled clinical pilot study. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2013;23:110-115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill E, Rubel B. Do dental educators need to improve their approach to teaching rubber dam use? J Dent Educ. 2008;72:1177-1181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varughese RE, Andrews P, Sigal MJ, Azarpazhooh A. An assessment of direct restorative material use in posterior teeth by American and Canadian Pediatric Dentists: II. Rubber Dam Isolation. Pediatr Dent. 2016;38:497-501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou H, Li Y, Lian X, Yan Y, Dai X, Wang G. Frequency and influencing factors of rubber dam usage in Tianjin: a questionnaire survey. Int J Dent. 2016;2016:7383212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan W, O'Connell A. The attitudes of undergraduate dental students to the use of the rubber dam. J Ir Dent Assoc. 2007;53:87-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad IA. Rubber dam usage for endodontic treatment a review. Int Endod J. 2009;42:963-972.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madarati A. Dental-dam for infection control and patient safety during clinical endodontic treatment: preferences of dental patients. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15:1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Sabri FA, Elmarakby AM, Hassan AM. Attitude and knowledge of isolation in operative field among undergraduate dental students. Eur J Dent. 2017;11:83-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slawinski D, Wilson S. Rubber dam use- a survey of paediatric dentistry training programs and private practitioners. Pediatr Dent. 2010;32:64-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lynch CD, McConnell RJ. Attitudes and use of rubber dam by Irish general dental practitioners. Int Endod J. 2007;40:427-432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Udoye C, Jafarzadeh H. Rubber dam use among a subpopulation. J Oral Sci. 2010;52:245-249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mala S, Lynch CD, Burke FM, Dummer PMH. Attitudes of final year dental students to the use of rubber dam. Int Endod J. 2009;42:632-638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Li C, Yuan H, et al. Rubber dam isolation for restorative treatment in dental patients. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;9:CD009858.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chisini LA, Collares K, Cademartori MG, et al. Restorations in primary teeth: a systematic review on survival and reasons for failures. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2018;28:123-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGrath C. Behavioral sciences in the promotion of oral health. J Dent Res. 2019;98:1418-1424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michie S, Atkins L, West R. The Behaviour Change Wheel: A Guide to Designing Interventions. Great Britain, UK: Silverback Publishing; 2014:325.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asimakopoulou K, Newton JT. The contributions of behaviour change science towards dental public health practice: a new paradigm. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 2015;43:2-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barker F, Atkins L, de Lusignan S. Applying the COM-B behaviour model and behaviour change wheel to develop an intervention to improve hearing-aid use in adult auditory rehabilitation. Int J Audiol. 2016;55:90-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maidment DW, Ali YH, Ferguson MA. Applying the COM-B model to assess the usability of smartphone-connected listening devices in adults with hearing loss. J Am Acad Audiol. 2019;30:417-430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heneghan MB, Hussain T, Barrera L, et al. Applying the COM-B model to patient-reported barriers to medication adherence in pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2020;67:e28216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson C, Eliasson L, Barber N, Weinman J. Applying COM-B to medication adherence: a suggested framework for research and interventions. Eur Health Psychol. 2014;16:7-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander KE, Brijnath B, Mazza D. Barriers and enablers to delivery of the Healthy Kids Check: an analysis informed by the Theoretical Domains Framework and COM-B model. Implement Sci. 2014;9:1-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flannery C, McHugh S, Anaba AE, et al. Enablers and barriers to physical activity in overweight and obese pregnant women: an analysis informed by the theoretical domains framework and COM-B model. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18:178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton JT, Asimakopoulou K. Minimally invasive dentistry: enhancing oral health related behaviour through behaviour change techniques. Br Dent J. 2017;223:147-150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Rawahi SH, Asimakopoulou K, Newton JT. Factors related to reducing free sugar intake among white ethnic adults in the UK: a qualitative study. BDJ Open. 2018;4:1-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abreu Placeres N, Newton JT, Pitts N, et al. Understanding dentists' caries management: the COM-B ICCMS™ questionnaire. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 2018;46:545-554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobar Pérez J, Cuervo MA. Validez De Contenido Y Juicio De Expertos: Una Aproximación A Su Utilización. Avances Med. 2008;6:27-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behling O, Law KS. Translating Questionnaires and Other Research Instruments. Problems and Solutions. (Sage University Paper Series on Quantitative Applications in the Social Sciences, No. 07-131). Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 2000:73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norman G. Likert scales, levels of measurement and the “laws” of statistics. Adv Health Sci Educ. 2010;15:625-632.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Winter JC, Dodou D. Five-point Likert items: t test versus Mann-Whitney-Wilcoxon. Pract Assess Res Evaluation. 2010;15:1-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J. A power primer. Psychol Bull. 1992;112:155-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olsson U. Maximum likelihood estimation of the polychoric correlation coefficient. Psychometrika. 1979;44:443-460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garrido LE, Abad FJ, Ponsoda V. A new look at Horn's parallel analysis with ordinal variables. Psychol Methods. 2013;18:454-474.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rhemtulla M, Brosseau-Liard PÉ, Savalei V. When can categorical variables be treated as continuous? A comparison of robust continuous and categorical SEM estimation methods under suboptimal conditions. Psychol Methods. 2012;17:354-373.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi D, Lee T, Fairchild AJ, Maydeu-Olivares A. Fitting ordinal factor analysis models with missing data: a comparison between pairwise deletion and multiple imputation. Educ Psychol Meas. 2020;80:41-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham JW. Missing data analysis: Making it work in the real world. Annu Rev Psycho. 2009;60:549-576.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>[dataset] Abreu-Placeres NA. 2020; RDIS.sav; RDIS questionnaire data; OSF. https://osf.io/2vyu9/?view_only=53f432750e574770af6bb441061403a8. Assesed July 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Little RJ. A test of missing completely at random for multivariate data with missing values. J Am Stat Assoc. 1998;83:1198-1202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: towards a unifying theory of behavior change. Psychol Rev. 1977;84:191-215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khawaldeh OA, Al-Hassan MA, Froelicher ES. Self-efficacy, self-management, and glycemic control in adults with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Diabetes Complications. 2012;26:10-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pollio HR, Beck HP. When the tail wags the dog: Perceptions of learning and grade orientation in, and by, contemporary college students and faculty. J Higher Educ. 2000;7:84-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scepansky JA, Bjornsen CA. Educational orientation, neo PI-R personality traits, and plans for graduate school. Coll Stud J. 2003;37:574-581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
