<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">32618613</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-7056</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in gastroenterology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Autoimmune pancreatitis type 2.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>417</StartPage>
          <EndPage>420</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>417-420</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MOG.0000000000000655</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis (AIP) is a rare inflammatory disease of the pancreas. Very few data have been published on this particular subtype, which differs from the 'classical' IgG4-related type 1 AIP in terms of pathological features, epidemiology and risk of relapse. The aim of the current review is to summarize the available literature, suggesting a diagnostic and therapeutic approach to this disease.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Based on the International Consensus Diagnostic Criteria, to achieve a 'definitive' diagnosis of type 2 AIP, histology is required. If a definitive histological diagnosis is lacking (not-performed or inconclusive), concomitant presence of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) and effective response to steroids are needed for a 'probable' diagnosis of type 2 AIP.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Type 2 AIP is a selective pancreatic disease, without association to other organ involvement. The lack of validated serological markers makes the diagnosis challenging in clinical practice, particularly in focal forms. A careful evaluation of the clinical profile (especially of a concomitant IBD), associated with an accurate imaging, might help in clinical practice to suspect type 2 AIP. Response to steroids is crucial to achieve diagnosis in patients without a diagnostic histology.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de Pretis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicolò</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Pancreas Institute, University of Verona, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frulloni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luca</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Gastroenterol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8506887</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0267-1379</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000081012" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Pancreatitis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010179" MajorTopicYN="N">Pancreas</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010195" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pancreatitis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32618613</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MOG.0000000000000655</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00001574-202009000-00010</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shomosegawa T, Chari ST, Frulloni L, et al. International Consensus Diagnostic Criteria for autoimmune pancreatitis: guidelines of the International Association of Pancreatology. Pancreas 2011; 40:352–358.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chari ST, Kloeppel G, Zhang L, et al. Autoimmune Pancreatitis International Cooperative Study Group (APICS). Histopathologic and clinical subtypes of autoimmune pancreatitis: the Honolulu consensus document. Pancreas 2010; 39:549–554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Kamisawa T, Brugge WR, et al. Long-term outcomes of autoimmune pancreatitis: a multicenter, international analysis. Gut 2013; 62:1771–1776.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone JH, Zen Y, Desphande V. IgG4-related disease. N Engl J Med 2012; 366:539–551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Notohara K, Burgart LJ, Yadav D, et al. Idiopathic chronic pancreatitis with periductal lymphoplasmacytic infiltration: clinicopathologic features of 35 cases. Am J Surg Pathol 2003; 27:1119–1127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamboni G, Luttges J, Capelli P, et al. Histopathological features of diagnostic and clinical relevance in autoimmune pancreatitis: a study on 53 resection specimens and 9 biopsy specimens. Virchows Arch 2004; 445:552–563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Levy MJ, Smyrk TC, et al. Clinical profiles and outcomes in idiopathic duct-centric chronic pancreatitis (type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis): the Mayo Clinic experience. Gut 2016; 65:1702–1709.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeura T, Manfredi R, Zamboni G, et al. Application of International Consensus Diagnostic Criteria to an Italian series of autoimmune pancreatitis. United European Gastroenterol J 2013; 1:276–284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawa S, Okazaki K, Notohara K, et al. Study Group for Pancreatitis Complicated with Inflammatory Bowel Disease organized by The Research Committee for Intractable Pancreatic Disease (Chairman: Tooru Shimosegawa) and The Research Committee for Intractable Inflammatory Bowel Disease (Chairman: Mamoru Watanabe), both of which are supported by the Ministry of Health, Labour, and Welfare of Japan. Autoimmune pancreatitis complicated with inflammatory bowel disease and comparative study of type 1 and type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. J Gastroenterol 2015; 50:805–815.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Zen Y, Chari ST. Recent advances in autoimmune pancreatitis. Gastroenterology 2015; 149:39–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Chari ST, Giday SA, et al. Clinical profile of autoimmune pancreatitis and its histological subtypes: an international multicenter survey. Pancreas 2011; 40:809–814.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lorenzo D, Maire F, Stefanescu C, et al. Features of autoimmune pancreatitis associated with inflammatory bowel disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2018; 16:59–67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Pretis N, Vieceli F, Brandolese A, et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis not otherwise specified (NOS): clinical features and outcomes of the forgotten type. Hepatobiliary Pancreat Dis Int 2019; 18:576–579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Negrelli R, Boninsegna E, Avesani G, et al. Type 1 and Type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. Distinctive clinical and pathological features, but are there any differences at magnetic resonance? Experience from a referral center. Pancreas 2018; 47:1115–1122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sah RP, Chari ST, Pannala R, et al. Differences in clinical profile and relapse rate of type 1 versus type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. Gastroenterology 2010; 139:140–148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S, Kim JH, Kim SY, et al. Comparison of diagnostic performance between CT and MRI in differentiating non-diffuse-type autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Eur Radiol 2018; 28:5267–5274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bodily KD, Takahashi N, Fletscher JG, et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis: pancreatic and extrapancreatic imaging findings. AJR Am J Roentgenol 2009; 192:431–437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Pretis N, Amodio A, Frulloni L. Updates in the field of autoimmune pancreatitis: a clinical guide. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 2018; 12:705–709.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frulloni L, Amodio A, Katsotourchhi AM, Vantini I. A practical approach to the diagnosis of autoimmune pancreatitis. World J Gastroenterol 2011; 17:2076–2079.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vitali F, Hansen T, Kiesslich R, et al. Frequency and characterization of benign lesions in patients undergoing surgery for the suspicion of solid pancreatic neoplasm. Pancreas 2014; 43:1329–1333.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Detlefsen S, Jorgensen MT, Mortensen MB. Microscopic findings in EUS-guided fine needle (SharkCore) biopsies with type 1 and type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. Pathol Int 2017; 67:514–520.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishikawa T, Itoh A, Kawashima H, et al. Endoscopic ultrasound-guided fine needle aspiration in the differentiation of type 1 and type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. World J Gastroenterol 2012; 18:3883–3888.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okazaki K, Chari ST, Frulloni L, et al. International consensus for the treatment of autoimmune pancreatitis. Pancreatology 2017; 17:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Shomosegawa T, Okazaki K, et al. Standard steroid treatment for autoimmune pancreatitis. Gut 2009; 58:1504–1507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
