<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32644657</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK559231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805">Seating And Wheelchair Evaluation</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owens</LastName><ForeName>Justin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Philadelphia College of Osteopathic Medicine</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Donald D.</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wellstar Atlanta Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>The wheelchair (WC) is one of the most important examples of mobility-assistive equipment (MAE) available to patients with impaired mobility. Otherwise known as a "wheeled mobility device" (WMD), the WC has revolutionized the treatment of patients experiencing disability and has had a significant impact on those with serious functional restrictions. According to the National Institutes of Health, fifty-three million Americans lived with a disability in 2017. In 2019, this number rose to over sixty-one million Americans (or 25.7% of the population). Furthermore, 5.5% of the overall U.S. population used MAE in 2019 with WC use comprising 1.6%. WC prescription has the potential to significantly increase the quality of life for these individuals and allow increased participation in the community. The World Health Organization (WHO) has developed guidelines that highlight eight steps to standardize the process of wheelchair service delivery. These include (1) referral and appointment; (2) patient assessment; (3) WC prescription; (4) funding and purchase; (5) device installation and preparation; (6) device fitting; (7) patient instruction and training; and, (8) follow-up maintenance/repairs. </AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s1">Definition/Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s2">Issues of Concern</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s3">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s4">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Interventions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s5">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Monitoring</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s6">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-28805" sec="article-28805.s7">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Frontera WR, Bean JF, Damiano D, Ehrlich-Jones L, Fried-Oken M, Jette A, Jung R, Lieber RL, Malec JF, Mueller MJ, Ottenbacher KJ, Tansey KE, Thompson A. Rehabilitation research at the National Institutes of Health moving the field forward (executive summary). Rehabil Psychol. 2017 Aug;62(3):387-396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28682094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao G, Okoro CA, Hsia J, Garvin WS, Town M. Prevalence of Disability and Disability Types by Urban-Rural County Classification-U.S., 2016. Am J Prev Med. 2019 Dec;57(6):749-756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theis KA, Steinweg A, Helmick CG, Courtney-Long E, Bolen JA, Lee R. Which one? What kind? How many? Types, causes, and prevalence of disability among U.S. adults. Disabil Health J. 2019 Jul;12(3):411-421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayley MT, Kirby RL, Farahani F, Titus L, Smith C, Routhier F, Gagnon DH, Stapleford P, Alavinia SM, Craven BC. Development of Wheeled Mobility indicators to advance the quality of spinal cord injury rehabilitation: SCI-High Project. J Spinal Cord Med. 2019 Oct;42(sup1):130-140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6783799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31573457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greer N, Brasure M, Wilt TJ. Wheeled mobility (wheelchair) service delivery: scope of the evidence. Ann Intern Med. 2012 Jan 17;156(2):141-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22250145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timm M, Samuelsson K. Wheelchair seating: A study on the healthy elderly. Scand J Occup Ther. 2016 Nov;23(6):458-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26958931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawatzky B, DiGiovine C, Berner T, Roesler T, Katte L. The need for updated clinical practice guidelines for preservation of upper extremities in manual wheelchair users: a position paper. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2015 Apr;94(4):313-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25299526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Requejo PS, Kerdanyan G, Minkel J, Adkins R, Waters R. Effect of rear suspension and speed on seat forces and head accelerations experienced by manual wheelchair riders with spinal cord injury. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2008;45(7):985-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonenblum SE, Sprigle SH, Martin JS, PE  Everyday sitting behavior of full-time wheelchair users. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2016;53(5):585-598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27898157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilchis-Aranguren R, Gayol-Mérida D, Quinzaños-Fresnedo J, Pérez-Zavala R, Galíndez-Novoa C. A prospective, longitudinal, descriptive study of the effect of a customized wheelchair cushion on clinical variables, satisfaction, and functionality among patients with spinal cord injury. Ostomy Wound Manage. 2015 Feb;61(2):26-36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25654779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linacre JM, Heinemann AW, Wright BD, Granger CV, Hamilton BB. The structure and stability of the Functional Independence Measure. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1994 Feb;75(2):127-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8311667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemann AW, Linacre JM, Wright BD, Hamilton BB, Granger C. Relationships between impairment and physical disability as measured by the functional independence measure. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1993 Jun;74(6):566-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8503745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar A, Schmeler MR, Karmarkar AM, Collins DM, Cooper R, Cooper RA, Shin H, Holm MB. Test-retest reliability of the functional mobility assessment (FMA): a pilot study. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2013 May;8(3):213-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22612721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mills T, Holm MB, Trefler E, Schmeler M, Fitzgerald S, Boninger M. Development and consumer validation of the Functional Evaluation in a Wheelchair (FEW) instrument. 2002 Jan 10-Feb 15Disabil Rehabil. 24(1-3):38-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11827153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rushton PW, Kirby RL, Miller WC. Manual wheelchair skills: objective testing versus subjective questionnaire. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2012 Dec;93(12):2313-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3951990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22728701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Best KL, Kirby RL, Smith C, MacLeod DA. Wheelchair skills training for community-based manual wheelchair users: a randomized controlled trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2005 Dec;86(12):2316-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16344029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitford M, Mitchell SJ, Marzloff GE, Zindle JK, Richmond MA, Bogie KM, Henzel MK. Wheelchair Mobility-Related Injuries Due to Inadvertent Lower Extremity Displacement on Footplates: Analysis of the FDA MAUDE Database From 2014 to 2018. J Patient Saf. 2021 Dec 01;17(8):e1785-e1792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valent L, Nachtegaal J, Faber W, Smit C, Kaandorp E, Pratt-Sutherland S, Houdijk H, Adriaansen J, ALLRISC. Groot de S, Post MWM. Experienced sitting-related problems and association with personal, lesion and wheelchair characteristics in persons with long-standing paraplegia and tetraplegia. Spinal Cord. 2019 Jul;57(7):603-613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30988398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabol TP, Haley ES. Wheelchair evaluation for the older adult. Clin Geriatr Med. 2006 May;22(2):355-75; ix.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16627083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metring NL, Gaspar MI, Mateus-Vasconcelos EC, Gomes MM, de Abreu DC. Influence of different types of seat cushions on the static sitting posture in individuals with spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2012 Aug;50(8):627-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22350034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takara K, Gaspar MI, Metring NL, Mateus-Vasconcelos EC, Cliquet A, Abreu DC. Evaluation of the influence of different types of seats on postural control in individuals with paraplegia. Spinal Cord. 2010 Nov;48(11):825-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragan R, Kernozek TW, Bidar M, Matheson JW. Seat-interface pressures on various thicknesses of foam wheelchair cushions: a finite modeling approach. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002 Jun;83(6):872-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12048671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lachenbruch C, Tzen YT, Brienza DM, Karg PE, Lachenbruch PA. The relative contributions of interface pressure, shear stress, and temperature on tissue ischemia: a cross-sectional pilot study. Ostomy Wound Manage. 2013 Mar;59(3):25-34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23475449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DiGiovine MM, Cooper RA, Boninger ML, Lawrence BM, VanSickle DP, Rentschler AJ. User assessment of manual wheelchair ride comfort and ergonomics. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2000 Apr;81(4):490-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonçalves DD, Franchini AE, Sardella A, Bonfim GH, Medola FO, Paschoarelli LC. Comfort, Stability and Body Posture in Wheelchair Cushions: a preliminary study with able bodied subjects. Stud Health Technol Inform. 2015;217:996-1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26294600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards K, McCluskey A. A survey of adult power wheelchair and scooter users. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2010;5(6):411-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20450455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AL, Groer S, Palacios P, Mitchell D, Sabharwal S, Kirby RL, Gavin-Dreschnack D, Powell-Cope G. Wheelchair-related falls in veterans with spinal cord injury residing in the community: a prospective cohort study. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2010 Aug;91(8):1166-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20684896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg K, Hines M, Allen S. Wheelchair users at home: few home modifications and many injurious falls. Am J Public Health. 2002 Jan;92(1):48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1447386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprigle S, McNair D, Sonenblum S. Pressure Ulcer Risk Factors in Persons with Mobility-Related Disabilities. Adv Skin Wound Care. 2020 Mar;33(3):146-154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonenblum SE, Seol D, Sprigle SH, Cathcart JM. Seated buttocks anatomy and its impact on biomechanical risk. J Tissue Viability. 2020 May;29(2):69-75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32008891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allman RM, Goode PS, Burst N, Bartolucci AA, Thomas DR. Pressure ulcers, hospital complications, and disease severity: impact on hospital costs and length of stay. Adv Wound Care. 1999 Jan-Feb;12(1):22-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10326353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghavan P, Raza WA, Ahmed YS, Chamberlain MA. Prevalence of pressure sores in a community sample of spinal injury patients. Clin Rehabil. 2003 Dec;17(8):879-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14682560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause JS, Broderick L. Patterns of recurrent pressure ulcers after spinal cord injury: identification of risk and protective factors 5 or more years after onset. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2004 Aug;85(8):1257-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15295750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brienza DM, Karg PE, Geyer MJ, Kelsey S, Trefler E. The relationship between pressure ulcer incidence and buttock-seat cushion interface pressure in at-risk elderly wheelchair users. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2001 Apr;82(4):529-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11295017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonenblum SE, Vonk TE, Janssen TW, Sprigle SH. Effects of wheelchair cushions and pressure relief maneuvers on ischial interface pressure and blood flow in people with spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2014 Jul;95(7):1350-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24480336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apatsidis DP, Solomonidis SE, Michael SM. Pressure distribution at the seating interface of custom-molded wheelchair seats: effect of various materials. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002 Aug;83(8):1151-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12161839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jan YK, Jones MA, Rabadi MH, Foreman RD, Thiessen A. Effect of wheelchair tilt-in-space and recline angles on skin perfusion over the ischial tuberosity in people with spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2010 Nov;91(11):1758-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21044723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brienza D, Kelsey S, Karg P, Allegretti A, Olson M, Schmeler M, Zanca J, Geyer MJ, Kusturiss M, Holm M. A randomized clinical trial on preventing pressure ulcers with wheelchair seat cushions. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010 Dec;58(12):2308-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21070197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwarciak AM, Turner JT, Guo L, Richter WM. The effects of four different stroke patterns on manual wheelchair propulsion and upper limb muscle strain. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2012 Nov;7(6):459-63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22295946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gellman H, Chandler DR, Petrasek J, Sie I, Adkins R, Waters RL. Carpal tunnel syndrome in paraplegic patients. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1988 Apr;70(4):517-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3356717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiang H, Chany AM, Smith GA. Wheelchair related injuries treated in US emergency departments. Inj Prev. 2006 Feb;12(1):8-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2563507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirby RL, Ackroyd-Stolarz SA, Brown MG, Kirkland SA, MacLeod DA. Wheelchair-related accidents caused by tips and falls among noninstitutionalized users of manually propelled wheelchairs in Nova Scotia. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 1994 Sep-Oct;73(5):319-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7917161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erickson B, Hosseini MA, Mudhar PS, Soleimani M, Aboonabi A, Arzanpour S, Sparrey CJ. The dynamics of electric powered wheelchair sideways tips and falls: experimental and computational analysis of impact forces and injury. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2016 Mar 02;13:20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4776350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26935331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corfman TA, Cooper RA, Fitzgerald SG, Cooper R. Tips and falls during electric-powered wheelchair driving: effects of seatbelt use, legrests, and driving speed. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2003 Dec;84(12):1797-802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14669186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas L, Borisoff J, Sparrey CJ. Manual wheelchair downhill stability: an analysis of factors affecting tip probability. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2018 Nov 06;15(1):95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6219167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30400911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice LA, Ousley C, Sosnoff JJ. A systematic review of risk factors associated with accidental falls, outcome measures and interventions to manage fall risk in non-ambulatory adults. Disabil Rehabil. 2015;37(19):1697-705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25354146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingstone R, Field D. Systematic review of power mobility outcomes for infants, children and adolescents with mobility limitations. Clin Rehabil. 2014 Oct;28(10):954-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24764156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganesh S, Hayter A, Kim J, Sanford J, Sprigle S, Hoenig H. Wheelchair use by veterans newly prescribed a manual wheelchair. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2007 Apr;88(4):434-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17398243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beeckman D, Vanderwee K. Skin protection wheelchair cushions for older nursing home residents reduce 6-month incidence of ischial tuberosity pressure ulcers compared with segmented foam cushions. Evid Based Nurs. 2011 Jul;14(3):79-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21646383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finley MA, Rodgers MM. Prevalence and identification of shoulder pathology in athletic and nonathletic wheelchair users with shoulder pain: A pilot study. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2004 May;41(3B):395-402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15543457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalyan M, Sherman A, Cardenas DD. Factors associated with contractures in acute spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 1998 Jun;36(6):405-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9648196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paralyzed Veterans of America Consortium for Spinal Cord Medicine. Preservation of upper limb function following spinal cord injury: a clinical practice guideline for health-care professionals. J Spinal Cord Med. 2005;28(5):434-70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1808273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16869091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice LA, Smith I, Kelleher AR, Greenwald K, Boninger ML. Impact of a wheelchair education protocol based on practice guidelines for preservation of upper-limb function: a randomized trial. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2014 Jan;95(1):10-19.e11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23856151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice LA, Smith I, Kelleher AR, Greenwald K, Hoelmer C, Boninger ML. Impact of the clinical practice guideline for preservation of upper limb function on transfer skills of persons with acute spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2013 Jul;94(7):1230-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23537608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolff JL, Agree EM, Kasper JD. Wheelchairs, walkers, and canes: what does Medicare pay for, and who benefits? Health Aff (Millwood) 2005 Jul-Aug;24(4):1140-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16012154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), HHS. Medicare program; conditions for payment of power mobility devices, including power wheelchairs and power-operated vehicles. Interim final rule with comment period. Fed Regist. 2005 Aug 26;70(165):50939-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16136723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh H, Scovil CY, Yoshida K, Oosman S, Kaiser A, Jaglal SB, Musselman KE. Capturing the psychosocial impacts of falls from the perspectives of wheelchair users with spinal cord injury through photo-elicitation. Disabil Rehabil. 2021 Sep;43(19):2680-2689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31906734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koontz AM, Bass SR, Kulich HR. Accessibility facilitators and barriers affecting independent wheelchair transfers in the community. Disabil Rehabil Assist Technol. 2021 Oct;16(7):741-748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoenig H, Landerman LR, Shipp KM, Pieper C, Pieper C, Richardson M, Pahel N, George L. A clinical trial of a rehabilitation expert clinician versus usual care for providing manual wheelchairs. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005 Oct;53(10):1712-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16181170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trefler E, Fitzgerald SG, Hobson DA, Bursick T, Joseph R. Outcomes of wheelchair systems intervention with residents of long-term care facilities. Assist Technol. 2004 Summer;16(1):18-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15357146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouldin ED, Andresen EM, Bauer SE, Whitney C, Tamayo CC, Schumacher JR, Hall AG. Visitability surveillance, prevalence, and correlates in Florida. Disabil Health J. 2015 Jan;8(1):140-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25190052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons RA, John A, Brophy S, Jones SJ, Johansen A, Kemp A, Lannon S, Patterson J, Rolfe B, Sander LV, Weightman A. Modification of the home environment for the reduction of injuries. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2006 Oct 18;(4):CD003600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17054179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gitlin LN, Corcoran M, Winter L, Boyce A, Hauck WW. A randomized, controlled trial of a home environmental intervention: effect on efficacy and upset in caregivers and on daily function of persons with dementia. Gerontologist. 2001 Feb;41(1):4-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11220813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32644657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
