<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32651841</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-6555</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>49</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of psycholinguistic research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Psycholinguist Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of Language Skills and Strategy Use on Vocabulary Learning Through Lexical Translation and Inferencing.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>975</StartPage>
          <EndPage>991</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>975-991</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10936-020-09720-9</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study explores how vocabulary learning strategy usage and skills in the four language domains relate to participants' increase in vocabulary size and to the learning of specific vocabulary items over a certain period of time. Sixty-one advanced L1 Arabic L2 learners of English read target words in semi-authentic reading materials and were instructed to either guess the meaning from context or consult a dictionary. Pre- and delayed post-tests assessed vocabulary size and knowledge of the target vocabulary items. Results showed that learning through inferencing, but not learning through dictionary use, depended on learners' familiarity with the particular learning strategy. Additionally, note taking and reading comprehension influenced lexical knowledge and acquisition in complex ways.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alahmadi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alaa</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Languages, Literatures and Linguistics, Bangor University, Bangor, Gwynedd, LL57 2DG, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Foltz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anouschka</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5117-3225</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of English Studies, University of Graz, Graz, Austria. anouschka.foltz@uni-graz.at.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Psycholinguist Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0333506</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0090-6905</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Educational Measurement</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007802" MajorTopicYN="Y">Language</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007858" MajorTopicYN="Y">Learning</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019303" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multilingualism</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011932" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reading</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vocabulary</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Language skills</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lexical inferencing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lexical translation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vocabulary acquisition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vocabulary learning strategies</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32651841</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7661419</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10936-020-09720-9</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10936-020-09720-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alahmadi, A. (2015). Exploring vocabulary learning strategies of Saudi undergraduate EFL students at King Abdulaziz University and its relationship to their vocabulary size. Unpublished PhD thesis, Bangor University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alahmadi, A., &amp; Foltz, A. (under revision). Exploring the effect of lexical inferencing and lexical translation on Saudi undergraduate EFL students’ vocabulary acquisition. PlosOne.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7392316</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alahmadi, A., Shank, C., &amp; Foltz, A. (2018). Vocabulary learning strategies and vocabulary size: Insights from educational level and learner styles. Vocabulary Learning and Instruction, 7(1), 1–21. 10.7820/vli.v07.1.alahmadi.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adolphs S, Schmitt N. Lexical coverage of spoken discourse. Applied Linguistics. 2003;24(4):425–438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed, M. (1988). Vocabulary learning strategies: A case study of Sudanese learners of English. Unpublished PhD thesis, University College of North Wales Bangor.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akpınar KD, Aşık A, Vural AS. The relationship between the effectiveness of vocabulary presentation modes and learners’ attitudes: Corpus based contextual guessing, dictionary use, and online instruction. The Asian EFL Journal Quarterly. 2015;17(17):90–115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Qahtani, M. (2005). The use of vocabulary learning strategies by EFL learners at three different educational levels. Unpublished PhD Thesis, University of Essex.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Masrai, A. (2009). Measuring the English vocabulary size of Saudi university students: Validating a new 10,000 word vocabulary size test. Unpublished Master’s Thesis, Swansea University, Swansea, UK.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Masrai A, Milton J. The vocabulary knowledge of university students in Saudi Arabia. Perspectives (TESOL Arabia) 2012;19:13–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Nujaidi, A. H. (2003). Relationship between vocabulary size, reading strategies, and reading comprehension of EFL learners in Saudi Arabia. Unpublished PhD Thesis, Oklahoma State University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alqurashi, N. (2013). Vocabulary learning strategies of Saudi undergraduate EFL students at Taif University and its relation to their vocabulary size. Unpublished MA Thesis, Anglia Ruskin University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AlSaif, A. (2011). Investigating vocabulary input and explaining vocabulary uptake among EFL learners in Saudi Arabia. Unpublished PhD Thesis, Swansea University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alyami M, Mohsen MA. The use of a reading lexicon to aid contextual vocabulary acquisition by EFL Arab learners. Journal of Psycholinguistic Research. 2019;48:1005. doi: 10.1007/s10936-019-09644-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10936-019-09644-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baayen RH.  Analyzing linguistic data: A practical introduction to statistics using R. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baharudin H, Ismail Z. Vocabulary learning strategies and Arabic vocabulary size among pre-university students in Malaysia. International Education Studies. 2014;7(13):219–226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bensoussan M, Laufer B. Lexical guessing in context in EFL reading comprehension. Journal of Research in Reading. 1984;7(1):15–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brysbaert M, Stevens M, Mandera P, Keuleers E. How many words do we know? Practical estimates of vocabulary size dependent on word definition, the degree of language input and the participant’s age. Frontiers in Psychology. 2016;7:1116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4965448</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27524974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catalan RMJ. Sex differences in L2 vocabulary learning strategies. International Journal of Applied Linguistics. 2003;13(1):54–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chamot AU. Issues in language learning strategy research and teaching. Electronic Journal of Foreign Language Teaching. 2004;1(1):14–26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobb T, Horst M.  Reading academic English: Carrying learners across the lexical threshold. In: Flowerdew J, Peacock M, editors. Research perspectives on English for academic purposes. Stuttgart: Ernst Klett Sprachen; 2001. pp. 315–329.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Chazal E, Rogers L.  Oxford EAP: A course in English for academic purposes. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2013. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de la Garza B, Harris RJ. Acquiring foreign language vocabulary through meaningful linguistic context: Where is the limit to vocabulary learning? Journal of Psycholinguistic Research. 2017;46(2):395–413. doi: 10.1007/s10936-016-9444-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10936-016-9444-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27364147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraser CA. Lexical processing strategy use and vocabulary learning through reading. Studies in Second Language Acquisition. 1999;21(2):225–241.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu Y, Johnson RK. Vocabulary learning strategies and language learning outcomes. Language Learning. 1996;46(4):643–679.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haastrup K.  Lexical inferencing procedures, or, talking about words: Receptive procedures in foreign language learning with special reference to English. Tübingen: Gunter Narr Verlag; 1991. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamzah MSG, Kafipour R, Abdullah SK. Vocabulary learning strategies of Iranian undergraduate EFL students and its relation to their vocabulary size. European Journal of Social Sciences. 2009;11(1):39–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haynes M. Patterns and perils of guessing in second language reading. On TESOL. 1984;83:163–176.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heidari K. Willingness to communicate: A predictor of pushing vocabulary knowledge from receptive to productive. Journal of Psycholinguistic Research. 2019;48:903. doi: 10.1007/s10936-019-09639-w.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10936-019-09639-w</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30941673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hulstijn JH.  Retention of inferred and given word meanings: Experiments in incidental vocabulary learning. In: Arnaud PJL, Béjoint H, editors. Vocabulary and applied linguistics. London: Palgrave Macmillan; 1992. pp. 113–125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knight S. Dictionary use while reading: The effects on comprehension and vocabulary acquisition for students of different verbal abilities. The Modern Language Journal. 1994;78(3):285–299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koizumi R, In’nami Y. Vocabulary knowledge and speaking proficiency among second language learners from novice to intermediate levels. Journal of Language Teaching and Research. 2013;4(5):900–914.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komol, T., &amp; Sripetpun, W. (2011). Vocabulary learning strategies employed by undergraduate students and its relationship to their vocabulary knowledge. In The 3rd international conference on humanities and social sciences April 2, 2011 Faculty of Liberal Arts, Prince of Songkla University (pp. 1–18). Faculty of Liberal Arts, Prince of Songkla University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroll JF, Curley J. Lexical memory in novice bilinguals: The role of concepts in retrieving second language words. Practical Aspects of Memory. 1988;2(8):389–395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laufer B.  What percentage of text-lexis is essential for comprehension? In: Lauren C, Nordman M, editors. Special Language: From Humans Thinking to Thinking Machines. Clevedon: Multilingual Matters; 1989. pp. 316–323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laufer B.  How much lexis is necessary for reading comprehension? In: Arnaud PJL, Béjoint H, editors. Vocabulary and applied linguistics. Berlin: Springer; 1992. pp. 126–132.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laufer B. The development of passive and active vocabulary in a second language: Same or different? Applied Linguistics. 1998;19(2):255–271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laufer B, Ravenhorst-Kalovski GC. Lexical threshold revisited: Lexical text coverage, learners’ vocabulary size and reading comprehension. Reading in a Foreign Language. 2010;22(1):15–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marefat, H., &amp; Shirazi, A. M. (2003). The impact of teaching direct learning strategies on the retention of vocabulary of EFL learners. The Reading Matrix, 3(2), 47–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milton J.  Measuring second language vocabulary acquisition. Bristol: Multilingual Matters; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mondria JA. The effects of inferring, verifying, and memorizing on the retention of L2 word meanings: An experimental comparison of the “meaning-inferred method” and the “meaning-given method”. Studies in Second Language Acquisition. 2003;25(4):473–499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nassaji H. L2 vocabulary learning from context: Strategies, knowledge sources, and their relationship with success in L2 lexical inferencing. TESOL Quarterly. 2003;37(4):645–670.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nation I. How large a vocabulary is needed for reading and listening? Canadian Modern Language Review. 2006;63(1):59–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nation ISP.  Learning vocabulary in another language. Stuttgart: Ernst Klett Sprachen; 2001. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Malley JM, Chamot A.  Learning strategies in second language acquisition. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 1990. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouellette GP. What’s meaning got to do with it: The role of vocabulary in word reading and reading comprehension. Journal of Educational Psychology. 2006;98(3):554–566.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oxford R.  Language learning strategies what every teacher should know. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Newbury House; 1990. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian D. Assessing the roles of depth and breadth of vocabulary knowledge in reading comprehension. Canadian Modern Language Review. 1999;56(2):282–308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian DD. Investigating the relationship between vocabulary knowledge and academic reading performance: An assessment perspective. Language Learning. 2002;52(3):513–536.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richards, J. C. (1976). The role of vocabulary teaching. TESOL Quarterly, 10(1), 77–89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richards JC, Renandya WA, editors. Methodology in language teaching: An anthology of current practice. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 2002. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt N.  Vocabulary learning strategies. In: Schmitt N, McCarthy M, editors. Vocabulary: Descriptive, acquisition and pedagogy. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press; 1997. pp. 199–228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt N.  Vocabulary in language teaching. Stuttgart: Ernst Klett Sprachen; 2000. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt N, Jiang X, Grabe W. The percentage of words known in a text and reading comprehension. The Modern Language Journal. 2011;95(1):26–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt D, Schmitt N.  Focus on vocabulary 2: Mastering the academic word list. London: Pearson Education; 2011. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stæhr LS. Vocabulary size and the skills of listening, reading and writing. Language Learning Journal. 2008;36(2):139–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanyer S, Ozturk Y. Pre-service English teachers’ vocabulary learning strategy use and vocabulary size: A cross-sectional evaluation. Journal of Language Teaching and Research. 2014;5(1):37–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L. Word association: Second language vocabulary acquisistion and instruction. TESL Reporter. 2007;40(1):49–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webb WB. The effects of prolonged learning on learning. Journal of Verbal Learning and Verbal Behavior. 1962;1(3):173–182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weigand E.  Contrastive lexical semantics. In: Weigand IE, editor. Contrastive lexical semantics. Amsterdam: John Benjamin; 1998. pp. 25–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wesche MB, Paribakht T.  Lexical inferencing in a first and second language: Cross-linguistic dimensions. Bristol: Multilingual Matters; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
