<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32697358</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4652</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>236</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of cellular physiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Physiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Hippo in the room: Targeting the Hippo signalling pathway for osteosarcoma therapies.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1606</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1615</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1606-1615</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcp.29967</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Osteosarcoma (OS) is a primary malignant bone tumour which usually occurs in children and adolescents. OS is primarily a result of chromosomal aberrations, a combination of acquired genetic changes and, hereditary, resulting in the dysregulation of cellular functions. The Hippo signalling pathway regulates cell and tissue growth by modulating cell proliferation, differentiation, and migration in developing organs. Mammalian STE20-like 1/2 (MST1/2) protein kinases are activated by neurofibromatosis type 2, Ras association domain family member 2, kidney and brain protein, or other factors. Interactions between MST1/2 and salvador family WW domain-containing protein 1 activate large tumour suppressor kinase 1/2 proteins, which in turn phosphorylate the downstream Yes-associated protein 1/transcriptional coactivator with PDZ-binding motif (YAP/TAZ). Moreover, dysregulation of this pathway can lead to aberrant cell growth, resulting in tumorigenesis. Interestingly, small molecules targeting the Hippo signalling pathways, through affecting YAP/TAZ cellular localisation and their interaction with members of the TEA/ATTS domain family of transcriptional enhancers are being developed and hold promise for the treatment of OS. This review discusses the existing knowledge about the involvement of the Hippo signalling cascade in OS and highlights several small molecule inhibitors as potential novel therapeutics.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rothzerg</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emel</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Perron Institute for Neurological and Translational Science, QEII Medical Centre, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ingley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Evan</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8112-9134</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Harry Perkins Institute of Medical Research, QEII Medical Centre, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Science, Health, Engineering and Education, Murdoch University, Murdoch, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mullin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology and Diabetes, Sir Charles Gairdner Hospital, Nedlands, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xue</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Key Laboratory of Biomaterials of Guangdong Higher Education Institutes, Jinan University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wood</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jiake</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8360-3899</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences, The University of Western Australia, Perth, Western Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Cell Physiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0050222</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9541</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017346">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008954" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Biological</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058990" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Targeted Therapy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012516" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteosarcoma</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000201" MajorTopicYN="Y">enzymology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017346" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Serine-Threonine Kinases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="Y">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Hippo signalling pathway</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">osteosarcoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">sarcoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">small molecule inhibitor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">targeted therapy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697358</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.29967</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed, A. A., Mohamed, A. D., Gener, M., Li, W., &amp; Taboada, E. (2017). YAP and the Hippo pathway in pediatric cancer. Molecular &amp; Cellular Oncology, 4, e1295127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Azevedo, J. W. V., de Medeiros Fernandes, T. A. A., Fernandes, J. V., Jr., de Azevedo, J. C. V., Lanza, D. C. F., Bezerra, C. M., … Fernandes, J. V. (2020). Biology and pathogenesis of human osteosarcoma. Oncology Letters, 19, 1099-1116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baglio, S. R., Lagerweij, T., Perez-Lanzon, M., Ho, X. D., Leveille, N., Melo, S. A., … Pegtel, D. M. (2017). Blocking tumor-educated MSC paracrine activity halts osteosarcoma progression. Clinical Cancer Research, 23, 3721-3733.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bao, Y., Nakagawa, K., Yang, Z., Ikeda, M., Withanage, K., Ishigami-Yuasa, M., … Hata, Y. (2011). A cell-based assay to screen stimulators of the Hippo pathway reveals the inhibitory effect of dobutamine on the YAP-dependent gene transcription. Journal of Biochemistry, 150, 199-208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basu, D., Lettan, R., Damodaran, K., Strellec, S., Reyes-Mugica, M., &amp; Rebbaa, A. (2014). Identification, mechanism of action, and antitumor activity of a small molecule inhibitor of hippo, TGF-beta, and Wnt signaling pathways. Molecular Cancer Therapeutics, 13, 1457-1467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basu-Roy, U., Bayin, N. S., Rattanakorn, K., Han, E., Placantonakis, D. G., Mansukhani, A., &amp; Basilico, C. (2015). Sox2 antagonizes the Hippo pathway to maintain stemness in cancer cells. Nature Communications, 6, 6411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basu-Roy, U., Han, E., Rattanakorn, K., Gadi, A., Verma, N., Maurizi, G., … Mansukhani, A. (2016). PPARgamma agonists promote differentiation of cancer stem cells by restraining YAP transcriptional activity. Oncotarget, 7, 60954-60970.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouvier, C., Macagno, N., Nguyen, Q., Loundou, A., Jiguet-Jiglaire, C., Gentet, J. C., … Salas, S. (2016). Prognostic value of the Hippo pathway transcriptional coactivators YAP/TAZ and beta1-integrin in conventional osteosarcoma. Oncotarget, 7, 64702-64710.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvert, N., Wu, J., Sneddon, S., Woodhouse, J., Carey-Smith, R., Wood, D., &amp; Ingley, E. (2018). The use of whole exome sequencing and murine patient derived xenografts as a method of chemosensitivity testing in sarcoma. Clinical Sarcoma Research, 8, 4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chai, J., Xu, S., &amp; Guo, F. (2017). TEAD1 mediates the oncogenic activities of Hippo-YAP1 signaling in osteosarcoma. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 488, 297-302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, Q., Song, S., Wei, S., Liu, B., Honjo, S., Scott, A., … Ajani, J. A. (2015). ABT-263 induces apoptosis and synergizes with chemotherapy by targeting stemness pathways in esophageal cancer. Oncotarget, 6, 25883-25896.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi, M. K., Kwon, M., Ahn, J. H., Kim, N. J., Bae, M. A., &amp; Song, I. S. (2014). Transport characteristics and transporter-based drug-drug interactions of TM-25659, a novel TAZ modulator. Biopharmaceutics and Drug Disposition, 35, 183-194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chou, L. Y., Chen, C. H., Lin, Y. H., Chuang, S. C., Chou, H. C., Lin, S. Y., … Wang, C. Z. (2020). Discoidin domain receptor 1 regulates endochondral ossification through terminal differentiation of chondrocytes. FASEB Journal, 34, 5767-5781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deel, M. D., Li, J. J., Crose, L. E., &amp; Linardic, C. M. (2015). A review: Molecular aberrations within Hippo signaling in bone and soft-tissue sarcomas. Frontiers in Oncology, 5, 190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibault, F., Bailly, F., Corvaisier, M., Coevoet, M., Huet, G., Melnyk, P., &amp; Cotelle, P. (2017). Molecular features of the YAP inhibitor verteporfin: Synthesis of hexasubstituted dipyrrins as potential inhibitors of YAP/TAZ, the downstream effectors of the Hippo pathway. ChemMedChem, 12, 954-961.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, L., &amp; Teng, L. (2015). YAP/TAZ for cancer therapy: Opportunities and challenges (review). International Journal of Oncology, 46, 1444-1452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hergovich, A. (2012). Mammalian Hippo signalling: A kinase network regulated by protein-protein interactions. Biochemical Society Transactions, 40, 124-128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jabbari, E., Sarvestani, S. K., Daneshian, L., &amp; Moeinzadeh, S. (2015). Optimum 3D matrix stiffness for maintenance of cancer stem cells is dependent on tissue origin of cancer cells. PLoS One, 10, e0132377.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Jong, Y., Monderer, D., Brandinelli, E., Monchanin, M., van den Akker, B. E., van Oosterwijk, J. G., … Bovee, Jvmg. (2018). Bcl-xl as the most promising Bcl-2 family member in targeted treatment of chondrosarcoma. Oncogenesis, 7, 74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juan, W. C., &amp; Hong, W. (2016). Targeting the Hippo signaling pathway for tissue regeneration and cancer therapy. Genes, 7(9), 55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khera, N., &amp; Rajput, S. (2017). Therapeutic potential of small molecule inhibitors. Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, 118, 959-961.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, M. S., Gernapudi, R., Choi, E. Y., Lapidus, R. G., &amp; Passaniti, A. (2017). Characterization of CADD522, a small molecule that inhibits RUNX2-DNA binding and exhibits antitumor activity. Oncotarget, 8, 70916-70940.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krzyszczyk, P., Acevedo, A., Davidoff, E. J., Timmins, L. M., Marrero-Berrios, I., Patel, M., … Yarmush, M. L. (2018). The growing role of precision and personalized medicine for cancer treatment. Technology, 6, 79-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai, Q., Ye, C., Gao, T., Xiao, J., Xie, A., Liu, X., … Zhang, B. (2017). Therapeutic effect of neoadjuvant chemotherapy combined with curettage to treat distal femoral osteosarcoma: A case report. Medicine, 96, e8672.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamplot, J. D., Denduluri, S., Qin, J., Li, R., Liu, X., Zhang, H., … Luu, H. H. (2013). The current and future therapies for human osteosarcoma. Current Cancer Therapy Reviews, 9, 55-77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, H. J., &amp; Zheng, J. J. (2010). PDZ domains and their binding partners: Structure, specificity, and modification. Cell Communication and Signaling, 8, 8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, N., Luo, D., Hu, X., Luo, W., Lei, G., Wang, Q., … Zheng, Q. (2015). RUNX2 and osteosarcoma. Anti-Cancer Agents in Medicinal Chemistry, 15, 881-887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, H., Du, S., Lei, T., Wang, H., He, X., Tong, R., &amp; Wang, Y. (2018). Multifaceted regulation and functions of YAP/TAZ in tumors (review). Oncology Reports, 40, 16-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, T. M., &amp; Lee, E. H. (2013). Transcriptional regulatory cascades in Runx2-dependent bone development. Tissue Engineering. Part B, Reviews, 19, 254-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, W., Ruan, M., Wang, Y., Song, R., Ji, X., Xu, J., … Xue, W. (2018). Light-triggered biomimetic nanoerythrocyte for tumor-targeted lung metastatic combination therapy of malignant melanoma. Small, 14, e1801754.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma, J., Huang, K., Ma, Y., Zhou, M., &amp; Fan, S. (2017). The TAZ-miR-224-SMAD4 axis promotes tumorigenesis in osteosarcoma. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 8, e2539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurizi, G., Verma, N., Gadi, A., Mansukhani, A., &amp; Basilico, C. (2018). Sox2 is required for tumor development and cancer cell proliferation in osteosarcoma. Oncogene, 37, 4626-4632.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirabello, L., Richards, E. G., Duong, L. M., Yu, K., Wang, Z., Cawthon, R., … Savage, S. A., Group National Osteosarcoma Etiology Study. (2011). Telomere length and variation in telomere biology genes in individuals with osteosarcoma. International Journal of Molecular Epidemiology and Genetics, 2, 19-29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mo, J. S., Park, H. W., &amp; Guan, K. L. (2014). The Hippo signaling pathway in stem cell biology and cancer. EMBO Reports, 15, 642-656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morice, S., Danieau, G., Redini, F., Brounais-Le-Royer, B., &amp; Verrecchia, F. (2020). Hippo/YAP signaling pathway: A promising therapeutic target in bone paediatric cancers? Cancers, 12(3), 645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mortus, J. R., Zhang, Y., &amp; Hughes, D. P. (2014). Developmental pathways hijacked by osteosarcoma. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology, 804, 93-118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oku, Y., Nishiya, N., Shito, T., Yamamoto, R., Yamamoto, Y., Oyama, C., &amp; Uehara, Y. (2015). Small molecules inhibiting the nuclear localization of YAP/TAZ for chemotherapeutics and chemosensitizers against breast cancers. FEBS Open Bio, 5, 542-549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan, D. (2010). The hippo signaling pathway in development and cancer. Developmental Cell, 19, 491-505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, H. W., &amp; Guan, K. L. (2013). Regulation of the Hippo pathway and implications for anticancer drug development. Trends In Pharmacological Sciences, 34, 581-589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pocaterra, A., Romani, P., &amp; Dupont, S. (2020). YAP/TAZ functions and their regulation at a glance. Journal of Cell Science, 133, 133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salah, Z., &amp; Aqeilan, R. I. (2011). WW domain interactions regulate the Hippo tumor suppressor pathway. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 2, e172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin, M. H., He, Y., Marrogi, E., Piperdi, S., Ren, L., Khanna, C., … Huang, J. (2016). A RUNX2-mediated epigenetic regulation of the survival of p53 defective cancer cells. PLoS Genetics, 12, e1005884.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun, G., &amp; Irvine, K. D. (2013). Ajuba family proteins link JNK to Hippo signaling. Science Signaling, 6, ra81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun, J., Wang, X., Tang, B., Liu, H., Zhang, M., Wang, Y., … Geng, M. (2018). A tightly controlled Src-YAP signaling axis determines therapeutic response to dasatinib in renal cell carcinoma. Theranostics, 8, 3256-3267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taccioli, C., Sorrentino, G., Zannini, A., Caroli, J., Beneventano, D., Anderlucci, L., … Del Sal, G. (2015). MDP, a database linking drug response data to genomic information, identifies dasatinib and statins as a combinatorial strategy to inhibit YAP/TAZ in cancer cells. Oncotarget, 6, 38854-38865.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Truebestein, L., &amp; Leonard, T. A. (2016). Coiled-coils: The long and short of it. BioEssays, 38, 903-916.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velletri, T., Xie, N., Wang, Y., Huang, Y., Yang, Q., Chen, X., … Shi, Y. (2016). P53 functional abnormality in mesenchymal stem cells promotes osteosarcoma development. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 7, e2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, D. Y., Wu, Y. N., Huang, J. Q., Wang, W., Xu, M., Jia, J. P., … Bi, W. Z. (2016). Hippo/YAP signaling pathway is involved in osteosarcoma chemoresistance. Chinese Journal of Cancer, 35, 47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, G., Zhan, Y., Wang, H., &amp; Li, W. (2012). ABT-263 sensitizes TRAIL-resistant hepatocarcinoma cells by downregulating the Bcl-2 family of anti-apoptotic protein. Cancer Chemotherapy and Pharmacology, 69, 799-805.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, S. Y., Hu, H. Z., Qing, X. C., Zhang, Z. C., &amp; Shao, Z. W. (2020). Recent advances of drug delivery nanocarriers in osteosarcoma treatment. Journal of Cancer, 11, 69-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, W., Li, N., Li, X., Tran, M. K., Han, X., &amp; Chen, J. (2015). Tankyrase inhibitors target YAP by stabilizing angiomotin family proteins. Cell Reports, 13, 524-532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, X., Zheng, H., Shou, T., Tang, C., Miao, K., &amp; Wang, P. (2017). Effectiveness of multi-drug regimen chemotherapy treatment in osteosarcoma patients: A network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Journal of Orthopaedic Surgery and Research, 12, 52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, X., Kua, H. Y., Hu, Y., Guo, K., Zeng, Q., Wu, Q., … Li, B. (2006). p53 functions as a negative regulator of osteoblastogenesis, osteoblast-dependent osteoclastogenesis, and bone remodeling. Journal of Cell Biology, 172, 115-125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y., Ji, X., Pang, P., Shi, Y., Dai, J., Xu, J., … Xue, W. (2018). Synthesis of JANUS Au nanorods/polydivinylbenzene hybrid nanoparticles for chemo-photothermal therapy. Journal of Materials Chemistry B: Materials for Biology and Medicine, 6, 2481-2488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Z., Ye, J., Deng, Y., Yan, Z., Denduluri, S., &amp; He, T. C. (2014). Wnt versus Hippo: A balanced act or dynamic duo? Genes &amp; Disease, 1, 127-128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Z. X., Yang, J. S., Pan, X., Wang, J. R., Li, J., Yin, Y. M., &amp; De, W. (2010). Functional and biological analysis of Bcl-xL expression in human osteosarcoma. Bone, 47, 445-454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng, Z., Rickles, R. J., Feng, S., Richard, S., Shaw, A. S., Schreiber, S. L., &amp; Brugge, J. S. (1995). Structure-function analysis of SH3 domains: SH3 binding specificity altered by single amino acid substitutions. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 15, 5627-5634.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, L., &amp; Yang, X. (2018). Targeting the Hippo pathway for breast cancer therapy. Cancers, 10(11), 422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang, S., Shao, X., Cao, J., Yang, B., He, Q., &amp; Ying, M. (2019). FAT10: Function and relationship with cancer. Current Molecular Pharmacology, 13, 182-191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, W., Han, W., Qin, A., Wang, Z., Xu, J., &amp; Qian, Y. (2018). The emerging role of Hippo signaling pathway in regulating osteoclast formation. Journal of Cellular Physiology, 233, 4606-4617.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, Y., Tan, J., Duan, X., Zhang, H., Feng, X., Wang, T., … Zhou, X. (2020). The association between polymorphisms in tankyrase gene and telomere length in omethoate-exposed workers. Chemosphere, 238, 124863.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi, X., Deng, X., Zhao, Y., Deng, B., Deng, J., Fan, H., … Hao, L. (2020). Ubiquitin-like protein FAT10 promotes osteosarcoma growth by modifying the ubiquitination and degradation of YAP1′. Experimental Cell Research, 387, 111804.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zanconato, F., Cordenonsi, M., &amp; Piccolo, S. (2019). YAP and TAZ: A signalling hub of the tumour microenvironment. Nature Reviews Cancer, 19, 454-464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, Y., Jin, Q., Xiao, W., &amp; Sun, C. (2019). Tankyrase1 antisense oligodeoxynucleotides suppress the proliferation, migration and invasion through Hippo/YAP pathway in human osteosarcoma cells. Pathology, Research and Practice, 215, 152381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, Z., Hu, T., Xu, Z., Lin, Z., Zhang, Z., Feng, T., … Qin, N. (2015). Targeting Hippo pathway by specific interruption of YAP-TEAD interaction using cyclic YAP-like peptides. FASEB Journal, 29, 724-732.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
