<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32715463</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>7</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
              <Day>24</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Zonisamide add-on therapy for focal epilepsy.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>CD001416</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>CD001416</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD001416</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The majority of people with epilepsy have a good prognosis, and their seizures can be well controlled with the use of a single antiepileptic agent, but up to 30% develop dug-resistant epilepsy, especially those with focal seizures. In this review, we summarised the evidence from randomised controlled trials (RCT) of zonisamide, used as an add-on treatment for focal epilepsy uncontrolled by one or more concomitant antiepileptic drug. This is an updated version of the Cochrane review previously published in 2018.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of zonisamide, when used as an add-on treatment for people with focal epilepsy uncontrolled by one or more concomitant antiepileptic drugs.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">For the latest update, we searched the Cochrane Register of Studies (CRS Web) and MEDLINE Ovid (September 2019). In addition, we contacted Eisai Limited (makers and licensees of zonisamide) and experts in the field, to seek any ongoing or unpublished studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">Randomised controlled trials, in which add-on zonisamide was compared with placebo or another antiepileptic drug in people with focal epilepsy, uncontrolled by one or more concomitant antiepileptic drugs.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">Two review authors independently selected trials for inclusion, extracted data, assessed for risk of bias using the Cochrane 'Risk of bias' tool, and assessed the certainty of the evidence, using the GRADE approach. The primary outcome was at least a 50% reduction in total seizure frequency; the secondary outcomes were (1) tolerability; and (2) adverse effects. We used an intention-to-treat approach for our primary analyses. We estimated summary risk ratios (RRs) for each outcome. We displayed a summary of the estimates of effects and certainty of the evidence for each outcome in a 'Summary of findings' table.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">We did not find any new studies since the last version of this review. We included eight studies (1636 participants) from previous versions of this review. The overall RR with 95% confidence interval (CI) for at least a 50% reduction in seizure frequency for 300 mg to 500 mg/day of zonisamide compared to placebo was 1.90 (95% CI 1.63 to 2.22; 7 trials, 1371 participants; moderate-certainty evidence). The RR for 50% reduction in seizure frequency compared to placebo for any dose of zonisamide (100 mg to 500 mg/day) was 1.86 (95% CI 1.60 to 2.17; 7 trials, 1429 participants; moderate-certainty evidence). The number needed to treat for an additional beneficial outcome was six (95% CI 4.1 to 6.8). Two trials provided evidence of a dose-response relationship for this outcome. The RR for treatment withdrawal for 300 mg to 500 mg/day of zonisamide compared to placebo was 1.59 (95% CI 1.18 to 2.13; 6 trials, 1099 participants; moderate-certainty evidence), and for 100 mg to 500 mg/day was 1.44 (95% CI 1.08 to 1.93; 6 trials, 1156 participants; moderate-certainty evidence). The number needed to treat for an additional harmful outcome was 15 (95% CI 9.3 to 36.7). The following adverse effects were more likely to be associated with zonisamide than with placebo: ataxia (RR 3.85, 99% CI 1.36 to 10.93; 4 trials, 734 participants; low-certainty evidence); somnolence (RR 1.52, 99% CI 1.00 to 2.31; 8 trials, 1636 participants; moderate-certainty evidence); agitation (RR 2.35, 99% CI 1.05 to 5.27; 4 trials, 598 participants; low-certainty evidence); and anorexia (RR 2.74, 99% CI 1.64 to 4.60; 6 trials, 1181 participants; low-certainty evidence). Across the eight studies, we rated risk of bias domains at low or unclear risk of bias, apart from two studies, which we rated at high risk of attrition bias. Five of the eight studies were sponsored by the drug companies that produced zonisamide.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">When used as an add-on treatment in people with focal epilepsy, uncontrolled by one or more concomitant antiepileptic drugs, moderate-certainty evidence found that zonisamide was more successful than placebo at reducing the frequency of seizures by at least 50%. We were unable to identify minimum effective and maximum tolerated doses. The included trials evaluated a maximum stable-dose phase of 18 weeks, so results cannot be used to confirm longer periods of efficacy in seizure control. The results cannot be extrapolated to monotherapy, or to people with other seizure types or epilepsy syndromes.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brigo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francesco</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Franz Tappeiner Hospital, Merano, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lattanzi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simona</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurological Clinic, Marche Polytechnic University, Ancona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Igwe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stanley C</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuropsychiatry, Federal Teaching Hospital, Abakaliki, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Behzadifar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masoud</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Social Determinants of Health Research Center, Lorestan University of Medical Sciences, Khorramabad, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bragazzi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicola Luigi</ForeName>
            <Initials>NL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Sciences, Postgraduate School of Public Health, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>459384H98V</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000078305">Zonisamide</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf">
          <RefSource>Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018 Oct 18;10:CD001416</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">30335200</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069279" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Resistant Epilepsy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004828" MajorTopicYN="N">Epilepsies, Partial</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057194" MajorTopicYN="N">Intention to Treat Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061366" MajorTopicYN="N">Numbers Needed To Treat</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017211" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Failure</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000078305" MajorTopicYN="N">Zonisamide</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>FB: Francesco Brigo received travel support and accomodation by Lusofarmaco to attend the annual Congress of the Italian Chapter of ILAE; he received fees for speaking from Lusofarmaco. SL: none known SI: none known MB: none known NLB: none known</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715463</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7389315</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies included in this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Duncan R, Vespignani H, Solyom A, Bitensky V. Dose-dependent safety and efficacy of zonisamide in refractory, localization-related epilepsy: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Epilepsia 2004;45(Suppl 7):131, Abstract no: 1.343. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Duncan R, Vespignani H, Solyom A, Bitensky V. Zonisamide is a effective adjunctive therapy for patients with refractory partial epilepsy: results from a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Epilepsia 2004;45(Suppl 3):155, Abstract no: p398. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Duncan R, Vespignani H, Solyom A, Bitenskyy V, Lucas C. Dose-dependent safety and efficacy of zonisamide: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in patients with refractory partial seizures. Epilepsia 2005;46(1):31-41. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Vespignani H. Efficacy of zonisamide against refractory partial seizures in an evaluable patient population. Epilepsia 2005;46(Suppl 6):117-8, Abstract no: p247. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Faught 2001 {published and unpublished data}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Faught E, Ayala R, Montouris GG, Leppik IE. Randomized controlled trial of zonisamide for the treatment of refractory partial-onset seizures. Neurology 2001;57(10):1774-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Guerrini 2013 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Guerrini R, Rosati A, Segieth J, Pellacani S, Bradshaw K, Giorgi L. A randomized phase III trial of adjunctive zonisamide in pediatric patients with partial epilepsy. Epilepsia 2013;54(8):1473-80. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lu 2011 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lu Y, Xiao Z, Yu W, Xiao F, Xiao Z, Hu Y, et al. Efficacy and safety of adjunctive zonisamide in adult patients with refractory partial-onset epilepsy. Clinical Drug Investigation 2011;31(4):221-9. [DOI: 10.2165/11539750-000000000-00000]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11539750-000000000-00000</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sackellares 2004 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sackellares JC, Ramsay RE, Wilder BJ, Browne TR III, Shellenberger MK. Randomized, controlled clinical trial of zonisamide as adjunctive treatment for refractory partial seizures. Epilepsia 2004;45(6):610-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wilder BJ, Ramsay RE, Guterman A. A double blind multicenter placebo controlled study of the efficacy of zonisamide in the treatment of complex partial seizures in medically refractory patients. Internal report of the Dainippon Pharmaceutical Company 1986. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Schmidt 1993 {published and unpublished data}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schmidt D, Jacob R, Loiseau P, Deisenhammer E, Klinger D, Despland A, et al. Zonisamide for add-on treatment of refractory partial epilepsy: a European double blind trial. Epilepsy Research 1993;15(1):67-73. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wu 2010 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wu X, Wu LW, Wang YP, Hong Z, Zhao ZX, Huang YG, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of zonisamide as adjunctive treatment in patients with refractory partial seizures. Chinese Journal of Neurology 2010;43(7):459-63. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Zhang 2011 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Zhang L, Liu Y, Ding C, Shi S, Lin W, Chen T, et al. The efficacy and safety of zonisamide as adjunctive therapy in patients with partial seizure: a multicenter, randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled trial. Chinese Journal of Contemporary Neurology and Neurosurgery 2011;11(4):408-12. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Shimizu 1988 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Shimizu A, Yamamoto J, Yamada Y, Tanaka M, Kawasaki T. The antiepileptic effect of zonisamide on patients with refractory seizures and its side effects. Japanese Journal of Psychiatry and Neurology 1988;42(3):583. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies awaiting assessment</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Anderson 1988 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Anderson TJ, Donaldson IM, McConnell H, Pollock M, Dobbs BR. Zonisamide: comparison with sodium valproate as additional treatment in refractory seizures. New Zealand Medical Journal 1988;101(854):611. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NCT00327717 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT00327717. Evaluating the efficacy and safety of zonisamide in the treatment of partial seizures. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00327717 (first posted 18 May 2006). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NCT01546688 {unpublished data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT01546688. A study to evaluate the safety and tolerability and explore the efficacy of zonisamide as add-on therapy in elderly patients with refractory partial seizures. clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01546688 (first posted 7 March 2012). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>Additional references</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Baulac 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baulac M, Leppik IE. Efficacy and safety of adjunctive zonisamide therapy for refractory partial seizures. Epilepsy Research 2007;75:75-83.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>BNF 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>British National Formulary (BNF). www.bnf.org (accessed May 2013).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Cockerell 1995</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Cockerell OC, Johnson AL, Sander JW, Hart YM, Shorvon SD. Remission of epilepsy: results from the National General Practice Study of Epilepsy. Lancet 1995;346:140-4.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hauser 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hauser WA, Annegers JF, Kurland LT. Incidence of epilepsy and unprovoked seizures in Rochester, Minnesota 1935 - 1984. Epilepsia 1993;34:453-68.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2008</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JP, White IR, Wood AM. Imputation methods for missing outcome data in meta-analysis of clinical trials. Clinical Trials 2008;5(3):225-39.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, Sterne JAC, editor(s). Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kwan 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kwan P, Arzimanoglou A, Berg AT, Brodie MJ, Hauser AW, Mathern G, et al. Definition of drug resistant epilepsy: consensus proposal by the ad hoc Task Force of the ILAE Commission on Therapeutic Strategies. Epilepsia 2010;51(6):1069-77.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lefebvre 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lefebvre C, Manheimer E, Glanville J. Chapter 6: Searching for studies. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Leppik 2004</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Leppik IE. Zonisamide: chemistry, mechanism of action, and pharmacokinetics. Seizure 2004;S13:S5-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Marson 2000</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Williamson PR, Hutton JL, Clough HE, Chadwick DW. Carbamazepine versus valproate monotherapy for epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2000, Issue 3. Art. No: CD001030. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001030]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001030</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Marson 2001</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Hutton JL, Leach JP, Castillo S, Schmidt D, White S, et al. Levetiracetam, oxcarbazepine, remacemide and zonisamide for drug resistant localization-related epilepsy: a systematic review. Epilepsy Research 2001;46(3):259-70.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Marson 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson A, Al-Kharusi A, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al. The SANAD study of effectiveness of carbamazepine, gabapentin, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine, or topiramate for treatment of partial epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2007;369(9566):1000-15.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>McCullagh 1989</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>McCullagh P, Nelder JA. Generalized Linear Models. Second edition. London: Chapman and Hall, 1989.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Mori 1998</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Mori A, Noda Y, Packer L. The anticonvulsant zonisamide scavenges free radicals. Epilepsy Research 1998;30:153-8.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Padgett 1997</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Padgett CS, Ayala R, Montouris GD. Zonisamide efficacy and dose response. Epilepsia 1997;38 Suppl 8:38-74.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sander 1996</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sander JW, Shorvon SD. Epidemiology of the epilepsies. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 1996;61(5):433-43.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Scheffer 2017</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Scheffer IE, Berkovic S, Capovilla G, Connolly MB, French J, Guilhoto L, et al. ILAE classification of the epilepsies: position paper of the ILAE Commission for Classification and Terminology. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):512-21.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Schünemann 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schünemann HJ, Oxman AD, Vist GE, Higgins JPT, Deeks JJ, Glasziou P, et al, Cochrane Applicability and Recommendations Methods Group. Chapter 12 Interpreting results and drawing conclusions. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Schünemann 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schünemann H, Brożek J, Guyatt G, Oxman A, editor(s). Handbook for grading the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations using the GRADE approach (updated October 2013). GRADE Working Group, 2013. Available from gdt.guidelinedevelopment.org/app/handbook/handbook.html.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ueda 2003</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ueda Y, Doi T, Tokumaru J, Willmore LJ. Effect of zonisamide on molecular regulation of glutamate and GABA transporter proteins during epileptogenesis in rats with hippocampal seizures. Molecular Brain Research 2003;116(1-2):1-6.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Whiting 2016</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Whiting P, Savović J, Higgins JP, Caldwell DM, Reeves BC, Shea B, Davies P, Kleijnen J, Churchill R, ROBIS group. ROBIS: A new tool to assess risk of bias in systematic reviews was developed. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 2016;69:225-34.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wilder 1986</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wilder BJ, Ramsay RE, Guterman A. Double blind multicenter placebo-controlled study of the efficacy and safety of zonisamide in the treatment of complex partial seizures in medically refractory patients. Internal Report of the Dianippon Pharmaceutical Co 1986. [CRSREF: 2934611]</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brigo 2018</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brigo F, Lattanzi S, Igwe SC, Behzadifar M, Bragazzi NL. Zonisamide add-on therapy for focal epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 10. Art. No: CD001416. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub4]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub4</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Carmichael 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Carmichael K, Pulman J, Lakhan SE, Parikh P, Marson AG. Zonisamide add-on for drug-resistant partial epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2013, Issue 12. Art. No: CD001416. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub3]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub3</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chadwick 2002</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chadwick DW, Marson AG. Zonisamide add-on for drug-resistant partial epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2002, Issue 2. Art. No: CD001416. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001416]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001416</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chadwick 2005</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chadwick DW, Marson AG. Zonisamide add-on for drug-resistant partial epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2005, Issue 4. Art. No: CD001416. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub2]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001416.pub2</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Marson 1996</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Kadir ZA, Chadwick DW. The new antiepileptic drugs: a systematic review of their efficacy and tolerability. BMJ 1996;313:1169-74.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Marson 1997</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Kadir ZA, Hutton JL, Chadwick DW. The new antiepileptic drugs: a systematic review of their efficacy and tolerability. Epilepsia 1997;38(8):859-80.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
