<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32809709</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK560874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432">Chlamydia Pneumonia</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gautam</LastName><ForeName>Jeevan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Maharajgunj Medical Campus</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krawiec</LastName><ForeName>Conrad</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Penn State College of Medicine</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Pneumonia is an infection of lung parenchyma caused by a variety of pathogens such as bacteria, viruses, fungi, and parasites. One type of bacteria includes Chlamydia species. These species consist of <i>C. pneumoniae, C. psittaci,</i> and<i> C. trachomatis,</i> which are obligate intracellular bacterial pathogens. They frequently infect the respiratory tract in humans. Most of the respiratory tract infections (about 70%) caused by <i>C. pneumoniae</i> are asymptomatic or only with mild symptoms, but a minority (30%) of them are responsible for more severe respiratory illnesses such as community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) with atypical symptoms, bronchitis and upper respiratory tract infections (URTIs). In addition, <i>C. pneumoniae</i> is involved not only in respiratory infections but also in the pathogenesis of multiple inflammatory conditions including chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), asthma, lung cancer, neurological disorders such as Alzheimer disease, multiple sclerosis, and schizophrenia as well as atherosclerosis and arthritis. Thus, the clinician must be able to promptly recognize, evaluate, and treat this condition to avoid its complications.  The following activity will provide an overview of the etiology, clinical features, evaluation, and approach to the management of a patient with chlamydial pneumonia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s11">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s12">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s13">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s14">Pearls and Other Issues</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s15">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s16">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-19432" sec="article-19432.s17">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie G. The definition and classification of pneumonia. Pneumonia (Nathan) 2016;8:14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5471962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28702293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porritt RA, Crother TR. Chlamydia pneumoniae Infection and Inflammatory Diseases. For Immunopathol Dis Therap. 2016;7(3-4):237-254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6345537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30687565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuo CC, Jackson LA, Campbell LA, Grayston JT. Chlamydia pneumoniae (TWAR). Clin Microbiol Rev. 1995 Oct;8(4):451-61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC172870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8665464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hahn DL, Azenabor AA, Beatty WL, Byrne GI. Chlamydia pneumoniae as a respiratory pathogen. Front Biosci. 2002 Mar 01;7:e66-76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11861211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contini C, Seraceni S, Cultrera R, Castellazzi M, Granieri E, Fainardi E. Chlamydophila pneumoniae Infection and Its Role in Neurological Disorders. Interdiscip Perspect Infect Dis. 2010;2010:273573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2825657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20182626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theunissen HJ, Lemmens-den Toom NA, Burggraaf A, Stolz E, Michel MF. Influence of temperature and relative humidity on the survival of Chlamydia pneumoniae in aerosols. Appl Environ Microbiol. 1993 Aug;59(8):2589-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC182324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8368846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balsamo G, Maxted AM, Midla JW, Murphy JM, Wohrle R, Edling TM, Fish PH, Flammer K, Hyde D, Kutty PK, Kobayashi M, Helm B, Oiulfstad B, Ritchie BW, Stobierski MG, Ehnert K, Tully TN. Compendium of Measures to Control Chlamydia psittaci Infection Among Humans (Psittacosis) and Pet Birds (Avian Chlamydiosis), 2017. J Avian Med Surg. 2017 Sep;31(3):262-282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28891690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra KN, Bhardwaj P, Mishra A, Kaushik A. Acute Chlamydia trachomatis respiratory infection in infants. J Glob Infect Dis. 2011 Jul;3(3):216-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3162806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21887051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blasi F, Tarsia P, Arosio C, Fagetti L, Allegra L. Epidemiology of Chlamydia pneumoniae. Clin Microbiol Infect. 1998 Jan;4 Suppl 4:S1-S6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11869264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunha BA. The atypical pneumonias: clinical diagnosis and importance. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2006 May;12 Suppl 3:12-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16669925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogerwerf L, DE Gier B, Baan B, VAN DER Hoek W. Chlamydia psittaci (psittacosis) as a cause of community-acquired pneumonia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Epidemiol Infect. 2017 Nov;145(15):3096-3105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28946931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelrahman YM, Belland RJ. The chlamydial developmental cycle. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 2005 Nov;29(5):949-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16043254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Pietro M, Filardo S, Romano S, Sessa R. Chlamydia trachomatis and Chlamydia pneumoniae Interaction with the Host: Latest Advances and Future Prospective. Microorganisms. 2019 May 16;7(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6560445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31100923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekman MR, Grayston JT, Visakorpi R, Kleemola M, Kuo CC, Saikku P. An epidemic of infections due to Chlamydia pneumoniae in military conscripts. Clin Infect Dis. 1993 Sep;17(3):420-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8218684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain V, Vashisht R, Yilmaz G, Bhardwaj A.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Aug 4, Pneumonia Pathology.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mordhorst CH, Dawson C. Sequelae of neonatal inclusion conjunctivitis and associated disease in parents. Am J Ophthalmol. 1971 Apr;71(4):861-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4928532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redecke V, Dalhoff K, Bohnet S, Braun J, Maass M. Interaction of Chlamydia pneumoniae and human alveolar macrophages: infection and inflammatory response. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 1998 Nov;19(5):721-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9806736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choroszy-Król I, Frej-Mądrzak M, Hober M, Sarowska J, Jama-Kmiecik A. Infections caused by Chlamydophila pneumoniae. Adv Clin Exp Med. 2014 Jan-Feb;23(1):123-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24596014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaillat J. [Clinical manifestations of Chlamydia pneumoniae infections]. Rev Med Interne. 1996;17(12):987-91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9008746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megran D, Peeling RW, Marrie TJ. Chlamydia pneumoniae pneumonia: An evolving clinical spectrum. Can J Infect Dis. 1995 Jul;6(4):191-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3327926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22514396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compendium of measures to control Chlamydia psittaci infection among humans (psittacosis) and pet birds (avian chlamydiosis), 2000. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. MMWR Recomm Rep. 2000 Jul 14;49(RR-8):3-17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10914931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer T. Diagnostic Procedures to Detect Chlamydia trachomatis Infections. Microorganisms. 2016 Aug 05;4(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5039585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27681919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowell SF, Peeling RW, Boman J, Carlone GM, Fields BS, Guarner J, Hammerschlag MR, Jackson LA, Kuo CC, Maass M, Messmer TO, Talkington DF, Tondella ML, Zaki SR, C. pneumoniae Workshop Participants  Standardizing Chlamydia pneumoniae assays: recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (USA) and the Laboratory Centre for Disease Control (Canada). Clin Infect Dis. 2001 Aug 15;33(4):492-503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11462186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pierce VM, Elkan M, Leet M, McGowan KL, Hodinka RL. Comparison of the Idaho Technology FilmArray system to real-time PCR for detection of respiratory pathogens in children. J Clin Microbiol. 2012 Feb;50(2):364-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim WS, van der Eerden MM, Laing R, Boersma WG, Karalus N, Town GI, Lewis SA, Macfarlane JT. Defining community acquired pneumonia severity on presentation to hospital: an international derivation and validation study. Thorax. 2003 May;58(5):377-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12728155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corrêa RA, Costa AN, Lundgren F, Michelin L, Figueiredo MR, Holanda M, Gomes M, Teixeira PJZ, Martins R, Silva R, Athanazio RA, Silva RMD, Pereira MC. 2018 recommendations for the management of community acquired pneumonia. J Bras Pneumol. 2018 Sep-Oct;44(5):405-423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6467584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30517341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zele-Starcević L, Plecko V, Budimir A, Kalenić S. [Choice of antimicrobial drug for infections caused by Chlamydia trachomatis and Chlamydophila pneumoniae]. Acta Med Croatica. 2004;58(4):329-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15700690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma L, Losier A, Tolbert T, Dela Cruz CS, Marion CR. Atypical Pneumonia: Updates on Legionella, Chlamydophila, and Mycoplasma Pneumonia. Clin Chest Med. 2017 Mar;38(1):45-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5679202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28159161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu J, Yarrarapu SNS, Durrani MI.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Aug 25, Psittacosis.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30855889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohseni M, Sung S, Takov V.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Dec 12, Chlamydia.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30725971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohlhoff SA, Huband MD, Hammerschlag MR. In vitro activity of AZD0914, a novel DNA gyrase inhibitor, against Chlamydia trachomatis and Chlamydia pneumoniae. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2014 Dec;58(12):7595-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4249501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25288086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dasaraju PV, Liu C.  Infections of the Respiratory System. In: Baron S, editor. Medical Microbiology. 4th. University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston; Galveston (TX): 1996. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21413304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert K, Fine MJ. Assessing prognosis and predicting patient outcomes in community-acquired pneumonia. Semin Respir Infect. 1994 Sep;9(3):140-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7831536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine MJ, Smith MA, Carson CA, Mutha SS, Sankey SS, Weissfeld LA, Kapoor WN. Prognosis and outcomes of patients with community-acquired pneumonia. A meta-analysis. JAMA. 1996 Jan 10;275(2):134-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8531309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhlestein JB, Anderson JL, Hammond EH, Zhao L, Trehan S, Schwobe EP, Carlquist JF. Infection with Chlamydia pneumoniae accelerates the development of atherosclerosis and treatment with azithromycin prevents it in a rabbit model. Circulation. 1998 Feb 24;97(7):633-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9495296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razavi SM, Mohazzab Torabi S, Salamati P. Treatment and prevention of acute respiratory infections among Iranian hajj pilgrims: a 5-year follow up study and review of the literature. Med J Islam Repub Iran. 2014;28:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4153519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25250272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller KE. Diagnosis and treatment of Chlamydia trachomatis infection. Am Fam Physician. 2006 Apr 15;73(8):1411-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16669564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
