<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">32809601</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK560766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645">Lissencephaly</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kattuoa</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad l.</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yarmouk University</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M Das</LastName><ForeName>Joe</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bahrain Specialist Hospital, Juffair, Bahrain</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Lissencephaly includes a range of severe brain malformations, including agyria (absent gyri), pachygyria (broad gyri), and subcortical band heterotopia. In lissencephaly (which literally means smooth brain), the surface of the brain appears smooth. It may occur as an isolated lissencephaly or in association with certain syndromes (Miller-Dieker syndrome). Lissencephaly is caused by a defect in neuronal migration during embryonic development between 12 and 24 weeks of gestation that results in the absence of normal development of brain gyri and sulci. Children with lissencephaly present with significant developmental delays and mental disability, but these vary from child to child depending on the degree of brain malformation and intractable epilepsy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s10">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s11">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s12">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s13">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s14">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-645" sec="article-645.s15">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Di Donato N, Chiari S, Mirzaa GM, Aldinger K, Parrini E, Olds C, Barkovich AJ, Guerrini R, Dobyns WB. Lissencephaly: Expanded imaging and clinical classification. Am J Med Genet A. 2017 Jun;173(6):1473-1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28440899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fry AE, Cushion TD, Pilz DT. The genetics of lissencephaly. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2014 Jun;166C(2):198-210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24862549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blazejewski SM, Bennison SA, Smith TH, Toyo-Oka K. Neurodevelopmental Genetic Diseases Associated With Microdeletions and Microduplications of Chromosome 17p13.3. Front Genet. 2018;9:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5876250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29628935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan AP, Chong WK, Mankad K. Comprehensive genotype-phenotype correlation in lissencephaly. Quant Imaging Med Surg. 2018 Aug;8(7):673-693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6127521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30211035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bershteyn M, Nowakowski TJ, Pollen AA, Di Lullo E, Nene A, Wynshaw-Boris A, Kriegstein AR. Human iPSC-Derived Cerebral Organoids Model Cellular Features of Lissencephaly and Reveal Prolonged Mitosis of Outer Radial Glia. Cell Stem Cell. 2017 Apr 06;20(4):435-449.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5667944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28111201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leruez-Ville M, Ville Y. Fetal cytomegalovirus infection. Best Pract Res Clin Obstet Gynaecol. 2017 Jan;38:97-107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27923540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavone L, Gullotta F, Incorpora G, Grasso S, Dobyns WB. Isolated lissencephaly: report of four patients from two unrelated families. J Child Neurol. 1990 Jan;5(1):52-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2299140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iefremova V, Manikakis G, Krefft O, Jabali A, Weynans K, Wilkens R, Marsoner F, Brändl B, Müller FJ, Koch P, Ladewig J. An Organoid-Based Model of Cortical Development Identifies Non-Cell-Autonomous Defects in Wnt Signaling Contributing to Miller-Dieker Syndrome. Cell Rep. 2017 Apr 04;19(1):50-59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28380362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan MJ, Tan K, Reck-Peterson SL. Lis1 is an initiation factor for dynein-driven organelle transport. J Cell Biol. 2012 Jun 25;197(7):971-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22711696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friocourt G, Kappeler C, Saillour Y, Fauchereau F, Rodriguez MS, Bahi N, Vinet MC, Chafey P, Poirier K, Taya S, Wood SA, Dargemont C, Francis F, Chelly J. Doublecortin interacts with the ubiquitin protease DFFRX, which associates with microtubules in neuronal processes. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2005 Jan;28(1):153-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15607950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moslehi M, Ng DCH, Bogoyevitch MA. Dynamic microtubule association of Doublecortin X (DCX) is regulated by its C-terminus. Sci Rep. 2017 Jul 12;7(1):5245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5507856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28701724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venø MT, Venø ST, Rehberg K, van Asperen JV, Clausen BH, Holm IE, Pasterkamp RJ, Finsen B, Kjems J. Cortical Morphogenesis during Embryonic Development Is Regulated by miR-34c and miR-204. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5299138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28232790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Agostino MD, Bernasconi A, Das S, Bastos A, Valerio RM, Palmini A, Costa da Costa J, Scheffer IE, Berkovic S, Guerrini R, Dravet C, Ono J, Gigli G, Federico A, Booth F, Bernardi B, Volpi L, Tassinari CA, Guggenheim MA, Ledbetter DH, Gleeson JG, Lopes-Cendes I, Vossler DG, Malaspina E, Franzoni E, Sartori RJ, Mitchell MH, Mercho S, Dubeau F, Andermann F, Dobyns WB, Andermann E. Subcortical band heterotopia (SBH) in males: clinical, imaging and genetic findings in comparison with females. Brain. 2002 Nov;125(Pt 11):2507-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12390976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gécz J, Cloosterman D, Partington M. ARX: a gene for all seasons. Curr Opin Genet Dev. 2006 Jun;16(3):308-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16650978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colombo E, Galli R, Cossu G, Gécz J, Broccoli V. Mouse orthologue of ARX, a gene mutated in several X-linked forms of mental retardation and epilepsy, is a marker of adult neural stem cells and forebrain GABAergic neurons. Dev Dyn. 2004 Nov;231(3):631-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15376319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitamura K, Yanazawa M, Sugiyama N, Miura H, Iizuka-Kogo A, Kusaka M, Omichi K, Suzuki R, Kato-Fukui Y, Kamiirisa K, Matsuo M, Kamijo S, Kasahara M, Yoshioka H, Ogata T, Fukuda T, Kondo I, Kato M, Dobyns WB, Yokoyama M, Morohashi K. Mutation of ARX causes abnormal development of forebrain and testes in mice and X-linked lissencephaly with abnormal genitalia in humans. Nat Genet. 2002 Nov;32(3):359-69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12379852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong SE, Shugart YY, Huang DT, Shahwan SA, Grant PE, Hourihane JO, Martin ND, Walsh CA. Autosomal recessive lissencephaly with cerebellar hypoplasia is associated with human RELN mutations. Nat Genet. 2000 Sep;26(1):93-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10973257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrini E, Conti V, Dobyns WB, Guerrini R. Genetic Basis of Brain Malformations. Mol Syndromol. 2016 Sep;7(4):220-233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5073505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27781032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph LD, Pushpalatha, Kuruvilla S. Cytomegalovirus infection with lissencephaly. Indian J Pathol Microbiol. 2008 Jul-Sep;51(3):402-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18723971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leventer R. Lissencephaly type I. Handb Clin Neurol. 2008;87:205-18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18809027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Rijk-van Andel JF, Arts WF, Hofman A, Staal A, Niermeijer MF. Epidemiology of lissencephaly type I. Neuroepidemiology. 1991;10(4):200-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1745330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Donato N, Timms AE, Aldinger KA, Mirzaa GM, Bennett JT, Collins S, Olds C, Mei D, Chiari S, Carvill G, Myers CT, Rivière JB, Zaki MS, University of Washington Center for Mendelian Genomics. Gleeson JG, Rump A, Conti V, Parrini E, Ross ME, Ledbetter DH, Guerrini R, Dobyns WB. Analysis of 17 genes detects mutations in 81% of 811 patients with lissencephaly. Genet Med. 2018 Nov;20(11):1354-1364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6195491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29671837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazurkiewicz-Bełdzińska M, Szmuda M, Matheisel A. Correlation of neuroradiological, electroencephalographic and clinical findings in cortical dysplasias in children. Folia Neuropathol. 2006;44(4):314-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17183458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang J, Zhao L, Chen C, Peng Y, Xia Y, Tang G, Bai T, Zhang Y, Ma R, Guo R, Mei L, Liang D, Cao Q, Wu L. Pachygyria, seizures, hypotonia, and growth retardation in a patient with an atypical 1.33Mb inherited microduplication at 22q11.23. Gene. 2015 Sep 10;569(1):46-50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26099517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hehr U, Uyanik G, Aigner L, Couillard-Despres S, Winkler J.  DCX-Related Disorders. In: Adam MP, Ardinger HH, Pagon RA, Wallace SE, Bean LJH, Gripp KW, Mirzaa GM, Amemiya A, editors. GeneReviews® [Internet] University of Washington, Seattle; Seattle (WA): 2007. Oct 19, </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20301364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tonni G, Pattacini P, Bonasoni MP, Araujo Júnior E. Prenatal Diagnosis of Lissencephaly Type 2 using Three-dimensional Ultrasound and Fetal MRI: Case Report and Review of the Literature. Rev Bras Ginecol Obstet. 2016 Apr;38(4):201-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27088705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobyns WB. The neurogenetics of lissencephaly. Neurol Clin. 1989 Feb;7(1):89-105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2646523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menascu S, Weinstock A, Farooq O, Hoffman H, Cortez MA. EEG and neuroimaging correlations in children with lissencephaly. Seizure. 2013 Apr;22(3):189-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23298604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devisme L, Bouchet C, Gonzalès M, Alanio E, Bazin A, Bessières B, Bigi N, Blanchet P, Bonneau D, Bonnières M, Bucourt M, Carles D, Clarisse B, Delahaye S, Fallet-Bianco C, Figarella-Branger D, Gaillard D, Gasser B, Delezoide AL, Guimiot F, Joubert M, Laurent N, Laquerrière A, Liprandi A, Loget P, Marcorelles P, Martinovic J, Menez F, Patrier S, Pelluard F, Perez MJ, Rouleau C, Triau S, Attié-Bitach T, Vuillaumier-Barrot S, Seta N, Encha-Razavi F. Cobblestone lissencephaly: neuropathological subtypes and correlations with genes of dystroglycanopathies. Brain. 2012 Feb;135(Pt 2):469-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22323514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viot G, Sonigo P, Simon I, Simon-Bouy B, Chadeyron F, Beldjord C, Tantau J, Martinovic J, Esculpavit C, Brunelle F, Munnich A, Vekemans M, Encha-Razavi F. Neocortical neuronal arrangement in LIS1 and DCX lissencephaly may be different. Am J Med Genet A. 2004 Apr 15;126A(2):123-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15057976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobyns WB, Truwit CL, Ross ME, Matsumoto N, Pilz DT, Ledbetter DH, Gleeson JG, Walsh CA, Barkovich AJ. Differences in the gyral pattern distinguish chromosome 17-linked and X-linked lissencephaly. Neurology. 1999 Jul 22;53(2):270-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10430413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okumura A, Hayashi M, Tsurui H, Yamakawa Y, Abe S, Kudo T, Suzuki R, Shimizu T, Shimojima K, Yamamoto T. Lissencephaly with marked ventricular dilation, agenesis of corpus callosum, and cerebellar hypoplasia caused by TUBA1A mutation. Brain Dev. 2013 Mar;35(3):274-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22633752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
