<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">32810000</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1549-8425</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>16</Volume>
            <Issue>3S Suppl 1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of patient safety</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Patient Saf</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>System-Level Patient Safety Practices That Aim to Reduce Medication Errors Associated With Infusion Pumps: An Evidence Review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>S42</StartPage>
          <EndPage>S47</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>S42-S47</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PTS.0000000000000722</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">In this literature review, we discuss 2 system-level, nurse-targeted patient safety practices (PSPs) that aim to reduce medication errors associated with infusion pumps, including smart pumps. One practice focuses on implementing structured process changes and redesigning workflows to improve efficiencies with pump use. The other focuses on investing in initial and ongoing staff training on the correct use, maintenance, and monitoring of infusion pumps.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Two databases were searched for "infusion pumps" and related synonyms, along with relevant terms for each PSP. Articles were excluded if outcomes were not directly relevant to the PSP addressed in this review, the article was out of scope, or study design was insufficiently described.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Limited research was found on best practices for reducing errors and improving infusion pump use through workflow and process changes, as well as education and training. Four studies reported medication administration errors, procedural errors, or deviations from hospital policy as clinical outcomes of workflow or process changes. Mixed results were found examining process outcomes related to pump handling. Education on the correct use of smart pumps was found to decrease medication errors and adverse drug events, and 2 studies found an increase in nurses' adherence to using the medication safety software library as a result of education.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Standardization of process and integration of technology and workflows were found as facilitators. Type and content of education provided were identified as facilitators, whereas time and energy constraints on nurse educators can be barriers to implementing large hospital-wide education programs.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bacon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Olivia</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Abt Associates, Inc, Rockville, Maryland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hoffman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lynn</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Patient Saf</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101233393</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1549-8417</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007260" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusion Pumps</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007262" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusions, Intravenous</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008508" MajorTopicYN="N">Medication Errors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061214" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Safety</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors disclose no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32810000</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7447176</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PTS.0000000000000722</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">01209203-202009001-00008</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute for Safe Medication Practices 
Proceedings from the ISMP Summit on the Use of Smart Infusion Pumps: Guidelines for Safe Implementation and Use. Philadelphia, PA: Institute for Safe Medication Practices; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox BI, Pedersen CA, Gumpper KF. ASHP national survey on informatics: assessment of the adoption and use of pharmacy informatics in US hospitals-2013 
Am J Health Syst Pharm. 2015;72:636–655.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25825187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute of Medicine; Aspden P Wolcott J Bootman JL, et al., eds. In: Preventing Medication Errors. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press; 2007:480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf ZR.
Strategies to reduce patient harm from infusion-associated medication errors: a scoping review. J Infus Nurs. 2018;36:58–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29293199</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food &amp; Drug Administration 
Infusion Pumps. 2018. 
Available at: https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/general-hospital-devices-and-supplies/infusion-pumps. Accessed March 10, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuliano KK.
IV smart pumps: the impact of a simplified user interface on clinical use. Biomed Instrum Technol. 2015;suppl:13–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26444045</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biltoft J, Finneman L.
Clinical and financial effects of smart pump-electronic medical record interoperability at a hospital in a regional health system. Am J Health Syst Pharm. 2018;75:1064–1068.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29987060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinger MB, Kline A.
Reflections on the current state of infusion therapy. Biomed Instrum Technol. 2016;50:253–262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27413829</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cain C, Haque S.
Organizational workflow and its impact on work quality. In: Hughes R, ed. Patient Safety and Quality: An Evidence-Based Handbook for Nurses. Rockville, MD: Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality; 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Troiano D Morrison J Federico F, et al. . 
Safely automating the medication use process. Not as easy as it looks. J Healthc Inf Manag. 2009;23:17–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19894482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keers RN Williams SD Cooke J, et al. . 
Causes of medication administration errors in hospitals: a systematic review of quantitative and qualitative evidence. Drug Saf. 2013;36:1045–1067.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3824584</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23975331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCartney P.
Evidence for practice with smart infusion pumps. MCN Am J Matern Child Nurs. 2014;39:270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24978008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food &amp; Drug Administration 
Infusion Pump Risk Reduction Strategies for Facility Administrators and Managers. 2018. 
Available at: https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/infusion-pumps/infusion-pump-risk-reduction-strategies-facility-administrators-and-managers. Accessed March 10, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D Liberati A Tetzlaff J, et al. The PRISMA Group . 
Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses: The PRISMA Statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6:e1000097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell RA Triscari D Murkowski K, et al. . 
Impact of computerized order entry to pharmacy interface on order-infusion pump discrepancies. J Drug Deliv. 2015;2015:686598.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4667052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26664749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiseman ML Poole S Ahlin A, et al. . 
Reducing intravenous infusion errors: an observational study of 16 866 patients over five years. J Pharm Pract Res. 2018;48:49–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schnock KO Dykes PC Albert J, et al. . 
The frequency of intravenous medication administration errors related to smart infusion pumps: a multihospital observational study. BMJ Qual Saf. 2017;26:131–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26908900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyons I Furniss D Blandford A, et al. . 
Errors and discrepancies in the administration of intravenous infusions: a mixed methods multihospital observational study. BMJ Qual Saf. 2018;27:892–901.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6225796</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29627799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Degraff B.
As medical devices proliferate, asset management is key. Biomed Instrum Technol. 2013;47:123–127.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23600348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaturvedi RR Etchegaray JM Raaen L, et al. . 
Technology isn’t the half of it: integrating electronic health records and infusion pumps in a large hospital. Jt Comm J Qual Patient Saf. 2019;45:649–661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31500950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferguson R, Williams ML, Beard B.
Combining quality improvement and staff development efforts to decrease patient-controlled analgesia pump errors. J Nurses Staff Dev. 2010;26:E1–E4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20885136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Sluijs AF van Slobbe-Bijlsma ER Goossens A, et al. . 
Reducing errors in the administration of medication with infusion pumps in the intensive care department: a lean approach. SAGE Open Med. 2019;7:2050312118822629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30637103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orto V Hendrix CC Griffith B, et al. . 
Implementation of a smart pump champions program to decrease potential patient harm. J Nurs Care Qual. 2015;30:138–143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25390367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gavriloff C.
A performance improvement plan to increase nurse adherence to use of medication safety software. J Pediatr Nurs. 2012;27:375–382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22703685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herring H Ripley TL Farmer KC, et al. . 
An intervention to increase safety feature use on smart pumps: a quality improvement initiative. J Pharm Technol. 2012;28:119–123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinkney S Trbovich P Fan M, et al. . 
Do smart pumps actually reduce medication errors? Biomed Instrum Technol. 2010;44(s1):64–69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemeth CP Brown J Crandall B, et al. . 
The mixed blessings of smart infusion devices and health care IT. Mil Med. 2014;179(suppl 8):4–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25102542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luctkar-Flude M, Pulling C, Larocque M.
Ending infusion confusion: evaluating a virtual intravenous pump educational module. Clin Simul Nurs. 2012;8:e39–e48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quattromani E Hassler M Rogers N, et al. . 
Smart pump app for infusion pump training. Clin Simul Nurs. 2018;17:28–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iacovides I Blandford A Cox A, et al. . 
Infusion device standardisation and dose error reduction software. Br J Nurs. 2014;23:S16, S18, S20 passim.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25158362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carayon P, Hundt AS, Wetterneck TB.
Nurses’ acceptance of smart IV pump technology. Int J Med Inform. 2010;79:401–411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2862878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20219423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee P.
A team approach to identify and manage risk in infusion therapy. Br J Nurs. 2010;19:S12–S18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subramanyam R Mahmoud M Buck D, et al. . 
Infusion medication error reduction by two-person verification: a quality improvement initiative. Pediatrics. 2016;138
pii: e20154413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27940663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
