<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32853741</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-7573</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>264</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of ethnopharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Ethnopharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Common garlic (Allium sativum L.) has potent Anti-Bacillus anthracis activity.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>113230</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>113230</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jep.2020.113230</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0378-8741(20)33112-3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="ETHNOPHARMACOLOGICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Gastrointestinal anthrax, a disease caused by Bacillus anthracis, remains an important but relatively neglected endemic disease of animals and humans in remote areas of the Indian subcontinent and some parts of Africa. Its initial symptoms include diarrhea and stomachache. In the current study, several common plants indicated for diarrhea, dysentery, stomachache or as stomachic as per traditional knowledge in the Indian subcontinent, i.e., Aegle marmelos (L.) Correa (Bael), Allium cepa L. (Onion), Allium sativum L. (Garlic), Azadirachta indica A. Juss. (Neem), Berberis asiatica Roxb. ex DC. (Daruharidra), Coriandrum sativum L. (Coriander), Curcuma longa L. (Turmeric), Cynodon dactylon (L.) Pers. (Bermuda grass), Mangifera indica L. (Mango), Morus indica L. (Black mulberry), Ocimum tenuiflorum L. (Ocimum sanctum L., Holy Basil), Ocimum gratissimum L. (Ram Tulsi), Psidium guajava L. (Guava), Zingiber officinale Roscoe (Ginger), were evaluated for their anti-Bacillus anthracis property. The usage of Azadirachta indica A. Juss. and Curcuma longa L. by Santals (India), and Allium sp. by biblical people to alleviate anthrax-like symptoms is well documented, but the usage of other plants is traditionally only indicated for different gastrointestinal disturbances/conditions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM OF THE STUDY" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Evaluate the above listed commonly available edible plants from the Indian subcontinent that are used in the traditional medicine to treat gastrointestinal diseases including those also indicated for anthrax-like symptoms for the presence of potent anti-B. anthracis activity in a form amenable to use by the general population in the endemic areas.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Aqueous extracts made from fourteen plants indicated above were screened for their anti-B. anthracis activity using agar-well diffusion assay (AWDA) and broth microdilution methods. The Aqueous Garlic Extract (AGE) that displayed most potent anti-B. anthracis activity was assessed for its thermostability, stability under pH extremes encountered in the gastrointestinal tract, and potential antagonistic interaction with bile salts as well as the FDA-approved antibiotics used for anthrax control. The bioactive fractions from the AGE were isolated by TLC coupled bioautography followed by their characterization using GC-MS.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Garlic (Allium sativum L.) extract was identified as the most promising candidate with bactericidal activity against B. anthracis. It consistently inhibited the growth of B. anthracis in AWDA and decreased the viable colony-forming unit counts in liquid-broth cultures by 6-logs within 6-12 h. The AGE displayed acceptable thermostability (&gt;80% anti-B. anthracis activity retained on incubation at 50 °C for 12 h) and stability in gastric pH range (2-8). It did not antagonize the activity of FDA-approved antibiotics used for anthrax control. GC-MS analysis of the TLC separated bioactive fractions of AGE indicated the presence of previously unreported constituents such as phthalic acid derivatives, acid esters, phenyl group-containing compounds, steroids etc. CONCLUSION: The Aqueous Garlic Extract (AGE) displayed potent anti-B. anthracis activity. It was better than that displayed by Azadirachta indica A. Juss. (Neem) and Mangifera indica L., while Curcuma longa L. (Turmeric) did not show any activity under the assay conditions used. Further work should be undertaken to explore the possible application of AGE in preventing anthrax incidences in endemic areas.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaur</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rajinder</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbial Biotechnology, Panjab University, Chandigarh, 160014, India. Electronic address: rajinderkaurabt@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tiwari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atul</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbial Biotechnology, Panjab University, Chandigarh, 160014, India. Electronic address: atultiwari.microbio@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manish</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manish</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biotechnology, Jawaharlal Nehru University, New Delhi, 110067, India. Electronic address: manishjnu8@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maurya</LastName>
            <ForeName>Indresh K</ForeName>
            <Initials>IK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbial Biotechnology, Panjab University, Chandigarh, 160014, India. Electronic address: inderwinner@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bhatnagar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rakesh</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biotechnology, Jawaharlal Nehru University, New Delhi, 110067, India. Electronic address: rakeshbhatnagar@jnu.ac.in.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Singh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samer</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbial Biotechnology, Panjab University, Chandigarh, 160014, India; Centre of Experimental Medicine and Surgery, Institute of Medical Sciences, Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi, 221005, India. Electronic address: samer@pu.ac.in.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Ireland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Ethnopharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7903310</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0378-8741</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010936">Plant Extracts</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001408" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacillus anthracis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005737" MajorTopicYN="Y">Garlic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008826" MajorTopicYN="N">Microbial Sensitivity Tests</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010936" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Extracts</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Allium sativum</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anthrax</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacillus anthracis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Edible plants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Garlic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Traditional medicine</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2018</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853741</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jep.2020.113230</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0378-8741(20)33112-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
