<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">32886172</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-3023</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>32</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International urogynecology journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int Urogynecol J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A systematic review comparing early with late removal of indwelling urinary catheters after pelvic organ prolapse surgery.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1361</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1372</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1361-1372</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00192-020-04522-y</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">An indwelling catheter is routinely used after pelvic organ prolapse surgery to prevent urinary retention. However, the timing of catheter removal remains controversial.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the optimal timing of catheter removal following prolapse surgery.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Electronic databases including the Cochrane Center Controlled Test Center, Embase, CINAHL, MEDLINE, PubMed, Web of Science and CNKI were searched up to January 2010. Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) comparing different timings of catheter removal after prolapse surgery were eligible. Results from RCTs comparing early versus late removal were pooled, and different durations of catheterization were divided into three sub-comparisons (≤ 2 days versus &gt; 2 days; ≤ 1 day versus 2 days; &lt; 1 day versus 1 day). Primary outcomes were urinary tract infection (UTI) and re-catheterization. Secondary outcomes were the length of hospital stay and patient-reported outcomes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Seven RCTs with 964 women were involved in the analysis. Early catheter removal was associated with a reduced incidence of UTI (RR 0.46, 95% CI 0.24 to 0.9) but an increased risk of re-catheterization (RR 2.67, 95% CI 1.6 to 4.48). Significant differences in primary outcomes were found in the sub-comparison of ≤ 2 days versus &gt; 2 days. Three of six trials found a significantly shorter length of hospital stay in the early removal group. The results for postoperative pain were mixed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Among patients following pelvic organ prolapse surgery, early catheter removal is preferred. Moreover, the timing for removal is preferably within 2 days postoperatively.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Xie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nansha</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urogynecology, Guangzhou Women and Children's Medical Center, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zeyin</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Center, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zengjie</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qiong</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urogynecology, Guangzhou Women and Children's Medical Center, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Intensive Care Unit, Guangzhou Women and Children's Medical Center, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nursing Administrative Office, Guangzhou Women and Children's Medical Center, Guangzhou, China. ly26937@126.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int Urogynecol J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101567041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0937-3462</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002408" MajorTopicYN="N">Catheters, Indwelling</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020878" MajorTopicYN="N">Device Removal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056887" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pelvic Organ Prolapse</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014546" MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary Catheterization</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062885" MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary Catheters</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016055" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Retention</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014552" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Tract Infections</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Catheter</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic organ prolapse</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary retention</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary tract infection</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32886172</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00192-020-04522-y</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00192-020-04522-y</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haylen BT, Maher CF, Barber MD, Camargo S, Dandolu V, Digesu A, et al. An International Urogynecological Association (IUGA)/International Continence Society (ICS) joint report on the terminology for female pelvic organ prolapse (POP). Int Urogynecol J. 2016;27(2):165–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26755051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinberg BJ, Finamore PS, Sastr DN, Holzberg AS, Caraballo R, Echols KT. Postoperative urinary retention following vaginal mesh procedures for the treatment of pelvic organ prolapse. Int Urogynecol J. 2010;21(12):1491–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Withagen MI, Milani AL, den Boon J, Vervest HA, Vierhout ME. Trocar-guided mesh compared with conventional vaginal repair in recurrent prolapse: a randomized controlled trial. ObstetGynecol. 2011;117(2 Pt 1):242–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geller EJ. Prevention and management of postoperative urinary retention after urogynecologic surgery. Int J Women's Health. 2014;6:829–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steggall M, Treacy C, Jones M. Post-operative urinary retention. Nurs Stand (R Coll Nurs (Great Britain): 1987). 2013;28(5):43–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-Aleem H, Aboelnasr MF, Jayousi TM, Habib FA. Indwelling bladder catheterisation as part of intraoperative and postoperative care for caesarean section. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;4. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD010322.pub2 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson R, Malmvall B, Andersson-Gäre B, Larsson B, Erlandsson I, Sund-Levander M, et al. Guidelines for preventing urinary retention and bladder damage during hospital care: guidelines for preventing urinary retention. J Clin Nurs. 2013;22(3-4):347–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22931456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flores-Mireles AL, Walker JN, Caparon M, Hultgren SJ. Urinary tract infections: epidemiology, mechanisms of infection and treatment options. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2015;13(5):269–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4457377</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4457377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saint S, Lipsky BA, Goold SD. Indwelling urinary catheters: a one-point restraint? Ann Intern Med. 2002;137(2):125–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12118969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smyth ETM, McIlveny G, Enstone JE, Emmerson AM, Humphreys H, Fitzpatrick F, et al. Hospital infection society prevalence survey steering group. Four country healthcare associated infection prevalence survey 2006: overview of the results. J Hosp Infect. 2008;69(3):230–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chenoweth CE, Gould CV, Saint S. Diagnosis, management, and prevention of catheter-associated urinary tract infections. Infect Dis Clin. 2014;28(1):105–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wald HL, Ma A, Bratzler DW, Kramer AM. Indwelling urinary catheter use in the postoperative period: analysis of the national surgical infection prevention project data. Arch Surg. 2008;143(6):551–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18559747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tambyah PA, Knasinski V, Maki DG. The direct costs of nosocomial catheter-associated urinary tract infection in the era of managed care. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2002;23(1):27–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11868889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell BG, Ferguson JK, Anderson M, Sear J, Barnett A. Length of stay and mortality associated with healthcare-associated urinary tract infections: a multi-state model. J Hosp Infect. 2016;93(1):92–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26944900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shuman EK, Chenoweth CE. Recognition and prevention of healthcare-associated urinary tract infections in the intensive care unit. Crit Care Med. 2010;38:S373–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang R, Greene MT, Chenoweth CE, Kuhn L, Shuman E, Rogers MA, et al. Epidemiology of hospital-acquired urinary tract-related bloodstream infection at a university hospital. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2011;32(11):1127–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22011543</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3198822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Guideline for prevention of catheter-associated urinary tract infections 2009. 2019. https://www.cdc.gov/infectioncontrol/pdf/guidelines/cauti-guidelines-H.pdf Accessed 20 Feb 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loveday HP, Wilson JA, Pratt RJ, Golsorkhi M, Tingle A, Bak A, et al. epic3: National Evidence-Based Guidelines for preventing healthcare-associated infections in NHS hospitals in England. J Hosp Infect. 2014;86:S1–S70. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0195-6701(13)60012-2 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0195-6701(13)60012-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24330862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hooton TM, Bradley SF, Cardenas DD, Colgan R, Geerlings SE, Rice JC, et al. Diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of catheter-associated urinary tract infection in adults: 2009 international clinical practice guidelines from the Infectious Diseases Society of America. Clin Infect Dis. 2010;50(5):625–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20175247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">20175247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang H, Dong L, Gu L. The timing of urinary catheter removal after gynecologic surgery: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Medicine. 2020;99(2):e18710. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000018710 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000018710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31914080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6959902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson G, Altman AD, Nick A, Meyer LA, Ramirez PT, Achtari C, et al. Guidelines for postoperative care in gynecologic/oncology surgery: enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS®) society recommendations — part II. Gynecol Oncol. 2016;140(2):323–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26757238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6038804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakvoort RA, Burger MP, Emanuel MH, Roovers JP. A nationwide survey to measure practice variation of catheterisation management in patients undergoing vaginal prolapse surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2009;20(7):813–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiøtz HA, Tanbo TG. Postoperative voiding, bacteriuria and urinary tract infection with Foley catheterization after gynecological surgery. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2006;85(4):476–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16612711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haya N, Feiner B, Baessler K, Christmann-Schmid C, Maher C. Perioperative interventions in pelvic organ prolapse surgery. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018;8. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD013105 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd SS, Tunitsky-Bitton E, O'Sullivan DM, Steinberg AC. Postoperative catheter management after pelvic reconstructive surgery: a survey of practice strategies. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg. 2018;24(2):188–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29300254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahajan ST, Elkadry EA, Kenton KS, Shott S, Brubaker L. Patient-centered surgical outcomes: the impact of goal achievement and urge incontinence on patient satisfaction one year after surgery. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2006;194(3):722–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16522404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkadry EA, Kenton KS, FitzGerald MP, Shott S, Brubaker L. Patient-selected goals: a new perspective on surgical outcome. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2003;189(6):1551–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14710061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151(4):264–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, Gøtzsche PC, Jüni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration’s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. Bmj. 2011;343:d5928. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.d5928 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3196245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins J, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 6 the Cochrane collaboration. 2019. Available at: https://training.cochrane.org/handbook/current . Accessed 25 Feb 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kokabi R, Fereidouni Z, Meshkibaf MH, Miladpoor B. Post-operative voiding efficacy after anterior colporrhaphy. Acta Medica Iranica. 2010;48(1):33–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21137666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aslam M, Bazzi A, Hagglund K, Osmundsen B. When to remove the indwelling catheter after minimally invasive sacrocolpopexy? CARESS (CAtheter REmoval after Sacrocolpopexy surgery). Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg. 2020;26(2):120–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31990800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahnaz A, Elham R, Kambiz A, Sara K. Comparison of 1 versus 3 days post-operative catheterization after anterior colporrhaphy. Asian J Pharm Res Health Care. 2016;8(S1):1–6. https://doi.org/10.18311/ajprhc/2016/7711 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18311/ajprhc/2016/7711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahmin K, Begum SN. Short term versus conventional catheterisation after genital prolapse surgery. Bangladesh J Obstet Gynaecol. 2011;26(2):68–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carter-Brooks CM, Zyczynski HM, Moalli PA, Brodeur PG, Shepherd JP. Early catheter removal after pelvic floor reconstructive surgery: a randomized trial. Int Urogynecol J. 2018;29(8):1203–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29600401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6612279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamilya G, Seal SL, Mukherji J, Bhattacharyya SK, Hazra A. A randomized controlled trial comparing short versus long-term catheterization after uncomplicated vaginal prolapse surgery. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2010;36(1):154–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20178542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kringel U, Reimer T, Tomczak S, Green S, Kundt G, Gerber B. Postoperative infections due to bladder catheters after anterior colporrhaphy: a prospective, randomized three-arm study. Int Urogynecol J. 2010;21(12):1499–504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20683580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weemhoff M, Wassen MM, Korsten L, Serroyen J, Kampschöer PH, Roumen FJ. Postoperative catheterization after anterior colporrhaphy: 2 versus 5 days, a multicentre randomized controlled trial. Int Urogynecol J. 2011;22(4):477–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20960149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrestha B, Marhatha R, Kayastha S, Jaishi S. Short-term versus long-term catheterization after vaginal prolapse surgery. Nepal Med Coll J. 2013;15:102–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24696926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallabh-Patel V, Popiel P, Salamon C. Indwelling versus immediate removal of transurethral catheter after robotic sacrocolpopexy: a randomized clinical trial. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg. 2018. https://doi.org/10.1097/SPV.0000000000000646 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez-Gonzalez S, Franco EM, Martínez-Cumplido R, Coll CM, González FO, Roig MDG, et al. Reducing postoperative catheterisation after anterior colporrhaphy from 48 to 24 h: a randomised controlled trial. Int Urogynecol J. 2019;30(11):1897–902.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30483852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tambyah PA, Maki DG. The relationship between pyuria and infection in patients with indwelling urinary catheters: a prospective study of 761 patients. Arch Intern Med. 2000;160(5):673–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10724053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price TK, Hilt EE, Dune TJ, Mueller ER, Wolfe AJ, Brubaker L. Urine trouble: should we think differently about UTI? Int Urogynecol J. 2018;29(2):205–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29279968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahman S, Shafi MI. Perioperative care in gynaecology. Obstet Gynaecol Reprod Med. 2014;24(12):371–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corty EW, Corty RW. Setting sample size to ensure narrow confidence intervals for precise estimation of population values. Nurs Res. 2011;60(2):148–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21336224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trowbridge ER, Dreisbach CN, Sarosiek BM, Dunbar CP, Evans SL, Hahn LA, et al. Review of enhanced recovery programs in benign gynecologic surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2018;29(1):3–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28871417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chong C, Kim HS, Suh DH, Jee BC. Risk factors for urinary retention after vaginal hysterectomy for pelvic organ prolapse. Obstet Gynecol Sci. 2016;59(2):137–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27004205</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4796084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalogera E, Nelson G, Liu J, Hu QL, Ko CY, Wick E, et al. Surgical technical evidence review for gynecologic surgery conducted for the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality safety program for improving surgical care and recovery. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2018;219(6):563–e1. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajog.2018.07.014 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2018.07.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30031749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fattah AN, Santoso BI. Urinary catheterization in gynecological surgery: when should it be removed? Med J Indones. 2013;22(3):183–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aromataris E, Pearson A. The systematic review: an overview. AJN Am J Nurs. 2014;114(3):53–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24572533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phipps S, Lim YN, McClinton S, Barry C, Rane A, N'Dow J. Short term urinary catheter policies following urogenital surgery in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2006;2006(2). https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD004374.pub2 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffiths R, Fernandez R. Strategies for the removal of short-term indwelling urethral catheters in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2007;2. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD004011.pub3 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savović J, Jones HE, Altman DG, Harris RJ, Jüni P, Pildal J, et al. Influence of reported study design characteristics on intervention effect estimates from randomized, controlled trials. Ann Intern Med. 2012;157(6):429–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22945832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berkman ND, Santaguida PL, Viswanathan M, Morton SC. The empirical evidence of bias in trials measuring treatment differences. Methods Research Report. 2014. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/sites/books/NBK253181/ Accessed 26 Feb 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Kunz R, Woodcock J, Brozek J, Helfand M, et al. GRADE guidelines: 7. Rating the quality of evidence—inconsistency. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(12):1294–302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakvoort RA, Thijs SD, Bouwmeester FW, Broekman AM, Ruhe IM, Vernooij MM, et al. Comparing clean intermittent catheterisation and transurethral indwelling catheterisation for incomplete voiding after vaginal prolapse surgery: a multicentre randomised trial. BJOG Int J Obstet Gynaecol. 2011;118(9):1055–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simsek YZ, Sureyya K. Postoperative urinary retention and nursing approaches. Int J. 2016;9(2):1154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geller EJ, Hankins KJ, Parnell BA, Robinson BL, Dunivan GC. Diagnostic accuracy of retrograde and spontaneous voiding trials for postoperative voiding dysfunction: a randomized controlled trial. Obstet Gynecol. 2011;118(3):637–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21860294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo TS, Shailaja N, Hsieh WC, Uy-Patrimonio MC, Yusoff FM, Ibrahim R. Predictors of voiding dysfunction following extensive vaginal pelvic reconstructive surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2017;28(4):575–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27647467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakvoort RA, Dijkgraaf MG, Burger MP, Emanuel MH, Roovers JPW. Predicting short-term urinary retention after vaginal prolapse surgery. Neurourol Urodyn. 2009;28(3):225–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19130599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. J Clin Epidemiol. 2010;63:834–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20346629</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
