<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32931694</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1540-0514</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Shock (Augusta, Ga.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Shock</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>CA1 Hippocampal Pyramidal Cells in Rats, Resuscitated From 8 Minutes of Ventricular Fibrillation Cardiac Arrest, Recover After 20 Weeks of Survival: A Retrospective Pilot Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>531</StartPage>
          <EndPage>538</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>531-538</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/SHK.0000000000001469</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">The cornu ammonis 1 (CA1) region of the hippocampus is specifically vulnerable to global ischemia. We hypothesized that histopathological outcome in a ventricular fibrillation cardiac arrest (VFCA) rat model depends on the time point of the examination.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Male Sprague-Dawley rats were put into VFCA for 8 min, received chest compressions for 2 min, and were defibrillated to achieve return of spontaneous circulation. Animals surviving for 80 min, 14 days and 140 days were compared with controls. Viable neurons were counted in a 500 μm sector of the CA1 region and layer thickness measured. Microglia cells and astrocytes were counted in a 250×300 μm aspect.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Control and 80 min surviving animals had similar numbers of pyramidal neurons in the CA1 region. In 14 days and 140 days survivors neuron numbers and layer thickness were severely diminished compared with controls (P &lt; 0.001). Two-thirds of the 140 days survivors showed significantly more viable neurons than the last third. Microglia was increased in 14 days survivors compared with controls and 140 days survivors, while astrocytes increased in 14 days and 140 days survivors compared with controls (P &lt; 0.001). 140 days survivors had significantly higher astrocyte counts compared with 14 days survivors.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The amount and type of brain lesions present after global ischemia depend on the survival time. A consistent reduction in pyramidal cells in the CA1 region was present in all animals 14 days after VFCA, but in two-thirds of animals a repopulation of pyramidal cells seems to have taken place after 140 days.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Weihs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wolfgang</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Warenits</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexandra-Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ettl</LastName>
            <ForeName>Florian</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Magnet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ingrid Anna Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>IAM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Herkner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Harald</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kramer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anne Margarethe</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Biomedical Research, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Teubenbacher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ursula</ForeName>
            <Initials>U</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathobiology, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lobmeyr</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elisabeth</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schriefl</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christoph</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Clodi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christian</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bauder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Barbara</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathobiology, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tiboldi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akos</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anaesthesia, Intensive Care Medicine and Pain Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Holzer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Janata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andreas</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Medical University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, Krankenanstalt Rudolfstiftung, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Högler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathobiology, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Shock</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9421564</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1073-2322</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056547" MajorTopicYN="N">CA1 Region, Hippocampal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006323" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Arrest</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017966" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014693" MajorTopicYN="N">Ventricular Fibrillation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32931694</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SHK.0000000000001469</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00024382-202010000-00013</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nürnberger A, Sterz F, Malzer R, Warenits A, Girsa M, Stöckl M, Hlavin G, Magnet IA, Weiser C, Zajicek A, et al. Out of hospital cardiac arrest in Vienna: incidence and outcome. Resuscitation 84 (1):4247, 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abella BS, Zhao D, Alvarado J, Hamann K, Vanden Hoek TL, Becker LB. Intra-arrest cooling improves outcomes in a murine cardiac arrest model. Circulation 109 (22):27862791, 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao D, Abella BS, Beiser DG, Alvarado JP, Wang H, Hamann KJ, Hoek TL, Becker LB. Intra-arrest cooling with delayed reperfusion yields higher survival than earlier normothermic resuscitation in a mouse model of cardiac arrest. Resuscitation 77 (2):242249, 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang L, Weil MH, Sun S, Cammarata G, Cao L, Tang W. Levosimendan improves postresuscitation outcomes in a rat model of CPR. J Lab Clin Med 146 (5):256261, 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teschendorf P, Albertsmeier M, Vogel P, Padosch SA, Spöhr F, Kirschfink M, Schwaninger M, Böttiger BW, Popp E. Neurological outcome and inflammation after cardiac arrest effects of protein C in rats. Resuscitation 79 (2):316324, 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosmann A, Schober A, Gruber A, Sterz F, Testori C, Warenits A, Weihs W, Högler S, Scherer T, Janata A, et al. Cerebral and peripheral metabolism to predict successful reperfusion after cardiac arrest in rats: a microdialysis study. Neurocrit Care 24 (2):283293, 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schober A, Warenits AM, Testori C, Weihs W, Hosmann A, Högler S, Sterz F, Janata A, Scherer T, Magnet IA, et al. Microdialysis assessment of cerebral perfusion during cardiac arrest, extracorporeal life support and cardiopulmonary resuscitation in rats—a pilot trial. PLoS One 11 (5):e0155303, 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weihs W, Warenits AM, Ettl F, Magnet IA, Teubenbacher U, Hilpold A, Schober A, Testori C, Tiboldi A, Mag KT, et al. Reduced long-term memory in a rat model of 8 minutes ventricular fibrillation cardiac arrest: a pilot trial. BMC Vet Res 12 (1):103, 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warenits AM, Sterz F, Schober A, Ettl F, Magnet IA, Högler S, Teubenbacher U, Grassmann D, Wagner M, Janata A, et al. Reduction of serious adverse events demanding study exclusion in model development: extracorporeal life support resuscitation of ventricular fibrillation cardiac arrest in rats. Shock 46 (6):704712, 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magnet IAM, Ettl F, Schober A, Warenits AM, Grassmann D, Wagner M, Schriefl C, Clodi C, Teubenbacher U, Högler S, et al. Extracorporeal life support increases survival after prolonged ventricular fibrillation cardiac arrest in the rat. Shock 48 (6):674680, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ettl F, Magnet IAM, Weihs W, Warenits A, Grassmann D, Wagner M, Teubenbacher U, Högler S, Sterz F, Janata A. Establishing a rodent model of ventricular fibrillation cardiac arrest with graded histologic and neurologic damage with different cardiac arrest durations. Shock 50 (2):219225, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moulaert VR, Verbunt JA, van Heugten CM, Wade DT. Cognitive impairments in survivors of out-of-hospital cardiac arrest: a systematic review. Resuscitation 80 (3):297305, 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squire LR, Zola-Morgan S, Chen KS. Human amnesia and animal models of amnesia: performance of amnesic patients on tests designed for the monkey. Behav Neurosci 102 (2):210221, 1988.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith ML, Auer RN, Siesjö BK. The density and distribution of ischemic brain injury in the rat following 2-10 min of forebrain ischemia. Acta Neuropathol 64 (4):319332, 1984.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakatomi H, Kuriu T, Okabe S, Yamamoto S, Hatano O, Kawahara N, Tamura A, Kirino T, Nakafuku M. Regeneration of hippocampal pyramidal neurons after ischemic brain injury by recruitment of endogenous neural progenitors. Cell 110 (4):429441, 2002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janata A, Drabek T, Magnet IA, Stezoski JP, Janesko-Feldman K, Popp E, Garman RH, Tisherman SA, Kochanek PM. Extracorporeal versus conventional cardiopulmonary resuscitation after ventricular fibrillation cardiac arrest in rats: a feasibility trial. Crit Care Med 41 (9):e211e222, 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anacker C, Hen R. Adult hippocampal neurogenesis and cognitive flexibility- linking memory and mood. Nat Rev Neurosci 18 (6):335346, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cain DP, Saucier D. The neuroscience of spatial navigation: focus on behavior yields advances. Rev Neurosci 7 (3):215231, 1996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moser E, Moser MB, Andersen P. Spatial learning impairment parallels the magnitude of dorsal hippocampal lesions, but is hardly present following ventral lesions. J Neurosci 13 (9):39163925, 1993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albertsmeier M, Teschendorf P, Popp E, Galmbacher R, Vogel P, Böttiger BW. Evaluation of a tape removal test to assess neurological deficit after cardiac arrest in rats. Resuscitation 74 (3):552558, 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Popp E, Rabsahl T, Schneider A, Russ N, Spöhr F, Vogel P, Böttiger BW, Teschendorf P. Intracerebroventricular application of granulocyte colony-stimulating factor after cardiac arrest does not promote beneficial effects on cerebral recovery after cardia arrests in rats. Resuscitation 80 (4):478483, 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider A, Teschendorf P, Vogel P, Russ N, Knapp J, Böttiger BW, Popp E. Facilitation of hypothermia by quinpirole and 8-OH-DPAT in a rat model of cardiac arrest. Resuscitation 83 (2):232237, 2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knapp J, Heinzmann A, Schneider A, Padosch SA, Böttiger BW, Teschendorf P, Popp E. Hypothermia and neuroprotection by sulfide after cardiac arrest and cardiopulmonary resuscitation. Resuscitation 82 (8):10761080, 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zuercher P, Springe D, Grandgirard D, Leib SL, Grossholz M, Jakob S, Takala J, Haenggi M. A randomized trial of the effects of the noble gases helium and argon on neuroprotection in a rodent cardiac arrest model. BMC Neurol 16:43, 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Popp E, Padosch SA, Vogel P, Schäbitz WR, Schwab S, Böttiger BW. Effects of intracerebroventricular application of brain-derived neurotrophic factor on cerebral recovery after cardiac arrest in rats. Crit Care Med 32: (9 suppl): 359365, 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bendel O, Alkass K, Bueters T, von Euler M, von Euler G. Reproducible loss of CA1 neurons following carotid artery occlusion combined with halothane induced hypotension. Brain Res 1033 (2):135142, 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bendel O, Bueters T, von Euler M, Ove Ogren S, Sandin J, von Euler G. Reappearance of hippocampal CA1 neurons after ischemia is associated with recovery of learning and memory. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 25 (12):15861595, 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langdon KD, Granter-Button S, Corbett D. Persistent behavioral impairments and neuroinflammation following global ischemia in the rat. Eur J Neurosci 28 (11):23102318, 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bueters T, von Euler M, Bendel O, von Euler G. Degeneration of newly formed CA1 neurons following global ischemia in the rat. Exp Neurol 209 (1):114124, 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuda Y, Shimoda T, Uno K, Tateishi N, Furuya S, Tsuchihashi Y, Kawai Y, Naruse S, Fujita S. Temporal and sequential changes of glial cells and cytokine expression during neuronal degeneration after transient global ischemia in rats. J Neuroinflammation 8:70, 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cope EC, Gould E. Adult neurogenesis, glia, and the extracellular matrix. Cell Stem Cell 24 (5):690705, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffiths BB, Ouyang YB, Xu L, Sun X, Giffard RG, Stary CM. Postinjury inhibition of miR-181a promotes restoration of hippocampal CA1 neurons after transient forebrain ischemia in rats. eNeuro 2019; 6 (4): pii: ENEURO.0002-19.2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanisch UK, Kettenmann H. Microglia: active sensor and versatile effector cells in the normal and pathologic brain. Nat Neurosci 10 (11):13871394, 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emsley JG, Mitchell BD, Kempermann G, Macklis JD. Adult neurogenesis and repair of the adult CNS with neural progenitors, precursors, and stem cells. Prog Neurobiol 75 (5):321341, 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alipanahzadeh H, Soleimani M, Soleimani Asl S, Pourheydar B, Nikkhah A, Mehdizadeh M. Transforming growth factor -( improves memory impairment and neurogenesis following ischemia reperfusion. Cell J 16 (3):315324, 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu YM, Gao X, Ni Y, Li W, Kent TA, Qiao SG, Wang C, Xu XX, Zhang HL. Sevoflurane postconditioning attenuates reactive astrogliosis and glial scar formation after ischemia-reperfusion brain injury. Neuroscience 356:125141, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li CY, Li X, Liu SF, Qu WS, Wang W, Tian DS. Inhibition of mTOR pathway restrains astrocyte proliferation, migration and production of inflammatory mediators after oxygen-glucose deprivation and reoxygenation. Neurochem Int 83-84:918, 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colburne F, Corbett D. Delayed and prolonged post-ischemic hypothermia is neuroprotective in the gerbil. Brain Res 654 (2):265272, 1994.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbett D, Nurse S. The problem of assessing effective neuroprotection in experimental cerebral ischemia. Prog Neurobiol 54 (5):531548, 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rapp P, Gallagher M. Preserved neuron number in the hippocampus of aged rats with spatial learning deficits. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 93 (18):99269930, 1996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilkenny C, Browne WJ, Cuthill IC, Emerson M, Altman DG. Improving bioscience research reporting: the ARRIVE guidelines for reporting animal research. PLoS Biol 8:e1000412, 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
