<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32943948</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1179-1454</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of experimental pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Exp Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>New Insights into the Mechanism of Action of Viloxazine: Serotonin and Norepinephrine Modulating Properties.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>285</StartPage>
          <EndPage>300</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>285-300</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/JEP.S256586</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Viloxazine was historically described as a norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor (NRI). Since NRIs have previously demonstrated efficacy in attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), viloxazine underwent contemporary investigation in the treatment of ADHD. Its clinical and safety profile, however, was found to be distinct from other ADHD medications targeting norepinephrine reuptake. Considering the complexity of neuropsychiatric disorders, understanding the mechanism of action (MoA) is an important differentiating point between viloxazine and other ADHD medications and provides pharmacology-based rationale for physicians prescribing appropriate therapy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Viloxazine was evaluated in a series of in vitro binding and functional assays. Its effect on neurotransmitter levels in the brain was evaluated using microdialysis in freely moving rats.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We report the effects of viloxazine on serotoninergic (5-HT) system. In vitro, viloxazine demonstrated antagonistic activity at 5-HT<sub>2B</sub> and agonistic activity at 5-HT<sub>2C</sub> receptors, along with predicted high receptor occupancy at clinical doses. In vivo, viloxazine increased extracellular 5-HT levels in the prefrontal cortex (PFC), a brain area implicated in ADHD. Viloxazine also exhibited moderate inhibitory effects on the norepinephrine transporter (NET) in vitro and in vivo, and elicited moderate activity at noradrenergic and dopaminergic systems.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Viloxazine's ability to increase 5-HT levels in the PFC and its agonistic and antagonistic effects on certain 5-HT receptor subtypes, which were previously shown to suppress hyperlocomotion in animals, indicate that 5-HT modulating activity of viloxazine is an important (if not the predominant) component of its MoA, complemented by moderate NET inhibition. Supported by clinical data, these findings suggest the updated psychopharmacological profile of viloxazine can be best explained by its action as a serotonin norepinephrine modulating agent (SNMA).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Yu et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chungping</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Garcia-Olivares</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jennie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Candler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shawn</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schwabe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maletic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vladimir</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry/Behavioral Science, University of South Carolina School of Medicine, Greenville, SC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Exp Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101530345</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1179-1454</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ADHD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SPN-812</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanism of action</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">norepinephrine transporter</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serotonin norepinephrine modulating agent</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">viloxazine</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>CY, JGO, SC, and SS are employees of Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc. VM is an employee of the University of South Carolina School of Medicine. He is a consultant for ACADIA Pharmaceuticals Inc.; Alfasigma USA, Inc.; Alkermes, Inc.; Allergan; Eisai-Purdue; Intra-Cellular Therapies; Janssen; H. Lundbeck A/S; Otsuka America Pharmaceutical, Inc.; Sage Pharmaceuticals; Sunovion Pharmaceuticals Inc.; Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc.; and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. He serves on the speakers bureau of ACADIA Pharmaceuticals Inc.; Alkermes, Inc.; Allergan; Ironshore; Intra-Cellular; Janssen; H. Lundbeck A/S; Otsuka America Pharmaceutical, Inc.; Sunovion Pharmaceuticals Inc.; and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. The authors report no other conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>49</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943948</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7473988</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JEP.S256586</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">256586</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foye WO. Pharmacodynamic agents In: Foye’s Principles of Medicinal Chemistry. Lemke TL, Williams DA, Roche VF, and Zito SW, eds. UK: Wolters Kluwer Health/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2013:610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinder RM, Brogden RN, Speight TM, Avery GS. Viloxazine: a review of its pharmacological properties and therapeutic efficacy in depressive illness. Drugs. 1977;13(6):401–421. doi:10.2165/00003495-197713060-00001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00003495-197713060-00001.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">324751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenwood DT. International vivalan symposium; Animal pharmacology of viloxazine (Vivalan). J Int Med Res. 1975;3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carlier PR, Lo MM, Lo PC, et al. Synthesis of a potent wide-spectrum serotonin-, norepinephrine-, dopamine-reuptake inhibitor (SNDRI) and a species-selective dopamine-reuptake inhibitor based on the gamma-amino alcohol functional group. Bioorg Med Chem Lett. 1998;8(5):487–492. doi:10.1016/S0960-894X(98)00062-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0960-894X(98)00062-6.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9871604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lippman W, Pugsley TA. Effects of viloxazine, an antidepressant agent, on biogenic amine uptake mechanisms and related activities. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 1976;54(4):494–509. doi:10.1139/y76-069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/y76-069.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">974878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ClinicalTrials.gov. Evaluation of SPN-812 ER low dose in children with ADHD.
Available from:
https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03247530?term=NCT03247530&amp;rank=1. 2018. 
Accessed October16, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinicaltrials.gov. Evaluation of SPN-812 ER low dose in adolescents with ADHD.
Available from:
https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03247517?term=NCT03247517&amp;rank=1. Accessed October16, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinicaltrials.gov. Evaluation of SPN-812 ER high dose in children with ADHD.
Available from:
https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03247543?term=NCT03247543&amp;rank=1. Accessed October16, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nageye F, Cortese S. Beyond stimulants: a systematic review of randomised controlled trials assessing novel compounds for ADHD. Expert Rev Neurother. 2019;19(7):707–717. doi:10.1080/14737175.2019.1628640.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2019.1628640.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31167583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JK, Liranso T, Saylor K, et al. A Phase II double-blind, placebo-controlled, efficacy and safety study of SPN-812 (Extended-Release Viloxazine) in children with ADHD. J Atten Disord. 2020;24(2):348–358. doi:10.1177/1087054719836159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1087054719836159.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6939319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30924702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Faison SL, Liranso T et al. An assessment of QTc effects with SPN-812 (Extended-Release Viloxazine) in healthy adults. Neuroscience Education Institute 15th Annual Congress; November
7–10, 2019; Colorado Springs, CO.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corona GL, Frattini P, Cucchi ML, et al. Viloxazine in depressed women: clinical response and cardiovascular effects. Int J Clin Pharmacol Ther Toxicol. 1987;25(6):322–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3623737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV. The pharmacology of amphetamine and methylphenidate: relevance to the neurobiology of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder and other psychiatric comorbidities. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2018;87:255–270. doi:10.1016/j.neubiorev.2018.02.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2018.02.001.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29428394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green EA, Raj V, Shibao CA, et al. Effects of norepinephrine reuptake inhibition on postural tachycardia syndrome. J Am Heart Assoc. 2013;2(5):e000395. doi:10.1161/JAHA.113.000395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.113.000395.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3835251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24002370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong DT, Threlkeld PG, Best KL, Bymaster FP. A new inhibitor of norepinephrine uptake devoid of affinity for receptors in rat brain. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1982;222(1):61–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6123593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong EH, Sonders MS, Amara SG, et al. Reboxetine: a pharmacologically potent, selective, and specific norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor. Biol Psychiatry. 2000;47(9):818–829. doi:10.1016/S0006-3223(99)00291-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-3223(99)00291-7.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10812041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bymaster FP, Katner JS, Nelson DL, et al. Atomoxetine increases extracellular levels of norepinephrine and dopamine in prefrontal cortex of rat: a potential mechanism for efficacy in attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2002;27(5):699–711. doi:10.1016/S0893-133X(02)00346-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0893-133X(02)00346-9.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12431845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tatsumi M, Groshan K, Blakely RD, Richelson E. Pharmacological profile of antidepressants and related compounds at human monoamine transporters. Eur J Pharmacol. 1997;340(2–3):249–258. doi:10.1016/S0014-2999(97)01393-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-2999(97)01393-9.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9537821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenwood DT. Viloxazine and neurotransmitter function. Adv Biochem Psychopharmacol. 1982;31:287–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6282059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnsten AF. The emerging neurobiology of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: the key role of the prefrontal association cortex. J Pediatr. 2009;154(5):I–S43. doi:10.1016/j.jpeds.2009.01.018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2009.01.018.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2894421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20596295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volkow ND, Morales M. The brain on drugs: from reward to addiction. Cell. 2015;162(4):712–725. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2015.07.046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2015.07.046.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26276628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bymaster FP, Zhang W, Carter PA, et al. Fluoxetine, but not other selective serotonin uptake inhibitors, increases norepinephrine and dopamine extracellular levels in prefrontal cortex. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 2002;160(4):353–361. doi:10.1007/s00213-001-0986-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-001-0986-x.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11919662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li D, Kerns EH, edited by. Blood-Brain Barrier in Drug Discovery: Optimizing Brain Exposure of CNS Drugs and Minimizing Brain Side Effects for Peripheral Drugs;2015. ISBN 978-1-118-78835-6 (hardback).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Settimo L, Taylor D. Evaluating the dose-dependent mechanism of action of trazodone by estimation of occupancies for different brain neurotransmitter targets. J Psychopharmacol. 2018;32(1):96–104. doi:10.1177/0269881117742101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881117742101.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29332554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paxinos G. The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates. 6th ed. Academic Press; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>STRATTERA®. Prescribing Information. Indianapolis, IN: Lilly USA, LLC; 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VYVANSE®. Prescribing Information. Lexington, MA: Shire US Inc; 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CONCERTA®. Prescribing Information. Titusville, NJ: Janssen Pharmaceuticals, Inc; 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin IL, Baker GB, Mitchell PR. The effect of viloxazine hydrochloride on the transport of noradrenaline, dopamine, 5-hydroxytryptamine and gamma-amino-butyric acid in rat brain tissue. Neuropharmacology. 1978;17(6):421–423. doi:10.1016/0028-3908(78)90018-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0028-3908(78)90018-7.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">673157</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones RS, Roberts MH
Effects of viloxazine on cortical neurone responses to monoamines and acetylcholine
Paper presented at: Proceedings of the British Association for Psychopharmacology; March, 1977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1667920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">843706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones RS, Roberts MH
Potentiation of monoamine responses of denervated cells by a noradrenaline uptake inhibitor (viloxazine)
Paper presented at: Proceedings of the British Association for Psychopharmacology; March, 1978.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1668201</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">638334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones RS, Roberts MH
Potentiation of responses to monoamines by antidepressants after destruction of monoamine afferents. Paper presented at: Proceedings of the British Association for Psychopharmacology; March, 1979.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1668645</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">311665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devroye C, Cathala A, Di Marco B, et al. Central serotonin(2B) receptor blockade inhibits cocaine-induced hyperlocomotion independently of changes of subcortical dopamine outflow. Neuropharmacology. 2015;97:329–337. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2015.06.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2015.06.012.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26116760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cathala A, Devroye C, Maitre M, et al. Serotonin2C receptors modulate dopamine transmission in the nucleus accumbens independently of dopamine release: behavioral, neurochemical and molecular studies with cocaine. Addict Biol. 2015;20(3):445–457. doi:10.1111/adb.12137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/adb.12137.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24661380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaw P, Stringaris A, Nigg J, Leibenluft E. Emotion dysregulation in attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. Am J Psychiatry. 2014;171(3):276–293. doi:10.1176/appi.ajp.2013.13070966.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2013.13070966.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4282137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24480998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnsten AF. Fundamentals of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: circuits and pathways. J Clin Psychiatry. 2006;67(Suppl 8):7–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16961424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maletic V, Eramo A, Gwin K, Offord SJ, Duffy RA. The role of norepinephrine and its alpha-adrenergic receptors in the pathophysiology and treatment of major depressive disorder and schizophrenia: a systematic review. Front Psychiatry. 2017;8:42. doi:10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00042.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00042.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5355451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28367128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koda K, Ago Y, Cong Y, Kita Y, Takuma K, Matsuda T. Effects of acute and chronic administration of atomoxetine and methylphenidate on extracellular levels of noradrenaline, dopamine and serotonin in the prefrontal cortex and striatum of mice. J Neurochem. 2010;114(1):259–270. doi:10.1111/j.1471-4159.2010.06750.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1471-4159.2010.06750.x.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20403082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCall JG, Siuda ER, Bhatti DL, et al. Locus coeruleus to basolateral amygdala noradrenergic projections promote anxiety-like behavior. Elife. 2017;6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5550275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28708061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cathala A, Devroye C, Drutel G, Revest JM, Artigas F, Spampinato U. Serotonin2B receptors in the rat dorsal raphe nucleus exert a GABA-mediated tonic inhibitory control on serotonin neurons. Exp Neurol. 2019;311:57–66. doi:10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.09.015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expneurol.2018.09.015.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30257183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreau JL, Bos M, Jenck F, Martin JR, Mortas P, Wichmann J. 5HT2C receptor agonists exhibit antidepressant-like properties in the anhedonia model of depression in rats. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 1996;6(3):169–175. doi:10.1016/0924-977X(96)00015-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0924-977X(96)00015-6.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8880075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenck F, Moreau JL, Berendsen HH, et al. Antiaversive effects of 5HT2C receptor agonists and fluoxetine in a model of panic-like anxiety in rats. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 1998;8(3):161–168. doi:10.1016/S0924-977X(97)00055-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0924-977X(97)00055-2.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9716307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palacios JM, Pazos A, Hoyer D. A short history of the 5-HT2C receptor: from the choroid plexus to depression, obesity and addiction treatment. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 2017;234(9–10):1395–1418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28265714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leggio GM, Cathala A, Moison D, Cunningham KA, Piazza PV, Spampinato U. Serotonin2C receptors in the medial prefrontal cortex facilitate cocaine-induced dopamine release in the rat nucleus accumbens. Neuropharmacology. 2009;56(2):507–513. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2008.10.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2008.10.005.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3130963</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18977370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berg KA, Clarke WP, Cunningham KA, Spampinato U. Fine-tuning serotonin2c receptor function in the brain: molecular and functional implications. Neuropharmacology. 2008;55(6):969–976. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2008.06.014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2008.06.014.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3124806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18602407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navailles S, Moison D, Cunningham KA, Spampinato U. Differential regulation of the mesoaccumbens dopamine circuit by serotonin2C receptors in the ventral tegmental area and the nucleus accumbens: an in vivo microdialysis study with cocaine. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2008;33(2):237–246. doi:10.1038/sj.npp.1301414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.npp.1301414.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17429406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chagraoui A, Whitestone S, Baassiri L, Manem J, Di Giovanni G, De Deurwaerdere P. Neurochemical impact of the 5-HT2C receptor agonist WAY-163909 on monoamine tissue content in the rat brain. Neurochem Int. 2019;124:245–255. doi:10.1016/j.neuint.2019.01.019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuint.2019.01.019.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30685320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitestone S, Deurwaerdere P, Baassiri L, et al. Effect of the 5-HT2C receptor agonist WAY-163909 on serotonin and dopamine metabolism across the rat brain: a quantitative and qualitative neurochemical study. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20:12. doi:10.3390/ijms20122925.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20122925.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6627111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31208016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding YS, Naganawa M, Gallezot JD, et al. Clinical doses of atomoxetine significantly occupy both norepinephrine and serotonin transports: implications on treatment of depression and ADHD. Neuroimage. 2014;86:164–171. doi:10.1016/j.neuroimage.2013.08.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2013.08.001.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23933039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hajos M, Fleishaker JC, Filipiak-Reisner JK, Brown MT, Wong EH. The selective norepinephrine reuptake inhibitor antidepressant reboxetine: pharmacological and clinical profile. CNS Drug Rev. 2004;10(1):23–44. doi:10.1111/j.1527-3458.2004.tb00002.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1527-3458.2004.tb00002.x.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6741733</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14978512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curatolo P, Paloscia C, D’Agati E, Moavero R, Pasini A. The neurobiology of attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2009;13(4):299–304. doi:10.1016/j.ejpn.2008.06.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2008.06.003.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18644740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou FC, Sari Y, Zhang JK. Expression of serotonin transporter protein in developing rat brain. Brain Res Dev Brain Res. 2000;119(1):33–45. doi:10.1016/S0165-3806(99)00152-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0165-3806(99)00152-2.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10648870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X, Petit EI, Dobrenis K, Sze JY. Spatiotemporal SERT expression in cortical map development. Neurochem Int. 2016;98:129–137. doi:10.1016/j.neuint.2016.05.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuint.2016.05.010.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27282696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Chiara G, Bassareo V, Fenu S, et al. Dopamine and drug addiction: the nucleus accumbens shell connection. Neuropharmacology. 2004;47(Suppl 1):227–241. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2004.06.032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2004.06.032.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15464140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heal DJ, Smith SL, Gosden J, Nutt DJ. Amphetamine, past and present–a pharmacological and clinical perspective. J Psychopharmacol. 2013;27(6):479–496. doi:10.1177/0269881113482532.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881113482532.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3666194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanagita T, Wakasa Y, Kiyohara H. Drug dependence potential of viloxazine hydrochloride tested in rhesus monkeys. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1980;12(1):155–161. doi:10.1016/0091-3057(80)90430-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-3057(80)90430-X.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6768070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cryan JF, Valentino RJ, Lucki I. Assessing substrates underlying the behavioral effects of antidepressants using the modified rat forced swimming test. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2005;29(4–5):547–569. doi:10.1016/j.neubiorev.2005.03.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2005.03.008.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15893822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Monitoring Centre for Drugs and Drug Addiction (EMCDDA), Drug Misuse Research Division, Health Research Board. Literature Review on the Relation Between Drug Use, Impaired Driving and Traffic Accidents (CT.97.EP.14). Lisbon: Portugal; 1999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papoian T, Jagadeesh G, Saulnier M, et al. Regulatory forum review*: utility of in vitro secondary pharmacology data to assess risk of drug-induced valvular heart disease in humans: regulatory considerations. Toxicol Pathol. 2017;45(3):381–388. doi:10.1177/0192623317690609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0192623317690609.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28421966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bharti S, Rani N, Bhatia J, Arya DS. 5-HT2B receptor blockade attenuates beta-adrenergic receptor-stimulated myocardial remodeling in rats via inhibiting apoptosis: role of MAPKs and HSPs. Apoptosis. 2015;20(4):455–465. doi:10.1007/s10495-014-1083-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10495-014-1083-z.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25544272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janssen W, Schymura Y, Novoyatleva T, et al. 5-HT2B receptor antagonists inhibit fibrosis and protect from RV heart failure. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:438403. doi:10.1155/2015/438403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/438403.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25667920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canal CE, Morgan D, Felsing D, et al. A novel aminotetralin-type serotonin (5-HT) 2C receptor-specific agonist and 5-HT2A competitive antagonist/5-HT2B inverse agonist with preclinical efficacy for psychoses. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2014;349(2):310–318. doi:10.1124/jpet.113.212373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/jpet.113.212373.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989798</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24563531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brody T. FDA’s Drug Review Process and the Package Label: Strategies for Writing Successful FDA Submissions. Academic Press; 2018:441–511.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maroteaux L, Ayme-Dietrich E, Aubertin-Kirch G, et al. New therapeutic opportunities for 5-HT2 receptor ligands. Pharmacol Ther. 2017;170:14–36. doi:10.1016/j.pharmthera.2016.10.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2016.10.008.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27771435</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herr N, Bode C, Duerschmied D. The effects of serotonin in immune cells. Front Cardiovasc Med. 2017;4:48. doi:10.3389/fcvm.2017.00048.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcvm.2017.00048.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5517399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28775986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krabbe G, Matyash V, Pannasch U, Mamer L, Boddeke HW, Kettenmann H. Activation of serotonin receptors promotes microglial injury-induced motility but attenuates phagocytic activity. Brain Behav Immun. 2012;26(3):419–428. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2011.12.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2011.12.002.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22198120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oades RD, Myint AM, Dauvermann MR, Schimmelmann BG, Schwarz MJ. Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) and glial integrity: an exploration of associations of cytokines and kynurenine metabolites with symptoms and attention. Behav Brain Funct. 2010;6(1):32. doi:10.1186/1744-9081-6-32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1744-9081-6-32.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2900218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20534153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felger JC, Lotrich FE. Inflammatory cytokines in depression: neurobiological mechanisms and therapeutic implications. Neuroscience. 2013;246:199–229. doi:10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.04.060.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.04.060.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3741070</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23644052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brus R, Nowak P, Szkilnik R, Mikolajun U, Kostrzewa RM. Serotoninergics attenuate hyperlocomotor activity in rats. Potential new therapeutic strategy for hyperactivity. Neurotox Res. 2004;6(4):317–325. doi:10.1007/BF03033442.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03033442.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15545015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kostrzewa RM, Brus R, Kalbfleisch JH, Perry KW, Fuller RW. Proposed animal model of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. Brain Res Bull. 1994;34(2):161–167. doi:10.1016/0361-9230(94)90013-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0361-9230(94)90013-2.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7913871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitney MS, Shemery AM, Yaw AM, Donovan LJ, Glass JD, Deneris ES. Adult brain serotonin deficiency causes hyperactivity, circadian disruption, and elimination of siestas. J Neurosci. 2016;36(38):9828–9842. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1469-16.2016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1469-16.2016.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5030349</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27656022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davids E, Zhang K, Kula NS, Tarazi FI, Baldessarini RJ. Effects of norepinephrine and serotonin transporter inhibitors on hyperactivity induced by neonatal 6-hydroxydopamine lesioning in rats. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2002;301(3):1097–1102. doi:10.1124/jpet.301.3.1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/jpet.301.3.1097.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12023542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoo JH, Kim JI, Kim BN, Jeong B. Exploring characteristic features of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: findings from multi-modal MRI and candidate genetic data. Brain Imaging Behav. 2019. doi:10.1007/s11682-019-00164-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11682-019-00164-x.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31321662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qureshi MNI, Oh J, Min B, Jo HJ, Multi-modal LB. Multi-measure, and multi-class discrimination of ADHD with hierarchical feature extraction and extreme learning machine using structural and functional brain MRI. Front Hum Neurosci. 2017;11:157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5378777</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sudre G, Szekely E, Sharp W, Kasparek S, Shaw P. Multimodal mapping of the brain’s functional connectivity and the adult outcome of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114(44):11787–11792. doi:10.1073/pnas.1705229114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1705229114.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5676882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29078281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao M, Shu N, Cao Q, Wang Y, He Y. Imaging functional and structural brain connectomics in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Mol Neurobiol. 2014;50(3):1111–1123. doi:10.1007/s12035-014-8685-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-014-8685-x.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24705817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conio B, Martino M, Magioncalda P, et al. Opposite effects of dopamine and serotonin on resting-state networks: review and implications for psychiatric disorders. Mol Psychiatry. 2020;25(1):82–93. doi:10.1038/s41380-019-0406-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41380-019-0406-4.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30953003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castellanos FX, Elia J, Kruesi MJ, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid monoamine metabolites in boys with attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder. Psychiatry Res. 1994;52(3):305–316. doi:10.1016/0165-1781(94)90076-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(94)90076-0.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7527565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oades RD. Dopamine may be ‘hyper’ with respect to noradrenaline metabolism, but ‘hypo’ with respect to serotonin metabolism in children with attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder. Behav Brain Res. 2002;130(1–2):97–102. doi:10.1016/S0166-4328(01)00440-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0166-4328(01)00440-5.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11864724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carhart-Harris RL, Nutt DJ. Serotonin and brain function: a tale of two receptors. J Psychopharmacol. 2017;31(9):1091–1120. doi:10.1177/0269881117725915.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881117725915.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5606297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28858536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyazaki KW, Miyazaki K, Doya K. Activation of dorsal raphe serotonin neurons is necessary for waiting for delayed rewards. J Neurosci. 2012;32(31):10451–10457. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0915-12.2012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0915-12.2012.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6621383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyazaki K, Miyazaki KW, Doya K. The role of serotonin in the regulation of patience and impulsivity. Mol Neurobiol. 2012;45(2):213–224. doi:10.1007/s12035-012-8232-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-012-8232-6.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3311865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22262065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cryan JF, Lucki I. Antidepressant-like behavioral effects mediated by 5-Hydroxytryptamine(2C) receptors. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2000;295(3):1120–1126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11082448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del’Guidice T, Lemay F, Lemasson M, et al. Stimulation of 5-HT2C receptors improves cognitive deficits induced by human tryptophan hydroxylase 2 loss of function mutation. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2014;39(5):1125–1134. doi:10.1038/npp.2013.313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2013.313.</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3957106</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24196946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
