<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">32949021</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>529</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Distinct proportions of cholinergic neurons in the rat prepositus hypoglossi nucleus according to their cerebellar projection targets.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1541</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1552</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1541-1552</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25035</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Cerebellar functions are modulated by cholinergic inputs, the density of which varies among cerebellar regions. Although the prepositus hypoglossi nucleus (PHN), a brainstem structure involved in controlling gaze holding, is known as one of the major sources of these cholinergic inputs, the proportions of cholinergic neurons in PHN projections to distinct cerebellar regions have not been quantitatively analyzed. In this study, we identified PHN neurons projecting to the cerebellum by applying retrograde labeling with dextran-conjugated Alexa 488 in choline acetyltransferase (ChAT)-tdTomato transgenic rats and compared the proportion of cholinergic PHN neurons in the PHN projections to four different regions of the cerebellum, namely the flocculus (FL), the uvula and nodulus (UN), lobules III-V in the vermis (VM), and the hemispheric paramedian lobule and crus 2 (PC). In the PHN, the percentage of cholinergic PHN neurons was lower in the projection to the FL than in the projection to the UN, VM or PC. Preposito-cerebellar neurons, except for preposito-FL neurons, included different proportions of cholinergic neurons at different rostrocaudal positions in the PHN. These results suggest that cholinergic PHN neurons project to not only the vestibulocerebellum but also the anterior vermis and posterior hemisphere and that the proportion of cholinergic neurons among projection neurons from the PHN differs depending on cerebellar target areas and the rostro-caudal regions of the PHN. This study provides insights regarding the involvement of cerebellar cholinergic networks in gaze holding.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sugimura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Taketoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology, Nara Medical University, Kashihara, Nara, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Saito</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yasuhiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0148-6597</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology, Nara Medical University, Kashihara, Nara, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001933" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Stem</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002531" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebellum</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059329" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008855" MajorTopicYN="N">Microscopy, Electron, Scanning</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009434" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Pathways</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055647" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Transgenic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">choline acetyltransferase</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">flocculus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gaze holding</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">neural integrator</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">uvula/nodulus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32949021</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25035</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ando, T., Ueda, M., Luo, Y., &amp; Sugihara, I. (2020). Heterogeneous vestibulocerebellar mossy fiber projections revealed by single axon reconstruction in the mouse. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 528(10), 1775-1802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andre, P., Fascetti, F., Pompeiano, O., &amp; White, S. R. (1994). The muscarinic agonist, bethanechol, enhances GABA-induced inhibition of Purkinje cells in the cerebellar cortex. Brain Research, 637(1-2), 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barmack, N. H. (2000). Cholinergic pathways and fucntions related to the vestibulo-cerebellum. In A. J. Beitz &amp; J. H. Anderson (Eds.), Neurochemistry of the vestibular system (pp. 269-285). Boca Raton: CRC Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barmack, N. H., Baughman, R. W., &amp; Eckenstein, F. P. (1992a). Cholinergic innervation of the cerebellum of rat, rabbit, cat, and monkey as revealed by choline acetyltransferase activity and immunohistochemistry. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 317(3), 233-249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barmack, N. H., Baughman, R. W., &amp; Eckenstein, F. P. (1992c). Cholinergic innervation of the cerebellum of the rat by secondary vestibular afferents. Annals of the new York Academy of Sciences, 656, 566-579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barmack, N. H., Baughman, R. W., Eckenstein, F. P., &amp; Shojaku, H. (1992). Secondary vestibular cholinergic projection to the cerebellum of rabbit and rat as revealed by choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry, retrograde and orthograde tracers. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 317(3), 250-270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belknap, D. B., &amp; McCrea, R. A. (1988). Anatomical connections of the prepositus and abducens nuclei in the squirrel monkey. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 268(1), 13-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, C., Arroyo, S., Berns, D., &amp; Hestrin, S. (2012). Mechanisms generating dual-component nicotinic EPSCs in cortical interneurons. The Journal of Neuroscience, 32(48), 17287-17296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanks, R. H., Precht, W., &amp; Torigoe, Y. (1983). Afferent projections to the cerebellar flocculus in the pigmented rat demonstrated by retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase. Experimental Brain Research, 52(2), 293-306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodal, A., &amp; Brodal, P. (1985). Observations on the secondary vestibulocerebellar projections in the macaque monkey. Experimental Brain Research, 58(1), 62-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collewijn, H., Tan, H. S., &amp; Van der Steen, J. (1992). Enhancement of optokinetic and vestibuloocular responses in the rabbit by cholinergic stimulation of the flocculus. Annals of the new York Academy of Sciences, 656, 612-629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delgado-García, J. M., Yajeya, J., &amp; Navarro-López Jde, D. (2006). A cholinergic mechanism underlies persistent neural activity necessary for eye fixation. Progress in Brain Research, 154, 211-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dityatev, A., Schachner, M., &amp; Sonderegger, P. (2010). The dual role of the extracellular matrix in synaptic plasticity and homeostasis. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 11(11), 735-746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epema, A. H., Gerrits, N. M., &amp; Voogd, J. (1990). Secondary vestibulocerebellar projections to the flocculus and uvulo-nodular lobule of the rabbit: A study using HRP and double fluorescent tracer techniques. Experimental Brain Research, 80(1), 72-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukushima, K., &amp; Kaneko, C. R. (1995). Vestibular integrators in the oculomotor system. Neuroscience Research, 22(3), 249-258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukushima, K., Kaneko, C. R., &amp; Fuchs, A. F. (1992). The neuronal substrate of integration in the oculomotor system. Progress in Neurobiology, 39(6), 609-639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaál, B., Kecskes, S., Matesz, C., Birinyi, A., Hunyadi, A., &amp; Rácz, É. (2015). Molecular composition and expression pattern of the extracellular matrix in a mossy fiber-generating precerebellar nucleus of rat, the prepositus hypoglossi. Neuroscience Letters, 594, 122-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garthwaite, J., &amp; Brodbelt, A. R. (1990). Glutamate as the principal mossy fibre transmitter in rat cerebellum: Pharmacological evidence. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 2(2), 177-180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godaux, E., &amp; Vanderkelen, B. (1984). Vestibulo-ocular reflex, optokinetic response and their interactions in the cerebellectomized cat. The Journal of Physiology, 346, 155-170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higo, S., Ito, K., Fuchs, D., &amp; McCarley, R. W. (1990). Anatomical interconnections of the pedunculopontine tegmental nucleus and the nucleus prepositus hypoglossi in the cat. Brain Research, 536(1-2), 79-85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwasaki, H., Kani, K., &amp; Maeda, T. (1999). Neural connections of the pontine reticular formation, which connects reciprocally with the nucleus prepositus hypoglossi in the rat. Neuroscience, 93(1), 195-208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaarsma, D., Ruigrok, T. J., Caffé, R., Cozzari, C., Levey, A. I., Mugnaini, E., &amp; Voogd, J. (1997). Cholinergic innervation and receptors in the cerebellum. Progress in Brain Research, 114, 67-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kheradmand, A., &amp; Zee, D. S. (2011). Cerebellum and ocular motor control. Frontiers in Neurology, 2, 53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotchabhakdi, N., &amp; Walberg, F. (1978). Cerebellar afferent projections from the vestibular nuclei in the cat: An experimental study with the method of retrograde axonal transport of horseradish peroxidase. Experimental Brain Research, 31(4), 591-604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langer, T., Fuchs, A. F., Scudder, C. A., &amp; Chubb, M. C. (1985). Afferents to the flocculus of the cerebellum in the rhesus macaque as revealed by retrograde transport of horseradish peroxidase. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 235(1), 1-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leigh, R. J., &amp; Zee, D. S. (2015). The neurology of eye movements. New York: Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lendvai, B., &amp; Vizi, E. S. (2008). Nonsynaptic chemical transmission through nicotinic acetylcholine receptors. Physiological Reviews, 88(2), 333-349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathoera, A. L., Frens, M. A., &amp; van der Steen, J. (2000). Effects of cholinergic neuromodulation in cerebellar flocculus on transparent motion processing in the rabbit. Experimental Brain Research, 134(2), 255-260.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCrea, R. A., &amp; Horn, A. K. (2006). Nucleus prepositus. Progress in Brain Research, 151, 205-230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moschovakis, A. K. (1997). The neural integrators of the mammalian saccadic system. Frontiers in Bioscience, 2, d552-d577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarro-Lopez Jde, D., Alvarado, J. C., Marquez-Ruiz, J., Escudero, M., Delgado-Garcia, J. M., &amp; Yajeya, J. (2004). A cholinergic synaptically triggered event participates in the generation of persistent activity necessary for eye fixation. The Journal of Neuroscience, 24, 5109-5118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarro-Lopez Jde, D., Delgado-Garcia, J. M., &amp; Yajeya, J. (2005). Cooperative glutamatergic and cholinergic mechanisms generate short-term modifications of synaptic effectiveness in prepositus hypoglossi neurons. The Journal of Neuroscience, 25, 9902-9906.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuki, H., Tokunaga, A., Ono, K., Hasebe, S., &amp; Tadokoro, Y. (1992). Distribution of efferent neurons projecting to the tectum and cerebellum in the rat prepositus hypoglossi nucleus. Investigative Ophthalmology &amp; Visual Science, 33(8), 2567-2574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ojima, H., Kawajiri, S., &amp; Yamasaki, T. (1989). Cholinergic innervation of the rat cerebellum: Qualitative and quantitative analyses of elements immunoreactive to a monoclonal antibody against choline acetyltransferase. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 290(1), 41-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paxinos, G., &amp; Watson, C. (2007). The rat brain in stereotaxic coordinates (6th ed.). Burlington: Academic Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Payne, J. N. (1983). Axonal branching in the projections from precerebellar nuclei to the lobulus simplex of the rat's cerebellum investigated by retrograde fluorescent double labeling. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 213(2), 233-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, D. A. (1974). The effect of cerebellectomy on the cat's vestibulo-ocular integrator. Brain Research, 71(2-3), 195-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, D. A. (1975). Oculomotor control signals. In G. Lennerstrand &amp; P. Bach-y-Rita (Eds.), Basic mechanisms of ocular motility and their clinical implications (pp. 337-374). Oxford: Pergamon Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, D. A. (1989). Integrating with neurons. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 12, 33-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Røste, G. K. (1989). Observations on the projection from the perihypoglossal nuclei to the cerebellar cortex and nuclei in the cat. A retrograde WGA-HRP and fluorescent tracer study. Anatomy and Embryology, 180(6), 521-533.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarter, M., Parikh, V., &amp; Howe, W. M. (2009). Phasic acetylcholine release and the volume transmission hypothesis: Time to move on. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 10(5), 383-390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato, Y., Kawasaki, T., &amp; Ikarashi, K. (1983). Afferent projections from the brainstem to the three floccular zones in cats. II. Mossy fiber projections. Brain Research, 272(1), 37-48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindelin, J., Arganda-Carreras, I., Frise, E., Kaynig, V., Longair, M., Pietzsch, T., … Cardona, A. (2012). Fiji: An open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nature Methods, 9(7), 676-682.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shino, M., Kaneko, R., Yanagawa, Y., Kawaguchi, Y., &amp; Saito, Y. (2011). Electrophysiological characteristics of inhibitory neurons of the prepositus hypoglossi nucleus as analyzed in Venus-expressing transgenic rats. Neuroscience, 197, 89-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, H. S., &amp; Collewijn, H. (1991). Cholinergic modulation of optokinetic and vestibulo-ocular responses: A study with microinjections in the flocculus of the rabbit. Experimental Brain Research, 85(3), 475-481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, H. S., Collewijn, H., &amp; Van der Steen, J. (1992). Optokinetic nystagmus in the rabbit and its modulation by bilateral microinjection of carbachol in the cerebellar flocculus. Experimental Brain Research, 90(3), 456-468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, H. S., Collewijn, H., &amp; Van der Steen, J. (1993). Unilateral cholinergic stimulation of the rabbit's cerebellar flocculus: Asymmetric effects on optokinetic responses. Experimental Brain Research, 92(3), 375-384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uematsu, M., Hirai, Y., Karube, F., Ebihara, S., Kato, M., Abe, K., … Kawaguchi, Y. (2008). Quantitative chemical composition of cortical GABAergic neurons revealed in transgenic venus-expressing rats. Cerebral Cortex, 18(2), 315-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Steen, J., &amp; Tan, H. S. (1997). Cholinergic control in the floccular cerebellum of the rabbit. Progress in Brain Research, 114, 335-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westheimer, G., &amp; Blair, S. M. (1974). Function organization of primate oculomotor system revealed by cerebellectomy. Experimental Brain Research, 21(5), 463-472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zee, D. S., Yamazaki, A., Butler, P. H., &amp; Gücer, G. (1981). Effects of ablation of flocculus and paraflocculus of eye movements in primate. Journal of Neurophysiology, 46(4), 878-899.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, C., Zhou, P., &amp; Yuan, T. (2016). The cholinergic system in the cerebellum: From structure to function. Reviews in the Neurosciences, 27(8), 769-776.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Y., Kaneko, R., Yanagawa, Y., &amp; Saito, Y. (2014). The vestibulo- and preposito-cerebellar cholinergic neurons of a ChAT-tdTomato transgenic rat exhibit heterogeneous firing properties and the expression of various neurotransmitter receptors. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 39(8), 1294-1313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmermann, D. R., &amp; Dours-Zimmermann, M. T. (2008). Extracellular matrix of the central nervous system: From neglect to challenge. Histochemistry and Cell Biology, 130(4), 635-653.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
