<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">33009156</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-0911</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>21</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Advances in neonatal care : official journal of the National Association of Neonatal Nurses</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Adv Neonatal Care</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Preterm Infant Incubator Humidity Levels: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>297</StartPage>
          <EndPage>307</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>297-307</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ANC.0000000000000791</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Numerous scholars have reported that inconsistent levels of incubator humidity in the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU) require attention. Evidence synthesis was needed to identify optimal incubator humidity levels and duration to decrease transepidermal water loss (TEWL) and the potential for infection.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this systematic review was to appraise and synthesize the evidence of preterm outcomes related to incubator humidity. The primary aim of this study was to determine how patient outcomes were impacted by incubator humidity levels and duration in premature infants born before 320/7 weeks cared for in the NICU.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS/SEARCH STRATEGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">The foundation of this systematic review was the Joanna Briggs Institute method for systematic reviews. Mefford's theory of health promotion for the preterm infant was used to address the wholeness of the preterm infant's body system. Evidence was classified using the Johns Hopkins evidence-based practice levels and quality of evidence.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twelve studies met inclusion criteria. The evidence demonstrated that the practice of incubator humidity is warranted; however, it does not come without risks. Microbial growth was increased in high levels of incubator humidity. Unnecessary TEWL was prevented by lowering high levels of incubator humidity after the first week of life, improving skin barrier formation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Incubator humidity of 60% to 70% in the first week of life was effective in preventing TEWL in infants born 26 weeks or more.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR RESEARCH" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Future incubator humidity research is needed for infants born before 26 weeks.Video Abstract available athttps://journals.lww.com/advancesinneonatalcare/Pages/videogallery.aspx?autoPlay=false&amp;videoId=39.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 by The National Association of Neonatal Nurses.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Glass</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laurie</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neonatal Intensive Care Unit, UPMC Magee Hamot Womens Hospital, Erie, Pennsylvania (Dr Glass); and School of Nursing, College of Health Services, Walden University, Minneapolis, Minnesota (Dr Valdez).</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Valdez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anna</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D059040">Video-Audio Media</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Adv Neonatal Care</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101125644</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1536-0903</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006813" MajorTopicYN="N">Humidity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Incubators, Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007234" MajorTopicYN="Y">Infant, Premature</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007363" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units, Neonatal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Reviews as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>27</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009156</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ANC.0000000000000791</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00149525-202108000-00010</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blackfan KD, Yaglou CP. The premature infant. Am J Dis Child. 1933;46:1175–1236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman WA, Blanc WA. The effect of humidity on survival of newly born premature infants. Pediatrics. 1957;20:477–487.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonucci R, Porcella A, Fanos V. The incubator in the neonatal intensive care unit: unresolved issues and future developments. J Perinat Med. 2009;37(6):587–598.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agren J, Sjors G, Sedin G. Ambient humidity influences the rate of skin barrier maturation in extremely preterm infants. J Pediatr. 2006;148(5):613–617.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harpin VA, Rutter N. Humidification of incubators. Arch Dis Child. 1985;60:219–224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lynam L, Biagotti L. Testing for colonization in an Ohmeda Medical Giraffe humidification system. Neonatal Intensive Care. 2002;15(2):50–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knobel RB. Thermal stability of the premature infant in neonatal intensive care. Newborn Infant Nurs Rev. 2014;14(2):72–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ludington-Hoe SM, Lewis T, Cong X, Anderson L. Breast-infant temperature with twins during shared kangaroo care. J Obstet Gynecol Neonatal Nurs. 2006;35(2):223–231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ludington-Hoe SM, Hashemi MS, Argote LA, Medelllin G, Rey H. Selected physiologic measures and behavior during paternal skin contact with Colombian preterm infants. J Dev Physiol. 1992;18(5):223–232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abouelfettoh A, Ludington-Hoe SM, Burant CJ, Visscher MO. Effects of skin-to-skin contact on preterm infant skin barrier function and hospital-acquired infection. J Clin Med Res. 2011;3(1):36–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deguines C, Decima P, Pelletier A, Degrugilliers L, Ghyselen L, Tourneux P. Variations in incubator temperature and humidity management: a survey of current practice. Acta Paediatr. 2012;101:230–235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinclair L, Crisp J, Sinn J. Variability in incubator humidity practices in the management of preterm infants. J Paediatr Child Health. 2009;45(9):535–540.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joanna Briggs Institute. The Joanna Briggs Institute Approach [Internet]. Adelaide, Australia: The University of Adelaide; 2019. http://joannabriggs.org.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mefford LC. A theory of health promotion for preterm infants based on Levine's conservation model of nursing. Nurs Sci Q. 2004;17(3):260–266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dang D, Dearholt S. Johns Hopkins Nursing Evidence-Based Practice: Model and Guidelines. 3rd ed. Indianapolis, IN: Sigma Theta Tau International; 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allwood M. Skin care guidelines for infants aged 23- 30 weeks' gestation: a review of the literature. Neonatal Paediatr Child Health Nurs. 2011;14(1):20–27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Carvalho M, Torrao CT, Moreira ME. Mist and water condensation inside incubators reduce the efficacy of phototherapy. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2011;96:138–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Goffau MC, Bergman KA, De Vries HJ, et al. Cold spots in neonatal incubators are hot spots for microbial contamination. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2011;77(24):8568–8572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Etienne KA, Subudhi CP, Chadwick PR, et al. Investigation of a cluster of cutaneous aspergillosis in a neonatal intensive care unit. J Hosp Infect. 2011; 79:344–348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlsson V, Heinemann AB, Sjors G, Nykvist KH, Agren J. Early skin-to-skin care in extremely preterm infants: thermal balance and care environment. J Pediatr. 2012;161(3):422–426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SM, Lee EY, Chen J, Ringer SA. Improved care and growth outcomes by using hybrid humidified incubators in very preterm infants. Pediatrics. 2010;125(1):e137–e145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kong YS, Cheong JL, Kotsanas D, Jolley D. The effect of incubator humidity on the body temperature of infants born at 28 weeks' gestation or less: a randomized controlled trial. Neonatal Paediatr Child Health Nurs. 2011;14(2):14–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maastrup R, Greisen G. Extremely preterm infants tolerate skin-to-skin contact during the first weeks of life. Acta Paediatr. 2010;99:1145–1149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prazad P, Cortez DR, Puppala BL, Donovan R, Kumar S, Gulati A. Airborne concentrations of volatile organic compounds in neonatal incubators. J Perinatol. 2008;28:534–540.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sung SI, Ahn SY, Seo HJ, et al. Insensible water loss during the first week of life of extremely low birth weight infants less than 25 gestational weeks under high humidification. Neonatal Med. 2013;20(1):51–57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Visscher M, Narendran V. The ontogeny of skin. Adv Would Care. 2014;3(4):291–303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fanaroff AA, Fanaroff JM. Klaus and Fanaroff's Care of the High-Risk Neonate. St Louis, MO: Elsevier Health Sciences; 2012:640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
