<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33021560</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-2031</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>55</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical gastroenterology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Is a Fundamental Design Change for Gastrointestinal Endoscopes Required?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>21</StartPage>
          <EndPage>24</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>21-24</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCG.0000000000001430</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Since the first fiberoptic instruments, gastrointestinal endoscopy has shaped the field of gastroenterology and is now a key diagnostic and therapeutic tool. Compared with the initial fiberoptic endoscopes state-of-the-art optical chips (or charge-coupled device technology) allowed a quantum leap in image quality. Despite these advances, gastrointestinal endoscopy is far from being perfect. The diagnostic yield (eg, for adenoma detection rates) is highly operator dependent and there is still the need for sedation or even anesthesia to address discomfort during the procedure. Despite highly standardized cleaning and high-level disinfection the reuse of contemporary (and difficult to clean) endoscopes with multiple channels exposes patients to the risk of transmission of infections. Artificial intelligence and pattern recognition should eliminate interindividual variability including polyp detection rates, self-propelled, and (potentially remotely controlled) scopes with a soft shaft could reduce the discomfort during procedures and abolish the need for sedation and anesthesia altogether and single-use designs should eliminate the risk of patient-to-patient transmission of infections. While these innovations are feasible and could be implemented rapidly utilizing available technology, they require a paradigm shift affecting all levels of the value chain from the supplier of the instruments to the end-users. Some may negate the need for a paradigm shift, but it is evident that a major redesign of the endoscopic equipment is overdue to fully utilize novel technologies and most importantly ensure the best possible outcomes for patients.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Holtmann</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gerald J</ForeName>
            <Initials>GJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Faculty of Health and Behavioural Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huelsen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexander</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Faculty of Health and Behavioural Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shah</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ayesha</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Faculty of Health and Behavioural Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hourigan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luke F</ForeName>
            <Initials>LF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Princess Alexandra Hospital, Brisbane.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Faculty of Health and Behavioural Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morrison</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mark</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Queensland Diamantina Institute, University of Queensland, Woolloongabba, QLD, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Gastroenterol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7910017</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0192-0790</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004203" MajorTopicYN="N">Disinfection</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019723" MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020776" MajorTopicYN="Y">Endoscopes, Gastrointestinal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016099" MajorTopicYN="N">Endoscopy, Gastrointestinal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>22</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33021560</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCG.0000000000001430</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00004836-202101000-00005</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirschowitz BI, Peters CW, Curtiss LE. Preliminary report on a long fiberscope for examination of stomach and duodenum. Med Bull (Ann Arbor). 1957;23:178–180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ho SH, Uedo N, Aso A, et al. Development of image-enhanced endoscopy of the gastrointestinal tract: a review of history and current evidences. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2018;52:295–306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner H, Stock C, Hoffmeister M. Effect of screening sigmoidoscopy and screening colonoscopy on colorectal cancer incidence and mortality: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials and observational studies. BMJ. 2014;348:g2467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishizawa T, Yahagi N. Long-term outcomes of using endoscopic submucosal dissection to treat early gastric cancer. Gut Liver. 2018;12:119–124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ning B, Abdelfatah MM, Othman MO. Endoscopic submucosal dissection and endoscopic mucosal resection for early stage esophageal cancer. Ann Cardiothorac Surg. 2017;6:88–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue H, Minami H, Kobayashi Y, et al. Peroral endoscopic myotomy (POEM) for esophageal achalasia. Endoscopy. 2010;42:265–271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen WC, Wallace MB. Endoscopic management of mucosal lesions in the gastrointestinal tract. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;10:481–495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumbhari V, Hill C, Sullivan S. Bariatric endoscopy: state-of-the-art. Curr Opin Gastroenterol. 2017;33:358–365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muguruma N, Tanaka K, Teramae S, et al. Colon capsule endoscopy: toward the future. Clin J Gastroenterol. 2017;10:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rees CJ, Koo S. Artificial intelligence—upping the game in gastrointestinal endoscopy? Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;16:584–585.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>East JE, Vleugels JL, Roelandt P, et al. Advanced endoscopic imaging: European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) Technology Review. Endoscopy. 2016;48:1029–1045.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Penz D, Ferlitsch A, Waldmann E, et al. Impact of adenoma detection rate on detection of advanced adenomas and endoscopic adverse events in a study of over 200,000 screening colonoscopies. Gastrointest Endosc. 2020;91:135–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kume K, Sakai N, Goto T. Development of a novel endoscopic manipulation system: the Endoscopic Operation Robot ver.3. Endoscopy. 2015;47:815–819.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeung BP, Chiu PW. Application of robotics in gastrointestinal endoscopy: a review. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22:1811–1825.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aljebreen AM, Almadi MA, Leung FW. Sedated vs unsedated colonoscopy: a prospective study. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:5113–5118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vargo JJ II. Sedation-related complications in gastrointestinal endoscopy. Gastrointest Endosc Clin N Am. 2015;25:147–158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Repici A, Maselli R, Colombo M, et al. Coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak: what the department of endoscopy should know. Gastrointest Endosc. 2020;92:192–197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arrowsmith JB, Gerstman BB, Fleischer DE, et al. Results from the American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy/US Food and Drug Administration collaborative study on complication rates and drug use during gastrointestinal endoscopy. Gastrointest Endosc. 1991;37:421–427.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy I, Gralnek IM. Complications of diagnostic colonoscopy, upper endoscopy, and enteroscopy. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2016;30:705–718.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neumann H, Meier PN. Complications in gastrointestinal endoscopy. Dig Endosc. 2016;28:534–536.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muscarella LF. Risk of transmission of carbapenem-resistant Enterobacteriaceae and related “superbugs” during gastrointestinal endoscopy. World J Gastrointest Endosc. 2014;6:457–474.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen BT, Cohen J, Hambrick RD III, et al. Multisociety guideline on reprocessing flexible GI endoscopes: 2016 update. Gastrointest Endosc. 2017;85:282.e1–294.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCafferty CE, Aghajani MJ, Abi-Hanna D, et al. An update on gastrointestinal endoscopy-associated infections and their contributing factors. Ann Clin Microbiol Antimicrob. 2018;17:36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alfa MJ, Singh H. Impact of wet storage and other factors on biofilm formation and contamination of patient-ready endoscopes: a narrative review. Gastrointest Endosc. 2020;91:236–247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valeriani F, Agodi A, Casini B, et al. Potential testing of reprocessing procedures by real-time polymerase chain reaction: a multicenter study of colonoscopy devices. Am J Infect Control. 2018;46:159–164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axon AT, Banks J, Cockel R, et al. Disinfection in upper-digestive-tract endoscopy in Britain. Lancet. 1981;1:1093–1094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ofstead CL, Heymann OL, Quick MR, et al. Residual moisture and waterborne pathogens inside flexible endoscopes: evidence from a multisite study of endoscope drying effectiveness. Am J Infect Control. 2018;46:689–696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cattoir L, Vanzieleghem T, Florin L, et al. Surveillance of endoscopes: comparison of different sampling techniques. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2017;38:1062–1069.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neves MS, da Silva MG, Ventura GM, et al. Effectiveness of current disinfection procedures against biofilm on contaminated GI endoscopes. Gastrointest Endosc. 2016;83:944–953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Ceglie A, Hassan C, Mangiavillano B, et al. Endoscopic mucosal resection and endoscopic submucosal dissection for colorectal lesions: a systematic review. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2016;104:138–155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
