<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33024295</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1759-4804</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>16</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Nature reviews. Rheumatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Nat Rev Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Fibromyalgia: an update on clinical characteristics, aetiopathogenesis and treatment.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>645</StartPage>
          <EndPage>660</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>645-660</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41584-020-00506-w</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Fibromyalgia is characterized by chronic widespread pain, fatigue, sleep disturbances and functional symptoms. The etiopathogenesis, diagnostic criteria and classification criteria of fibromyalgia are still debated and, consequently, so are the strategies for treating this condition. Fibromyalgia is the third most frequent musculoskeletal condition, and its prevalence increases with age. However, although diagnosis has improved with the evolution of more accurate diagnostic criteria, a considerable proportion of physicians still fail to recognize the syndrome. Many factors contribute to the development of fibromyalgia in a unique manner: genetic predisposition, personal experiences, emotional-cognitive factors, the mind-body relationship and a biopsychological ability to cope with stress. The multiple components of the pathogenesis and maintenance of the condition necessitate a multi-modal treatment approach. Individually tailored treatment is an important consideration, with the increasing recognition that different fibromyalgia subgroups exist with different clinical characteristics. Consequently, although an evidence-based approach to fibromyalgia management is always desirable, the approach of physicians is inevitably empirical, and must have the aim of creating a strong alliance with the patient and formulating shared, realistic treatment goals.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sarzi-Puttini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Piercarlo</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8673-5133</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, ASST Fatebenefratelli-Sacco, Luigi Sacco University Hospital, Milan, Italy. piercarlo.sarziputtini@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Giorgi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Valeria</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0369-1700</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, ASST Fatebenefratelli-Sacco, Luigi Sacco University Hospital, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marotto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniela</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3255-3307</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, ATS Sardegna, Paolo Dettori Hospital, Tempio Pausania, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Atzeni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fabiola</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, Department of Internal and Experimental Medicine, University of Messina, Messina, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Nat Rev Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101500080</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1759-4790</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005356" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fibromyalgia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>48</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024295</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41584-020-00506-w</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41584-020-00506-w</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Queiroz, L. P. Worldwide epidemiology of fibromyalgia. Curr. Pain. Headache Rep. 17, 356 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23801009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones, G. T. et al. The prevalence of fibromyalgia in the general population: a comparison of the American College of Rheumatology 1990, 2010, and modified 2010 classification criteria. Arthritis Rheumatol. 67, 568–575 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25323744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrot, S. Fibromyalgia: a misconnection in a multiconnected world? Eur. J. Pain. 23, 866–873 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30663833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macfarlane, G. J. et al. EULAR revised recommendations for the management of fibromyalgia. Ann. Rheum. Dis. 76, 318–328 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Branco, J. C. et al. Prevalence of fibromyalgia: a survey in five European countries. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 39, 448–453 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19250656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaaya, M. et al. High burden of rheumatic diseases in Lebanon: a COPCORD study. Int. J. Rheum. Dis. 15, 136–143 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22462416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura, I. et al. An epidemiologic internet survey of fibromyalgia and chronic pain in Japan. Arthritis Care Res. 66, 1093–1101 (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turhanoglu, A. D. et al. The epidemiological aspects of fibromyalgia syndrome in adults living in Turkey: a population based study. J. Musculoskelet. Pain 16, 141–147 (2008).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guermazi, M. et al. [Fibromyalgia prevalence in Tunisia]. Tunis. Med. 86, 806–811 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19472780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigues Senna, E. et al. Prevalence of rheumatic diseases in Brazil: a study using the COPCORD approach. J. Rheumatol. 31, 594–597 (2004).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White, K. P., Speechley, M., Harth, M. &amp; Ostbye, T. The London fibromyalgia epidemiology study: the prevalence of fibromyalgia syndrome in London, Ontario. J. Rheumatol. 26, 1570–1576 (1999).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent, A. et al. Prevalence of fibromyalgia: a population-based study in Olmsted County, Minnesota, utilizing the Rochester epidemiology project. Arthritis Care Res. 65, 786–792 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scudds, R. A., Li, E. K. M. &amp; Scudds, R. J. The prevalence of fibromyalgia syndrome in Chinese people in Hong Kong. J. Musculoskelet. Pain 14, 3–11 (2006).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ablin, J. N. et al. Prevalence of fibromyalgia in the Israeli population: a population-based study to estimate the prevalence of fibromyalgia in the Israeli population using the London Fibromyalgia Epidemiology Study Screening Questionnaire (LFESSQ). Clin Exp Rheumatol 30, 39–43 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23191939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prescott, E. et al. Fibromyalgia in the adult danish population. I. A prevalence study. Scand. J. Rheumatol. 22, 233–237 (1993).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8235493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F. et al. Prevalence of musculoskeletal conditions in an Italian population sample: Results of a regional community-based study. I. The MAPPING study. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 23, 819–828 (2005).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16396700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spaeth, M. Epidemiology, costs, and the economic burden of fibromyalgia. Arthritis Res. Ther. 11, 2–3 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W., Sarzi-Puttini, P. &amp; Fitzcharles, M. A. Fibromyalgia syndrome: under-, over- and misdiagnosis. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 37, 90–97 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lachaine, J., Beauchemin, C. &amp; Landry, P.-A. Clinical and economic characteristics of patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Clin. J. Pain 26, 284–290 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20393262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger, A., Dukes, E., Martin, S., Edelsberg, J. &amp; Oster, G. Characteristics and healthcare costs of patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Int. J. Clin. Pract. 61, 1498–1508 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17655684</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2040193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knight, T. et al. Health-resource use and costs associated with fibromyalgia in France, Germany, and the United States. Clinicoecon. Outcomes Res. 5, 171–180 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23637545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3637123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacasse, A., Bourgault, P. &amp; Choinière, M. Fibromyalgia-related costs and loss of productivity: a substantial societal burden. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 17, 168 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27084363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4833946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guymer, E. K., Littlejohn, G. O., Brand, C. K. &amp; Kwiatek, R. A. Fibromyalgia onset has a high impact on work ability in Australians. Intern. Med. J. 46, 1069–1074 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27242134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gracely, R. H., Grant, M. A. &amp; Giesecke, T. Evoked pain measures in fibromyalgia. Best Pract. Res. Clin. Rheumatol. 17, 593–609 (2003).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12849714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koroschetz, J. et al. Fibromyalgia and neuropathic pain — differences and similarities. A comparison of 3057 patients with diabetic painful neuropathy and fibromyalgia. BMC Neurol. 11, 55 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21612589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3125308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rehm, S. E. et al. A cross-sectional survey of 3035 patients with fibromyalgia: subgroups of patients with typical comorbidities and sensory symptom profiles. Rheumatology 49, 1146–1152 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20236955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossi, A. et al. Fibromyalgia and nutrition: what news? Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 33, S117–S125 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25786053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bossema, E. R., Van Middendorp, H., Jacobs, J. W. G., Bijlsma, J. W. J. &amp; Geenen, R. Influence of weather on daily symptoms of pain and fatigue in female patients with fibromyalgia: a multilevel regression analysis. Arthritis Care Res. 65, 1019–1025 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staud, R., Robinson, M. E., Weyl, E. E. &amp; Price, D. D. Pain variability in fibromyalgia is related to activity and rest: role of peripheral tissue impulse input. J. Pain 11, 1376–1383 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20451465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2932794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casale, R. et al. Fibromyalgia and the concept of resilience. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 37, 105–113 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandıkçı, S. C. &amp; Özbalkan, Z. Fatigue in rheumatic diseases. Eur. J. Rheumatol. 2, 109–113 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27708942</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5047251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleinman, L. et al. Assessment of sleep in patients with fibromyalgia: qualitative development of the fibromyalgia sleep diary. Health Qual. Life Outcomes 12, 111 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25017455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4110695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, R. M., Jones, J., Turk, D. C., Russell, I. J. &amp; Matallana, L. An internet survey of 2,596 people with fibromyalgia. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 8, 27 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17349056</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1829161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glass, J. M. Review of cognitive dysfunction in fibromyalgia: a convergence on working memory and attentional control impairments. Rheum. Dis. Clin. North Am. 35, 299–311 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walitt, B. et al. The longitudinal outcome of fibromyalgia: a study of 1555 patients. J. Rheumatol. 38, 2238–2246 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21765102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ifergane, G., Buskila, D., Simiseshvely, N., Zeev, K. &amp; Cohen, H. Prevalence of fibromyalgia syndrome in migraine patients. Cephalalgia 26, 451–456 (2006).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16556247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathieu, N. [Somatic comorbidities in irritable bowel syndrome: fibromyalgia, chronic fatigue syndrome, and interstitial cystitis]. Gastroenterol. Clin. Biol. 33, S17–S25 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19303534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nickel, J. C. et al. Interstitial cystitis/painful bladder syndrome and associated medical conditions with an emphasis on irritable bowel syndrome, fibromyalgia and chronic fatigue syndrome. J. Urol. 184, 1358–1363 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20719340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalichman, L. Association between fibromyalgia and sexual dysfunction in women. Clin. Rheumatol. 28, 365–369 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19165555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, L. M. et al. AAPT diagnostic criteria for fibromyalgia. J. Pain 20, 611–628 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30453109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solano, C. et al. Autonomic dysfunction in fibromyalgia assessed by the composite autonomic symptoms scale (COMPASS). J. Clin. Rheumatol. 15, 172–176 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19342959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent, A. et al. A report of the autonomic symptom profile in patients with fibromyalgia. J. Clin. Rheumatol. 20, 106–108 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24561417</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3933822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe, F. et al. The American College of Rheumatology 1990 Criteria for the Classification of Fibromyalgia. Report of the Multicenter Criteria Committee. Arthritis Rheum. 33, 160–172 (1990).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2306288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yunus, M. B. &amp; Aldag, J. C. Restless legs syndrome and leg cramps in fibromyalgia syndrome: a controlled study. BMJ 312, 1339 (1996).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8646049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2351040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viola-Saltzman, M., Watson, N. F., Bogart, A., Goldberg, J. &amp; Buchwald, D. High prevalence of restless legs syndrome among patients with fibromyalgia: a controlled cross-sectional study. J. Clin. Sleep Med. 6, 423–427 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20957840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2952743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stehlik, R., Arvidsson, L. &amp; Ulfberg, J. Restless legs syndrome is common among female patients with fibromyalgia. Eur. Neurol. 61, 107–111 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19065057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones, K. D., Horak, F. B., Winters-Stone, K., Irvine, J. M. &amp; Bennett, R. M. Fibromyalgia is associated with impaired balance and falls. J. Clin. Rheumatol. 15, 16–21 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19125137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2836495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galvez-Sánchez, C. M., Duschek, S. &amp; Del Paso, G. A. R. Psychological impact of fibromyalgia: current perspectives. Psychol. Res. Behav. Manag. 12, 117–127 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30858740</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6386210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González, E., Elorza, J. &amp; Failde, I. Fibromyalgia and psychiatric comorbidity: their effect on the quality of life patients. Actas Esp. Psiquiatr. 38, 295–300 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21117004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kessler, R. C. et al. The epidemiology of major depressive disorder: results from the National Comorbidity Survey Replication (NCS-R). JAMA 289, 3095–3105 (2003).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12813115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreyer, L., Kendall, S., Danneskiold-Samsøe, B., Bartels, E. M. &amp; Bliddal, H. Mortality in a cohort of Danish patients with fibromyalgia: Increased frequency of suicide. Arthritis Rheum. 62, 3101–3108 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20583101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gill, H. et al. The prevalence of suicidal behaviour in fibromyalgia patients. Prog. Neuropsychopharmacol. Biol. Psychiatry https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2020.110078 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2020.110078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, R. M. Fibrositis: misnomer for a common rheumatic disorder. West. J. Med. 134, 405–413 (1981).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6167073</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1272765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe, F. et al. Fibromyalgia criteria and severity scales for clinical and epidemiological studies: a modification of the ACR preliminary diagnostic criteria for fibromyalgia. J. Rheumatol. 38, 1113–1122 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe, F. et al. The American College of Rheumatology preliminary diagnostic criteria for fibromyalgia and measurement of symptom severity. Arthritis Care Res. 62, 600–610 (2010).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe, F. et al. 2016 Revisions to the 2010/2011 fibromyalgia diagnostic criteria. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 46, 319–329 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27916278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atzeni, F. et al. One year in review 2019: fibromyalgia. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 37, S3–S10 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrot, S., Bouhassira, D. &amp; Fermanian, J. Development and validation of the fibromyalgia rapid screening tool (FiRST). Pain 150, 250–256 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20488620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baron, R. et al. Improving the primary care physicians’ decision making for fibromyalgia in clinical practice: development and validation of the fibromyalgia detection (FibroDetect®) screening tool. Health Qual. Life Outcomes 12, 128 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25341959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4221679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F. et al. Development and validation of the SImple FIbromyalgia Screening questionnaire for improving the recognition of fibromyalgia in daily practice. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 38, 9–16 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31577216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yunus, M. B. Central sensitivity syndromes: a new paradigm and group nosology for fibromyalgia and overlapping conditions, and the related issue of disease versus illness. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 37, 339–352 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18191990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe, F. Fibromyalgianess. Arthritis Care Res. 61, 715–716 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F., Di Carlo, M., Arcà, S. &amp; Galeazzi, M. Categorisation of disease severity states in fibromyalgia: a first step to support decision-making in health care policy. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 36, 1074–1081 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30325304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis, F. et al. Characterizing classes of fibromyalgia within the continuum of central sensitization syndrome. J. Pain Res. 11, 2551–2560 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30425566</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6205129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballantyne, J. C. &amp; Sullivan, M. D. Intensity of chronic pain — the wrong metric? N. Engl. J. Med. 373, 2098–2099 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F., Sarzi-Puttini, P., Ciapetti, A. &amp; Atzeni, F. Clinimetric evaluations of patients with chronic widespread pain. Best Pract. Res. Clin. Rheumatol. 25, 249–270 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22094200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burckhardt, C. S., Clark, S. R. &amp; Bennett, R. M. The fibromyalgia impact questionnaire: development and validation. J. Rheumatol. 18, 728–733 (1991).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1865419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, R. M. et al. The Revised Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire (FIQR): validation and psychometric properties. Arthritis Res. Ther. 11, R120 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19664287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2745803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F. et al. Psychometric characteristics of the Italian version of the revised Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire using classical test theory and Rasch analysis. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 31, S41–S49 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23806265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F. et al. Development and validation of the self-administered Fibromyalgia Assessment Status: a disease-specific composite measure for evaluating treatment effect. Arthritis Res. Ther. 11, R125 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19686606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2745809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iannuccelli, C. et al. Psychometric properties of the Fibromyalgia Assessment Status (FAS) index: a national web-based study of fibromyalgia. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 29, S49–S54 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22011656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W. et al. Validation of the fibromyalgia survey questionnaire within a cross-sectional survey. PLoS ONE 7, e37504 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3360780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W., Brähler, E., Wolfe, F. &amp; Henningsen, P. Patient Health Questionnaire 15 as a generic measure of severity in fibromyalgia syndrome: surveys with patients of three different settings. J. Psychosom. Res. 76, 307–311 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24630181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosek, E. et al. Do we need a third mechanistic descriptor for chronic pain states? Pain 157, 1382–1386 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26835783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yunus, M. B. Central sensitivity syndromes: a unified concept for fibromyalgia and other similar maladies. J. Indian Rheumatol. Assoc. 8, 27–33 (2000).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borchers, A. T. &amp; Gershwin, M. E. Fibromyalgia: a critical and comprehensive review. Clin. Rev. Allergy Immunol. 49, 100–151 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ceko, M., Bushnell, M. C. &amp; Gracely, R. H. Neurobiology underlying fibromyalgia symptoms. Pain Res. Treat. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/585419 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2012/585419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22191023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desmeules, J. A. et al. Neurophysiologic evidence for a central sensitization in patients with fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 48, 1420–1429 (2003).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12746916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sörensen, J., Graven-Nielsen, T., Henriksson, K. G., Bengtsson, M. &amp; Arendt-Nielsen, L. Hyperexcitability in fibromyalgia. J. Rheumatol. 25, 152–155 (1998).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9458220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staud, R., Vierck, C. J., Cannon, R. L., Mauderli, A. P. &amp; Price, D. D. Abnormal sensitization and temporal summation of second pain (wind-up) in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Pain 91, 165–175 (2001).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11240089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDermid, A. J., Rollman, G. B. &amp; McCain, G. A. Generalized hypervigilance in fibromyalgia: evidence of perceptual amplification. Pain 66, 133–144 (1996).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8880834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geisser, M. E. et al. A psychophysical study of auditory and pressure sensitivity in patients with fibromyalgia and healthy controls. J. Pain 9, 417–422 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18280211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martenson, M. E. et al. A possible neural mechanism for photosensitivity in chronic pain. Pain 157, 868–878 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26785323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4794405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris, R. E. &amp; Clauw, D. J. How do we know that the pain in fibromyalgia is “Real”? Curr. Pain Headache Rep. 10, 403–407 (2006).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17087863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gracely, R. H., Petzke, F., Wolf, J. M. &amp; Clauw, D. J. Functional magnetic resonance imaging evidence of augmented pain processing in fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 46, 1333–1343 (2002).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12115241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, D. B. et al. Functional imaging of pain in patients with primary fibromyalgia. J. Rheumatol. 31, 364–378 (2004).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14760810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgmer, M. et al. Altered brain activity during pain processing in fibromyalgia. Neuroimage 44, 502–508 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen, K. B. et al. Evidence of dysfunctional pain inhibition in fibromyalgia reflected in rACC during provoked pain. Pain 144, 95–100 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19410366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dehghan, M. et al. Coordinate-based (ALE) meta-analysis of brain activation in patients with fibromyalgia. Hum. Brain Mapp. 37, 1749–1758 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26864780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6867581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Napadow, V. et al. Intrinsic brain connectivity in fibromyalgia is associated with chronic pain intensity. Arthritis Rheum. 62, 2545–2555 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20506181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2921024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pujol, J. et al. Mapping brain response to pain in fibromyalgia patients using temporal analysis of fMRI. PLoS ONE 4, e5224 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19381292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2667672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen, K. B. et al. Patients with fibromyalgia display less functional connectivity in the brain’s pain inhibitory network. Mol. Pain 8, 32 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22537768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3404927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Julien, N., Goffaux, P., Arsenault, P. &amp; Marchand, S. Widespread pain in fibromyalgia is related to a deficit of endogenous pain inhibition. Pain 114, 295–302 (2005).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15733656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vierck, C. J. et al. The effect of maximal exercise on temporal summation of second pain (windup) in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. J. Pain 2, 334–344 (2001).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14622813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Normand, E. et al. Pain inhibition is deficient in chronic widespread pain but normal in major depressive disorder. J. Clin. Psychiatry 72, 219–224 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20816025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lutz, J. et al. White and gray matter abnormalities in the brain of patients with fibromyalgia: a diffusion-tensor and volumetric imaging study. Arthritis Rheum. 58, 3960–3969 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19035484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell, I. J. et al. Elevated cerebrospinal fluid levels of substance P in patients with the fibromyalgia syndrome. Arthritis Rheum. 37, 1593–1601 (1994).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7526868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris, R. E. et al. Decreased central mu-opioid receptor availability in fibromyalgia. J. Neurosci. 27, 10000–10006 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6672650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baraniuk, J. N., Whalen, G., Cunningham, J. &amp; Clauw, D. J. Cerebrospinal fluid levels of opioid peptides in fibromyalgia and chronic low back pain. BMC Musculoskelet. Disord. 5, 48 (2004).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15588296</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">539267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell, I. J., Vaeroy, H., Javors, M. &amp; Nyberg, F. Cerebrospinal fluid biogenic amine metabolites in fibromyalgia/fibrositis syndrome and rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 35, 550–556 (1992).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1374252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yunus, M. B., Dailey, J. W., Aldag, J. C., Masi, A. T. &amp; Jobe, P. C. Plasma tryptophan and other amino acids in primary fibromyalgia: a controlled study. J. Rheumatol. 19, 90–94 (1992).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1556707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood, P. B. et al. Fibromyalgia patients show an abnormal dopamine response to pain. Eur. J. Neurosci. 25, 3576–3582 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17610577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood, P. B. et al. Reduced presynaptic dopamine activity in fibromyalgia syndrome demonstrated with positron emission tomography: a pilot study. J. Pain 8, 51–58 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17023218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris, R. E. Elevated excitatory neurotransmitter levels in the fibromyalgia brain. Arthritis Res. Ther. 12, 141 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20959024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2991003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foerster, B. R. et al. Reduced insular γ-aminobutyric acid in fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 64, 579–583 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21913179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3374930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, L. M. et al. Family study of fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 50, 944–952 (2004).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15022338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stormorken, H. &amp; Brosstad, F. Fibromyalgia: family clustering and sensory urgency with early onset indicate genetic predisposition and thus a “true” disease. Scand. J. Rheumatol. 21, 207 (1992).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1529291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buskila, D., Neumann, L., Hazanov, I. &amp; Carmi, R. Familial aggregation in the fibromyalgia syndrome. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 26, 605–611 (1996).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8989805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ablin, J. N. &amp; Buskila, D. Update on the genetics of the fibromyalgia syndrome. Best Pract. Res. Clin. Rheumatol. 29, 20–28 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26266996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, S. B. et al. Large candidate gene association study reveals genetic risk factors and therapeutic targets for fibromyalgia. Arthritis Rheum. 64, 584–593 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21905019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3237946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haliloglu, S., Carlioglu, A., Akdeniz, D., Karaaslan, Y. &amp; Kosar, A. Fibromyalgia in patients with other rheumatic diseases: prevalence and relationship with disease activity. Rheumatol. Int. 34, 1275–1280 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24589726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan, A. et al. Frequency of concomitant fibromyalgia in rheumatic diseases: monocentric study of 691 patients. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 47, 129–132 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28216193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Affaitati, G. et al. Effects of treatment of peripheral pain generators in fibromyalgia patients. Eur. J. Pain 15, 61–69 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20889359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doppler, K., Rittner, H. L., Deckart, M. &amp; Sommer, C. Reduced dermal nerve fiber diameter in skin biopsies of patients with fibromyalgia. Pain 156, 2319–2325 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26164586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clauw, D. J. What is the meaning of “small fiber neuropathy” in fibromyalgia? Pain 156, 2115–2116 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26307862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren, K. &amp; Dubner, R. Interactions between the immune and nervous systems in pain. Nat. Med. 16, 1267–1276 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20948535</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3077564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarzi-Puttini, P. et al. Anti-polymer antibodies are correlated with pain and fatigue severity in patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. Autoimmunity 41, 74–79 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18176867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bazzichi, L. et al. Association between thyroid autoimmunity and fibromyalgic disease severity. Clin. Rheumatol. 26, 2115–2120 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17487449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassisi, G., Sarzi-Puttini, P. &amp; Cazzola, M. Chronic widespread pain and fibromyalgia: could there be some relationships with infections and vaccinations? Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 29, S118–S126 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22243559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wormser, G. P. et al. Long-term assessment of fibromyalgia in patients with culture-confirmed Lyme disease. Arthritis Rheumatol. 67, 837–839 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25470117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W., Kosseva, M., Üceyler, N., Klose, P. &amp; Sommer, C. Emotional, physical, and sexual abuse in fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res. 63, 808–820 (2011).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W. et al. Self-reported childhood maltreatment, lifelong traumatic events and mental disorders in fibromyalgia syndrome: a comparison of US and German outpatients. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 33, S86–S92 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25786049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4750383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paras, M. L. et al. Sexual abuse and lifetime diagnosis of somatic disorders. JAMA 302, 550 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19654389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meeus, M. et al. Heart rate variability in patients with fibromyalgia and patients with chronic fatigue syndrome: a systematic review. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 43, 279–287 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23838093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furlan, R. et al. Abnormalities of cardiovascular neural control and reduced orthostatic tolerance in patients with primary fibromyalgia. J. Rheumatol. 32, 1787–1793 (2005).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16142879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez-Martínez, L. A., Mora, T., Vargas, A., Fuentes-Iniestra, M. &amp; Martínez-Lavín, M. Sympathetic nervous system dysfunction in fibromyalgia, chronic fatigue syndrome, irritable bowel syndrome, and interstitial cystitis: a review of case-control studies. J. Clin. Rheumatol. 20, 146–150 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24662556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez-Lavín, M. &amp; Hermosillo, A. G. Autonomic nervous system dysfunction may explain the multisystem features of fibromyalgia. Semin. Arthritis Rheum. 29, 197–199 (2000).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10707988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnevali, L., Koenig, J., Sgoifo, A. &amp; Ottaviani, C. Autonomic and brain morphological predictors of stress resilience. Front. Neurosci. 12, 228 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29681793</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5897537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Raecke, R., Niemeier, A., Ihle, K., Ruether, W. &amp; May, A. Brain gray matter decrease in chronic pain is the consequence and not the cause of pain. J. Neurosci. 29, 13746–13750 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19889986</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6666725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, A. C., Jaaniste, T. &amp; Champion, D. Chronic widespread pain and fibromyalgia syndrome: life-course risk markers in young people. Pain Res. Manag. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/6584753 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/6584753</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6525804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson, R. W., Arnkoff, D. B. &amp; Glass, C. R. Conceptualizing mindfulness and acceptance as components of psychological resilience to trauma. Trauma Violence Abuse 12, 220–235 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21908440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, J. M., Rohleder, N. &amp; Sturmberg, J. P. Biopsychosocial approach to understanding resilience: Stress habituation and where to intervene. J. Eval. Clin. Pract. 24, 1339–1346 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30338615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hassett, A. L. &amp; Finan, P. H. The role of resilience in the clinical management of chronic pain. Curr. Pain. Headache Rep. 20, 39 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27115770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel, G. The need for a new medical model: a challenge for biomedicine. Science 196, 129–136 (1977).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">847460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gracely, R. H. et al. Pain catastrophizing and neural responses to pain among persons with fibromyalgia. Brain 127, 835–843 (2004).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14960499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellingson, L. D., Stegner, A. J., Schwabacher, I. J., Lindheimer, J. B. &amp; Cook, D. B. Catastrophizing interferes with cognitive modulation of pain in women with fibromyalgia. Pain Med. 19, 2408–2422 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29474665</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6659027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geisser, M. E. et al. Perception of noxious and innocuous heat stimulation among healthy women and women with fibromyalgia: association with mood, somatic focus, and catastrophizing. Pain 102, 243–250 (2003).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lami, M. J., Martínez, M. P., Miró, E., Sánchez, A. I. &amp; Guzmán, M. A. Catastrophizing, acceptance, and coping as mediators between pain and emotional distress and disability in fibromyalgia. J. Clin. Psychol. Med. Settings 25, 80–92 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29450798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broadbent, P., Liossi, C. &amp; Schoth, D. E. Attentional bias to somatosensory stimuli in chronic pain patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain https://doi.org/10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002040 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002040</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32833792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alciati, A. et al. Childhood adversities in patients with fibromyalgia: are they related to comorbid lifetime major depression? Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 35, 112–118 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28681713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein, S. A. et al. Psychiatric disorders in patients with fibromyalgia. Psychosomatics 40, 57–63 (1999).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9989122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alciati, A., Sgiarovello, P., Atzeni, F. &amp; Sarzi-Puttini, P. Psychiatric problems in fibromyalgia: clinical and neurobiological links between mood disorders and fibromyalgia. Reumatismo 64, 268–274 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23024971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarzi-Puttini, P. et al. Dysfunctional syndromes and fibromyalgia: a 2012 critical digest. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 30, 143–151 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23261014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choy, E. H. S. The role of sleep in pain and fibromyalgia. Nat. Rev. Rheumatol. 11, 513–520 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25907704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzi, M. et al. Influence of autonomic nervous system dysfunction in the genesis of sleep disorders in fibromyalgia patients. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 35, 74–80 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28681708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lentz, M. J., Landis, C. A., Rothermel, J. &amp; Shaver, J. L. Effects of selective slow wave sleep disruption on musculoskeletal pain and fatigue in middle aged women. J. Rheumatol. 26, 1586–1592 (1999).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10405949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, M. T., Edwards, R. R., McCann, U. D. &amp; Haythornthwaite, J. A. The effects of sleep deprivation on pain inhibition and spontaneous pain in women. Sleep 30, 494–505 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17520794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moldofsky, H., Scarisbrick, P., England, R. &amp; Smythe, H. Musculosketal symptoms and non-REM sleep disturbance in patients with “fibrositis syndrome” and healthy subjects. Psychosom. Med. 37, 341–351 (1975).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">169541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yalinay Dikmen, P., Yavuz, B. G. &amp; Aydinlar, E. I. The relationships between migraine, depression, anxiety, stress, and sleep disturbances. Acta Neurol. Belg. 115, 117–122 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24889393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sivertsen, B., Harvey, A. G., Pallesen, S. &amp; Hysing, M. Mental health problems in adolescents with delayed sleep phase: results from a large population-based study in Norway. J. Sleep. Res. 24, 11–18 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25358244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haase, L. et al. When the brain does not adequately feel the body: links between low resilience and interoception. Biol. Psychol. 113, 37–45 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26607442</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giusti, E. M., Castelnuovo, G., &amp; Molinari, E. Differences in multidisciplinary and interdisciplinary treatment programs for fibromyalgia: a mapping review. Pain Res. Manag. https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/7261468 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/7261468</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28620267</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5460453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gendelman, O. et al. Time to diagnosis of fibromyalgia and factors associated with delayed diagnosis in primary care. Best Pract. Res. Clin. Rheumatol. 32, 489–499 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31174818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Ríos, M. C. et al. Effectiveness of health education in patients with fibromyalgia: a systematic review. Eur. J. Phys. Rehabil. Med. 55, 301–313 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30698402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clauw, D. J. Fibromyalgia: a clinical review. JAMA 311, 1547–1555 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24737367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W. &amp; Fitzcharles, M. A. Facts and myths pertaining to fibromyalgia. Dialogues Clin. Neurosci. 20, 53–62 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6016048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fitzcharles, M. A., Ste-Marie, P. A. &amp; Pereira, J. X. Fibromyalgia: evolving concepts over the past 2 decades. Can. Med. Assoc. J. 185, 645–651 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearson, J. et al. Fibromyalgia self-management: mapping the behaviour change techniques used in a practice-based programme. Musculoskelet. Care 18, 372–382 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrepf, A. et al. Improvement in the spatial distribution of pain, somatic symptoms, and depression after a weight loss intervention. J. Pain 18, 1542–1550 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28847734</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5841588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busch, A. J., Barber, K. A. R., Overend, T. J., Peloso, P. M. J. &amp; Schachter, C. L. Exercise for treating fibromyalgia syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 17, CD003786 (2007).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Dwyer, T., Maguire, S., Mockler, D., Durcan, L. &amp; Wilson, F. Behaviour change interventions targeting physical activity in adults with fibromyalgia: a systematic review. Rheumatol. Int. 39, 805–817 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30864109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bjørklund, G., Dadar, M., Chirumbolo, S. &amp; Aaseth, J. Fibromyalgia and nutrition: therapeutic possibilities? Biomed. Pharmacother. 103, 531–538 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29677539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pagliai, G., Giangrandi, I., Dinu, M., Sofi, F. &amp; Colombini, B. Nutritional Interventions in the management of fibromyalgia syndrome. Nutrients 12, 2525 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clauw, D. J. Diagnosing and treating chronic musculoskeletal pain based on the underlying mechanism(s). Best Pract. Res. Clin. Rheumatol. 29, 6–19 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26266995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W., Petzke, F., Üçeyler, N. &amp; Sommer, C. Comparative efficacy and acceptability of amitriptyline, duloxetine and milnacipran in fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Rheumatology 50, 532–543 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21078630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W., Wolfe, F., Tölle, T., Uçeyler, N. &amp; Sommer, C. The role of antidepressants in the management of fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. CNS Drugs 26, 297–307 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22452526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calandre, E. P., Rico-Villademoros, F. &amp; Slim, M. An update on pharmacotherapy for the treatment of fibromyalgia. Expert. Opin. Pharmacother. 16, 1347–1368 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26001183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Häuser, W., Urrútia, G., Tort, S., Üçeyler, N. &amp; Walitt, B. Serotonin and noradrenaline reuptake inhibitors (SNRIs) for fibromyalgia syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 31, CD010292 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lunn, M. P., Hughes, R. A. &amp; Wiffen, P. J. Duloxetine for treating painful neuropathy, chronic pain or fibromyalgia. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 3, CD007115 (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pickering, G. et al. Milnacipran poorly modulates pain in patients suffering from fibromyalgia: a randomized double-blind controlled study. Drug Des. Devel. Ther. 12, 2485–2496 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30127596</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6089099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Üçeyler, N., Sommer, C., Walitt, B. &amp; Häuser, W. Anticonvulsants for fibromyalgia. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 16, CD010782 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper, T. E., Derry, S., Wiffen, P. J. &amp; Moore, R. A. Gabapentin for fibromyalgia pain in adults. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 1, CD012188 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28045473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Straube, S., Derry, S., Moore, R. A. &amp; McQuay, H. J. Pregabalin in fibromyalgia: meta-analysis of efficacy and safety from company clinical trial reports. Rheumatology 49, 706–715 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20056767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derry, S. et al. Pregabalin for pain in fibromyalgia in adults. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 9, CD011790 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27684492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alciati, A. et al. Controlled-release pregabalin in the treatment of fibromyalgia. Expert. Rev. Neurother. 18, 617–623 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tofferi, J. K., Jackson, J. L. &amp; O’Malley, P. G. Treatment of fibromyalgia with cyclobenzaprine: a meta-analysis. Arthritis Rheum. 51, 9–13 (2004).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14872449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giovannitti, J. A., Thoms, S. M. &amp; Crawford, J. J. Alpha-2 adrenergic receptor agonists: a review of current clinical applications. Anesth. Prog. 62, 31–38 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25849473</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4389556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malanga, G. A., Gwyn, M. W., Smith, R. &amp; Miller, D. Tizanidine is effective in the treatment of myofascial pain syndrome. Pain Physician 5, 422–432 (2002).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16886022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>See, S. &amp; Ginzburg, R. Choosing a skeletal muscle relaxant. Am. Fam. Physician 78, 365 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18711953</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Littlejohn, G. O., Guymer, E. K. &amp; Ngian, G.-S. Is there a role for opioids in the treatment of fibromyalgia? Pain Manag. 6, 347–355 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27296831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Younger, J., Noor, N., McCue, R. &amp; MacKey, S. Low-dose naltrexone for the treatment of fibromyalgia: findings of a small, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, counterbalanced, crossover trial assessing daily pain levels. Arthritis Rheum. 65, 529–538 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23359310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, P. S. &amp; Fishman, M. A. Low-dose naltrexone for chronic pain: update and systemic review. Curr. Pain Headache Rep. 24, 64 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Painter, J. T. &amp; Crofford, L. J. Chronic opioid use in fibromyalgia syndrome: a clinical review. J. Clin. Rheumatol. 19, 72–77 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23364665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cazzola, M., Sarzi-Puttini, P., Buskila, D. &amp; Atzeni, F. [Pharmacological treatment of fibromyalgia]. Reumatismo 59, 280–291 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18157284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clauw, D. J. &amp; Hassett, A. L. The role of centralised pain in osteoarthritis. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 35, S79–S84 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moldofsky, H., Lue, F. A., Mously, C., Roth-Schechter, B. &amp; Reynolds, W. J. The effect of zolpidem in patients with fibromyalgia: a dose ranging, double blind, placebo controlled, modified crossover study. J. Rheumatol. 23, 529–533 (1996).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8832997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walitt, B., Klose, P., Üçeyler, N., Phillips, T. &amp; Häuser, W. Antipsychotics for fibromyalgia in adults. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2016, CD011804 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6457603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calandre, E. P. et al. Quetiapine extended-release (Seroquel-XR) versus amitriptyline monotherapy for treating patients with fibromyalgia: a 16-week, randomized, flexible-dose, open-label trial. Psychopharmacology 231, 2525–2531 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24398824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strouse, T. B. Cannabinoids in medical practice. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res. 1, 38–43 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28861478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5576598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walitt, B., Klose, P., Ma, F., Phillips, T. &amp; Häuser, W. Cannabinoids for fibromyalgia (Review). Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 7, CD011694 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27428009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farrell, M. et al. Cannabis and cannabinoids for the treatment of people with chronic noncancer pain conditions. Pain 159, 1932–1954 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29847469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aviram, J. &amp; Samuelly-Leichtag, G. Efficacy of cannabis-based medicines for pain management: a systematic review and meta- analysis of randomized controlled trials. Pain Physician 20, E755–E796 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill, K. P., Palastro, M. D., Johnson, B. &amp; Ditre, J. W. Cannabis and pain: a clinical review. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res. 2, 96–104 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28861509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5549367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fiz, J., Duràn, M., Capellà, D., Carbonell, J. &amp; Farré, M. Cannabis use in patients with fibromyalgia: effect on symptoms relief and health-related quality of life. PLoS ONE 6, e18440 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21533029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3080871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarzi-Puttini, P. et al. Medical cannabis and cannabinoids in rheumatology: where are we now? Expert Rev. Clin. Immunol. 15, 1019–1032 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31512536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habib, G. &amp; Artul, S. Medical cannabis for the treatment of fibromyalgia. J. Clin. Rheumatol. 24, 255–258 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29461346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van de Donk, T. et al. An experimental randomized study on the analgesic effects of pharmaceutical-grade cannabis in chronic pain patients with fibromyalgia. Pain 160, 860–869 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30585986</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6430597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yassin, M., Oron, A. &amp; Robinson, D. Effect of adding medical cannabis to analgesic treatment in patients with low back pain related to fibromyalgia: an observational cross-over single centre study. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 37, 13–20 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30418116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giorgi, V. et al. Adding medical cannabis to standard analgesic treatment for fibromyalgia: a prospective observational study. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 38, 53–59 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32116208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Pain Report. Marijuana rated most effective for treating fibromyalgia, http://nationalpainreport.com/marijuana-rated-most-effective-for-treating-fibromyalgia-8823638.html (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathore, F. A. &amp; Afridi, A. Is combination pharmacotherapy effective for management of fibromyalgia in adults? — a Cochrane Review summary with commentary. J. Musculoskelet. Neuronal Interact. 20, 297–300 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7493437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boomershine, C. S. &amp; Crofford, L. J. A symptom-based approach to pharmacologic management of fibromyalgia. Nat. Rev. Rheumatol. 5, 191–199 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19337283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorpe, J., Shum, B., Ra, M., Pj, W. &amp; Gilron, I. Combination pharmacotherapy for the treatment of fibromyalgia in adults (Review). Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2018, CD010585 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6491103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mease, P. J. et al. Milnacipran combined with pregabalin in fibromyalgia: a randomized, open-label study evaluating the safety and efficacy of adding milnacipran in patients with incomplete response to pregabalin. Ther. Adv. Musculoskelet. Dis. 5, 113–126 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23858335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3707344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilron, I. et al. Combination of pregabalin with duloxetine for fibromyalgia. Pain 157, 1532–1540 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26982602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, L. M. et al. Efficacy and safety of pregabalin in patients with fibromyalgia and comorbid depression taking concurrent antidepressant medication: a randomized, placebo-controlled study. J. Rheumatol. 42, 1237–1244 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26034150</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernardy, K., Klose, P., Welsch, P. &amp; Häuser, W. Efficacy, acceptability and safety of cognitive behavioural therapies in fibromyalgia syndrome - A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur. J. Pain 22, 242–260 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28984402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs, H. et al. The impact of a group-based multidisciplinary rehabilitation program on the quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia: results from the QUALIFIBRO Study. J. Clin. Rheumatol. https://doi.org/10.1097/RHU.0000000000001120 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RHU.0000000000001120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31232906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernardy, K., Klose, P., Welsch, P. &amp; Häuser, W. Efficacy, acceptability and safety of Internet-delivered psychological therapies for fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur. J. Pain 23, 3–14 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrot, S. &amp; Russell, I. J. More ubiquitous effects from non-pharmacologic than from pharmacologic treatments for fibromyalgia syndrome: a meta-analysis examining six core symptoms. Eur. J. Pain 18, 1067–1080 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25139817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gálvez, I., Torres-Piles, S. &amp; Ortega-Rincón, E. Balneotherapy, immune system, and stress response: a hormetic strategy? Int. J. Mol. Sci. 19, 1687 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6032246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naumann, J. &amp; Sadaghiani, C. Therapeutic benefit of balneotherapy and hydrotherapy in the management of fibromyalgia syndrome: a qualitative systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arthritis Res. Ther. 16, R141 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25000940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4227103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fioravanti, A. et al. Is balneotherapy effective for fibromyalgia? Results from a 6-month double-blind randomized clinical trial. Clin. Rheumatol. 37, 2203–2212 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29730741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honda Y. et al. Effects of physical-agent pain relief modalities for fibromyalgia patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Pain Res. Manag. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/2930632 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurt, E. E., Koçak, F. A., Erdem, H. R., Tuncay, F. &amp; Kelez, F. Which non-pharmacological treatment is more effective on clinical parameters in patients with fibromyalgia: balneotherapy or aerobic exercise? Arch. Rheumatol. 31, 162–169 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29900959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5827833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guidelli, G. M., Tenti, S., de Nobili, E. &amp; Fioravanti, A. Fibromyalgia syndrome and spa therapy: myth or reality? Clin. Med. Insights Arthritis Musculoskelet. Disord. 5, 19–26 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22408369</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3296493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langhorst, J., Klose, P., Dobos, G. J., Bernardy, K. &amp; Häuser, W. Efficacy and safety of meditative movement therapies in fibromyalgia syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Rheumatol. Int. 33, 193–207 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22350253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mist, S. D., Firestone, K. A. &amp; Jones, K. D. Complementary and alternative exercise for fibromyalgia: a meta-analysis. J. Pain Res. 6, 247–260 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23569397</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3616139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng, C.-A. et al. Effectiveness of Tai Chi on fibromyalgia patients: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Complement. Ther. Med. 46, 1–8 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31519264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, C. et al. Effect of tai chi versus aerobic exercise for fibromyalgia: comparative effectiveness randomized controlled trial. BMJ 360, k851 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29563100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5861462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Gordon, W., Shonin, E., Dunn, T. J., Garcia-Campayo, J. &amp; Griffiths, M. D. Meditation awareness training for the treatment of fibromyalgia syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Br. J. Health Psychol. 22, 186–206 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27885763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haugmark, T., Hagen, K. B., Smedslund, G. &amp; Zangi, H. A. Mindfulness- and acceptance-based interventions for patients with fibromyalgia — a systematic review and meta-analyses. PLoS One 14, e0221897 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31479478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6719827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauche, R., Cramer, H., Dobos, G., Langhorst, J. &amp; Schmidt, S. A systematic review and meta-analysis of mindfulness-based stress reduction for the fibromyalgia syndrome. J. Psychosom. Res. 75, 500–510 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24290038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luciano, J. V. et al. Effectiveness of group acceptance and commitment therapy for fibromyalgia: A 6-month randomized controlled trial (EFFIGACT study). Pain 155, 693–702 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24378880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luciano, J. V. et al. Cost-utility of group acceptance and commitment therapy for fibromyalgia versus recommended Drugs: an economic analysis alongside a 6-month randomized controlled trial conducted in Spain (EFFIGACT Study). J. Pain 18, 868–880 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen, M. P. Hypnosis for chronic pain management: a new hope. Pain 146, 235–237 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19596518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zech, N., Hansen, E., Bernardy, K. &amp; Häuser, W. Efficacy, acceptability and safety of guided imagery/hypnosis in fibromyalgia — a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur. J. Pain 21, 217–227 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27896907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deare, J. C. et al. Acupuncture for treating fibromyalgia. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2013, CD007070 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4105202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, B. et al. Efficacy of acupuncture on fibromyalgia syndrome: a meta-analysis. J. Tradit. Chin. Med. 34, 381–391 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25185355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atzeni, F. et al. Hyperbaric oxygen treatment of fibromyalgia: a prospective observational clinical study. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 37, 63–69 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747099</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efrati, S. et al. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy can diminish fibromyalgia syndrome — prospective clinical trial. PLoS ONE 10, e0127012 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010952</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4444341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moisset, X., Lanteri-Minet, M. &amp; Fontaine, D. Neurostimulation methods in the treatment of chronic pain. J. Neural Transm. 127, 673–686 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31637517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atzeni, F. et al. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy in fibromyalgia and the diseases involving the central nervous system. Clin. Exp. Rheumatol. 38, S94–S98 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brighina, F. et al. Brain modulation by electric currents in fibromyalgia: a structured review on non-invasive approach with transcranial electrical stimulation. Front. Hum. Neurosci. 11, 13–40 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mhalla, A. et al. Long-term maintenance of the analgesic effects of transcranial magnetic stimulation in fibromyalgia. Pain 152, 1478–1485 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21397400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Solà, M. et al. Towards a neurophysiological signature for fibromyalgia. Pain 158, 34–47 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27583567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5161739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clauw, D. J., Essex, M. N., Pitman, V. &amp; Jones, K. D. Reframing chronic pain as a disease, not a symptom: rationale and implications for pain management. Postgrad. Med. 131, 185–198 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, R. Fibromyalgia: shining a light on fibromyalgia treatment. Nat. Rev. Rheumatol. 12, 568–569 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27627866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, L. M. Duloxetine and other antidepressants in the treatment of patients with fibromyalgia. Pain Med. 8, S63–S74 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17714117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzellos, T. G. et al. Gabapentin and pregabalin in the treatment of fibromyalgia: a systematic review and a meta-analysis. J. Clin. Pharm. Ther. 35, 639–656 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21054455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Üçeyler, N., Sommer, C., Walitt, B. &amp; Häuser, W. Anticonvulsants for fibromyalgia. Cochrane Database Syst. Rev. 2017, 2–5 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarzi-Puttini, P. et al. Cannabinoids in the treatment of rheumatic diseases: pros and cons. Autoimmun. Rev. 18, 102409 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31648042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Food and Drug Administration. Drug approval package: Cymbalta (duloxetine hydrochloride), 20, 30, and 60 mg capsules. FDA https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/nda/2010/022516_cymbalta_tocEDT.cfm (2010).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IBM Micromedex. Duloxetine (Oral Route). Mayo Foundation for Medical Education and Research (MFMER). https://www.mayoclinic.org/drugs-supplements/duloxetine-oral-route/side-effects/drg-20067247 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IBM Micromedex. Milnacipran (Oral Route). Mayo Foundation for Medical Education and Research (MFMER)2. https://www.mayoclinic.org/drugs-supplements/milnacipran-oral-route/side-effects/drg-20072479 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Drug approval package: Savella (Milnacipran HCI) Tablets. FDA https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/nda/2009/022256s000TOC.cfm (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Drug approval package: Lyrica (pregabalin) Oral Solution 20 mg/ml. FDA https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/nda/2010/022488_lyrica_toc.cfm (2010).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
