<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33029958</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1738-6586</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>16</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical neurology (Seoul, Korea)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Anti-SOX1 Antibodies in Paraneoplastic Neurological Syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>530</StartPage>
          <EndPage>546</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>530-546</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3988/jcn.2020.16.4.530</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Anti-Sry-like high mobility group box (SOX) 1 antibodies (abs) are partly characterized onconeural autoantibodies (autoabs) due to their correlation with neoplastic diseases. Anti-SOX1 abs are associated with various clinical manifestations, including Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome (LEMS) and paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration (PCD). However, the clinical characteristics of patients with anti-SOX1 abs have not been described in detail. This review systematically explores the reported patients with anti-SOX1 abs and analyzes these cases for demographic characteristics, clinical features, coexisting neuronal autoabs, neuroimaging findings, treatment, and clinical outcomes. In addition, considering that PCD is the most common paraneoplastic neurological syndrome and that the association between PCD and anti-SOX1 abs remains unclear, we focus on the presence of autoabs in relation to PCD and associated tumors. PCD-associated autoabs include various intracellular autoabs (e.g., anti-Hu, anti-Yo, anti-Ri, and anti-SOX1) and cell-surface autoabs (anti-P/Q-type voltage-gated calcium channel). Commonly involved tumors in PCD are small-cell lung cancer (SCLC), gynecological, and breast tumors. LEMS is the most common clinical symptom in patients with anti-SOX1 abs, followed by PCD, and multiple neuronal autoabs coexist in 47.1% of these patients. SCLC is still the predominant tumor in patients with anti-SOX1 abs, while non-SCLC is uncommon. No consistent imaging feature is found in patients with anti-SOX1 abs, and there is no consensus on either the therapy choice or therapeutic efficacy. In conclusion, the presence of anti-SOX1 abs alone is a potential predictor of an uncommon paraneoplastic neurological disorder, usually occurring in the setting of LEMS, PCD, and SCLC. The detection of anti-SOX1 abs contributes to an early diagnosis of underlying tumors, given the diversity of clinical symptoms and the absence of characteristic neuroimaging features.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 Korean Neurological Association.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6894-3342</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Neurological Department of the Second Medical Centre, National Clinical Research Center of Geriatric Diseases, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Tan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jiping</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1121-9975</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Neurological Department of the Second Medical Centre, National Clinical Research Center of Geriatric Diseases, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hui</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8748-6880</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, the First Medical Centre, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1313-9883</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Neurological Department of the Second Medical Centre, National Clinical Research Center of Geriatric Diseases, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Weiping</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3955-5826</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Neurological Department of the Second Medical Centre, National Clinical Research Center of Geriatric Diseases, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jianjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0747-4132</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Neurological Department of the Second Medical Centre, National Clinical Research Center of Geriatric Diseases, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhenfu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1394-4962</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Neurological Department of the Second Medical Centre, National Clinical Research Center of Geriatric Diseases, Chinese PLA General Hospital, Beijing, China. zhenfuw@sina.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101252374</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1738-6586</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SOXB1 transcription factors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibodies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carcinoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-small-cell lung</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small cell lung carcinoma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no potential conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029958</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7541980</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3988/jcn.2020.16.4.530</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">16.530</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalmau J, Rosenfeld MR. Paraneoplastic syndromes of the CNS. Lancet Neurol. 2008;7:327–340.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2367117</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18339348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iorio R, Smitt PS.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. In: Gruol DL, Koibuchi N, Manto M, Molinari M, Schmahmann JD, Shen Y, editors. Essentials of cerebellum and cerebellar disorders. Cham: Springer; 2016. pp. 587–593.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bentea G, Sculier C, Grigoriu B, Meert AP, Durieux V, Berghmans T, et al.  Autoimmune paraneoplastic syndromes associated to lung cancer: a systematic review of the literature: Part 3: neurological paraneoplastic syndromes, involving the central nervous system. Lung Cancer. 2017;106:83–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28285700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giometto B, Grisold W, Vitaliani R, Graus F, Honnorat J, Bertolini G, et al.  Paraneoplastic neurologic syndrome in the PNS Euronetwork database: a European study from 20 centers. Arch Neurol. 2010;67:330–335.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20212230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalmau J, Graus F. Antibody-Mediated Encephalitis. N Engl J Med. 2018;378:840–851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29490181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graus F, Vincent A, Pozo-Rosich P, Sabater L, Saiz A, Lang B, et al.  Anti-glial nuclear antibody: marker of lung cancer-related paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. J Neuroimmunol. 2005;165:166–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2586939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15949849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabater L, Titulaer M, Saiz A, Verschuuren J, Güre AO, Graus F. SOX1 antibodies are markers of paraneoplastic Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome. Neurology. 2008;70:924–928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wegner M. From head to toes: the multiple facets of Sox proteins. Nucleic Acids Res. 1999;27:1409–1420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC148332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10037800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schepers GE, Teasdale RD, Koopman P. Twenty pairs of Sox: extent, homology, and nomenclature of the mouse and human Sox transcription factor gene families. Dev Cell. 2002;3:167–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12194848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malas S, Duthie SM, Mohri F, Lovell-Badge R, Episkopou V. Cloning and mapping of the human SOX1: a highly conserved gene expressed in the developing brain. Mamm Genome. 1997;8:866–868.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9337405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Titulaer MJ, Klooster R, Potman M, Sabater L, Graus F, Hegeman IM, et al.  SOX antibodies in small-cell lung cancer and Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome: frequency and relation with survival. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27:4260–4267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19667272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz-García R, Martínez-Hernández E, García-Ormaechea M, Español-Rego M, Sabater L, Querol L, et al.  Caveats and pitfalls of SOX1 autoantibody testing with a commercial line blot assay in paraneoplastic neurological investigations. Front Immunol. 2019;10:769. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31031763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanaji N, Watanabe N, Kita N, Bandoh S, Tadokoro A, Ishii T, et al.  Paraneoplastic syndromes associated with lung cancer. World J Clin Oncol. 2014;5:197–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4127595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25114839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Güre AO, Stockert E, Scanlan MJ, Keresztes RS, Jäger D, Altorki NK, et al.  Serological identification of embryonic neural proteins as highly immunogenic tumor antigens in small cell lung cancer. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2000;97:4198–4203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC18195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10760287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hardy-Werbin M, Arpí O, Taus A, Rocha P, Joseph-Pietras D, Nolan L, et al.  Assessment of neuronal autoantibodies in patients with small cell lung cancer treated with chemotherapy with or without ipilimumab. Oncoimmunology. 2017;7:e1395125. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5749672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29308329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabater L, Höftberger R, Boronat A, Saiz A, Dalmau J, Graus F. Antibody repertoire in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and small cell lung cancer. PLoS One. 2013;8:e60438. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3607586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23536908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho HJ, Kim R, Lee HW, Jun JS. Encephalitis with anti-SOX1 antibodies presenting with new-onset refractory status epilepticus. J Clin Neurol. 2019;15:564–565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785471</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31591846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger B, Dersch R, Ruthardt E, Rasiah C, Rauer S, Stich O. Prevalence of anti-SOX1 reactivity in various neurological disorders. J Neurol Sci. 2016;369:342–346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27653921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li N, Li S. Epigenetic inactivation of SOX1 promotes cell migration in lung cancer. Tumour Biol. 2015;36:4603–4610.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25613070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogan Onugoren M, Deuretzbacher D, Haensch CA, Hagedorn HJ, Halve S, Isenmann S, et al.  Limbic encephalitis due to GABAB and AMPA receptor antibodies: a case series. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86:965–972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25300449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stich O, Klages E, Bischler P, Jarius S, Rasiah C, Voltz R, et al.  SOX1 antibodies in sera from patients with paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. Acta Neurol Scand. 2012;125:326–331.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21751968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitoma H, Manto M, Hampe CS. Immune-mediated cerebellar ataxias: practical guidelines and therapeutic challenges. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2019;17:33–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341499</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30221603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadjivassiliou M. Immune-mediated acquired ataxias. Handb Clin Neurol. 2012;103:189–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21827889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shams'ili S, Grefkens J, de Leeuw B, van den Bent M, Hooijkaas H, van der Holt B, et al.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with antineuronal antibodies: analysis of 50 patients. Brain. 2003;126:1409–1418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12764061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alessandro L, Schachter D, Farez MF, Varela F. Cerebellar ataxia with extreme photophobia associated with anti-sox1 antibodies. Neurohospitalist. 2019;9:165–168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6582382</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alcock J, Lowe J, England T, Bath P, Sottile V. Expression of Sox1, Sox2 and Sox9 is maintained in adult human cerebellar cortex. Neurosci Lett. 2009;450:114–116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19061938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alcock J, Sottile V. Dynamic distribution and stem cell characteristics of Sox1-expressing cells in the cerebellar cortex. Cell Res. 2009;19:1324–1333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19823196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venkatraman A, Opal P. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with anti-Yo antibodies-a review. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2016;3:655–663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999597</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27606347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitoma H, Manto M, Hampe CS. Immune-mediated cerebellar ataxias: from bench to bedside. Cerebellum Ataxias. 2017;4:16. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5609024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ducray F, Demarquay G, Graus F, Decullier E, Antoine JC, Giometto B, et al.  Seronegative paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: the PNS Euronetwork experience. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21:731–735.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24471811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasadsri L, Lee J, Wang BH, Yekkirala L, Wang M. Anti-Yo associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a man with large cell cancer of the lung. Case Rep Neurol Med. 2013;2013:725936. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24167748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huemer F, Melchardt T, Tränkenschuh W, Neureiter D, Moser G, Magnes T, et al.  Anti-Hu antibody associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in head and neck cancer. BMC Cancer. 2015;15:996. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4687318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graus F, Lang B, Pozo-Rosich P, Saiz A, Casamitjana R, Vincent A. P/Q type calcium-channel antibodies in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with lung cancer. Neurology. 2002;59:764–766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12221175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai G, Sun X, Yu J, Meng X, Li J. Non-small cell lung cancer associated with late-onset Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome and paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Neurol Sci. 2020;41:1277–1279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31735997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruylant K, Crols R, Humbel RL, Appel B, De Deyn PP. Probably anti-Tr associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration as initial presentation of a squamous cell carcinoma of the lung. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2006;108:415–417.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16644410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabater L, Bataller L, Carpentier AF, Aguirre-Cruz ML, Saiz A, Benyahia B, et al.  Protein kinase Cgamma autoimmunity in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and non-small-cell lung cancer. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:1359–1362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiasa Y, Kunishige M, Mitsui T, Kondo S, Kuriwaka R, Shigekiyo S, et al.  Complicated paraneoplastic neurological syndromes: a report of two patients with small cell or non-small cell lung cancer. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2003;106:47–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14643918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konishi J, Yamazaki K, Chikai K, Nagashima K, Sakai K, Kinoshita I, et al.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration (PCD) associated with squamous cell carcinoma of the lung. Intern Med. 2004;43:602–606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15335190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Day J, Yan B, Boer RD, Tsui A. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with squamous cell carcinoma of the lung. J Clin Neurosci. 2013;20:1448–1449.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23790624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li C, Wang X, Sun L, Deng H, Han Y, Zheng W. Anti-SOX1 antibodypositive paraneoplastic neurological syndrome presenting with Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome and small cell lung cancer: a case report. Thorac Cancer. 2020;11:465–469.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6997017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31880403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirallas O, Rial N, Martín-Cullell B, Recio-Iglesias J. A rare case of long-term paraesthesia diagnosed as a paraneoplastic syndrome by anti-SOX1 antibody determination. BMJ Case Rep. 2019;12:e228916 </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6663210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge FF, Li MX, Ruan Z, Chang T, Liu Y, Li HH, et al.  [Clinical, electrophysiological profile and prognosis in paraneoplastic syndrome with SRY-like high-mobility group superfamily of developmental transcription factors 1 antibody] Chin J Neurol. 2019;52:104–109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu L, Ma QY, Kang WT, Yu D, Qiao ZX, Jing Y, et al.  [A case of myasthenia gravis as a paraneoplastic syndrome and sensory peripheral neuropathy with anti-SOX1 antibodies] Chin J Neurol. 2017;50:683–685.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ji MH, Bai SF, Zhai MM, Cheng LN. [Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in anti-SOX1 antibodies: a case report and literature review] J Apoplexy Nerv Dis. 2019;7:651–653.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graus F, Saiz A, Lai M, Bruna J, López F, Sabater L, et al.  Neuronal surface antigen antibodies in limbic encephalitis: clinical-immunologic associations. Neurology. 2008;71:930–936.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2586945</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18794496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tschernatsch M, Singh P, Gross O, Gerriets T, Kneifel N, Probst C, et al.  Anti-SOX1 antibodies in patients with paraneoplastic and non-paraneoplastic neuropathy. J Neuroimmunol. 2010;226:177–180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20701982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vural B, Chen LC, Saip P, Chen YT, Ustuner Z, Gonen M, et al.  Frequency of SOX Group B (SOX1, 2, 3) and ZIC2 antibodies in Turkish patients with small cell lung carcinoma and their correlation with clinical parameters. Cancer. 2005;103:2575–2583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15880380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zekeridou A, Majed M, Heliopoulos I, Lennon VA. Paraneoplastic autoimmunity and small-cell lung cancer: neurological and serological accompaniments. Thorac Cancer. 2019;10:1001–1004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6449272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30810271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Titulaer MJ, Maddison P, Sont JK, Wirtz PW, Hilton-Jones D, Klooster R, et al.  Clinical Dutch-English Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome (LEMS) tumor association prediction score accurately predicts smallcell lung cancer in the LEMS. J Clin Oncol. 2011;29:902–908.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21245427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zoccarato M, Gastaldi M, Zuliani L, Biagioli T, Brogi M, Bernardi G, et al.  Diagnostics of paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. Neurol Sci. 2017;38:237–242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29030766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kacem M, Belloumi N, Bachouche I, Mersni M, Chermiti Ben Abdallah F, Fenniche S. Paraneoplastic limbic encephalitis revealing a small cell carcinoma of the lung. Respir Med Case Rep. 2018;26:157–160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6319301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30622890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zuliani L, Saiz A, Tavolato B, Giometto B, Vincent A, Graus F. Paraneoplastic limbic encephalitis associated with potassium channel antibodies: value of anti-glial nuclear antibodies in identifying the tumour. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:204–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Höftberger R, van Sonderen A, Leypoldt F, Houghton D, Geschwind M, Gelfand J, et al.  Encephalitis and AMPA receptor antibodies: novel findings in a case series of 22 patients. Neurology. 2015;84:2403–2412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4478035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25979696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Höftberger R, Titulaer MJ, Sabater L, Dome B, Rózsás A, Hegedus B, et al.  Encephalitis and GABAB receptor antibodies: novel findings in a new case series of 20 patients. Neurology. 2013;81:1500–1506.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3888170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24068784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuda TG, do Rosário MS, Branco RCC, Fukuda JS, de Souza E Souza RA, Oliveira-Filho J, et al.  Multiple paraneoplastic antibodies (anti-SOX1, anti-Hu, and anti-Amphiphysin) detected in a patient with limbic encephalitis and small cell lung cancer. Neurol India. 2017;65:1127–1128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28879908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boronat A, Sabater L, Saiz A, Dalmau J, Graus F. GABA(B) receptor antibodies in limbic encephalitis and anti-GAD-associated neurologic disorders. Neurology. 2011;76:795–800.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3053332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21357831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai M, Hughes EG, Peng X, Zhou L, Gleichman AJ, Shu H, et al.  AMPA receptor antibodies in limbic encephalitis alter synaptic receptor location. Ann Neurol. 2009;65:424–434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2677127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19338055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueno T, Hasegawa Y, Hagiwara R, Kon T, Nunomura JI, Tomiyama M. Integrated treatment for autonomic paraneoplastic syndrome improves performance status in a patient with small lung cell carcinoma: a case report. BMC Neurol. 2018;18:189. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6230283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang YT, Li RL, Liu ZH, Dong HQ. [A case of cancerous Lambert-Eaton syndrome with SOXl antibody positive] J Neurosci Ment Health. 2016;16:735–737.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeffery OJ, Lennon VA, Pittock SJ, Gregory JK, Britton JW, McKeon A. GABAB receptor autoantibody frequency in service serologic evaluation. Neurology. 2013;81:882–887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3885220</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23925760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dik A, Strippel C, Mönig C, Golombeck KS, Schulte-Mecklenbeck A, Wiendl H, et al.  Onconeural antigen spreading in paraneoplastic neurological disease due to small cell lung cancer. Oxf Med Case Reports. 2018;2018:omy034. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6037119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30002861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson HH, Marsit CJ, Christensen BC, Houseman EA, Kontic M, Wiemels JL, et al.  Key epigenetic changes associated with lung cancer development: results from dense methylation array profiling. Epigenetics. 2012;7:559–566.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3398985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22522909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saraya AW, Worachotsueptrakun K, Vutipongsatorn K, Sonpee C, Hemachudha T. Differences and diversity of autoimmune encephalitis in 77 cases from a single tertiary care center. BMC Neurol. 2019;19:273. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6833261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31694559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horta ES, Lennon VA, Lachance DH, Jenkins SM, Smith CY, McKeon A, et al.  Neural autoantibody clusters aid diagnosis of cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2014;20:3862–3869.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24833664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kunstreich M, Kreth JH, Oommen PT, Schaper J, Karenfort M, Aktas O, et al.  Paraneoplastic limbic encephalitis with SOX1 and PCA2 antibodies and relapsing neurological symptoms in an adolescent with Hodgkin lymphoma. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2017;21:661–665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28389060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubey D, Lennon VA, Gadoth A, Pittock SJ, Flanagan EP, Schmeling JE, et al.  Autoimmune CRMP5 neuropathy phenotype and outcome defined from 105 cases. Neurology. 2018;90:e103–e110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29222126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen DS, Mellman I. Oncology meets immunology: the cancer-immunity cycle. Immunity. 2013;39:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23890059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKeon A, Pittock SJ. Paraneoplastic encephalomyelopathies: pathology and mechanisms. Acta Neuropathol. 2011;122:381–400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21938556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grativvol RS, Cavalcante WCP, Castro LHM, Nitrini R, Simabukuro MM. Updates in the Diagnosis and Treatment of Paraneoplastic Neurologic Syndromes. Curr Oncol Rep. 2018;20:92. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30415318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corsini E, Gaviani P, Chiapparini L, Lazzaroni M, Ciusani E, Bisogno R, et al.  Intrathecal synthesis of onconeural antibodies in patients with paraneoplastic syndromes. J Neuroimmunol. 2016;290:119–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26711581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graus F, Delattre JY, Antoine JC, Dalmau J, Giometto B, Grisold W, et al.  Recommended diagnostic criteria for paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2004;75:1135–1140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15258215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Andrés C, Esquivel A, de Villoria JG, Graus F, Sánchez-Ramón S. Unusual magnetic resonance imaging and cerebrospinal fluid find ings in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: a sequential study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:562–563.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077528</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16543544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi KD, Kim JS, Park SH, Kim YK, Kim SE, Smitt PS. Cerebellar hypermetabolism in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77:525–528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077501</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16543536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitoma H, Hadjivassiliou M, Honnorat J. Guidelines for treatment of immune-mediated cerebellar ataxias. Cerebellum Ataxias. 2015;2:14. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641375</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26561527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipka AF, Verschuuren JJ, Titulaer MJ. SOX1 antibodies in Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome and screening for small cell lung carcinoma. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2012;1275:70–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23278580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paz-Ares L, Chen Y, Reinmuth N, Hotta K, Trukhin D, Statsenko G, et al.  PL02.11 Overall survival with durvalumab plus etoposide-platinum in first-line extensive-stage SCLC: results from the CASPIAN study. J Thorac Oncol. 2019;14:S7–S8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le May M, Dent S. Anti-Yo antibody-mediated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with cognitive affective syndrome in a patient with breast cancer: a case report and literature review. Curr Oncol. 2018;25:e585–e591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6291278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finsterer J, Voigtländer T, Grisold W. Deterioration of anti-Yo-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neurol Sci. 2011;308:139–141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21762925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debes JD, Lagarde SM, Hulsenboom E, Sillevis Smitt PA, ten Kate FJ, Sulter GA, et al.  Anti-Yo-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a man with adenocarcinoma of the gastroesophageal junction. Dig Surg. 2007;24:395–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17785986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meglic B, Graus F, Grad A. Anti-Yo-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a man with gastric adenocarcinoma. J Neurol Sci. 2001;185:135–138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11311295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sutton IJ, Fursdon Davis CJ, Esiri MM, Hughes S, Amyes ER, Vincent A. Anti-Yo antibodies and cerebellar degeneration in a man with adenocarcinoma of the esophagus. Ann Neurol. 2001;49:253–257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11220746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matschke J, Kromminga A, Erbersdobler A, Lamszus K, Anders S, Köfüncü E. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and anti-Yo antibodies in a man with prostatic adenocarcinoma. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:775–777.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2117687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17189300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanriverdi O, Meydan N, Barutca S, Ozsan N, Gurel D, Veral A. Anti-Yo antibody-mediated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a female patient with pleural malignant mesothelioma. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2013;43:563–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23475537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirouse A, Gobert D, Chamouard JM, Iordache L, Mekinian A, Fain O. Sudden death occurring after anti-Hu associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and dysautonomia revealing a small cell lung carcinoma. Rev Med Interne. 2014;35:757–759.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24411475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storstein A, Raspotnig M, Vitaliani R, Giometto B, Graus F, Grisold W, et al.  Prostate cancer, Hu antibodies and paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. J Neurol. 2016;263:1001–1007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27007485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsukamoto T, Mochizuki R, Mochizuki H, Noguchi M, Kayama H, Hiwatashi M, et al.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and limbic encephalitis in a patient with adenocarcinoma of the colon. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1993;56:713–716.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC489629</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8509793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de la Sayette V, Bertran F, Honnorat J, Schaeffer S, Iglesias S, Defer G. Paraneoplastic cerebellar syndrome and optic neuritis with anti-CV2 antibodies: clinical response to excision of the primary tumor. Arch Neurol. 1998;55:405–408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9520015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honnorat J, Cartalat-Carel S, Ricard D, Camdessanche JP, Carpentier AF, Rogemond V, et al.  Onco-neural antibodies and tumour type determine survival and neurological symptoms in paraneoplastic neurological syndromes with Hu or CV2/CRMP5 antibodies. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80:412–416.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2664637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aliprandi A, Terruzzi A, Rigamonti A, Bazzigaluppi E, Tremolizzo L, Ferrarese C, et al.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with anti-CV2/CRMP5 antibodies and prostate adenocarcinoma. Neurol Sci. 2015;36:1501–1503.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25686614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brieva-Ruíz L, Diaz-Hurtado M, Matias-Guiu X, Márquez-Medina D, Tarragona J, Graus F. Anti-Ri-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and breast cancer: an autopsy case study. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2008;110:1044–1046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18701208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bazine A, Fetohi M, Berri MA, Oufroukhi Y, Ichou M, Errihani H. Occult breast carcinoma presenting with anti-Ri-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration revealed with FDG-PET. Cancer Clin Oncol. 2014;4:9–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mancuso M, Orsucci D, Bacci A, Caldarazzo Ienco E, Siciliano G. Anti-Ri-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Report of a case and revision of the literature. Arch Ital Biol. 2011;149:318–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22028093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ameneiros-Lago E, Fernández-Fernández FJ, Lijó-Carballeda C. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with anti-Ma2 antibodies. Med Clin (Barc) 2016;147:e55–e56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27650210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bataller L, Wade DF, Graus F, Stacey HD, Rosenfeld MR, Dalmau J. Antibodies to Zic4 in paraneoplastic neurologic disorders and smallcell lung cancer. Neurology. 2004;62:778–782.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2574539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15007130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabater L, Bataller L, Suárez-Calvet M, Saiz A, Dalmau J, Graus F. ZIC antibodies in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and small cell lung cancer. J Neuroimmunol. 2008;201-202:163–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2582201</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18639938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavolucci L, Giannini G, Giannoccaro MP, Foschini MP, Lang B, Avoni P, et al.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and lambert-eaton myasthenia in a patient with merkel cell carcinoma and voltage-gated calcium channel antibodies. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56:998–1000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28006860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang C, Emery L, Lancaster E. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with noncutaneous Merkel cell carcinoma. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2014;1:e17. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4202670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25340069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sillevis Smitt P, Kinoshita A, De Leeuw B, Moll W, Coesmans M, Jaarsma D, et al.  Paraneoplastic cerebellar ataxia due to autoantibodies against a glutamate receptor. N Engl J Med. 2000;342:21–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10620645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lancaster E, Lai M, Peng X, Hughes E, Constantinescu R, Raizer J, et al.  Antibodies to the GABA(B) receptor in limbic encephalitis with seizures: case series and characterisation of the antigen. Lancet Neurol. 2010;9:67–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19962348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
