<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">33085412</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK563265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630">Subglottic Stenosis</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jagpal</LastName><ForeName>Nitish</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nassau University Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shabbir</LastName><ForeName>Nadeem</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nassau University Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Subglottic stenosis can be defined as the narrowing of the upper airway, which lies between the vocal folds and the lower border of the cricoid cartilage. Normally, the subglottic lumen is 4.5 mm to 5.5 mm in a full-term neonate, while a 3.5 mm lumen is normal in a premature neonate. A subglottic diameter of 4 mm or less in a full-term neonate is considered as narrow. Causes of subglottic stenosis can be either congenital, acquired, or idiopathic<b>. </b>In congenital subglottic stenosis, there is no history of endotracheal intubation or any other acquired cause of the stenosis. A rare genetic disorder called Pallister Killian syndrome is caused by tetrasomy 12p mosaicism and presents phenotypically with multisystem morphologic defects involving the respiratory system and progressive subglottic stenosis.  Acquired subglottic stenosis is more common than congenital due to the introduction of prolonged intubation in the 1960s, and it does not improve with time. Avoidance of tracheostomy in patients with subglottic stenosis is paramount and this is possible by advances in balloon dilation and endoscopic cricoid split techniques. Tracheostomy decannulation can be more likely with laryngotracheal reconstruction and cricotracheal resection. Idiopathic subglottic stenosis is very rare and is characterized by circumferential stenosis in the subglottic region and upper trachea. A single-stage laryngotracheal resection and reconstruction are the preferred definitive treatment for idiopathic subglottic stenosis. Signs and symptoms range from recurrent croup and exertional stridor to complete airflow obstruction requiring tracheostomy.  Symptoms of idiopathic subglottic stenosis can be misinterpreted as asthma. When asthma medication fails to treat symptoms, the patient is diagnosed with an endoscopic evaluation. Depending on the severity of the stenosis, the treatment can involve Grillo’s technique, cricoplasty, or a combination of resection and enlargement techniques using rib cartilage grafts.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s6">Histopathology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s7">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s8">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s9">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s10">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s11">Staging</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s12">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s13">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s14">Consultations</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s15">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s16">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s17">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29630" sec="article-29630.s18">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shiohama T, Fujii K, Shimizu K, Ohashi H, Takatani T, Okamoto N, Nishimura G, Kato M, Shimojo N. Progressive subglottic stenosis in a child with Pallister-Killian syndrome. Congenit Anom (Kyoto) 2018 May;58(3):102-104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28745802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axtell AL, Mathisen DJ. Idiopathic subglottic stenosis: techniques and results. Ann Cardiothorac Surg. 2018 Mar;7(2):299-305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5900086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29707509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marston AP, White DR. Subglottic Stenosis. Clin Perinatol. 2018 Dec;45(4):787-804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30396418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanlon K, Boesch RP, Jacobs I. Subglottic Stenosis. Curr Probl Pediatr Adolesc Health Care. 2018 Apr;48(4):129-135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29801771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoetzenecker K, Schweiger T, Klepetko W. [Idiopathic Progressive Subglottic Stenosis: Surgical Techniques]. Zentralbl Chir. 2016 Sep;141 Suppl 1:S12-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27607884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walner DL, Loewen MS, Kimura RE. Neonatal subglottic stenosis--incidence and trends. Laryngoscope. 2001 Jan;111(1):48-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11192899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aravena C, Almeida FA, Mukhopadhyay S, Ghosh S, Lorenz RR, Murthy SC, Mehta AC. Idiopathic subglottic stenosis: a review. J Thorac Dis. 2020 Mar;12(3):1100-1111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7139051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32274178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajose-Popoola O, Su E, Hamamoto A, Wang A, Jing JC, Nguyen TD, Chen JJ, Osann KE, Chen Z, Ahuja GS, Wong BJ. Diagnosis of subglottic stenosis in a rabbit model using long-range optical coherence tomography. Laryngoscope. 2017 Jan;127(1):64-69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5326617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27559721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah A, Alrabiah A, Habib SS, Aljathlany Y, Aljasser A, Bukhari M, Al-Ammar AY. The Value of Spirometry in Subglottic Stenosis. Ear Nose Throat J. 2019 Feb;98(2):98-101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30885002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feinstein AJ, Goel A, Raghavan G, Long J, Chhetri DK, Berke GS, Mendelsohn AH. Endoscopic Management of Subglottic Stenosis. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2017 May 01;143(5):500-505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5824311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shabani S, Hoffman MR, Brand WT, Dailey SH. Endoscopic Management of Idiopathic Subglottic Stenosis. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol. 2017 Feb;126(2):96-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27864505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damrose EJ, Manson L, Nekhendzy V, Collins J, Campbell R. Management of subglottic stenosis in pregnancy using advanced apnoeic ventilatory techniques. J Laryngol Otol. 2019 May;133(5):399-403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30975234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avelino M, Maunsell R, Jubé Wastowski I. Predicting outcomes of balloon laryngoplasty in children with subglottic stenosis. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2015 Apr;79(4):532-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25677564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guarisco JL, Yang CJ. Balloon dilation in the management of severe airway stenosis in children and adolescents. J Pediatr Surg. 2013 Aug;48(8):1676-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23932606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang J, Zhang Z, Zhang T. Tracheotomy-coblation for acquired subglottic tracheal stenosis: a case report. J Cardiothorac Surg. 2019 Jul 04;14(1):128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6610943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31272475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrissey MS, Bailey CM. Diagnosis and management of subglottic stenosis after neonatal ventilation. Arch Dis Child. 1990 Oct;65(10):1103-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1792352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2248497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sittel C. [Pathologies of the larynx and trachea in childhood]. Laryngorhinootologie. 2014 Mar;93 Suppl 1:S70-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24710786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linna O, Hyrynkangas K, Lanning P, Nieminen P. Central airways stenosis in school-aged children: differential diagnosis from asthma. Acta Paediatr. 2002;91(4):399-402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12061354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumoulin E, Stather DR, Gelfand G, Maranda B, Maceachern P, Tremblay A. Idiopathic subglottic stenosis: a familial predisposition. Ann Thorac Surg. 2013 Mar;95(3):1084-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23438539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyduck A, Pickhard A, Brosch S, Hoffmann TK, Reiter R. [Subglottic pathologies]. Laryngorhinootologie. 2019 Jul;98(7):461-472.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hseu AF, Benninger MS, Haffey TM, Lorenz R. Subglottic stenosis: a ten-year review of treatment outcomes. Laryngoscope. 2014 Mar;124(3):736-41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24122779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quesnel AM, Lee GS, Nuss RC, Volk MS, Jones DT, Rahbar R. Minimally invasive endoscopic management of subglottic stenosis in children: success and failure. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2011 May;75(5):652-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21377219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto K, Monnier P, Holtz F, Jaquet Y. Laryngotracheal reconstruction for pediatric glotto-subglottic stenosis. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2014 Sep;78(9):1476-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25022423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndoro S. Effective multidisciplinary working: the key to high-quality care. Br J Nurs. 2014 Jul 10-23;23(13):724-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25072333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Biju A, Wang S, Gao S, Irfan O, Harrawood A, Martinez S, Brewer E, Perkins A, Unverzagt FW, Lasiter S, Zarzaur B, Rahman O, Boustani M, Khan B. Mobile critical care recovery program (m-CCRP) for acute respiratory failure survivors: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2018 Feb 07;19(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5803999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29415760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33085412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
