<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">33085287</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK563140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843">Phototherapy</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rathod</LastName><ForeName>Dipali G.</ForeName><Initials>DG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Board of Examinations, Delhi</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muneer</LastName><ForeName>Hira</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sandeman Provincial Hospital Quetta</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masood</LastName><ForeName>Sadia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aga Khan University Hospital karachi</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Phototherapy is a major effective therapeutic treatment modality in dermatology and has influenced the treatment of various skin diseases dramatically. It consists of a controlled administration of non-ionizing radiation to the skin in various dermatoses, which involves the ultraviolet part of the electromagnetic spectrum and commonly includes ultraviolet A (UVA) spectrum, ultraviolet A-1 (UVA-1) spectrum, UVA spectrum with a psoralene sensitizer (PUVA), and ultraviolet B (UVB) spectrum, i.e., broad-band (BB)-UVB, or narrow-band (NB)-UVB. The UVA spectrum is usually between 320 and 400nm, whereas UVA-1 (340-400nm) has longer wavelengths of UVA..  The UVB spectrum is between 280-320nm, which may be delivered as full-spectrum (broad-band UVB lamps 270-350nm, along with the shorter wavelengths from UVA spectrum) or delivered as small-spectrum (narrow-band UVB lamps 311-313nm). Few specialized types of phototherapy exist, that include lasers, photodynamic therapy (PDT), bath-PUVA, and extracorporeal photochemotherapy. Phototherapy is still the most frequently used treatment modality for different skin diseases, including parapsoriasis, psoriasis, pityriasis lichenoides chronica, eczema, atopic dermatitis, vitiligo, photodermatitis, polymorphous light eruption, actinic prurigo, hydroa vacciniforme,  cutaneous porphyrias, Mycosis fungoides, and many others. UVB phototherapy has different properties like anti-inflammatory, immunosuppressive, and cytotoxic. The mechanisms of its action are unclear but include the induction of <i>cis</i>-urocanic acid, Langerhans cell depletion, altered antigen presentation, decreased activity of natural killer(NK) cells, and apoptosis of T lymphocytes and keratinocytes. The mechanisms of action of PUVA include the cross-linking of DNA through psoralen photoadducts, DNA replication inhibition, depletion of Langerhans cell, and immunosuppressive effects on T-lymphocyte function and migration.UVA-1 phototherapy penetrates deeper into the dermis, and it induces interstitial collagenase and cytokines, resulting in the softening of the sclerotic skin. Photopheresis results in dendritic cells acquiring antigen from apoptotic lymphocytes, which elicit a specific immune response without causing systemic immunosuppression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s3">Indications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s4">Contraindications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s5">Equipment</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s6">Preparation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s7">Technique</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s8">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s9">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s10">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s11">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Interventions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s12">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Monitoring</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s13">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-114843" sec="article-114843.s14">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abel EA. Phototherapy. Dermatol Clin. 1995 Oct;13(4):841-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8785888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad S, Coias J, Chen HW, Jacobe H. Utilizing UVA-1 Phototherapy. Dermatol Clin. 2020 Jan;38(1):79-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guitart J. Psoralen Plus UV-A Therapy in the 21st Century: Use It or Lose It. JAMA Dermatol. 2019 May 01;155(5):529-531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell J. Safe and effective use of phototherapy and photochemotherapy in the treatment of psoriasis. Br J Nurs. 2020 May 28;29(10):547-552.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32463760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atci T, Baykal C. Efficacy of narrow-band ultraviolet-B therapy in patch-stage mycosis fungoides: A clinical study and review of the literature. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2020 Jul;36(4):271-277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32145109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Yang M, Cheng Y, Liu GJ, Zhang M. Narrow-band ultraviolet B phototherapy versus broad-band ultraviolet B or psoralen-ultraviolet A photochemotherapy for psoriasis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2013 Oct 23;(10):CD009481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24151011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara S, Mowla MR, Alam M, Khan I. Efficacy of oral methotrexate (MTX) monotherapy vs oral MTX plus narrowband ultraviolet light B phototherapy in palmoplantar psoriasis. Dermatol Ther. 2020 Jul;33(4):e13486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32356586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukumoto T, Nishiyama S, Oka M, Nishigori C. Implication of phototherapy for rare comorbidity of psoriasis and pemphigus foliaceus: Case report and review of literature. Dermatol Ther. 2020 Nov;33(6):e13889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32578319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunjan MK, Brockley JR, Buka R, Ramesh R. Treatment of paediatric eczema with narrowband ultraviolet light B therapy. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2021 Mar;37(2):105-110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33012054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marka A, Carter JB. Phototherapy for Cutaneous T-Cell Lymphoma. Dermatol Clin. 2020 Jan;38(1):127-135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang HC, Lin MH, Tsai HH. Efficacy of Combination Therapy With Fractional Carbon Dioxide Laser and Ultraviolet B Phototherapy for Vitiligo: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Aesthet Surg J. 2020 Jan 01;40(1):NP46-NP50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31605101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JY, Kim MH, Lee JH, Han HS, Seo SJ, Park KY, Park YM. Phototherapy May be a Useful Adjuvant Therapy for Retractable Chronic Spontaneous Urticaria: A Systematic Review. Photochem Photobiol. 2020 Jul;96(4):738-740.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32144786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh G, Latif I, Lone KS, Hassan I, Jabeen Y, Keen A. Role of Adjuvant Narrow Band Ultraviolet B Phototherapy in the Treatment of Chronic Urticaria. Indian J Dermatol. 2019 May-Jun;64(3):250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31148870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juarez MC, Grossberg AL. Phototherapy in the Pediatric Population. Dermatol Clin. 2020 Jan;38(1):91-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson KG, Kim N. Distinguishing Myth from Fact: Photocarcinogenesis and Phototherapy. Dermatol Clin. 2020 Jan;38(1):25-35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31753190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datz E, Zeman F, Koller M, Szeimies RM, Berneburg M, Landthaler M, Bosserhoff AK, Karrer S. Phototherapy-induced elevation of serum level of melanoma inhibitory activity. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2019 Jul;35(4):255-260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30815924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33085287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
