<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33139547</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1091-6490</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>117</Volume>
            <Issue>46</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Geographies of insecure water access and the housing-water nexus in US cities.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>28700</StartPage>
          <EndPage>28707</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>28700-28707</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1073/pnas.2007361117</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Safe, reliable, and equitable water access is critical to human health and livelihoods. In the United States, an estimated 471,000 households or 1.1 million individuals lack a piped water connection and 73% of households are located in cities, close to networked supply. In this study, we undertake a nationwide analysis of urban water access in the United States, with the aim of explaining the drivers of infrastructural inequality in the 50 largest metropolitan areas. Drawing on statistical analysis and regression modeling of census microdata at the household scale, our analysis reveals spatial and sociodemographic patterns of racialized, class-based, and housing disparities that characterize plumbing poverty. Among unplumbed households, we show that households headed by people of color are almost 35% more likely to lack piped water as compared to white, non-Hispanic households. Precarious housing conditions are an equally strong predictor: Renter-occupied households in the 50 largest US metros were 1.61 times more likely than owner-occupied households to lack piped water. We argue that insecure domestic water access in the United States should be understood as a housing issue that reflects structural inequalities of race and class, particularly in cities with widening wealth gaps. The article concludes with a call for research and action at the intersection of water provision, housing, and social inequality-a paradigm we call the housing-water nexus.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 the Author(s). Published by PNAS.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meehan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katie</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8330-4736</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Geography, King's College London, London WC2B 4BG, United Kingdom; katie.meehan@kcl.ac.uk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jurjevich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jason R</ForeName>
            <Initials>JR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8451-0539</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Geography, Development and Environment, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ 85721-0137.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas M J W</ForeName>
            <Initials>NMJW</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4153-9163</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Geography, Development and Environment, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ 85721-0137.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sherrill</LastName>
            <ForeName>Justin</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9155-4951</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>ECONorthwest, Portland, OR 97201.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7505876</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0027-8424</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006798" MajorTopicYN="N">Housing</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016015" MajorTopicYN="N">Logistic Models</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000085222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Insecurity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014881" MajorTopicYN="Y">Water Supply</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cities</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">household water insecurity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">housing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">infrastructure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">sustainability</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33139547</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682390</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2007361117</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">2007361117</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNESCO World Water Assessment Programme , “The United Nations world water development report 2019: Leaving no one behind” (UNESCO, 2019). https://en.unesco.org/themes/water-security/wwap/wwdr/2019. Accessed 15 October 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wutich A., Brewis A., Food, water, and scarcity: Toward a broader anthropology of resource insecurity. Curr. Anthropol.
55, 444–468 (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosinger A. Y., Brewis A., Life and death: Toward a human biology of water. Am. J. Hum. Biol.
32, e23361 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31782854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadley C., Freeman M. C., Assessing reliability, change after intervention, and performance of a water insecurity scale in rural Ethiopia. Food Secur.
8, 855–864 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosinger A. Y., Household water insecurity after a historic flood: Diarrhea and dehydration in the Bolivian Amazon. Soc. Sci. Med.
197, 192–202 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29253721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams E. A., Stoler J., Adams Y., Water insecurity and urban poverty in the Global South: Implications for health and human biology. Am. J. Hum. Biol.
32, e23368 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31769124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wutich A., Intrahousehold disparities in women and men’s experiences of water insecurity and emotional distress in urban Bolivia. Med. Anthropol. Q.
23, 436–454 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20092053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewis A., Choudhary N., Wutich A., Household water insecurity may influence common mental disorders directly and indirectly through multiple pathways: Evidence from Haiti. Soc. Sci. Med. 1982
238, 112520 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31473576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sultana F., Suffering for water, suffering from water: Emotional geographies of resource access, control and conflict. Geoforum
42, 163–172 (2011).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wutich A., Ragsdale K., Water insecurity and emotional distress: Coping with supply, access, and seasonal variability of water in a Bolivian squatter settlement. Soc. Sci. Med.
67, 2116–2125 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18954928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevenson E. G. J., et al. , Water insecurity in 3 dimensions: An anthropological perspective on water and women’s psychosocial distress in Ethiopia. Soc. Sci. Med.
75, 392–400 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3394402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22575697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wutich A., Brewis A., Tsai A., Water and mental health. WIREs. Water
7, e1461 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosinger A. Y., Young S. L., The toll of household water insecurity on health and human biology: Current understandings and future directions. WIREs Water, e1468 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewis A., et al. , Community hygiene norm violators are consistently stigmatized: Evidence from four global sites and implications for sanitation interventions. Soc. Sci. Med.
220, 12–21 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30390470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prüss-Ustün A., et al. , Burden of disease from inadequate water, sanitation and hygiene for selected adverse health outcomes: An updated analysis with a focus on low- and middle-income countries. Int. J. Hyg. Environ. Health
222, 765–777 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6593152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rusca M., Alda-Vidal C., Hordijk M., Kral N., Bathing without water, and other stories of everyday hygiene practices and risk perception in urban low-income areas: The case of Lilongwe, Malawi. Environ. Urban.
29, 533–550 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staddon C., et al. , Water insecurity compounds the global coronavirus crisis. Water Int.
45, 416–422 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connolly C., Keil R., Ali S. H., Extended urbanisation and the spatialities of infectious disease: Demographic change, infrastructure and governance. Urban Stud., 10.1177/0042098020910873 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0042098020910873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meehan K., et al. , Exposing the myths of household water insecurity in the global North: A critical review. WIREs. Water, 10.1002/wat2.1486 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wat2.1486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pauli B. J., Flint Fights Back: Environmental Justice and Democracy in the Flint Water Crisis (MIT Press, 2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jepson W., Vandewalle E., Household water insecurity in the global North: A study of rural and periurban settlements on the Texas–Mexico border. Prof. Geogr.
68, 66–81 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jepson W., Measuring “no-win” waterscapes: Experience-based scales and classification approaches to assess household water security in colonias on the US–Mexico border. Geoforum
51, 107–120 (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patrick R. J., Uneven access to safe drinking water for first nations in Canada: Connecting health and place through source water protection. Health Place
17, 386–389 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21074479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deitz S., Meehan K., Plumbing poverty: Mapping hot spots of racial and geographic inequality in U.S. household water insecurity. Ann. Am. Assoc. Geogr.
109, 1092–1109 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balazs C., Morello-Frosch R., Hubbard A., Ray I., Social disparities in nitrate-contaminated drinking water in California’s San Joaquin Valley. Environ. Health Perspect.
119, 1272–1278 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3230390</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21642046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wescoat J. L., Headington L., Theobald R., Water and poverty in the United States. Geoforum
38, 801–814 (2007).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mack E. A., Wrase S., A burgeoning crisis? A nationwide assessment of the geography of water affordability in the United States. PLoS One
12, e0169488 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5226794</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28076374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balazs C. L., Morello-Frosch R., Hubbard A. E., Ray I., Environmental justice implications of arsenic contamination in California’s San Joaquin valley: A cross-sectional, cluster-design examining exposure and compliance in community drinking water systems. Environ. Health
11, 84 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3533865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23151087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>London J., et al. , The Struggle for Water Justice in California’s San Joaquin Valley: A Focus on Disadvantaged Unincorporated Communities (University of California Davis Center for Regional Change, 2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierce G., Jimenez S., Unreliable water access in U.S. mobile homes: Evidence from the American housing survey. Hous. Policy Debate
25, 739–753 (2015).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierce G., Gonzalez S. R., Public drinking water system coverage and its discontents: The prevalence and severity of water access problems in California’s mobile home parks. Environ. Justice
10, 168–173 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Speer J., The right to infrastructure: A struggle for sanitation in Fresno, California homeless encampments. Urban Geogr.
37, 1049–1069 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meehan K., Disciplining de facto development: Water theft and hydrosocial order in Tijuana. Environ. Plan. Soc. Space
31, 319–336 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeMyers C., Warpinski C., Wutich A., Urban water insecurity: A case study of homelessness in Phoenix, Arizona. Environ. Justice
10, 72–80 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hale M. R., Fountains for environmental justice: Public water, homelessness, and migration in the face of global environmental change. Environ. Justice
12, 33–40 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doyle M. W., et al. , Environmental science. Aging infrastructure and ecosystem restoration. Science
319, 286–287 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18202277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teodoro M. P., Water and sewer affordability in the United States. AWWA Water Sci.
1, e1129 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fedinick K. P., Wu M., Olson E. D., “Threats on tap: Widespread violations highlight need for investment in water infrastructure and protections” (The Natural Resources Defense Council). https://www.nrdc.org/resources/threats-tap-widespread-violations-water-infrastructure. Accessed 15 October 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Switzer D., Teodoro M. P., Class, race, ethnicity, and justice in safe drinking water compliance. Soc. Sci. Q.
99, 524–535 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pulido L., Flint, environmental racism, and racial capitalism. Capitalism Nat. Socialism
27, 1–16 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranganathan M., Thinking with flint: Racial liberalism and the roots of an American water tragedy. Capitalism Nat. Socialism
27, 17–33 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadler R. C., Highsmith A. R., Rethinking tiebout: The contribution of political fragmentation and racial/economic segregation to the flint water crisis. Environ. Justice
9, 143–151 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wutich A., et al. , Advancing methods for research on household water insecurity: Studying entitlements and capabilities, socio-cultural dynamics, and political processes, institutions and governance. Water Secur.
2, 1–10 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5844501</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29532811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leker H. G., MacDonald Gibson J., Relationship between race and community water and sewer service in North Carolina, USA. PLoS One
13, e0193225 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5862451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29561859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald Gibson J., DeFelice N., Sebastian D., Leker H., Racial disparities in access to community water supply service in wake County, North Carolina. Am. J. Public Health
104, e45 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balazs C. L., Ray I., The drinking water disparities framework: On the origins and persistence of inequities in exposure. Am. J. Public Health
104, 603–611 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4025716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24524500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jepson W., et al. , Advancing human capabilities for water security: A relational approach. Water Secur.
1, 46–52 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothstein R., The Color of Law: A Forgotten History of How Our Government Segregated America (Liveright Publishing Corporation, 2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mule T., “2010 census coverage measurement estimation report: Summary of estimates of coverage for persons in the United States” (US Census Bureau, 2012). https://www2.census.gov/programs-surveys/decennial/2010/technical-documentation/methodology/g-series/g01.pdf. Accessed 15 October 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>US Department of Housing and Urban Development , “HUD 2019 continuum of care: Homeless assistance programs homeless populations and subpopulations” (2019). https://www.hudexchange.info/programs/coc/coc-homeless-populations-and-subpopulations-reports/. Accessed 15 October 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fields D., Constructing a new asset class: Property-led financial accumulation after the crisis. Econ. Geogr.
94, 118–140 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fields D., Kohli R., Schafran A., The Emerging Economic Geography of Single-Family Rental Securitization (Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco, Community Development Investment Center, 2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meehan K., Jurjevich J. R., Chun N. M. J. W., Sherrill J., Metropolitan geographic definitions and codes for “Geographies of urban water access and infrastructural inequality in US cities.” University of Arizona Research Data Repository. 10.25422/azu.data.12456536.v2. Deposited 24 September 2020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25422/azu.data.12456536.v2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plane D. A., Rogerson P., The Geographical Analysis of Population: With Applications to Planning and Business (Wiley, 1994).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teodoro M. P., Measuring household affordability for water and sewer utilities: Measuring household affordability for water and sewer utilities. J. Am. Water Works Assoc.
110, 13–24 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jurjevich J. R., et al. , Navigating statistical uncertainty: How urban and regional planners understand and work with American community survey (ACS) data for guiding policy. J. Am. Plann. Assoc.
84, 112–126 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
