<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33179247</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2020</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>11</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Rufinamide add-on therapy for drug-resistant epilepsy.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>CD011772</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>CD011772</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD011772</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD011772.pub3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Epilepsy is a central nervous system disorder (neurological disorder). Epileptic seizures are the result of excessive and abnormal cortical nerve cell electrical activity in the brain. Despite the development of more than 10 new antiepileptic drugs (AEDs) since the early 2000s, approximately a third of people with epilepsy remain resistant to pharmacotherapy, often requiring treatment with a combination of AEDs. In this review, we summarised the current evidence regarding rufinamide, a novel anticonvulsant medication, which, as a triazole derivative, is structurally unrelated to any other currently used anticonvulsant medication when used as an add-on treatment for drug-resistant epilepsy. In January 2009, rufinamide was approved by the US Food and Drug Administration for the treatment of children four years of age and older with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. It is also approved as an add-on treatment for adults and adolescents with focal seizures. This is an updated version of the original Cochrane Review published in 2018.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of rufinamide when used as an add-on treatment for people with drug-resistant epilepsy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">We imposed no language restrictions. We contacted the manufacturers of rufinamide and authors in the field to identify any relevant unpublished studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">Randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, add-on trials of rufinamide, recruiting people (of any age or gender) with drug-resistant epilepsy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">Two review authors independently selected trials for inclusion and extracted the relevant data. We assessed the following outcomes: 50% or greater reduction in seizure frequency (primary outcome); seizure freedom; treatment withdrawal; and adverse effects (secondary outcomes). Primary analyses were intention-to-treat (ITT) and we presented summary risk ratios (RRs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs). We evaluated dose response in regression models. We carried out a risk of bias assessment for each included study using the Cochrane 'Risk of bias' tool and assessed the overall certainty of evidence using the GRADE approach.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">The review included six trials, representing 1759 participants. Four trials (1563 participants) included people with uncontrolled focal seizures. Two trials (196 participants) included individuals with established Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Overall, the age of adults ranged from 18 to 80 years and the age of children ranged from 4 to 16 years. Baseline phases ranged from 28 to 56 days and double-blind phases from 84 to 96 days. Five of the six included trials described adequate methods of concealment of randomisation, and only three described adequate blinding. All analyses were by ITT. Overall, five studies were at low risk of bias and one had unclear risk of bias due to lack of reported information around study design. All trials were sponsored by the manufacturer of rufinamide and therefore were at high risk of funding bias. The overall RR for 50% or greater reduction in seizure frequency was 1.79 (95% CI 1.44 to 2.22; 6 randomised controlled trials (RCTs), 1759 participants; moderate-certainty evidence), indicating that rufinamide (plus conventional AED) was significantly more effective than placebo (plus conventional AED) in reducing seizure frequency by at least 50% when added to conventionally used AEDs in people with drug-resistant focal epilepsy. Data from only one study (73 participants) reported seizure freedom: RR 1.32 (95% CI 0.36 to 4.86; 1 RCT, 73 participants; moderate-certainty evidence). The overall RR for treatment withdrawal (for any reason and due to AED) was 1.83 (95% CI 1.45 to 2.31; 6 RCTs, 1759 participants; moderate-certainty evidence), showing that rufinamide was significantly more likely to be withdrawn than placebo. Most adverse effects were significantly more likely to occur in the rufinamide-treated group. Adverse events significantly associated with rufinamide were headache, dizziness, somnolence, vomiting, nausea, fatigue, and diplopia. The RRs for these adverse effects were as follows: headache 1.36 (95% Cl 1.08 to 1.69; 3 RCTs, 1228 participants; high-certainty evidence); dizziness 2.52 (95% Cl 1.90 to 3.34; 3 RCTs, 1295 participants; moderate-certainty evidence); somnolence 1.94 (95% Cl 1.44 to 2.61; 6 RCTs, 1759 participants; moderate-certainty evidence); vomiting 2.95 (95% Cl 1.80 to 4.82; 4 RCTs, 777 participants; low-certainty evidence); nausea 1.87 (95% Cl 1.33 to 2.64; 3 RCTs, 1295 participants; moderate-certainty evidence); fatigue 1.46 (95% Cl 1.08 to 1.97; 3 RCTs, 1295 participants; moderate-certainty evidence); and diplopia 4.60 (95% Cl 2.53 to 8.38; 3 RCTs, 1295 participants; low-certainty evidence). There was no important heterogeneity between studies for any outcomes. Overall, we assessed the evidence as moderate to low certainty due to wide CIs and potential risk of bias from some studies contributing to the analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">For people with drug-resistant focal epilepsy, rufinamide when used as an add-on treatment was effective in reducing seizure frequency. However, the trials reviewed were of relatively short duration and provided no evidence for long-term use of rufinamide. In the short term, rufinamide as an add-on was associated with several adverse events. This review focused on the use of rufinamide in drug-resistant focal epilepsy, and the results cannot be generalised to add-on treatment for generalised epilepsies. Likewise, no inference can be made about the effects of rufinamide when used as monotherapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Panebianco</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mariangela</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Pharmacology, Institute of Translational Medicine, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prabhakar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hemanshu</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroanaesthesiology and Critical Care, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anthony G</ForeName>
            <Initials>AG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Clinical Pharmacology, Institute of Translational Medicine, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Walton Centre NHS Foundation Trust, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Liverpool Health Partners, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT00334958</AccessionNumber>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT01146951</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014230">Triazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>WFW942PR79</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C079703">rufinamide</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf">
          <RefSource>Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018 Apr 25;4:CD011772</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">29691835</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015982" MajorTopicYN="N">Bias</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069279" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Resistant Epilepsy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014230" MajorTopicYN="N">Triazoles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>MP: none known. HP: none known. AGM: is funded in part by the National Institute for Health Research Applied Research Collaboration North West Coast (NIHR ARC NWC). A consortium of pharmaceutical companies (GSK, EISAI, UCB Pharma) funded the National Audit of Seizure Management in Hospitals (NASH) through grants paid to University of Liverpool. .</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33179247</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8094157</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011772.pub3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies included in this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Biton 2011 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Biton V, Krauss G, Vasquez-Santana B, Bibbiani F, Mann A, Perdomo C, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel-group study of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy for refractory partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia 2011;52(2):234-42. [DOI: 10.1111/j.1528-1167.2010.02729.x] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2010.02729.x</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20887365</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 2009 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Aldenkamp AP, Alpherts WCJ. The effect of the new antiepileptic drug rufinamide on cognitive functions. Epilepsia 2006;47(7):1153-9. [DOI: 10.1111/j.1528-1167.2006.00589.x] [ISSN: 0013-9580] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2006.00589.x</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16886978</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Rosenfeld W, Vasquez B, Sachdeo R, Ko D, Perdomo C, et al. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy in adult patients with inadequately controlled partial seizures. Epilepsia 2005;46 Suppl 8:171, Abstract no: 2.239. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Rosenfeld W, Vazquez B, Sachdeo R, Perdomo C, Mann A, et al. Rufinamide for the adjunctive treatment of partial seizures in adults and adolescents: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Epilepsia 2009;50(8):1899-909. [DOI: 10.1111/j.1528-1167.2009.02160.x] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2009.02160.x</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19490053</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rosenfeld W, Brodie M, Vazquez B, Sachdeo R, Ko D, Perdomo C, et al. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy in adult patients with inadequately controlled partial seizures. Epilepsia 2006;47 Suppl 3:140, Abstract no: p538. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Vazquez BR, Sachdeo R, Maxoutova AL, Beydoun A, Karolchyk MA, Mesenbrink PG. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy in adult patients with therapy-resistant partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia 2000;41 Suppl 7:255, Abstract no: L.09. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Elger 2010 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Elger C, Stefan H, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Dose-range relationships of rufinamide in patients with inadequately controlled partial seizures. Epilepsia 2005;46 Suppl 8:83-4, Abstract no: 1.201. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Elger C, Stefan H, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Dose-range relationships of rufinamide in patients with inadequately controlled partial seizures. Epilepsia 2006;47 Suppl 3:140, Abstract no: p539. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Elger CE, Stefan H, Mann A, Narurkar M, Sun Y, Perdomo C. A 24-week multicenter, randomized, double-blind, parallel-group, dose ranging study of rufinamide in adults and adolescents with inadequately controlled partial seizures. Epilepsy Research 2010;88(2-3):255-63. [DOI: 10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2009.12.003] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2009.12.003</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20061123</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Stefan H, Remy C, Guberman A, Thomson A, De Arbelaiz R, Karolchyk MA. A multicenter double-blind randomized placebo-controlled 5-arm, parallel-group trial of rufinamide in patients with therapy-resistant partial seizures. Epilepsia 2000;41 Suppl Florence:39. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Glauser 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Arzimanoglou A, Litzinger M, Frank LM, Vigevano F, Perdomo C. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy for inadequately controlled partial seizures in pediatric patients. Epilepsia 2005;46 Suppl 8:194-5. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Glauser 2008 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Krauss G, Arroyo S. Effects of rufinamide on the frequency of different seizure types in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a long-term study. Epilepsia 2007;48 Suppl 7:156, Abstract no: p415. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Sachdeo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Rufinamide for generalized seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome. Neurology 2008;70(21):1950-8. [DOI: 10.1212/01.wnl.0000303813.95800.0d] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000303813.95800.0d</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401024</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Sachdeo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Short-term and long-term efficacy and safety of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy in patients with inadequately controlled Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Annals of Neurology 2005;58 Suppl 9:S92, Abstract no: M15. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Sachedo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide adjunctive therapy in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (LGS): a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, parallel trial. Neurology 2005;64(10):1826, Abstract no: LBS.001. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Santana BV, Wang W, Narurkar M. Early and sustained response to rufinamide as adjunctive therapy for seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2009;50 Suppl 11:261, Abstract no: 2.229. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kluger G, Glauser T, Sachdeo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Short-term and long-term efficacy and safety of rufinamide as adjunctive therapy in patients with inadequately controlled Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2006;47 Suppl 3:139, Abstract no: p537. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Krauss GL, Glauser T, Kluger G, Arroyo S. Long-term safety of rufinamide in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2007;48 Suppl 6:359, Abstract no: 3.303. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>McMurray R, Striano P. Treatment of adults with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: further analysis of efficacy and safety/tolerability of rufinamide. Neurology &amp; Therapy 2016;5(1):35-43. [DOI: ] [ISSN: 2193-8253 2193-6536] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4919131</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26861566</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ohtsuka 2014 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Long-term safety and seizure outcome in Japanese patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome receiving adjunctive rufinamide therapy: an open-label study following a randomized clinical trial. Epilepsy Research 2016;121:1-7. [DOI: 10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2016.01.002] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2016.01.002</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827266</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Rufinamide as an adjunctive therapy for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial in Japan. Epilepsy Research 2014;108(9):1627-36. [DOI: 10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.08.019] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.08.019</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25219353</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Benedict 2010 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Benedict A, Verdian L, Maclaine G. The cost effectiveness of rufinamide in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome in the UK. Pharmacoeconomics 2010;28(3):185-99. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20151724</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Biton 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Biton V, Sachdeo R, Rosenfeld W, Schachter S, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Efficacy and safety of adjunctive rufinamide in patients with inadequately controlled primary generalized tonic-clonic seizures. Epilepsia 2005;46(8):206. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Critchley 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Critchley D, Fuseau E, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic parameters of adjunctive rufinamide in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2005;46 Suppl 8:209. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kim 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kim SH, Eun SH, Kang HC, Kwon EJ, Byeon JH, Lee YM. Rufinamide as an adjuvant treatment in children with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Seizure 2012;21(4):288-91. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421185</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kluger 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kluger G, Bauer B. Role of rufinamide in the management of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (childhood epileptic encephalopathy). Neuropsychiatric Disease &amp; Treatment 2007;3(1):3-11. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654531</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19300535</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Knupp 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Knupp KG, Leister E, Coryell J, Nickels KC, Ryan N, Juarez-Colunga E, et al, Pediatric Epilepsy Research Consortium. Response to second treatment after initial failed treatment in a multicenter prospective infantile spasms cohort. Epilepsia 2016;57(11):1834-42. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5863234</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27615012</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lesser 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lesser RP, Biton V, Sackellares JC, Van Ness PC, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide monotherapy for treatment of patients with refractory partial seizures. Epilepsia 2005;46 Suppl 8:177-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Madeddu 2013 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Madeddu F, Moavero R, Battaglia D, Matricardi S, Coppola G, Balestri M. Efficacy of rufinamide in epileptic encephalopathies secondary to complex brain malformations. Bollettino - Lega Italiana Contro l'Epilessia 2013;145:278-80. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Palhagen 2001 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Palhagen S, Canger R, Henriksen O, Parys JA, Riviere ME, Karolchyk MA. Rufinamide: a double-blind, placebo-controlled proof of principle trial in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 2001;43(2):115-24. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11164700</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Racine 2000 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Racine A, Rouan MC, Chang SW, Yeh CM, Karolchyk MA. Population pharmacokinetics and drug-drug interactions of rufinamide in a multicenter, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, 5-arm parallel trial in patients with partial seizures on up to three concomitant antiepileptic drugs. Epilepsia 2000;41 Suppl:149-50. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Todorov 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Todorov A, Biton V, Krauss GL, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Efficacy and safety of high-versus low-dose rufinamide monotherapy in patients with inadequately controlled partial seizures. Epilepsia 2005;46 Suppl 8:218-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Xu 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Xu M, Ni Y, Zhou Y, He X, Li H, Chen H. Pharmacokinetics and tolerability of rufinamide following single and multiple oral doses and effect of food on pharmacokinetics in healthy Chinese subjects. European Journal of Drug Metabolism and Pharmacokinetics 2016;41(5):541-8. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26294172</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to ongoing studies</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Arzimanoglou 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Arzimanoglou A, Ferreira JA, Satlin A, Mendes S, Williams B, Critchley D, et al. Safety and pharmacokinetic profile of rufinamide in pediatric patients aged less than 4 years with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: an interim analysis from a multicenter, randomized, active-controlled, open-label study. European Journal of Paediatric Neurology: EJPN 2016;20(3):393-402. </Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26805435</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>Additional references</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Coppola 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Coppola G. Update on rufinamide in childhood epilepsy. Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment 2011;7:399-407.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3140292</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21792306</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>GRADEpro GDT [Computer program]</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hamilton (ON): McMaster University (developed by Evidence Prime) GRADEpro GDT. Hamilton (ON): McMaster University (developed by Evidence Prime), Version accessed 9 May 2019. Available at gradepro.org.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Granata 2009</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Granata T, Marchi N, Carlton E, Chosh C, Gonzalez-Martinez J, Alexopoulous A, et al. Management of the patient with medically refractory epilepsy. Expert Review of Neurotherapeutics 2009;9(12):1791-802.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761964</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19951138</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JPT, Green S (editors). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 [updated March 2011]. Available from www.handbook.cochrane.org edition. The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hsieh 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hsieh DT, Thiele EA. Efficacy and safety of rufinamide in pediatric epilepsy. Therapeutic Advances in Neurological Disorders 2013;6(3):189-98.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3625016</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23634191</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>ILAE Commission on Epidemiology and Prognosis 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ILAE Commission on Epidemiology and Prognosis. Guidelines for epidemiologic studies on epilepsy. Epilepsia 1993;34(4):592-6. [DOI: 10.1111/j.1528-1157.1993.tb00433.x] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1993.tb00433.x</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8330566</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kirkham 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kirkham JJ, Dwan KM, Altman DG, Gamble C, Dodd S, Smyth R, et al. The impact of outcome reporting bias in randomised controlled trials on a cohort of systematic reviews. BMJ 2010;340:c365. [DOI: 10.1136/bmj.c365] [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.c365</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20156912</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lefebvre 2019</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lefebvre C, Glanville J, Briscoe S, Littlewood A, Marshall C, Metzendorf M-I, et al. Technical Supplement to Chapter 4. Searching for and selecting studies. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston MS, Li T, Page MJ, et al (eds). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6. Cochrane, 2019. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/supplementary-materials.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Panebianco 2015a</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Panebianco M, Rigby A, Marson AG, Pulman J. Vagus nerve stimulation for partial seizures. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2015, Issue 4. Art. No: CD002896. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD002896.pub2]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002896.pub2</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7138043</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25835947</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Review Manager 2014 [Computer program]</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>The Cochrane Collaboration Review Manager 5 (RevMan 5). Version 5.3. Copenhagen, Nordic Cochrane Centre: The Cochrane Collaboration, 2014.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Schünemann 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schünemann H, Brożek J, Guyatt G, Oxman A, editor(s). Handbook for grading the quality of evidence and the strength of recommendations using the GRADE approach (updated October 2013). GRADE Working Group. Available from gdt.guidelinedevelopment.org/app/handbook/handbook.html.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sterne 2000</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sterne JA, Gavaghan D, Egger M. Publication and related bias in meta-analysis: power of statistical tests and prevalence in literature. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 2000;53(11):1119-29.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11106885</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wheless 2009</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wheless J, Conry J, Krauss G, Mann A, LoPresti A, Narurkar M. Safety and tolerability of rufinamide in children with epilepsy: a pooled analysis of seven clinical trials. Journal of Child Neurology 2009;50:1158-66.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955344</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wheless 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wheless JW, Vazquez B. Rufinamide: a novel broad-spectrum antiepileptic drug. Epilepsy Currents 2010;10(1):1-6.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2812713</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20126329</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Panebianco 2015b</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Panebianco M, Marson AG. Rufinamide add-on therapy for refractory epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2015, Issue 6. Art. No: CD011772. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011772]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011772</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494418</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691835</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Panebianco 2018</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Panebianco M, Prabhakar H, Marson AG. Rufinamide add-on therapy for refractory epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 4. Art. No: CD011772. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011772.pub2]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011772.pub2</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494418</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691835</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
