<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33207065</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1948-7134</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>45</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of vector ecology : journal of the Society for Vector Ecology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Vector Ecol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Molecular detection of Bartonella henselae, Bartonella clarridgeiae and Rickettsia felis in cat and dog fleas in Tenerife, Canary Islands, Spain.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>233</StartPage>
          <EndPage>240</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>233-240</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jvec.12394</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The cat flea Ctenocephalides felis is the main vector of Bartonella henselae and Bartonella clarridgeiae, the causative agents of cat-scratch disease (CSD) and the spotted-fever agent Rickettsia felis. In spite of their worldwide distribution, there are no data on the occurrence of CSD-causing Bartonella species or the prevalence of Rickettsia species in the Canary Islands, Spain. Therefore, the aim of our study was to screen cat and dog fleas for both pathogens. A total of 128 C. felis from cats and dogs were screened for Bartonella and Rickettsia by PCR. Bartonella henselae (2.3%) and B. clarridgeiae (3.9%) were found in fleas infesting cats, whereas R. felis was identified in both cat (36.6%) and dog (40.7%) fleas. Further, co-infections were observed. This work constitutes the first finding of CSD-causing Bartonella species and the first study on the prevalence of R. felis in fleas from domestic animals in the Canary Islands. These results indicate public health importance, as associated infections could be misdiagnosed in the Archipelago despite their clinical relevance. Establishing human and animal routine diagnosis procedures for these pathogens along with improving vector control in shelters is necessary in order to prevent the spread of the infections among animals.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 The Society for Vector Ecology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abreu-Yanes</LastName>
            <ForeName>Estefanía</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Universitario de Enfermedades Tropicales y Salud Pública de Canarias, Universidad de La Laguna. Avda. Astrofísico F. Sánchez, s/n, 38203, La Laguna, Canary Islands, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nertalab S.L. José Rodríguez Mouré, 38008, Santa Cruz de Tenerife, Canary Islands, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departament Obstetricia y Ginecología, Pediatría, Medicina Preventiva y Salud Pública, Toxicología, Medicina Legal y Forense y Parasitología, Universidad de La Laguna, 38203, La Laguna, Canary Islands, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abreu-Acosta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Néstor</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nertalab S.L. José Rodríguez Mouré, 38008, Santa Cruz de Tenerife, Canary Islands, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kosoy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>KB One Health LLC, Fort Collins, CO, 80521, U.S.A.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Foronda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pilar</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Universitario de Enfermedades Tropicales y Salud Pública de Canarias, Universidad de La Laguna. Avda. Astrofísico F. Sánchez, s/n, 38203, La Laguna, Canary Islands, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departament Obstetricia y Ginecología, Pediatría, Medicina Preventiva y Salud Pública, Toxicología, Medicina Legal y Forense y Parasitología, Universidad de La Laguna, 38203, La Laguna, Canary Islands, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Vector Ecol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9512496</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1081-1710</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000649393">Bartonella clarridgeiae</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001473" MajorTopicYN="N">Bartonella</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018416" MajorTopicYN="N">Bartonella henselae</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002415" MajorTopicYN="N">Cats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058251" MajorTopicYN="N">Ctenocephalides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010802" MajorTopicYN="N">Phylogeny</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D041161" MajorTopicYN="N">Rickettsia felis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013030" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Spain</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Bartonella clarridgeiae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Bartonella henselae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Canary Islands</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Ctenocephalides felis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Rickettsia felis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cat flea</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33207065</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jvec.12394</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES CITED</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbot, R.C., B.B. Chomel, R.W. Kasten, K.A. Floyd-Hawkins, Y. Kikuchi, J.E. Koehler, and N.C. Pedersen. 1997. Experimental and natural infection with Bartonella henselae in domestic cats. Comp. Immunol. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 20: 41-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abreu-Yanes, E., A. Martín-Alonso, N. Martín-Carrillo, K. García-Livia, A. Marrero-Gagliardi, B. Valladares, C. Feliu, and P. Foronda. 2018. Bartonella in rodents and ectoparasites in the Canary Islands, Spain: new insights into host-vector-pathogen relationships. Microb. Ecol. 75: 264-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson, B.E. and M.A. Neuman. 1997. Bartonella spp. as emerging human pathogen. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 10: 203-219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avidor, B., M. Graidy, G. Efrat, C. Leibowitz, G. Shapira, A. Schattner, O. Zimhony, and M. Giladi. 2004. Bartonella koehlerae, a new cat-associated agent of culture-negative human endocarditis. J. Clin. Microbiol. 42: 3462-3468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai, Y., M.F. Rizzo, D. Álvarez, D. Moran, L.F. Peruski, and M. Kosoy. 2015. Coexistence of Bartonella henselae and B. clarridgeiae in populations of cats and their fleas in Guatemala. J. Vector Ecol. 40: 327-332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhengsri, S., H.C. Baggett, S. Edouard, S.F. Dowell, G.A. Dasch, T.L. Fisk, D. Raoult, and P. Parola. 2016. Sennetsu neorickettsiosis, spotted fever group, and typhus group ricettsioses in three provinces in Thailand. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 95: 43-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanton, L.S. and D.H. Walker. 2017. Flea-borne rickettsioses and Rickettsiae. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 96: 53-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouchouicha, R., B. Durand, M. Monteil, B.B. Chomel, M. Berrich, M. Arvand, R.J. Birtles, E.B. Breitschwertd, J.E. Koehler, R. Maggi, S. Maruyama, R. Kasten, E. Petit, H.J. Boulouis, and N. Haddad. 2009. Molecular epidemiology of feline and human Bartonella henselae isolates. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 15: 813-816.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulouis, H.J., C.C. Chang, J.B. Henn, R.W. Kasten, and B.B. Chomel. 2005. Factors associated with the rapid emergence of zoonotic Bartonella infections. Vet. Res. 36: 383-410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouyer, D.H., J. Stenos, P. Crocquet-Valdes, C.G. Moron, V.L. Popov, J.E. Zavala-Velázquez, L.D. Foil, D.R. Stothard, A.F. Azad, and D.H. Walker. 2001. Rickettsia felis: molecular characterization of a new member of the spotted fever group. Int. J. Sys. Evol. Microbiol. 51: 339-347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt, E.B., R.G. Maggi, P.M. Lantos, C.W. Woods, B.C. Hegarty, and J.M. Bradley. 2010. Bartonella vinsonii subsp. berkhofﬁi and Bartonella henselae bacteremia in a father and daughter with neurological disease. Parasit. Vectors. 3: 29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cáceres, A.G., C.P. Padilla-Rojas, J. Arias-Stella, G. Huatuco-Crisanto, and A. González-Pérez. 2013. Detection of Bartonella spp. and Rickettsia spp. in fleas, ticks and lice collected in rural areas of Peru. Rev. Peru. Biol. 20: 165-169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chikeka, I. and J.S. Dumler. 2015. Neglected bacterial zoonoses. Clin. Microbiol. Infect. 21: 404-415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi, Y.J., W.J. Jang, J.H. Kim, J.S. Ryu, S.H. Lee, K.H. Park, H.S. Paik, Y.S. Koh, M.S. Choi, and I.S. Kim. 2005. Spotted fever group and Typhus group rickettsioses in humans, South Korea. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 11: 237-244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B.B., H.J. Boulouis, and E.B. Breitschwerdt. 2004. Cat scratch disease and other zoonotic Bartonella infections. J. Am. Vet. Med. Assoc. 224: 1270-1279.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B.B., H.J. Boulouis, S. Maruyama, and E.B. Breitschwerdt. 2006. Bartonella spp. in pets and effect on human health. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 12: 389-394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colborn, J.M., M.Y. Kosoy, V.L. Motin, M.V. Telepnev, G. Valbuena, K.S. Myint, Y. Fofanov, C. Putonti, C. Feng, and L. Peruski. 2010. Improved detection of Bartonella DNA in mammalian hosts and arthropod vectors by real-time PCR using the NADH dehydrogenase gamma subunit (nuoG). J. Clin. Microbiol. 48: 4630-4633.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foil, L., E. Andress, R.L. Freeland, A.F. Roy, R. Rutledge, P.C. Triche, and K.L. O'Reilly. 1998. Experimental infection of domestic cats with Bartonella henselae by inoculation of Ctenocephalides felis (Siphonaptera: Pulicidae) feces. J. Med. Entomol. 35:625-628.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedenberg, S.G., N. Balakrishnan, J. Guillaumin, E.S. Cooper, K. Lewis, D.S. Russell, and E.B. Breitschwerdt. 2015. Splenic vasculitis, thrombosis, and infarction in a febrile dog infected with Bartonella henselae. J. Vet. Emerg. Crit. Care (San Antonio). 25: 789-794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gil, H., R. Escudero, I. Pons, M. Rodríguez-Vargas, C. García-Esteban, I. Rodríguez-Moreno, C. García-Amil, B. Lobo, F. Valcárcel, A. Pérez, S. Jiménez, I. Jado, R. Juste, F. Segura, and P. Anda. 2013. Distribution of Bartonella henselae variants in patients, reservoir hosts and vectors in Spain. PLos One. 8: e68248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilles, J., F.T. Just, C. Silaghi, I. Pradel, L.M. Friche-Passos, H. Lengauer, K. Hellmann, and K. Pfister. 2008. Rickettsia felis in fleas, Germany. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 14: 1294-1296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giudice, E., S. Di Petro, A. Alaimo, V. Blanda, R. Lelli, F. Francaviglia, S. Caracappa, and A. Torina. 2014. A molecular survey of Rickettsia felis in fleas from cats and dogs in Sicily (southern Italy). PLos One. 9: e106820.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gracia, M.J., J.M. Marcén, R. Pinal, C. Calvete, and D. Rodes. 2015. Prevalence of Rickettsia and Bartonella species in Spanish cats and their fleas. J. Vector. Ecol. 40: 233-239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill, L., C.C. Wu, H. HogenEsch, L.N. Slater, N. Glickman, A. Dunham, H. Syme, and L. Glickman. 2004. Prevalence, risk factors and genetic diversity of Bartonella henselae infections in pet cats in four regions of the United States. J. Clin. Microbiol. 42: 652-659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gutiérrez, R., Y. Nachum-Biala, and S. Harrus. 2015. Relationship between the presence of Bartonella species and bacterial loads in cats and cat fleas (Ctenocephalides felis) under natural conditions. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 81: 5613-5621.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández-Cabrera, M., A. Ángel-Moreno, E. Santana, M. Bolaños, A. Francès, A.M. Martín-Sánchez, and J.L. Pérez-Arellano. 2004. Murine typhus with renal involvement in Canary Islands, Spain. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 10: 740-743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hii, S.F., S.R. Kopp, M.F. Thompson, C.A. O'Leary, R.L. Rees, and R.J. Traub. 2011. Molecular evidence of Rickettsia felis infection in dogs from Northern Territory, Australia. Parasites Vectors 4: 198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kernif, T., C. Socolovschi, K. Wells, M.B. Lakim, S. Inthalad, G. Slesak, N. Boudebouch, J.C. Beaucournu, P.N. Newton, D. Raoult, and P. Parola. 2012. Bartonella and Rickettsia in arthropods from the Lao PDR and from Borneo, Malaysia. Comp. Immunol. Microbiol. Infect. Dis. 35: 51-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klotz, S.A., V. Ianas, and S.P. Elliott. 2011. Cat-scratch disease. Am. Fam. Physician 83: 152-155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kordick, D.L., E.J. Hilyard, T.L. Hadfield, K.H. Wilson, A.G. Steigerwalt, D.J. Brenner, and E.B. Breitschwerdt. 1997. Bartonella clarridgeiae, a newly recognized zoonotic pathogen causing inoculation papules, fever, and limphadenopathy (cat scratch disease). J. Clin. Microbiol. 35: 1813-1818.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosoy, M.Y., R.L. Regnery, O.I. Kosaya, D.C. Jones, E.L. Marston, and J.E. Childs. 1998. Isolation of Bartonella spp. from embryons and neonates of naturally infected rodents. J. Wildl. Dis. 34: 305-309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosoy, M., D.T. Hayman, and K.S. Chan. 2012. Bartonella bacteria in nature: where does population variability end and species start? Infect. Genet. Evol. 12: 894-904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, S., G. Stecher, M. Li, C. Knyaz, and K. Tamura. 2018. MEGA X: Molecular evolutionary genetics analysis across computing platforms. Mol. Biol. Evol. 35: 1547-1549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labruna, M.B. and D.H. Walker. 2014. Rickettsia felis and changing paradigms about pathogenic Rickettsiae. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 20: 1768-1769.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lappin, M.R. and J. Hawley. 2009. Presence of Bartonella species and Rickettsia species DNA in the blood, oral cavity, skin and claw beds of cats in the United States. Vet. Dermatol. 20: 509-514.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawrence, A.L., G.K. Brown, B. Peters, D.S. Spielman, V. Morin-Adeline, and J. Slapeta. 2014. High phylogenetic diversity of the cat flea (Ctenocephalides felis) at two mitochondrial DNA markers. Vet. Med. Entomol. 28: 330-336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López, C., S. Clemente, C. Almeida, A. Brito, and M. Hernández. 2015. A genetic approach to the origin of Millepora sp. in the eastern Atlantic. Coral Reefs 34: 631-638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maguina, C., H. Guerra, and P. Ventosilla. 2009. Bartonellosis. Clin. Dermatol. 27: 271-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Márquez, F.J., J. Millán, J.J. Rodríguez-Liébana, I. García-Egea, and M.A. Muniaín. 2009. Detection and identification of Bartonella sp. in fleas from carnivorous mammals in Andalusia, Spain. Med. Vet. Entomol. 23: 393-398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazur-Melewska, K., A. Mania, P. Kemnitz, M. Figlerowicz, and W. Sluzewski. 2015. Cat-scratch disease: a wide spectrum of clinical pictures. Postepy Dermatol. Alergol. 32: 216-220.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mba, P.A., J.L. Marie, J.M. Rolain, B. Davoust, J.C. Beaucournu, D. Raoult, and P. Parola. 2011. Rickettsia felis and Bartonella henselae in fleas from Lebanon. Vector Borne Zoonotic Dis. 11: 991-992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mokthar, A.S. and S.T. Tay. 2011. Short report: Molecular detection of Rickettsia felis, Bartonella henselae and B. clarridgeiae in fleas from domestic dogs and cats in Malaysia. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 85: 931-933.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosbacher, M.E., S. Klotz, J. Klotz, and J.L. Pinnas. 2011. Bartonella henselae and the potential for arthropod vector-borne transmission. Vector Borne Zoonotic. Dis. 11: 471-477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nei, M. and S. Kumar. 2000. Molecular Evolution and Phylogenetics. Oxford University Press, NY.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng-Nguyen, D., S.F. Hii, M.T. Hoang, V.T. Nguyen, R. Rees, J. Stenos, and R.J. Traub. 2020. Domestic dogs are mammalian reservoirs for the emerging zoonoses flea-borne spotted fever, caused by Rickettsia felis. Sci. Rep. 10: 4151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noden, B.H., F.I. Tshavuka, B.E. van der Colf, I. Chipare, and R. Wilkinson. 2014. Exposure and risk factors to Coxiella burnetii, spotted fever group and typhus group rickettsiae, and Bartonella henselae among volunteer blood donors in Namibia. PLoS One. 9: e108674.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norman, A.F., R. Regnery, P. Jameson, C. Greene, and D.C. Krause. 1995. Differentiation of Bartonella-like isolates at the species level by PCR-restriction fragment length polymorphism in the citrate synthase gene. J. Clin. Microbiol. 33: 1797-1803.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira, A.M., R.G. Maggi, C.W. Woods, and E.B. Breitschwerdt. 2010. Case report: suspected needle stick transmission of Bartonella vinsonii subspecies berkhofﬁi to a veterinarian. J. Vet. Int. Med. 24:1229-1232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pérez-Arellano, J.L., F. Fenollar, A. Angel-Moreno, M. Bolaños, M. Hernández, E. Santana, M. Hemmersbach-Miller, AM. Martín, and D. Raoult. 2005. Human Rickettsia felis infection, Canary Islands, Spain. Emerg. Infect. Dis. 11: 1961-1964.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rakotonanahary, R.J., A. Harrison, A.N. Maina, J. Jiang, A.L. Richards, M. Rajerison, and S. Telfer. 2017. Molecular and serological evidence of flea-associated typhus group and spotted fever group rickettsial infections in Madagascar. Parasit. Vectors 10: 125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reif, K.E. and K.R. Macaluso. 2009. Ecology of Rickettsia felis. J. Med. Entomol. 46: 723-736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roux, V. and D. Raoult. 2000. Phylogenetic analysis of members of the genus Rickettsia using the gene encoding the outer-membrane protein rOmpB (ompB). Int. J. Sys. Evol. Microbiol. 50: 1449-1455.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rust, M.K. 2005. Advances in the control of Ctenocephalides felis (cat flea) on cats and dogs. Parasitology 21: 232-236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zouari, S., F. Khrouf, Y. M'ghirbi, and A. Bouattour. 2017. First molecular detection and characterization of zoonotic Bartonella species in fleas infesting domestic animals in Tunisia. Parasit. Vectors. 10: 436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
