<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">33202062</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-9114</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pharmacotherapy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pharmacotherapy</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Differences in Predicted Warfarin Dosing Requirements Between Hmong and East Asians Using Genotype-Based Dosing Algorithms.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>265</StartPage>
          <EndPage>276</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>265-276</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/phar.2487</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Warfarin's narrow therapeutic index and high variability in dosage requirements make dosage selection critical. Genetic factors are known to impact warfarin dosage selection. The Hmong are a unique Asian subpopulation numbering over 278,000 in the United States whose participation in genetics-based research is virtually nonexistent. The translational significance of early reports of warfarin pharmacogene differences in Hmong has not been evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">(i) To validate previously identified allele frequency differences relevant to warfarin dosing in Hmong versus East Asians and (ii) to compare predicted warfarin sensitivity and maintenance doses between a Hmong population and an East Asian cohort.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD">DNA collected from two independent cohorts (n=236 and n=198) of Hmong adults were genotyped for CYP2C9 (*2, *3), VKORC1 (G-1639A), and CYP4F2 (*3). Allele frequencies between the combined Hmong cohort (n=433) and East Asians (n=1165) from the 2009 International Warfarin Pharmacogenetics Consortium (IWPC) study were compared using a χ<sup>2</sup> test. Percentages of Hmong and East Asian participants predicted to be very sensitive to warfarin were compared using a χ<sup>2</sup> test, and the predicted mean warfarin maintenance dose was compared with a t test.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The allele frequencies of CYP2C9*3 in the combined Hmong cohort and CYP4F2*3 in the VIP-Hmong cohort are significantly different from those in East Asians (18.9% vs 3.0%, p&lt;0.001 and 9.8% vs 22.1%, p&lt;0.001, respectively). Comparing the combined Hmong cohort to the East Asian cohort, the percentage of participants predicted to be very sensitive to warfarin was significantly higher (28% vs 5%, p&lt;0.01) and the mean predicted warfarin maintenance dose was significantly lower (19.8 vs 21.3 mg/week, p&lt;0.001), respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The unique allele frequencies related to warfarin when combined with nongenetic factors observed in the Hmong translate into clinically relevant differences in predicted maintenance dose requirements for Hmong versus East Asians.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Pharmacotherapy Publications, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Boguang</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Experimental and Clinical Pharmacology, College of Pharmacy, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ya-Feng</ForeName>
            <Initials>YF</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5090-4153</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Experimental and Clinical Pharmacology, College of Pharmacy, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Culhane-Pera</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kathleen A</ForeName>
            <Initials>KA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Minnesota Community Care, St. Paul, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Muaj</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Minnesota Community Care, St. Paul, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xiong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Txia</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Minnesota Community Care, St. Paul, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Koobmeej</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Minnesota Community Care, St. Paul, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kerui</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Titus Family Department of Clinical Pharmacy, School of Pharmacy, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thyagarajan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bharat</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, School of Medicine, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bishop</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeffrey R</ForeName>
            <Initials>JR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Experimental and Clinical Pharmacology, College of Pharmacy, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zierhut</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heather</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1941-664X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Genetics, Cell Biology and Development, College of Biological Science, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Straka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert J</ForeName>
            <Initials>RJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9541-7823</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Experimental and Clinical Pharmacology, College of Pharmacy, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>UL1TR002494</GrantID>
            <Acronym>TR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pharmacotherapy</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8111305</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0277-0008</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>5Q7ZVV76EI</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014859">Warfarin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D044466" MajorTopicYN="Y">Asians</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014859" MajorTopicYN="Y">Warfarin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Asian Americans</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">anticoagulant drugs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">minority health</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacogenetics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">precision medicine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">warfarin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33202062</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/phar.2487</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnes GD, Lucas E, Alexander GC, Goldberger ZD. National trends in ambulatory oral anticoagulant use. Am J Med 2015;128(12):1300-5 e2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein TE, Altman RB, Eriksson N, et al. Estimation of the warfarin dose with clinical and pharmacogenetic data. N Engl J Med 2009;360(8):753-64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JA, Caudle KE, Gong L, et al. Clinical pharmacogenetics implementation consortium (CPIC) guideline for pharmacogenetics-guided warfarin dosing: 2017 update. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2017;102(3):397-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danese E, Raimondi S, Montagnana M, et al. Effect of CYP4F2, VKORC1, and CYP2C9 in influencing coumarin dose: a single-patient data meta-analysis in more than 15,000 individuals. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2019;105(6):1477-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shehab N, Lovegrove MC, Geller AI, Rose KO, Weidle NJ, Budnitz DS. US emergency department visits for outpatient adverse drug events, 2013-2014. JAMA 2016;316(20):2115-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson JA, Gong L, Whirl-Carrillo M, et al. Clinical pharmacogenetics implementation consortium guidelines for CYP2C9 and VKORC1 genotypes and warfarin dosing. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2011;90(4):625-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gage BF, Bass AR, Lin H, et al. Effect of genotype-guided warfarin dosing on clinical events and anticoagulation control among patients undergoing hip or knee arthroplasty: the GIFT randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2017;318(12):1115-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pirmohamed M, Burnside G, Eriksson N, et al. A randomized trial of genotype-guided dosing of warfarin. N Engl J Med 2013;369(24):2294-303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimmel SE, French B, Kasner SE, et al. A pharmacogenetic versus a clinical algorithm for warfarin dosing. N Engl J Med 2013;369(24):2283-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaye JB, Schultz LE, Steiner HE, Kittles RA, Cavallari LH, Karnes JH. Warfarin pharmacogenomics in diverse populations. Pharmacotherapy 2017;37(9):1150-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Census Bureau. American Community Survey 1-Year Estimates 2016. Available from https://factfinder.census.gov/faces/tableservices/jsf/pages/productview.xhtml?pid=ACS_16_1YR_S0201&amp;prodType=table. Accessed March 15, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mushiroda T, Ohnishi Y, Saito S, et al. Association of VKORC1 and CYP2C9 polymorphisms with warfarin dose requirements in Japanese patients. J Hum Genet 2006;51(3):249-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi H, Wilkinson GR, Nutescu EA, et al. Different contributions of polymorphisms in VKORC1 and CYP2C9 to intra- and inter-population differences in maintenance dose of warfarin in Japanese, Caucasians and African-Americans. Pharmacogenet Genomics 2006;16(2):101-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao F, Loke C, Rankin SC, et al. Novel CYP2C9 genetic variants in Asian subjects and their influence on maintenance warfarin dose. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2004;76(3):210-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen YF, Culhane-Pera KA, Thyagarajan B, et al. Potential clinical relevance of differences in allele frequencies found within very important pharmacogenes between hmong and East Asian populations. Pharmacotherapy 2020;40(2):142-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Straka RJ, Yang Y, Lochungvu M, et al. Comparisons of SNP frequencies for CYP2C9 and VKORC1 between Hmong and Combined Han-Chinese and Japanese Cohorts Poster Session II (PII 1-84). Clin Pharmacol Ther 2010;87:S39-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lenzini P, Wadelius M, Kimmel S, et al. Integration of genetic, clinical, and INR data to refine warfarin dosing. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2010;87(5):572-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WARFARIN SODIUM-warfarin tablet [package insert]. Bridgewater, NJ. Available from https://dailymed.nlm.nih.gov/dailymed/drugInfo.cfm?setid=541c9a70-adaf-4ef3-94ba-ad4e70dfa057. Accessed November 15, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tham LS, Goh BC, Nafziger A, et al. A warfarin-dosing model in Asians that uses single-nucleotide polymorphisms in vitamin K epoxide reductase complex and cytochrome P450 2C9. Clin Pharmacol Ther 2006;80(4):346-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miao L, Yang J, Huang C, Shen Z. Contribution of age, body weight, and CYP2C9 and VKORC1 genotype to the anticoagulant response to warfarin: proposal for a new dosing regimen in Chinese patients. Eur J Clin Pharmacol 2007;63(12):1135-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang SW, Chen HS, Wang XQ, et al. Validation of VKORC1 and CYP2C9 genotypes on interindividual warfarin maintenance dose: a prospective study in Chinese patients. Pharmacogenet Genomics 2009;19(3):226-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chumnumwat S, Yi K, Lucksiri A, et al. Comparative performance of pharmacogenetics-based warfarin dosing algorithms derived from Caucasian, Asian, and mixed races in Thai population. Cardiovasc Ther 2018;36(2). https://doi.org/10.1111/1755-5922.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rotimi CN, Marshall PA. Tailoring the process of informed consent in genetic and genomic research. Genome Med 2010;2(3):20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Millon Underwood S, Buseh AG, Kelber ST, Stevens PE, Townsend L. Enhancing the participation of African Americans in health-related genetic research: findings of a collaborative academic and community-based research study. Nurs Res Pract 2013;2013:749563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Culhane-Pera KA, Straka RJ, Moua M, et al. Engaging Hmong adults in genomic and pharmacogenomic research: toward reducing health disparities in genomic knowledge using a community-based participatory research approach. J Community Genet 2017;8(2):117-125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roman YM, Culhane-Pera KA, Menk J, Straka RJ. Assessment of genetic polymorphisms associated with hyperuricemia or gout in the Hmong. Per Med 2016;13(5):429-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Z, Cheng G, Wang P, Khalighi B, Khalighi K. Clinical model for predicting warfarin sensitivity. Sci Rep 2019;9(1):12856.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>PharmGKB [Internet]. Palo Alto, CA: Stanford University. VIP Variant in CYP4F2*3. Available from https://www.pharmgkb.org/haplotype/PA165860687. Accessed October 30, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verhoef TI, Ragia G, de Boer A, et al. A randomized trial of genotype-guided dosing of acenocoumarol and phenprocoumon. N Engl J Med 2013;369(24):2304-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ageno W, Gallus AS, Wittkowsky A, Crowther M, Hylek EM, Palareti G. Oral anticoagulant therapy: antithrombotic therapy and prevention of thrombosis, 9th ed: American College of Chest Physicians evidence-based clinical practice guidelines. Chest 2012;141(2):e44S-88S.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Akl EA, Ornelas J, et al. Antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest 2016;149(2):315-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lip GYH, Banerjee A, Boriani G, et al. Antithrombotic therapy for atrial fibrillation: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest 2018;154(5):1121-201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez W, Gamazon ER, Aquino-Michaels K, et al. Ethnicity-specific pharmacogenetics: the case of warfarin in African Americans. Pharmacogenomics J. 2014;14(3):223-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holzer K, Culhane-Pera KA, Straka RJ, et al. Hmong participants' reactions to return of individual and community pharmacogenetic research results: "A positive light for our community" [published online ahead of print August 6, 2020]. J Community Genet 2020. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12687-020-00475-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Listman JB, Malison RT, Sanichwankul K, Ittiwut C, Mutirangura A, Gelernter J. Southeast Asian origins of five Hill Tribe populations and correlation of genetic to linguistic relationships inferred with genome-wide SNP data. Am J Phys Anthropol. 2011;144(2):300-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Listman JB, Malison RT, Sughondhabirom A, et al. Demographic changes and marker properties affect detection of human population differentiation. BMC Genet. 2007;8:21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, Cai X, Winograd-Cort ER, et al. Mitochondrial DNA diversity and population differentiation in southern East Asia. Am J Phys Anthropol. 2007;134(4):481-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen B, Li H, Gao S, et al. Genetic structure of Hmong-Mien speaking populations in East Asia as revealed by mtDNA lineages. Mol Biol Evol. 2005;22(3):725-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Besaggio D, Fuselli S, Srikummool M, et al. Genetic variation in Northern Thailand Hill Tribes: origins and relationships with social structure and linguistic differences. BMC Evol Biol 2007;7(Suppl 2):S12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai X, Qin Z, Wen B, et al. Human migration through bottlenecks from Southeast Asia into East Asia during Last Glacial Maximum revealed by Y chromosomes. PLoS One 2011;6(8):e24282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>All of Us Research Program I, Denny JC, Rutter JL, et al. The "all of us" research program. N Engl J Med 2019;381(7):668-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fung E, Patsopoulos NA, Belknap SM, et al. Effect of genetic variants, especially CYP2C9 and VKORC1, on the pharmacology of warfarin. Semin Thromb Hemost 2012;38(8):893-904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caldwell MD, Awad T, Johnson JA, et al. CYP4F2 genetic variant alters required warfarin dose. Blood 2008;111(8):4106-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Andreu V, Roldan V, Anton AI, et al. Pharmacogenetic relevance of CYP4F2 V433M polymorphism on acenocoumarol therapy. Blood 2009;113(20):4977-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan SL, Thalamuthu A, Goh BC, et al. Exon sequencing and association analysis of EPHX1 genetic variants with maintenance warfarin dose in a multiethnic Asian population. Pharmacogenet Genomics 2011;21(1):35-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandyopadhyay PK. Vitamin K-dependent γ-glutamylcarboxylation: an ancient posttranslational modification. Vitamins Hormones 2008;78:157-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
