<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">33232079</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK564409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352">Spinal Opioids In Anesthetic Practice</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Champagne</LastName><ForeName>Katelynn</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fecek</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Peconic Bay Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldstein</LastName><ForeName>Sheldon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Montefiore MC - Albert Einstein College</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Regional anesthesia, consisting of spinal, caudal, and epidural blocks, was first utilized for surgical procedures at the turn of the twentieth century. Initially deemed unsafe due to reports of permanent neurologic injury, a large-scale study in the 1950s proved complications were rare when blocks were performed skillfully and with attention to sterile technique, combined with the improved safety profile of injected medications. Initial work showing improved pain management in cancer patients has expanded spinal opioids for postoperative pain management. (Katz, 1981; Cunningham, 1983; Vanstrum, 1988). Spinal anesthesia now has a long track record of safety. In some circumstances, it is the anesthetic of choice and, at times, even the safest option. While local anesthetics are used to provide surgical anesthesia, they are often combined with intrathecal (IT) opioids to supplement intraoperative analgesia and provide postoperative analgesia once the local anesthetic has worn off. Spinal opioids are also used to manage chronic pain, sometimes as single injections, but more often via implantable infusion pumps.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s3">Anatomy and Physiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s4">Indications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s5">Contraindications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s6">Equipment</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s7">Personnel</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s8">Preparation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s9">Technique</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s10">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s11">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s12">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s13">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-29352" sec="article-29352.s14">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wang JK. Intrathecal morphine for intractable pain secondary to cancer of pelvic organs. Pain. 1985 Jan;21(1):99-102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3838582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope JE, Deer TR, Amirdelfan K, McRoberts WP, Azeem N. The Pharmacology of Spinal Opioids and Ziconotide for the Treatment of Non-Cancer Pain. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2017;15(2):206-216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26861471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bujedo BM. Current evidence for spinal opioid selection in postoperative pain. Korean J Pain. 2014 Jul;27(3):200-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4099232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins MJ, Mather LE. Intrathecal and epidural administration of opioids. Anesthesiology. 1984 Sep;61(3):276-310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6206753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoelting RK. Intrathecal morphine--an underused combination for postoperative pain management. Anesth Analg. 1989 Jun;68(6):707-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2660627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahl JB, Jeppesen IS, Jørgensen H, Wetterslev J, Møiniche S. Intraoperative and postoperative analgesic efficacy and adverse effects of intrathecal opioids in patients undergoing cesarean section with spinal anesthesia: a qualitative and quantitative systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Anesthesiology. 1999 Dec;91(6):1919-27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10598635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brogan S, Junkins S. Interventional therapies for the management of cancer pain. J Support Oncol. 2010 Mar-Apr;8(2):52-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20464881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deer TR, Pope JE, Hanes MC, McDowell GC. Intrathecal Therapy for Chronic Pain: A Review of Morphine and Ziconotide as Firstline Options. Pain Med. 2019 Apr 01;20(4):784-798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6442748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30137539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatnagar S, Gupta M. Evidence-based Clinical Practice Guidelines for Interventional Pain Management in Cancer Pain. Indian J Palliat Care. 2015 May-Aug;21(2):137-47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26009665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodgers A, Walker N, Schug S, McKee A, Kehlet H, van Zundert A, Sage D, Futter M, Saville G, Clark T, MacMahon S. Reduction of postoperative mortality and morbidity with epidural or spinal anaesthesia: results from overview of randomised trials. BMJ. 2000 Dec 16;321(7275):1493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11118174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisman SJ, Bernstein B, Schechter NL. Consequences of inadequate analgesia during painful procedures in children. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 1998 Feb;152(2):147-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9491040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kehlet H. Surgical stress: the role of pain and analgesia. Br J Anaesth. 1989 Aug;63(2):189-95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2669908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hilt H, Gramm HJ, Link J. Changes in intracranial pressure associated with extradural anaesthesia. Br J Anaesth. 1986 Jun;58(6):676-80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3707805</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka M, Balki M, McLeod A, Carvalho JC. Regional anesthesia and non-preeclamptic thrombocytopenia: time to re-think the safe platelet count. Rev Bras Anestesiol. 2009 Mar-Apr;59(2):142-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19488526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi S, Brull R. Neuraxial techniques in obstetric and non-obstetric patients with common bleeding diatheses. Anesth Analg. 2009 Aug;109(2):648-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19608843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiting D, DiNardo JA. TEG and ROTEM: technology and clinical applications. Am J Hematol. 2014 Feb;89(2):228-32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24123050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies JR, Fernando R, Hallworth SP. Hemostatic function in healthy pregnant and preeclamptic women: an assessment using the platelet function analyzer (PFA-100) and thromboelastograph. Anesth Analg. 2007 Feb;104(2):416-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17242101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein S, Dean D, Kim SJ, Cocozello K, Grofsik J, Silver P, Cody RP. A survey of spinal and epidural techniques in adult cardiac surgery. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2001 Apr;15(2):158-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11312472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebl JR, Horlocker TT, Kopp SL, Schroeder DR. Neuraxial blockade in patients with preexisting spinal stenosis, lumbar disk disease, or prior spine surgery: efficacy and neurologic complications. Anesth Analg. 2010 Dec;111(6):1511-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perlas A, Chan VW. Neuraxial anesthesia and multiple sclerosis. Can J Anaesth. 2005 May;52(5):454-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15872120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eng RH, Seligman SJ. Lumbar puncture-induced meningitis. JAMA. 1981 Apr 10;245(14):1456-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7206149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chestnut DH. Spinal anesthesia in the febrile patient. Anesthesiology. 1992 May;76(5):667-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1575331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teele DW, Dashefsky B, Rakusan T, Klein JO. Meningitis after lumbar puncture in children with bacteremia. N Engl J Med. 1981 Oct 29;305(18):1079-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6974306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald SB. Is neuraxial blockade contraindicated in the patient with aortic stenosis? Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2004 Sep-Oct;29(5):496-502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15372397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deykin D, Janson P, McMahon L. Ethanol potentiation of aspirin-induced prolongation of the bleeding time. N Engl J Med. 1982 Apr 08;306(14):852-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7062964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horlocker TT, Vandermeuelen E, Kopp SL, Gogarten W, Leffert LR, Benzon HT. Regional Anesthesia in the Patient Receiving Antithrombotic or Thrombolytic Therapy: American Society of Regional Anesthesia and Pain Medicine Evidence-Based Guidelines (Fourth Edition). Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2018 Apr;43(3):263-309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29561531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook TM, Counsell D, Wildsmith JA, Royal College of Anaesthetists Third National Audit Project  Major complications of central neuraxial block: report on the Third National Audit Project of the Royal College of Anaesthetists. Br J Anaesth. 2009 Feb;102(2):179-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19139027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Practice Guidelines for Obstetric Anesthesia: An Updated Report by the American Society of Anesthesiologists Task Force on Obstetric Anesthesia and the Society for Obstetric Anesthesia and Perinatology. Anesthesiology. 2016 Feb;124(2):270-300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauchat JR, Weiniger CF, Sultan P, Habib AS, Ando K, Kowalczyk JJ, Kato R, George RB, Palmer CM, Carvalho B. Society for Obstetric Anesthesia and Perinatology Consensus Statement: Monitoring Recommendations for Prevention and Detection of Respiratory Depression Associated With Administration of Neuraxial Morphine for Cesarean Delivery Analgesia. Anesth Analg. 2019 Aug;129(2):458-474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31082964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gnaho A, Nguyen V, Villevielle T, Frota M, Marret E, Gentili ME. Assessing the depth of the subarachnoid space by ultrasound. Rev Bras Anestesiol. 2012 Jul;62(4):520-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22793967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabinowitz A, Bourdet B, Minville V, Chassery C, Pianezza A, Colombani A, Eychenne B, Samii K, Fourcade O. The paramedian technique: a superior initial approach to continuous spinal anesthesia in the elderly. Anesth Analg. 2007 Dec;105(6):1855-7, table of contents.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18042894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho AM, Chung DC, Joynt GM. Neuraxial blockade and hematoma in cardiac surgery: estimating the risk of a rare adverse event that has not (yet) occurred. Chest. 2000 Feb;117(2):551-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10669702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottschalk A, Smith DS. New concepts in acute pain therapy: preemptive analgesia. Am Fam Physician. 2001 May 15;63(10):1979-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11388713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaney MA. Side effects of intrathecal and epidural opioids. Can J Anaesth. 1995 Oct;42(10):891-903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8706199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlgren G, Hultstrand C, Jakobsson J, Norman M, Eriksson EW, Martin H. Intrathecal sufentanil, fentanyl, or placebo added to bupivacaine for cesarean section. Anesth Analg. 1997 Dec;85(6):1288-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9390596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer CM, Emerson S, Volgoropolous D, Alves D. Dose-response relationship of intrathecal morphine for postcesarean analgesia. Anesthesiology. 1999 Feb;90(2):437-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9952150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George RB, Allen TK, Habib AS. Serotonin receptor antagonists for the prevention and treatment of pruritus, nausea, and vomiting in women undergoing cesarean delivery with intrathecal morphine: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Anesth Analg. 2009 Jul;109(1):174-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khlebtovsky A, Weitzen S, Steiner I, Kuritzky A, Djaldetti R, Yust-Katz S. Risk factors for post lumbar puncture headache. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2015 Apr;131:78-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25725481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angle P, Thompson D, Halpern S, Wilson DB. Second stage pushing correlates with headache after unintentional dural puncture in parturients. Can J Anaesth. 1999 Sep;46(9):861-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10490155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davoudi M, Tarbiat M, Ebadian MR, Hajian P. Effect of Position During Spinal Anesthesia on Postdural Puncture Headache After Cesarean Section: A Prospective, Single-Blind Randomized Clinical Trial. Anesth Pain Med. 2016 Aug;6(4):e35486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5100205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27843773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pal A, Acharya A, Pal ND, Dawn S, Biswas J. Do pencil-point spinal needles decrease the incidence of postdural puncture headache in reality? A comparative study between pencil-point 25G Whitacre and cutting-beveled 25G Quincke spinal needles in 320 obstetric patients. Anesth Essays Res. 2011 Jul-Dec;5(2):162-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4173408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25885381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horlocker TT, McGregor DG, Matsushige DK, Schroeder DR, Besse JA. A retrospective review of 4767 consecutive spinal anesthetics: central nervous system complications. Perioperative Outcomes Group. Anesth Analg. 1997 Mar;84(3):578-84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9052305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin JJ, Kuh SU, Cho YE. Surgical management of spontaneous spinal epidural hematoma. Eur Spine J. 2006 Jun;15(6):998-1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16758110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada K, Abe Y, Satoh S, Yanagibashi Y, Hyakumachi T, Masuda T. Large Increase in Blood Pressure After Extubation and High Body Mass Index Elevate the Risk of Spinal Epidural Hematoma After Spinal Surgery. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2015 Jul 01;40(13):1046-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25768686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucklin BA, Hawkins JL, Anderson JR, Ullrich FA. Obstetric anesthesia workforce survey: twenty-year update. Anesthesiology. 2005 Sep;103(3):645-53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16129992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afolabi BB, Lesi FE. Regional versus general anaesthesia for caesarean section. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012 Oct 17;10:CD004350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23076903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaupre LA, Jones CA, Saunders LD, Johnston DW, Buckingham J, Majumdar SR. Best practices for elderly hip fracture patients. A systematic overview of the evidence. J Gen Intern Med. 2005 Nov;20(11):1019-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1490246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16307627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas A, Perlas A, Ghosh M, Chin K, Niazi A, Pandher B, Chan V. Relative Contributions of Adductor Canal Block and Intrathecal Morphine to Analgesia and Functional Recovery After Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2018 Feb;43(2):154-160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29315129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roediger L, Joris J, Senard M, Larbuisson R, Canivet JL, Lamy M. The use of pre-operative intrathecal morphine for analgesia following coronary artery bypass surgery. Anaesthesia. 2006 Sep;61(9):838-44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16922749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yapici D, Altunkan ZO, Atici S, Bilgin E, Doruk N, Cinel I, Dikmengil M, Oral U. Postoperative effects of low-dose intrathecal morphine in coronary artery bypass surgery. J Card Surg. 2008 Mar-Apr;23(2):140-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18304128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlow JL, Steele RG, O'Reilly D. Low dose intrathecal morphine facilitates early extubation after cardiac surgery: results of a retrospective continuous quality improvement audit. Can J Anaesth. 2005 Jan;52(1):94-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15625264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Metz S, Schwann N, Hassanein W, Yuskevich B, Nixon T. Intrathecal morphine for off-pump coronary artery bypass grafting. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2004 Aug;18(4):451-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15365926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellenberger C, Sologashvili T, Bhaskaran K, Licker M. Impact of intrathecal morphine analgesia on the incidence of pulmonary complications after cardiac surgery: a single center propensity-matched cohort study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2017 Aug 22;17(1):109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28830362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammer GB, Ramamoorthy C, Cao H, Williams GD, Boltz MG, Kamra K, Drover DR. Postoperative analgesia after spinal blockade in infants and children undergoing cardiac surgery. Anesth Analg. 2005 May;100(5):1283-1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15845670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gadsden J, Hart S, Santos AC. Post-cesarean delivery analgesia. Anesth Analg. 2005 Nov;101(5 Suppl):S62-S69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16334493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan TJ. Poorly controlled postoperative pain: prevalence, consequences, and prevention. J Pain Res. 2017;10:2287-2298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29026331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng DC. Pro: early extubation after cardiac surgery decreases intensive care unit stay and cost. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 1995 Aug;9(4):460-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7579120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitwalli MY, Elmoheen A, Bashir K. Acute Spontaneous Spinal Subdural Hematoma: A Case Report. Am J Case Rep. 2020 Aug 03;21:e922416.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7423169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah JA, Patel NN, Michael KW. Spontaneous Spinal Epidural Hematoma: An Atypical Clinical Presentation and Discussion of Management. Int J Spine Surg. 2020 Apr;14(2):158-161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7188101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33232079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
