<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33279374</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2509</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>230</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Schizophrenia research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Schizophr Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Sequential Multiple-Assignment Randomized Trials to Compare Antipsychotic Treatments (SMART-CAT) in first-episode schizophrenia patients: Rationale and trial design.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>87</StartPage>
          <EndPage>94</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>87-94</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.schres.2020.11.010</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0920-9964(20)30529-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Accumulated studies have investigated pharmacological interventions for first-episode schizophrenia (FES) patients. However, studies on subsequent treatment steps, which are essential to guide clinicians, are largely missing. This Sequential Multiple-Assignment Randomized Trials comparing Antipsychotic Treatments (SMART-CAT) program intends to evaluate the effectiveness of commonly used antipsychotic drugs in FES patients. The major goals of this study are to examine: 1) what would be the optimal subsequent sequential treatment if the first antipsychotic drug failed; 2) whether clozapine could be used in those first-trial failed and have superior efficacy compared to other atypical antipsychotics. In this article we will report the detail protocol of SMART-CAT. The SMART-CAT is a randomized controlled clinical multicenter trial in which 9 institutions in China will participate. A total of 720 FES patients will be enrolled and followed up for 12 months in this study. The trial includes three treatment phases (each phase lasting for 8 weeks) and a naturalistic follow-up phase; participants who do well on an assigned treatment will remain on that treatment for the duration of the 12-month treatment period, while non-responders will move to the next phase of the study to receive a new treatment. Phase 1 is a randomized controlled trial; patients will be randomly assigned to one of the treatments with oral olanzapine, risperidone, amisulpride, aripiprazole or perphenazine. Subjects who fail to respond after 8 weeks will enter the phase 2 randomization. Phase 2 is an equipoise-stratified randomization trial, and patients will be randomly assigned to oral olanzapine, amisulpride or clozapine for 8 weeks. Subjects who fail to respond after phase 2 will enter an open label trial (phase 3); patients who receive clozapine in phase 2 and fail to respond will be assigned to an extended clozapine treatment or modified electroconvulsive therapy add-on therapy (Phase 3A). Patients who were not assigned to clozapine in phase 2 will be assigned to treatment with clozapine or another SGAs not previously used in phase 1 and 2 (Phase 3B). The primary outcome for the treatment phase is the treatment efficacy rate, which is defined as at least 40% reduction in Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale (PANSS) total score. We hypothesize that clozapine is more therapeutically effective than any other SGAs to patients who failed to meet efficacy criteria in Phase 1, and earlier treatment with clozapine can improve the functional outcomes of schizophrenia patients. As for the naturalistic follow-up phase, time to all-cause treatment failure, marked by its discontinuation is selected as the primary outcome, since it reflects both efficacy and side effects. The all-cause discontinuation is defined as discontinuing for any reasons, including poor efficacy, intolerance of adverse reactions, poor compliance and other reasons. The results of the SMART-CAT trial will provide evidence for the selection of antipsychotics in FES patients who fail to respond to the first trial of an antipsychotic drug. It will also provide evidence for the efficacy and safety of using clozapine in the early phase of schizophrenia treatment by comparing with other SGAs. The study is based on the combination of sequential therapy and dynamic therapy, which can be more suitable to assess the effectiveness of treatment options in the real-world clinical setting. As a result, we hope that this study can provide guidance for an optimal treatment algorithm in first-episode schizophrenia patients. Trial registration: ID NCT03510325 in ClinicalTrials.gov.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaoyun</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaoduo</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Psychotic Disorders Program, UMass Memorial Medical Center, University of Massachusetts Medical School, Worcester, MA 01605, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Feng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tienan</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Research Institute, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 20020, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chuanyue</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beijing An Ding Hospital, Capital University of Medical Sciences, Beijing 100088, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhijian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The Affiliated Brain Hospital of Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing 210029, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiufeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, The First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming 650032, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhiyu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Seventh People's Hospital of Hangzhou, Hangzhou 310013, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huiling</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University, Wuhan 430060, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shoufu</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Seventh People's Hospital of Dalian, Dalian 116023, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jiangjiang</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Shanghai Health Development Research Center, Shanghai 200040, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhuo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kaiming</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qiong</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Haixin</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jinhong</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Smith</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert C</ForeName>
            <Initials>RC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University School of Medicine, Hewlett, NY 11557-0316, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hua</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of California at San Diego, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Keshavan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Matcheri S</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA 02115, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephen R</ForeName>
            <Initials>SR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Semel Institute for Neuroscience at University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Davis</LastName>
            <ForeName>John M</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL 60612, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kaida</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yifeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China; Shanghai Key Laboratory of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China; Shanghai Clinical Research Center for Mental Health, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China; Institute of Mental Health, Fudan University, Shanghai 200030, China. Electronic address: hyyyyb@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dengtang</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First-episode Schizophrenia and Early Psychosis Program, Division of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China; Shanghai Key Laboratory of Psychotic Disorders, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China; Shanghai Clinical Research Center for Mental Health, Shanghai Mental Health Center, Shanghai Jiao Tong University School of Medicine, Shanghai 200030, China; Institute of Mental Health, Fudan University, Shanghai 200030, China. Electronic address: liudengtang@smhc.org.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT03510325</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Netherlands</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Schizophr Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8804207</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0920-9964</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014150">Antipsychotic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>12794-10-4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001569">Benzodiazepines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>J60AR2IKIC</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003024">Clozapine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014150" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antipsychotic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001569" MajorTopicYN="N">Benzodiazepines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003024" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clozapine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schizophrenia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Antipsychotic drugs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Effectiveness</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">First-episode</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Schizophrenia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Sequential Multiple-Assignment Randomized Trials</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest All authors declare that they have no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>41</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33279374</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2020.11.010</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0920-9964(20)30529-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
