<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33270923</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2761</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>44</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of fish diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Fish Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Phenotype, genotype and pathogenicity of Streptococcus agalactiae isolated from cultured tilapia (Oreochromis spp.) in Taiwan.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>747</StartPage>
          <EndPage>756</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>747-756</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jfd.13296</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Tilapia (Oreochromis spp.) is globally used as an aquaculture fish species due to its high growth rate and disease resistance. However, it faces an increased risk of streptococcosis. Streptococcus agalactiae, also known as group B streptococcus (GBS), is the most important tilapia pathogen in Asia. Studies of Str. agalactiae infection in Taiwan are still unclear. Thus, this study aimed to explore the phenotype, genotype and pathogenicity of Str. agalactiae isolated from cultured tilapia in Taiwan in 2016-2018. The analysis revealed that 85% of the strains displayed β-haemolysis and 15% showed γ-haemolysis, with the same capsule level, and were positive for the CAMP test. The Rapid ID 32 Strep test showed a similarity of Rapid ID 32 Strep is more than 99.5% to GBS. Genotypic distribution by molecular serotyping detected only serotype Ia from all isolates, despite the regional differences. Pulsed-field gel electrophoresis (PFGE) was categorized into 3 and 10 clusters by restriction enzymes SmaI and ApaI, respectively. Virulence genes and antimicrobial resistance genes presented the same profile in all isolates. The challenge test with 10<sup>6</sup>  CFU/fish (LD<sub>50</sub> ), administered intraperitoneally, showed that the β-haemolysis strains had a higher mortality rate than γ-haemolysis, although they were from the same cluster from PFGE, year and region.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sudpraseart</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chiranan</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0665-2256</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Degree Program of Ornamental Fish Technology and Aquatic Animal Health, International College, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pei-Chi</ForeName>
            <Initials>PC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7986-1625</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Degree Program of Ornamental Fish Technology and Aquatic Animal Health, International College, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, College of Veterinary Medicine, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Veterinary Medicine, Southern Taiwan Fish Diseases Research Centre, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shih-Chu</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2885-9370</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Degree Program of Ornamental Fish Technology and Aquatic Animal Health, International College, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, College of Veterinary Medicine, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Veterinary Medicine, Southern Taiwan Fish Diseases Research Centre, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Research Centre for Animal Biologics, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, Pingtung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Fish Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9881188</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0140-7775</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D023681" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cichlids</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005393" MajorTopicYN="N">Fish Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="Y">Genotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="Y">Phenotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013290" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcal Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="Y">veterinary</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013292" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus agalactiae</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000472" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathogenicity</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013624" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Taiwan</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014774" MajorTopicYN="N">Virulence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Streptococcus agalactiae
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PFGE</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cultured tilapia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genotype</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenicity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phenotype</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33270923</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfd.13296</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azmai, M. N. A., &amp; Saad, M. (2011). Streptococcosis in tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus): A review. Journal of Tropical Agricultural Science, 34, 195-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brochet, M., Couvé, E., Zouine, M., Vallaeys, T., Rusniok, C., Lamy, M. C., Buchrieser, C., Trieu-Cuot, P., Kunst, F., Poyart, C., &amp; Glaser, P. (2006). Genomic diversity and evolution within the species Streptococcus agalactiae. Microbes and Infection, 8(5), 1227-1243. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micinf.2005.11.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodeur, B. R., Boyer, M., Charlebois, I., Hamel, J., Couture, F., Rioux, C. R., &amp; Martin, D. (2000). Identification of Group B Streptococcal Sip Protein, which elicits cross-protective immunity. Infection and Immunity, 68(10), 5610-5618. https://doi.org/10.1128/IAI.68.10.5610-5618.2000</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, M., Wang, R., Luo, F.-G., Huang, Y., Liang, W.-W., Huang, T., Lei, A.-Y., Gan, X.-L., &amp; Li, L.-P. (2015). Streptococcus agalactiae isolates of serotypes Ia, III and V from human and cow are able to infect tilapia. Veterinary Microbiology, 180, 129-135. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2015.07.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, S. L. (2019). Genomic insights into the distribution and evolution of Group B Streptococcus. Frontiers in Microbiology, 10, 1447. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2019.01447</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Da Cunha, V., Davies, M. R., Douarre, P. E., Rosinski-Chupin, I., Margarit, I., Spinali, S., Perkins, T., Lechat, P., Dmytruk, N., Sauvage, E., Ma, L., Romi, B., Tichit, M., Lopez-Sanchez, M. J., Descorps-Declere, S., Souche, E., Buchrieser, C., Trieu-Cuot, P., Moszer, I., … Glaser, P. (2014). Streptococcus agalactiae clones infecting humans were selected and fixed through the extensive use of tetracycline. Nature Communications, 5, 4544. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms5544</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dangwetngam, M., Suanyuk, N., Kong, F., &amp; Phromkunthong, W. (2016). Serotype distribution and antimicrobial susceptibilities of Streptococcus agalactiae isolated from infected cultured tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus) in Thailand: Nine-year perspective. Journal of Medical Microbiology, 65(3), 247-254. https://doi.org/10.1099/jmm.0.000213</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darwish, A. M., Rawles, S. D., &amp; Griffin, B. R. (2002). Laboratory efficacy of oxytetracycline for the control of Streptococcus iniae infection in blue tilapia. Journal of Aquatic Animal Health, 14(3), 184-190. https://doi.org/10.1577/1548-8667(2002)014&lt;0184:LEOOFT&gt;2.0.CO;2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng, L., Li, Y., Geng, Y., Zheng, L., Rehman, T., Zhao, R., Wang, K., Ping, O., Chen, D., Huang, X., He, C., Yang, Z., &amp; Lai, W. (2019). Molecular serotyping and antimicrobial susceptibility of Streptococcus agalactiae isolated from fish in China. Aquaculture, 510, 84-89. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaculture.2019.05.046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doran, K. S., Liu, G. Y., &amp; Nizet, V. (2003). Group B streptococcal beta-hemolysin/cytolysin activates neutrophil signaling pathways in brain endothelium and contributes to development of meningitis. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 112(5), 736-744. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI17335</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duriez, P., Zhang, Y., Lu, Z., Scott, A., &amp; Topp, E. (2008). Loss of virulence genes in Escherichia coli populations during manure storage on a commercial swine farm. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 74(13), 3935-3942. https://doi.org/10.1128/aem.02710-07</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans, J. J., Bohnsack, J. F., Klesius, P. H., Whiting, A. A., Garcia, J. C., Shoemaker, C. A., &amp; Takahashi, S. (2008). Phylogenetic relationships among Streptococcus agalactiae isolated from piscine, dolphin, bovine and human sources: A dolphin and piscine lineage associated with a fish epidemic in Kuwait is also associated with human neonatal infections in Japan. Journal of Medical Microbiology, 57(11), 1369-1376. https://doi.org/10.1099/jmm.0.47815-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans Joyce, K. P., Craig, S., &amp; Pasnik, D. (2006). Identification and epidemiology of Streptococcus iniae and S. agalactiae in tilapias Oreochromis spp. Paper presented at the International Symposium on Tilapia in Aquaculture Charles TownWV, USA, American Tilapia Association.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FAO. (2019). FAO yearbook. Fishery and Aquaculture Statistics 2017/FAO annuaire. Statistiques des pêches et de l'aquaculture 2017/FAO anuario. Estadísticas de pesca y acuicultura 2017. Rome/Roma.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filho, C. I., Muller, E. E., Pretto-Giordano, L., &amp; Bracarense, A. P. (2009). Histological finding of experimental Streptococcus agalactiae infection in Nile tilapias (Oreochromis niloticus). Brazilian Journal of Veterinary Pathology, 2, 12-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francois, B., Charles, M., &amp; Courvalin, P. (1997). Conjugative transfer of tet(S) between strains of Enterococcus faecalis is associated with the exchange of large fragments of chromosomal DNA. Microbiology, 143(Pt 7), 2145-2154. https://doi.org/10.1099/00221287-143-7-2145</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freney, J., Bland, S., Etienne, J., Desmonceaux, M., Boeufgras, J. M., &amp; Fleurette, J. (1992). Description and evaluation of the semiautomated 4-hour rapid ID 32 Strep method for identification of streptococci and members of related genera. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 30(10), 2657-2661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeric, P. E., Lopardo, H., Vidal, P., Arduino, S., Fernandez, A., Orman, B. E., Sordelli, D. O., &amp; Centrón, D. (2002). Multicenter study on spreading of the tet(M) gene in tetracycline-resistant Streptococcus group G and C isolates in Argentina. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 46(1), 239-241. https://doi.org/10.1128/aac.46.2.239-241.2002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones, N., Bohnsack, J. F., Takahashi, S., Oliver, K. A., Chan, M.-S., Kunst, F., Glaser, P., Rusniok, C., Crook, D. W. M., Harding, R. M., Bisharat, N., &amp; Spratt, B. G. (2003). Multilocus sequence typing system for group B Streptococcus. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 41(6), 2530-2536. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.41.6.2530-2536.2003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kayansamruaj, P., Pirarat, N., Katagiri, T., Hirono, I., &amp; Rodkhum, C. (2014). Molecular characterization and virulence gene profiling of pathogenic Streptococcus agalactiae populations from tilapia (Oreochromis sp.) farms in Thailand. Journal of Veterinary Diagnostic Investigation, 26(4), 488-495. https://doi.org/10.1177/1040638714534237</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kayansamruaj, P., Soontara, C., Unajak, S., Dong, H. T., Rodkhum, C., Kondo, H., Hirono, I., &amp; Areechon, N. (2019). Comparative genomics inferred two distinct populations of piscine pathogenic Streptococcus agalactiae, serotype Ia ST7 and serotype III ST283, in Thailand and Vietnam. Genomics, 111(6), 1657-1667. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygeno.2018.11.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klesius, P. H., Shoemaker, C., &amp; Evans, J. (2008). Streptococcus: A worldwide fish health problem. Proceedings of the 8th International Symposium on Tilapia in Aquaculture, 83-107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leal, C. A. G., Queiroz, G. A., Pereira, F. L., Tavares, G. C., &amp; Figueiredo, H. C. P. (2019). Streptococcus agalactiae sequence type 283 in farmed fish, Brazil. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 25(4), 776-779. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2504.180543</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, L., Wang, R., Liang, W., Gan, X., Huang, T., Huang, Y., Li, J., Shi, Y., Chen, M., &amp; Luo, H. (2013). Rare serotype occurrence and PFGE genotypic diversity of Streptococcus agalactiae isolated from tilapia in China. Veterinary Microbiology, 167(3), 719-724. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2013.09.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao, P.-C., Tsai, Y.-L., Chen, Y.-C., Wang, P.-C., Liu, S.-C., &amp; Chen, S.-C. (2020). Analysis of streptococcal infection and correlation with climatic factors in cultured tilapia Oreochromis spp, Taiwan. Applied Sciences, 10(11), 2076-3417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Limansky, A. S., Sutich, E. G., Guardati, M. C., Toresani, I. E., &amp; Viale, A. M. (1998). Genomic diversity among Streptococcus agalactiae isolates detected by a degenerate oligonucleotide-primed amplification assay. Journal of Infectious Diseases, 177(5), 1308-1313. https://doi.org/10.1086/515275</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nandlal, S., &amp; Pickering, T. (2004). Tilapia fish farming in Pacific Island Countries, Vol. 1. Tilapia Hatchery Operation.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Netto, L. N., Leal, C. A., &amp; Figueiredo, H. C. (2011). Streptococcus dysgalactiae as an agent of septicaemia in Nile tilapia, Oreochromis niloticus (L.). Journal of Fish Diseases, 34(3), 251-254. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2761.2010.01220</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen, H. T., Kanai, K., &amp; Yoshikoshi, K. (2002). Ecological investigation of Streptococcus iniae in cultured Japanese flounder (Paralichthys olivaceus) using selective isolation procedures. Aquaculture, 205(1), 7-17. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0044-8486(01)00667-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul, J. (2014). Characterization of immunogenic properties of Streptococcus agalactiae biotype I and II. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gdata.2014.06.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira, U. P., Mian, G. F., Oliveira, I. C., Benchetrit, L. C., Costa, G. M., &amp; Figueiredo, H. C. (2010). Genotyping of Streptococcus agalactiae strains isolated from fish, human and cattle and their virulence potential in Nile tilapia. Veterinary Microbiology, 140(1-2), 186-192. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2009.07.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pham, T. H., Cheng, T.-C., Wang, P.-C., &amp; Chen, S.-C. (2020). Genotypic diversity, and molecular and pathogenic characterization of Photobacterium damselae subsp. piscicida isolated from different fish species in Taiwan. Journal of Fish Diseases, 43(7), 757-774. https://doi.org/10.1111/jfd.13173</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pillay, T. V. R. (1990). Aquaculture: Principles and practices. Blackwell Science.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poyart, C., Jardy, L., Quesne, G., Berche, P., &amp; Trieu-Cuot, P. (2003). Genetic basis of antibiotic resistance in Streptococcus agalactiae strains isolated in a French hospital. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 47(2), 794-797. https://doi.org/10.1128/aac.47.2.794-797.2003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poyart, C., Tazi, A., Réglier-Poupet, H., Billoët, A., Tavares, N., Raymond, J., &amp; Trieu-Cuot, P. (2007). Multiplex PCR assay for rapid and accurate capsular typing of group B streptococci. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 45(6), 1985-1988. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.00159-07</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rolland, K., Marois, C., Siquier, V., Cattier, B., &amp; Quentin, R. (1999). Genetic features of Streptococcus agalactiae strains causing severe neonatal infections, as revealed by pulsed-field gel electrophoresis and hylB gene analysis. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 37(6), 1892-1898. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.37.6.1892-1898.1999</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shiomitsu, K., Kusuda, R., Osuga, H., &amp; Munekiyo, M. (1980). Studies on chemotherapy of fish disease with erythromycin-II: Its clinical studies against streptococcal infection in cultured yellowtails. Fish Pathology, 15(1), 17-23. https://doi.org/10.3147/jsfp.15.17</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sørensen, U. B. S., Poulsen, K., Ghezzo, C., Margarit, I., &amp; Kilian, M. (2010). Emergence and global dissemination of host-specific Streptococcus agalactiae clones. American Society for Microbiology, 1(3), e00178-110. https://doi.org/10.1128/mBio.00178-10</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sutcliffe, J., Grebe, T., Tait-Kamradt, A., &amp; Wondrack, L. (1996). Detection of erythromycin-resistant determinants by PCR. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 40(11), 2562-2566. https://doi.org/10.1128/AAC.40.11.2562</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suwannasang, A., Suanyuk, N., Issaro, A., Wutiporn, P., Tantikitti, C., Itami, T., &amp; Yoshida, T. (2017). Growth, immune responses and protection of Nile tilapia Oreochromis niloticus immunized with formalin-killed Streptococcus agalactiae serotype Ia and III vaccines. Songklanakarin Journal of Science and Technology, 39(4), 429-437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syuhada, R., Zamri-Saad, M., Ina-Salwany, M. Y., Mustafa, M., Nasruddin, N. N., Desa, M. N. M., Nordin, S. A., Barkham, T., &amp; Amal, M. N. A. (2020). Molecular characterization and pathogenicity of Streptococcus agalactiae serotypes Ia ST7 and III ST283 isolated from cultured red hybrid tilapia in Malaysia. Aquaculture, 515, 734543. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquaculture.2019.734543</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, S., Lin, Y., Foo, K., Koh, H. F., Tow, C., Zhang, Y., Ang, L. W., Cui, L., Badaruddin, H., Ooi, P. L., Lin, R. T. P., &amp; Cutter, J. (2016). Group B Streptococcus serotype III sequence type 283 bacteremia associated with consumption of raw fish, Singapore. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 22(11), 1970-1973. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2211.160210</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tenover, F. C., Arbeit, R. D., Goering, R. V., Mickelsen, P. A., Murray, B. E., Persing, D. H., &amp; Swaminathan, B. (1995). Interpreting chromosomal DNA restriction patterns produced by pulsed-field gel electrophoresis: Criteria for bacterial strain typing. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 33(9), 2233-2239. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.33.9.2233-2239.1995</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trewavas, E. (1983). Tilapia fishes of the genera Sarotherodon, Oreochromis, and Danakilia. British Museum (Natural History).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warsa, U. C., Nonoyama, M., Ida, T., Okamoto, R., Okubo, T., Shimauchi, C., Kuga, A., &amp; Inoue, M. (1996). Detection of tet(K) and tet(M) in Staphylococcus aureus of Asian countries by the polymerase chain reaction. The Journal of Antibiotics (Tokyo), 49(11), 1127-1132. https://doi.org/10.7164/antibiotics.49.1127</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanong, R., &amp; Francis-Floyd, R. (2002). Streptococcal Infections of Fish 1. Report from University of Florida.Series from the Department of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences, Florida Cooperative Extension Service, Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences, University of Florida.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamri-Saad, M., Amal, M. N., &amp; Siti-Zahrah, A. (2010). Pathological changes in red tilapias (Oreochromis spp.) naturally infected by Streptococcus agalactiae. Journal of Comparative Pathology, 143(2-3), 227-229. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcpa.2010.01.020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Z., Lan, J., Li, Y., Hu, M., Yu, A., Zhang, J., &amp; Wei, S. (2018). The pathogenic and antimicrobial characteristics of an emerging Streptococcus agalactiae serotype IX in Tilapia. Microbial Pathogenesis, 122, 39-45. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micpath.2018.05.053</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
