<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33272960</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-2060</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>80</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
              <Day>03</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of the rheumatic diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Upadacitinib for psoriatic arthritis refractory to biologics: SELECT-PsA 2.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>312</StartPage>
          <EndPage>320</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>312-20</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">annrheumdis-2020-218870</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-218870</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Upadacitinib is a Janus kinase inhibitor under evaluation for the treatment of psoriatic arthritis (PsA). We evaluated upadacitinib in patients with PsA and prior inadequate response or intolerance to at least one biologic disease-modifying antirheumatic drug (DMARD).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this 24-week randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind, phase 3 trial, 642 patients were randomised (2:2:1:1) to once per day upadacitinib 15 mg or 30 mg, placebo followed by upadacitinib 15 mg or placebo followed by upadacitinib 30 mg at week 24. The primary endpoint was the proportion of patients achieving American College of Rheumatology (ACR) 20 response at week 12. Achievement of minimal disease activity (MDA) was assessed at week 24. Treatment-emergent adverse events are reported for all patients who received at least one dose of trial drug.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At week 12, significantly more patients receiving upadacitinib 15 mg and 30 mg versus placebo achieved ACR20 (56.9% and 63.8% vs 24.1%; p&lt;0.001 for both comparisons). At week 24, MDA was achieved by more upadacitinib 15 mg-treated (25.1%) and 30 mg-treated patients (28.9%) versus placebo (2.8%; p&lt;0.001 for both comparisons). Generally, the rates of treatment-emergent adverse events were similar with placebo and upadacitinib 15 mg and higher with upadacitinib 30 mg at week 24. Rates of serious infections were 0.5%, 0.5% and 2.8% with placebo, upadacitinib 15 mg and upadacitinib 30 mg, respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this trial of patients with active PsA who had inadequate response or intolerance to at least one biologic DMARD, upadacitinib 15 mg and 30 mg was more effective than placebo over 24 weeks in improving signs and symptoms of PsA.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">NCT03104374.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2020. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mease</LastName>
            <ForeName>Philip J</ForeName>
            <Initials>PJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6620-0457</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology, Swedish Medical Center, Seattle, Washington, USA pmease@philipmease.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lertratanakul</LastName>
            <ForeName>Apinya</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Anderson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jaclyn K</ForeName>
            <Initials>JK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0893-3900</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Papp</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kim</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Probity Medical Research and K Papp Clinical Research Inc, Waterloo, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Van den Bosch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Filip</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Pediatrics, Ghent University, VIB Center for Inflammation Research, Ghent, Belgium, Gent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsuji</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shigeyoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics/Rheumatology, National Hospital Organization, Osaka Minami Medical Center, Kawachi-Nagano, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dokoupilova</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eva</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Plus, Uherske Hradiste, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, University of Veterinary and Pharmaceutical Sciences Brno, Brno, Jihomoravský, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Keiserman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mauro</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Section, Pontifical Catholic University, School of Medicine, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xin</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>McCaskill</LastName>
            <ForeName>Reva M</ForeName>
            <Initials>RM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zueger</LastName>
            <ForeName>Patrick</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pangan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aileen L</ForeName>
            <Initials>AL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tillett</LastName>
            <ForeName>William</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Royal National Hospital for Rheumatic Disease, Bath, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy and Pharmacology, Centre for Therapeutic Innovation and Institute for Mathematical Innovation, University of Bath, Bath, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT03104374</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Rheum Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372355</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0003-4967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arthritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biological therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psoriatic</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Competing interests: PJM has received research grants, consulting fees and/or speaker’s fees from AbbVie, Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Galapagos, Genentech, Gilead, Janssen, Merck, Novartis, Pfizer, Sun Pharma and UCB. KP received honoraria or fees for advisory board, speaker and consultant services from AbbVie, Amgen, Astellas, Baxalta, Baxter, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Centocor, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Forward Pharma, Galderma, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen, Kyowa-Hakko Kirin, Leo Pharma, MedImmune, Merck-Serono, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron, Roche, Sanofi-Genzyme, Stiefel, Sun Pharma, Takeda, UCB and Valeant and received research grants from AbbVie, Amgen, Astellas, Baxalta, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Centocor, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Galderma, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen, Kyowa-Hakko Kirin, Leo Pharma, MedImmune, Merck-Serono, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron, Roche, Sanofi-Genzyme, Stiefel, Takeda, UCB and Valeant. WT received grant/research support from AbbVie, Celgene and Eli Lilly and is a consultant for AbbVie, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Janssen, Novartis, and Pfizer, Speakers bureau: AbbVie, Amgen, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Janssen, Novartis, UCB and Pfizer. FEVdB received speaker and/or consultancy fees from AbbVie, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Janssen, Merck, Novartis, Pfizer and UCB. ST received speaker fees from AbbVie, Asahi Kasei, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Eisai, Mitsubishi Tanabe, Celgene and Novartis Pharma. ED received grant/research support from AbbVie, Eli Lilly, Glaxo Smith &amp; Kline, Novartis, Pfizer, UCB Biopharma SPRL, Sanofi – Aventis, Hexal AG, Gilead, R-Pharm, Janssen-Cilag, Galapagos NV. MK has participated in Advisory Boards and/or lectures for Pfizer, Abbott, Actelion, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Roche, Bristol Myers Squibb and Janssen and has received clinical trial honoraria from Pfizer, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Anthera Pharmaceuticals, Bristol Myers Squibb, Biogen Idec, Celltrion, Eli Lilly, Human Genome Sciences, Novartis, Roche, Sanofi, UCB Inc. AL, JKA, XW, SZ, PZ, ALP and RMM are AbbVie employees and may own AbbVie stock or options.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>37</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33272960</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7892371</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-218870</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">annrheumdis-2020-218870</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Coates LC, Kavanaugh A, Mease PJ, et al. . 
Group for research and assessment of psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis 2015 treatment recommendations for psoriatic arthritis. Arthritis Rheumatol
2016;68:1060–71. 10.1002/art.39573
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26749174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gossec L, Baraliakos X, Kerschbaumer A, et al. . 
EULAR recommendations for the management of psoriatic arthritis with pharmacological therapies: 2019 update. Ann Rheum Dis
2020;79:700–12. 10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217159
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286048</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Singh JA, Guyatt G, Ogdie A, et al. . 
Special article: 2018 American College of Rheumatology/National psoriasis Foundation guideline for the treatment of psoriatic arthritis. Arthritis Care Res
2019;71:2–29. 10.1002/acr.23789
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.23789</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30499259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mease PJ, van der Heijde D, Ritchlin CT, et al. . 
Ixekizumab, an interleukin-17A specific monoclonal antibody, for the treatment of biologic-naive patients with active psoriatic arthritis: results from the 24-week randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled and active (adalimumab)-controlled period of the phase III trial SPIRIT-P1. Ann Rheum Dis
2017;76:79–87. 10.1136/annrheumdis-2016-209709
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2016-209709</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5264219</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27553214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mease P, van der Heijde D, Landewé R, et al. . 
Secukinumab improves active psoriatic arthritis symptoms and inhibits radiographic progression: primary results from the randomised, double-blind, phase III future 5 study. Ann Rheum Dis
2018;77:890–7. 10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-212687
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-212687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5965348</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29550766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mease P, Hall S, FitzGerald O, et al. . 
Tofacitinib or adalimumab versus placebo for psoriatic arthritis. N Engl J Med
2017;377:1537–50. 10.1056/NEJMoa1615975
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1615975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29045212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mease P, Coates LC, Helliwell PS, et al. . 
Efficacy and safety of filgotinib, a selective Janus kinase 1 inhibitor, in patients with active psoriatic arthritis (EQUATOR): results from a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet
2018;392:2367–77. 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32483-8
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32483-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30360969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
McInnes IB, Kavanaugh A, Gottlieb AB, et al. . 
Efficacy and safety of ustekinumab in patients with active psoriatic arthritis: 1 year results of the phase 3, multicentre, double-blind, placebo-controlled PSUMMIT 1 trial. Lancet
2013;382:780–9. 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60594-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60594-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23769296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Deodhar A, Gottlieb AB, Boehncke W-H, et al. . 
Efficacy and safety of guselkumab in patients with active psoriatic arthritis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 2 study. Lancet
2018;391:2213–24. 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30952-8
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30952-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29893222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Parmentier JM, Voss J, Graff C, et al. . 
In vitro and in vivo characterization of the JAK1 selectivity of upadacitinib (ABT-494). BMC Rheumatol
2018;2:23. 10.1186/s41927-018-0031-x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41927-018-0031-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390583</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30886973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Burmester GR, Kremer JM, Van den Bosch F, et al. . 
Safety and efficacy of upadacitinib in patients with rheumatoid arthritis and inadequate response to conventional synthetic disease-modifying anti-rheumatic drugs (SELECT-NEXT): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet
2018;391:2503–12. 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31115-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31115-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29908669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fleischmann R, Pangan AL, Song I-H, et al. . 
Upadacitinib versus placebo or adalimumab in patients with rheumatoid arthritis and an inadequate response to methotrexate: results of a phase III, double-blind, randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Rheumatol
2019;71:1788–800. 10.1002/art.41032
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31287230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Genovese MC, Fleischmann R, Combe B, et al. . 
Safety and efficacy of upadacitinib in patients with active rheumatoid arthritis refractory to biologic disease-modifying anti-rheumatic drugs (SELECT-BEYOND): a double-blind, randomised controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet
2018;391:2513–24. 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31116-4
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31116-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29908670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Smolen JS, Pangan AL, Emery P, et al. . 
Upadacitinib as monotherapy in patients with active rheumatoid arthritis and inadequate response to methotrexate (SELECT-MONOTHERAPY): a randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind phase 3 study. Lancet
2019;393:2303–11. 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30419-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30419-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31130260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
van Vollenhoven R, Takeuchi T, Pangan AL, et al. . 
Efficacy and safety of Upadacitinib monotherapy in Methotrexate-naïve patients with moderately to severely active rheumatoid arthritis (SELECT-EARLY): a randomized, double-blind, Active-comparator, multi-center, Multi-country trial. Arthritis Rheumatol
2020. 10.1002/art.41384. [Epub ahead of print: 08 Jul 2020].
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41384</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7589375</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Taylor W, Gladman D, Helliwell P, et al. . 
Classification criteria for psoriatic arthritis: development of new criteria from a large international study. Arthritis Rheum
2006;54:2665–73. 10.1002/art.21972
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.21972</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16871531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fries JF, Spitz PW, Young DY. 
The dimensions of health outcomes: the health assessment questionnaire, disability and pain scales. J Rheumatol
1982;9:789–93.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7175852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chandran V, Bhella S, Schentag C, et al. . 
Functional assessment of chronic illness therapy-fatigue scale is valid in patients with psoriatic arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis
2007;66:936–9. 10.1136/ard.2006.065763
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2006.065763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1955111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17324972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ware J, Kosinski MA, Dewey JE. 
How to score version two of the SF-36 health survey. Lincoln, RI: Quality Metric, 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Langley RGB, Feldman SR, Nyirady J, et al. . 
The 5-point investigator's global assessment (IgA) scale: a modified tool for evaluating plaque psoriasis severity in clinical trials. J Dermatolog Treat
2015;26:23–31. 10.3109/09546634.2013.865009
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09546634.2013.865009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24354461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fredriksson T, Pettersson U. 
Severe psoriasis-oral therapy with a new retinoid. Dermatologica
1978;157:238–44. 10.1159/000250839
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000250839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">357213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Armstrong AW, Banderas B, Foley C, et al. . 
Development and psychometric evaluation of the self-assessment of psoriasis symptoms (SAPS) - clinical trial and the SAPS - real world patient-reported outcomes. J Dermatolog Treat
2017;28:505–14. 10.1080/09546634.2017.1290206
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09546634.2017.1290206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28147886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Coates LC, Fransen J, Helliwell PS. 
Defining minimal disease activity in psoriatic arthritis: a proposed objective target for treatment. Ann Rheum Dis
2010;69:48–53. 10.1136/ard.2008.102053
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2008.102053</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19147615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Healy PJ, Helliwell PS. 
Measuring clinical enthesitis in psoriatic arthritis: assessment of existing measures and development of an instrument specific to psoriatic arthritis. Arthritis Rheum
2008;59:686–91. 10.1002/art.23568
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.23568</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Maksymowych WP, Mallon C, Morrow S, et al. . 
Development and validation of the spondyloarthritis research Consortium of Canada (SPARCC) Enthesitis index. Ann Rheum Dis
2009;68:948–53. 10.1136/ard.2007.084244
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2007.084244</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18524792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Helliwell PS, Firth J, Ibrahim GH, et al. . 
Development of an assessment tool for dactylitis in patients with psoriatic arthritis. J Rheumatol
2005;32:1745–50.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16142872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schoels M
Psoriatic arthritis indices. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2014;32:109–12.
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25365098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gladman D, Rigby W, Azevedo VF, et al. . 
Tofacitinib for psoriatic arthritis in patients with an inadequate response to TNF inhibitors. N Engl J Med
2017;377:1525–36. 10.1056/NEJMoa1615977
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1615977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29045207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nash P, Kirkham B, Okada M, et al. . 
Ixekizumab for the treatment of patients with active psoriatic arthritis and an inadequate response to tumour necrosis factor inhibitors: results from the 24-week randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled period of the SPIRIT-P2 phase 3 trial. Lancet
2017;389:2317–27. 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)31429-0
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)31429-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28551073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mease PJ, McInnes IB, Kirkham B, et al. . 
Secukinumab inhibition of interleukin-17A in patients with psoriatic arthritis. N Engl J Med
2015;373:1329–39. 10.1056/NEJMoa1412679
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1412679</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26422723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
