<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33280211</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1399-3046</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>25</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pediatric transplantation</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Transplant</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Complications of surgical mesh patches after kidney transplantation in children-A case series.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e13935</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e13935</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/petr.13935</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Abdominal compartment syndrome after kidney transplantation in pediatric recipients is a recognized complication relating to size discrepancy requiring abdominal wall closure over a large adult allograft. In order to circumvent this problem, our center implemented use of a surgical mesh, Surgisis<sup>®</sup> (Cook Surgical, Bloomington, IN), for abdominal wall closure in very small children to increase the surface covering over the organ and prevent compression. In this article, we report on the complications encountered following the use of these mesh patches.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective case review was conducted of all pediatric kidney transplants from September 2006 to December 2018 and divided into abdominal wall closure with and without implantation of Surgisis<sup>®</sup> mesh patch. Review of clinical notes was performed to identify information with respect to clinical course and post-operative outcomes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A surgical mesh patch was used in 7 pediatric recipients, of which 5 (71%) presented with post-operative complications. Three recipients were found to have bowel obstruction related to the surgical patch, necessitating bowel resection in one child. In addition, three children developed large serous fluid collections between the subcutaneous layers and the surgical mesh, requiring surgical drainage in two.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In view of these findings, we recommend close surveillance for potential complications in this cohort. Future research is needed to explore the safety of different approaches to achieve abdominal wall closure in this group.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Amir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Noa</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1632-6462</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Westmead, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Taher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amir</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Westmead, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The University of New England, Sydney, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thomas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gordon</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Westmead, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Albert</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Westmead, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Durkan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anne</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5721-2114</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Children's Hospital at Westmead, Westmead, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The University of Sydney, Sydney, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Denmark</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Transplant</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9802574</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1397-3142</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D034861" MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal Wall</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="Y">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003161" MajorTopicYN="N">Compartment Syndromes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016030" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Transplantation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011183" MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative Complications</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013526" MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical Mesh</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058106" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wound Closure Techniques</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adverse events</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complications</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric kidney transplantation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical complications</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>22</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33280211</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/petr.13935</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maione C, Gambino G, Di Bona A, et al. PTFE mesh in renal allograft compartment syndrome. Transplant Proc. 2006;38(4):1049-1050.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Humar A, Sharpe J, Hollomby D. Salvage of a renal allograft with renal vein occlusion secondary to extrinsic compression. Am J Kidney Dis. 1996;28(4):622-623.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nery JR, Weppler D, DeFaria W, Liu P, Romero R, Tzakis AG. Is the graft too big or too small? Technical variations to overcome size incongruity in visceral organ transplantation. Transplant Proc. 1998;30(6):2640-2641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pentlow A, Smart NJ, Richards SK, Inward CD, Morgan JD. The use of porcine dermal collagen implants in assisting abdominal wall closure of pediatric renal transplant recipients with donor size discrepancy. Pediatr Transplant. 2008;12(1):20-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halawa A. Abdominal wall closure of renal transplant recipients: an undermined challenge. Int J Organ Transplant Med. 2010;1(2):73-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taher A, Zhu B, Ma S, Shun A, Durkan AM. Intra-abdominal Complications After Pediatric Kidney Transplantation: Incidence and Risk Factors. Transplantation. 2019;103(6):1234-1239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodenough CJ, Ko TC, Kao LS, et al. Development and validation of a risk stratification score for ventral incisional hernia after abdominal surgery: hernia expectation rates in intra-abdominal surgery (the HERNIA Project). J Am Coll Surg. 2015;220(4):405-413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coccolini F, Catena F, Bertuzzo VR, Ercolani G, Pinna A, Ansaloni L. Abdominal wall defect repair with biological prosthesis in transplanted patients: single center retrospective analysis and review of the literature. Updates Surg. 2013;65(3):191-196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehrabi A, Fonouni H, Wente M, et al. Wound complications following kidney and liver transplantation. Clin Transplant. 2006;20(Suppl 17):97-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flechner SM, Zhou L, Derweesh I, et al. The impact of sirolimus, mycophenolate mofetil, cyclosporine, azathioprine, and steroids on wound healing in 513 kidney-transplant recipients. Transplantation. 2003;76(12):1729-1734.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee YC, Hung SY, Wang HH, et al. Different Risk of Common Gastrointestinal Disease Between Groups Undergoing Hemodialysis or Peritoneal Dialysis or With Non-End Stage Renal Disease: A Nationwide Population-Based Cohort Study. Medicine (Baltimore). 2015;94(36):e1482.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karpelowsky JS, Thomas G, Shun A. Definitive abdominal wall closure using a porcine intestinal submucosa biodegradable membrane in pediatric transplantation. Pediatr Transplant. 2009;13(3):285-289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller G, Boman J, Shrier I, Gordon PH. Etiology of small bowel obstruction. Am J Surg. 2000;180(1):33-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baylón K, Rodríguez-Camarillo P, Elías-Zúñiga A, Díaz-Elizondo JA, Gilkerson R, Lozano K. Past, present and future of surgical meshes: a review. Membranes (Basel). 2017;7(3):47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langbach O, Holmedal SH, Grandal OJ, Røkke O. Adhesions to mesh after ventral hernia mesh repair are detected by MRI but are not a cause of long term chronic abdominal pain. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2016;2016:2631598.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grant HW, Parker MC, Wilson MS, et al. Population-based analysis of the risk of adhesion-related readmissions after abdominal surgery in children. J Pediatr Surg. 2006;41(8):1453-1456.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguayo P, Ho B, Fraser JD, Gamis A, St Peter SD, Snyder CL. Bowel obstruction after treatment of intra-abdominal tumors. Eur J Pediatr Surg. 2010;20(4):234-236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lautz TB, Barsness KA. Adhesive small bowel obstruction-acute management and treatment in children. Semin Pediatr Surg. 2014;23(6):349-352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attard JA, MacLean AR. Adhesive small bowel obstruction: epidemiology, biology and prevention. Can J Surg. 2007;50(4):291-300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richard HM. Perirenal transplant fluid collections. Semin Intervent Radiol. 2004;21(4):235-237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asarias JR, Nguyen PT, Mings JR, Gehrich AP, Pierce LM. Influence of mesh materials on the expression of mediators involved in wound healing. J Invest Surg. 2011;24(2):87-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gowda AU, McNichols CH, Asokan I, et al. Porcine Acellular Dermal Matrix for Hernia Repair in Transplant Patients. Ann Plast Surg. 2016;77(6):674-677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dietz UA, Winkler MS, Härtel RW, et al. Importance of recurrence rating, morphology, hernial gap size, and risk factors in ventral and incisional hernia classification. Hernia. 2014;18(1):19-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helgstrand F, Rosenberg J, Kehlet H, Jorgensen LN, Bisgaard T. Nationwide prospective study of outcomes after elective incisional hernia repair. J Am Coll Surg. 2013;216(2):217-228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Ramshorst GH, Eker HH, Hop WC, Jeekel J, Lange JF. Impact of incisional hernia on health-related quality of life and body image: a prospective cohort study. Am J Surg. 2012;204(2):144-150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ah-Kee EY, Kallachil T, O'Dwyer PJ. Patient awareness and symptoms from an incisional hernia. Int Surg. 2014;99(3):241-246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
