<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">33290287</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2162-0989</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Asia-Pacific journal of ophthalmology (Philadelphia, Pa.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Asia Pac J Ophthalmol (Phila)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Current Approach for the Diagnosis and Management of Noninfective Scleritis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>212</StartPage>
          <EndPage>223</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>212-223</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/APO.0000000000000341</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Scleritis is a rare, vision-threatening inflammation of the sclera that is often associated with life-threatening systemic illnesses. Rheumatoid arthritis remains the most common associated systemic rheumatic disease and the commonest systemic association of scleritis. Granulomatosis with polyangiitis is the most common cause of vasculitis-associated scleritis. The etiopathogenesis of scleritis remains unclear, but can be immune complex-mediated or due to a local delayed hypersensitivity reaction. Scleritis can involve either the anterior or posterior sclera, and has a wide spectrum of clinical presentations. Among the subtypes of scleritis, necrotizing scleritis has an increased risk of complications and is more commonly associated with anterior uveitis and peripheral ulcerative keratitis. Posterior scleritis is often not diagnosed or missed due to its subtle clinical signs and protean manifestations. Meticulous history taking, detailed ocular examination, and a targeted array of investigations with a multi-disciplinary approach to find any underlying systemic disease are crucial for the management of a case of scleritis. Corticosteroids remain the mainstay of short-term treatment of scleritis; mild to moderate scleral inflammation may respond well to treatment with nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drug or topical corticosteroid. Corticosteroid-sparing immunosuppressive therapies are useful in cases with an inadequate response or failure to provide long-term control of inflammation, and to prevent recurrence of scleritis. Biologic agents are increasingly used in the management of scleritis, not responding to the conventional therapies. This review provides an overview of the various subtypes of scleritis and its systemic associations and evaluates current trends in the diagnosis and management of noninfective scleritis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 Asia-Pacific Academy of Ophthalmology. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of the Asia-Pacific Academy of Ophthalmology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dutta Majumder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Parthopratim</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Uvea and Intraocular Inflammation, Sankara Nethralaya, Chennai, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Agrawal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rupesh</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Healthcare Group Eye Institute, Tan Tock Seng Hospital, Singapore.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>McCluskey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Peter</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ocular Infections and Antimicrobials Research Group, Singapore Eye Research Institute, Singapore.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Biswas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jyotirmay</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Uveitis and Ocular Pathology, Sankara Nethralaya, Chennai, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>China</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Asia Pac J Ophthalmol (Phila)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101583622</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2162-0989</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000305">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000894">Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000305" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000894" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003320" MajorTopicYN="Y">Corneal Ulcer</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012590" MajorTopicYN="N">Sclera</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015423" MajorTopicYN="Y">Scleritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33290287</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/APO.0000000000000341</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">01599573-202104000-00015</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson PG, Hayreh SS. Scleritis and episcleritis. Br J Ophthalmol 1976; 60:163–191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benson WE. Posterior scleritis. Surv Ophthalmol 1988; 32:297–316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang P, Ye Z, Tang J, et al. Clinical features and complications of scleritis in Chinese patients. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2018; 26:387–396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wieringa WG, Wieringa JE, ten Dam-van Loon NH, Los LI. Visual outcome, treatment results, and prognostic factors in patients with scleritis. Ophthalmology 2013; 120:379–386.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta Majumder P, Ghose A, Chidambaram M, Ganesh SK, Biswas J. Clinical profile of patients with necrotizing scleritis in a tertiary eye care center in Southern India. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2018; 26:412–416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka R, Kaburaki T, Ohtomo K, et al. Clinical characteristics and ocular complications of patients with scleritis in Japanese. Jpn J Ophthalmol 2018; 62:517–524.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lane J, Nyugen E, Morrison J, et al. Clinical features of scleritis across the Asia-Pacific region. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2019; 27:920–926.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahman Z, Jafarullah O, Huq N, Hasan K, Magesan K, Dutta Majumder P. Clinical profile of patients with scleritis in Bangladesh. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2020; 1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A, Ghose A, Biswas J, Dutta Majumder P. Clinical profile of patients with posterior scleritis: a report from Eastern India. Indian J Ophthalmol 2018; 66:1109–1112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manandhar A. Patterns of uveitis and scleritis in Nepal: a tertiary referral center study. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2017; 25:S54–S62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keino H, Watanabe T, Taki W, Nakashima C, Okada AA. Clinical features and visual outcomes of Japanese patients with scleritis. Br J Ophthalmol 2010; 94:1459–1463.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calthorpe CM, Watson PG, McCartney AC. Posterior scleritis: a clinical and histological survey. Eye Lond Engl 1988; 2:267–277.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta Majumder P, Ali S, George A, Ganesh S, Biswas J. Clinical Profile of Scleritis in Children. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2019; 27:535–539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Maesen K, D’Haens EJ, van Rijn LJ, Pigeaud-Klessens MLE, Meenken C. Posterior scleritis in a 7-month-old infant. J Pediatr Ophthalmol Strabismus 2007; 44:377–378.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Molina N, Gonzalez-Gonzalez LA, Doctor PP, Tauber J, Foster CS. Clinical characteristics of a large cohort of patients with scleritis and episcleritis. Ophthalmology 2012; 119:43–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-López JJ, Lavric A, Dutta Majumder P, et al. Bilateral posterior scleritis: analysis of 18 cases from a large cohort of posterior scleritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2016; 24:16–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao NA, Marak GE, Hidayat AA. Necrotizing scleritis. A clinico-pathologic study of 41 cases. Ophthalmology 1985; 92:1542–1549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riono WP, Hidayat AA, Rao NA. Scleritis: a clinicopathologic study of 55 cases. Ophthalmology 1999; 106:1328–1333.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernauer W, Watson PG, Daicker B, Lightman S. Cells perpetuating the inflammatory response in scleritis. Br J Ophthalmol 1994; 78:381–385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Girolamo N, Lloyd A, McCluskey P, Filipic M, Wakefield D. Increased expression of matrix metalloproteinases in vivo in scleritis tissue and in vitro in cultured human scleral fibroblasts. Am J Pathol 1997; 150:653–666.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakefield D, Di Girolamo N, Thurau S, Wildner G, McCluskey P. Scleritis: immunopathogenesis and molecular basis for therapy. Prog Retin Eye Res 2013; 35:44–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seo KY, Lee HK, Kim EK, Lee JH. Expression of tumor necrosis factor-alpha and matrix metalloproteinase-9 in surgically induced necrotizing scleritis. Ophthalmic Res 2006; 38:66–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Molins B, Mesquida M, et al. Interleukin-22 serum levels are elevated in active scleritis. Acta Ophthalmol (Copenh) 2016; 94:e395–399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anshu A, Chee SP. Posterior scleritis and its association with HLA-B27 haplotype. Ophthalmologica 2007; 221:275–278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vergouwen DPC, Rothova A, Berge JCT, et al. Current insights in the pathogenesis of scleritis. Exp Eye Res 2020; 197:108078.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson PG, Young RD. Scleral structure, organization and disease. A review. Exp Eye Res 2004; 78:609–623.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li F, Ma X, Du L, et al. Identification of susceptibility SNPs in CTLA-4 and PTPN22 for scleritis in Han Chinese. Clin Exp Immunol 2019; 197:230–236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Jabbur NS, Foster CS. Severity of scleritis and episcleritis. Ophthalmology 1994; 101:389–396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jabs DA, Mudun A, Dunn JP, Marsh MJ. Episcleritis and scleritis: clinical features and treatment results. Am J Ophthalmol 2000; 130:469–476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raiji VR, Palestine AG, Parver DL. Scleritis and systemic disease association in a community-based referral practice. Am J Ophthalmol 2009; 148:946–950.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Homayounfar G, Borkar DS, Tham VM, Nardone N, Acharya NR. Clinical characteristics of scleritis and episcleritis: results from the pacific ocular inflammation study. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2014; 22:403–404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okhravi N, Odufuwa B, McCluskey P, Lightman S, Scleritis. Surv Ophthalmol 2005; 50:351–363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith JR, Mackensen F, Rosenbaum JT. Therapy insight: scleritis and its relationship to systemic autoimmune disease. Nat Clin Pract Rheumatol 2007; 3:219–226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akpek EK, Thorne JE, Qazi FA, Do DV, Jabs DA. Evaluation of patients with scleritis for systemic disease. Ophthalmology 2004; 111:501–506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erhardt CC, Mumford PA, Venables PJ, Maini RN. Factors predicting a poor life prognosis in rheumatoid arthritis: an eight-year prospective study. Ann Rheum Dis 1989; 48:7–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster CS, Forstot SL, Wilson LA. Mortality rate in rheumatoid arthritis patients developing necrotizing scleritis or peripheral ulcerative keratitis. Effects of systemic immunosuppression. Ophthalmology 1984; 91:1253–1263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCluskey PJ, Watson PG, Lightman S, Haybittle J, Restori M, Branley M. Posterior scleritis: clinical features, systemic associations, and outcome in a large series of patients. Ophthalmology 1999; 106:2380–2386.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoang LT, Lim LL, Vaillant B, Choi D, Rosenbaum JT. Antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibody-associated active scleritis. Arch Ophthalmol 2008; 126:651–655.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta Majumder P, Sudharshan S, George AE, Ganesh SK, Biswas J. Antineutrophil cytoplasmic antibody-positive scleritis: clinical profile of patients from a tuberculosis-endemic region. Indian J Ophthalmol 2018; 66:1587–1591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavesio CE, Meier FM. Systemic disorders associated with episcleritis and scleritis. Curr Opin Ophthalmol 2001; 12:471–478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu CS, Hsu CW, Lu MC, Koo M. Risks of ophthalmic disorders in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus - a secondary cohort analysis of population-based claims data. BMC Ophthalmol 2020; 20:96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavric A, Gonzalez-Lopez JJ, Dutta Majumder P, et al. Posterior scleritis: analysis of epidemiology, clinical factors, and risk of recurrence in a cohort of 114 patients. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2016; 24:6–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Molina N, Gonzalez-Gonzalez LA, Doctor PP, Tauber J, Foster CS. Scleritis associated with relapsing polychondritis. Br J Ophthalmol 2016; 100:1290–1294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanagida C, Usui Y, Sakai JI, Goto H. An unusual case of Behcet disease with posterior scleritis: a case report. Medicine (Baltimore) 2019; 98:e16886.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Philippakis E, Cassoux N, Charlotte F, et al. IgG4-related disease masquerading as recurrent scleritis and chronic conjunctivitis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2015; 23:168–172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds GL, Norris JH, Aslam S, Sharma S. IgG4-related disease presenting as posterior scleritis and vitritis, progressing to multifocal orbital involvement. BMJ Case Rep 2017; 219568.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berkowitz E, Arnon E, Yaakobi A, Cohen Y, Tiosano B. IgG4-related disease presenting as isolated scleritis. Case Rep Ophthalmol Med 2017; 4876587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moorthy RS, London NJS, Garg SJ, Cunningham ET. Drug-induced uveitis. Curr Opin Ophthalmol 2013; 24:589–597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraunfelder FW, Fraunfelder FT. Bisphosphonates and ocular inflammation. N Engl J Med 2003; 348:1187–1188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abtahi MA, Abtahi SH, Fazel F, et al. Topiramate and the vision: a systematic review. Clin Ophthalmol 2012; 6:117–131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turgeon PW, Slamovits TL. Scleritis as the presenting manifestation of procainamide-induced lupus. Ophthalmology 1989; 96:68–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahrokni A, Matuszczak J, Rajebi MR, Saif MW. Erlotinib-induced episcleritis in a patient with pancreatic cancer. JOP J Pancreas 2008; 9:216–219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taban M, Dupps WJ, Mandell B, Perez VL. Etanercept (enbrel)-associated inflammatory eye disease: case report and review of the literature. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2006; 14:145–150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzales JA, Shantha J, Acharya NR. Combination nivolumab- and cabiralizumab-associated acute bilateral anterior and posterior scleritis and anterior uveitis. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2018; 10:117–118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aktas Z, Bektas C, Hasanreisoglu M. Panscleritis as an unusual complication of gonioscopy-assisted transluminal trabeculotomy. J Glaucoma 2019; 28:e21–e23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madanagopalan VG, Shivananda N, Krishnan T. Surgically induced necrotizing scleritis after retinal detachment surgery masquerading as scleral abscess. GMS Ophthalmol Cases 2019; 9: Doc18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ram R. Tectonic corneal lamellar grafting for surgically induced necrotizing scleritis after strabismus surgery: case report &amp; literature review. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2018; 11:28–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu L, Xu S, Ge S, et al. Tailored treatment for the management of scleral necrosis following pterygium excision. Exp Ther Med 2017; 13:845–850.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryu SJ, Kang MH, Seong M, Cho H, Shin YU. Anterior scleritis following intravitreal injections in a patient with rheumatoid arthritis: a case report. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017; 96:e8925.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>L Zagora S, McCluskey P. Diagnostic Approach to Scleritis. In: Pavesio C, ed. Scleritis, Essentials in Ophthalmology. Springer International Publishing; 59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albini TA, Rao NA, Smith RE. The diagnosis and management of anterior scleritis. Int Ophthalmol Clin 2005; 45:191–204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabbara KF. Tuberculosis. Curr Opin Ophthalmol 2007; 18:493–501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kariyawasam AGTA, Fonseka CL, De Silva PUT, et al. Frequently relapsing anterior nodular scleritis as the initial presentation of a lethal systemic infection: disseminated tuberculosis with HIV coinfection. Case Rep Infect Dis 2020; 2020:9020864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta Majumder P. Presumed tuberculous sclerokeratitis presenting with hypopyon. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2019; 27:1121–1123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yangzes S, Sharma VK, Singh SR, Ram J. Scleromalacia perforans in rheumatoid arthritis. QJM Mon J Assoc Physicians 2019; 112:459–460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu CC, Yu HC, Yen JH, Tsai WC, Liu HW. Rare extraarticular manifestation of rheumatoid arthritis: scleromalacia perforans. Kaohsiung J Med Sci 2005; 21:233–235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Foster CS, Jabbur NS, Baltatzis S. Ocular characteristics and disease associations in scleritis-associated peripheral keratopathy. Arch Ophthalmol 19602002; 120:15–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung CMG, Chee SP. Posterior scleritis in children: clinical features and treatment. Ophthalmology 2012; 119:59–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agrawal R, Lavric A, Restori M, Pavesio C, Sagoo MS. Nodular posterior scleritis: clinico-sonographic characteristics and proposed diagnostic criteria. Retina Phila Pa 2016; 36:392–401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fiebai B, Padhi TR, Panda KG, Modi RR. Posterior scleritis with retinal pigment epithelium rip: an unusual presentation. Int Ophthalmol 2015; 35:141–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilhelmus KR, Grierson I, Watson PG. Histopathologic and clinical associations of scleritis and glaucoma. Am J Ophthalmol 1981; 91:697–705.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamei RW. Posterior scleritis associated with central retinal vein occlusion and cystoid macular edema: case report. Arq Bras Oftalmol 2012; 75:358–360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stead RE, Mokashi A, Subramaniam S. Bilateral disc swelling associated with posterior scleritis. Eye Lond Engl 2010; 24:1422–1423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ugurbas SH, Alpay A, Ugurbas SC. Posterior scleritis presenting with angle closure glaucoma. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2012; 20:218–220.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain SS, Rao P, Kothari K, Bhatt D, Jain S. Posterior scleritis presenting as unilateral secondary angle-closure glaucoma. Indian J Ophthalmol 2004; 52:241–244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quinlan MP, Hitchings RA. Angle-closure glaucoma secondary to posterior scleritis. Br J Ophthalmol 1978; 62:330–335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeda N, Ikeda T, Nomura C, Mimura O. Ciliochoroidal effusion syndrome associated with posterior scleritis. Jpn J Ophthalmol 2007; 51:49–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litwak AB. Posterior scleritis with secondary ciliochoroidal effusion. J Am Optom Assoc 1989; 60:300–306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sen HN, Sangave AA, Goldstein DA, et al. A standardized grading system for scleritis. Ophthalmology 2011; 118:768–771.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCluskey P, Wakefield D. Prediction of response to treatment in patients with scleritis using a standardised scoring system. Aust N Z J Ophthalmol 1991; 19:211–215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bashir H, Sridhar U, Mazumdar S, Tripathy K. Panscleritis masquerading as an attack of primary acute angle-closure glaucoma. GMS Ophthalmol Cases 2019; 9:Doc31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinz C, Bograd N, Koch J, Heiligenhaus A. Ocular hypertension and glaucoma incidence in patients with scleritis. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol 2013; 251:139–142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palkar A, Sudharshan S, George AE, Ganesh SK, Biswas J, Dutta Majumder P. Cataract surgery in the setting of scleritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2020; 1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axmann S, Ebneter A, Zinkernagel MS. Imaging of the sclera in patients with scleritis and episcleritis using anterior segment optical coherence tomography. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2016; 24:29–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levison AL, Lowder CY, Baynes KM, Kaiser PK, Srivastava SK. Anterior segment spectral domain optical coherence tomography imaging of patients with anterior scleritis. Int Ophthalmol 2016; 36:499–508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson P, Romano A. The impact of new methods of investigation and treatment on the understanding of the pathology of scleral inflammation. Eye 2014; 28:915–930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biswas J, Mittal S, Ganesh SK, Shetty NS, Gopal L. Posterior scleritis: clinical profile and imaging characteristics. Indian J Ophthalmol 1998; 46:195–202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diogo MC, Jager MJ, Ferreira TA. CT and MR imaging in the diagnosis of scleritis. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 2016; 37:2334–2339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Auer C, Herbort CP. Indocyanine green angiographic features in posterior scleritis. Am J Ophthalmol 1998; 126 (3):471–476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal AM, Dutta Majumder P. Tubercular posterior scleritis: a case report and review of literature. Indian J Ophthalmol 2019; 67:1362–1365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taki W, Keino H, Watanabe T, Okada AA. Enhanced depth imaging optical coherence tomography of the choroid in recurrent unilateral posterior scleritis. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol 2013; 251:1003–1004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin P, Bhullar SS, Tessler HH, Goldstein DA. Immunologic markers as potential predictors of systemic autoimmune disease in patients with idiopathic scleritis. Am J Ophthalmol 2008; 145:463–471.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soukiasian SH, Foster CS, Niles JL, Raizman MB. Diagnostic value of anti-neutrophil cytoplasmic antibodies in scleritis associated with Wegener granulomatosis. Ophthalmology 1992; 99:125–132.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derzko-Dzulynsky L. IgG4-related disease in the eye and ocular adnexa. Curr Opin Ophthalmol 2017; 28:617–622.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Foster CS. Necrotizing scleritis after ocular surgery. A clinicopathologic study. Ophthalmology 1991; 98:1720–1726.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Hemady RK, Foster CS. Infectious scleritis: report of four cases. Doc Ophthalmol Adv Ophthalmol 1993; 83:33–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hwang YS, Chen YF, Lai CC, Chen HSL, Hsiao CH. Infectious scleritis after use of immunomodulators. Arch Ophthalmol 2002; 120:1093–1094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biswas J, Aparna AC, Annamalai R, Vaijayanthi K, Bagyalakshmi R. Tuberculous scleritis in a patient with rheumatoid arthritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2012; 20:49–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaliki S, Freitag SK, Chodosh J. Nodulo-ulcerative ocular surface squamous neoplasia in 6 patients: a rare presentation. Cornea 2017; 36:322–326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shields JA, Augsburger JJ, Brown GC, Stephens RF. The differential diagnosis of posterior uveal melanoma. Ophthalmology 1980; 87:518–522.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kafkala C, Daoud YJ, Paredes I, Foster CS. Masquerade scleritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2005; 13:479–482.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Molina N, Gonzalez-Gonzalez LA, Doctor PP, Tauber J, Foster CS. Scleritis therapy. Ophthalmology 2012; 119:51–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>2016; Agrawal R, Lee CS, Gonzalez-Lopez JJ, Khan S, Rodrigues V, Pavesio C. Flurbiprofen: a nonselective cyclooxygenase (COX) inhibitor for treatment of noninfectious, nonnecrotizing anterior scleritis. 24:35–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gumus K, Mirza GE, Cavanagh HD, Karakucuk S. Topical cyclosporine A as a steroid-sparing agent in steroid-dependent idiopathic ocular myositis with scleritis: a case report and review of the literature. Eye Contact Lens 2009; 35:275–278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yazu H, Miyazaki D, Fujishima H. Experience with 0.1% tacrolimus eye drop for noninfectious, nonnecrotizing anterior scleritis. Eye Contact Lens 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee YJ, Kim SW, Seo KY. Application for tacrolimus ointment in treating refractory inflammatory ocular surface diseases. Am J Ophthalmol 2013; 155:804–813.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson KS, Chu DS. Evaluation of sub-Tenon triamcinolone acetonide injections in the treatment of scleritis. Am J Ophthalmol 2010; 149:77–81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sohn EH, Wang R, Read R, et al. Long-term, multicenter evaluation of subconjunctival injection of triamcinolone for nonnecrotizing, noninfectious anterior scleritis. Ophthalmology 2011; 118:1932–1937.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roufas A, Jalaludin B, Gaskin C, McCluskey P. Subconjunctival triamcinolone treatment for nonnecrotizing anterior scleritis. Br J Ophthalmol 2010; 94:743–747.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamir E, Read RW, Smith RE, Wang RC, Rao NA. A prospective evaluation of subconjunctival injection of triamcinolone acetonide for resistant anterior scleritis. Ophthalmology 2002; 109:798–805.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozzello DJ, Kolfenbach JR, Palestine AG. Uveitis specialists and rheumatologists select different therapies for idiopathic nonnecrotizing anterior scleritis. Ophthalmol Ther 2016; 5:245–252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gangaputra S, Newcomb CW, Liesegang TL, et al. Methotrexate for ocular inflammatory diseases. Ophthalmology 2009; 116:2188–2198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pasadhika S, Kempen JH, Newcomb CW, et al. Azathioprine for ocular inflammatory diseases. Am J Ophthalmol 2009; 148:500–509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoang-Xaun T, Foster CS, Rice BA. Scleritis in relapsing polychondritis. Response to therapy. Ophthalmology 1990; 97:892–898.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellado F, Talesnik E, Castiglione E. Azathioprine as monotherapy for scleritis in relapsing polychondritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2012; 20:235–236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniel E, Thorne JE, Newcomb CW, et al. Mycophenolate mofetil for ocular inflammation. Am J Ophthalmol 2010; 149:423–432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathinam SR, Gonzales JA, Thundikandy R, et al. Effect of corticosteroid-sparing treatment with mycophenolate mofetil vs methotrexate on inflammation in patients with uveitis. JAMA 2019; 322:936–945.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pujari SS, Kempen JH, Newcomb CW, et al. Cyclophosphamide for ocular inflammatory diseases. Ophthalmology 2010; 117:356–365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeon HS, Hyon JY, Kim MK, et al. Efficacy and safety of immunosuppressive agents in the treatment of necrotising scleritis: a retrospective, multicentre study in Korea. Br J Ophthalmol 2016; 100:1066–1070.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sen HN, Sangave A, Hammel K, Levy-Clarke G, Nussenblatt RB. Infliximab for the treatment of active scleritis. Can J Ophthalmol 2009; 44:e9–e12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma SM, Damato E, Hinchcliffe AE, et al. Long-term efficacy and tolerability of TNF-alpha inhibitors in the treatment of noninfectious ocular inflammation: an 8-year prospective surveillance study. Br J Ophthalmol 2019; 312767.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabiani C, Sota J, Sainz de la Maza M, et al. Effectiveness of TNF-alpha blockade in the treatment of refractory noninfectious scleritis: a multicenter study. Clin Exp Rheumatol 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suhler EB, Lim LL, Beardsley RM, et al. Rituximab therapy for refractory scleritis: results of a phase I/II dose-ranging, randomized, clinical trial. Ophthalmology 2014; 121:1885–1891.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joshi L, Tanna A, McAdoo SP, et al. Long-term outcomes of rituximab therapy in ocular granulomatosis with polyangiitis: impact on localized and nonlocalized disease. Ophthalmology 2015; 122:1262–1268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao JH, Oray M, Cocho L, Foster CS. Rituximab in the treatment of refractory noninfectious scleritis. Am J Ophthalmol 2016; 164:22–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz-Medrano J, Díaz-Valle D, Cuiña R, et al. The role of tocilizumab in the treatment of inflammatory diseases of the eye and orbit: a useful alternative. J Fr Ophtalmol 2018; 41:759–766.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poelman HJ, Van Daele PLA, Rothova A. Successful tocilizumab treatment for scleritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2020; 28:285–287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimizu H, Nishioka H. Successful treatment with tocilizumab for refractory scleritis associated with relapsing polychondritis. Scand J Rheumatol 2017; 46:418–419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabiani C, Sota J, Sainz de la Maza M, et al. New potential weapons for refractory scleritis in the era of targeted therapy. Mediators Inflamm 2020; 8294560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iijima T, Suwabe T, Sumida K, et al. Tocilizumab improves systemic rheumatoid vasculitis with necrotizing crescentic glomerulonephritis. Mod Rheumatol 2015; 25:138–142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michael E, Lange EL, Guest S. Paradoxical nodular scleritis during tocilizumab therapy: a case report. J Rheumatol 2017; 44:1760–1761.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paley MA, Karacal H, Rao PK, Margolis TP, Miner JJ. Tofacitinib for refractory uveitis and scleritis. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2019; 13:53–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erkanli L, Akova YA, Guney-Tefekli E, Tugal-Tutkun I. Clinical features, prognosis, and treatment results of patients with scleritis from 2 tertiary eye care centers in Turkey. Cornea 2010; 29:26–33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bin Ismail MA, Lim RHF, Fang HM, et al. Ocular Autoimmune Systemic Inflammatory Infectious Study (OASIS)-report 4: analysis and outcome of scleritis in an East Asian population. J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect 2017; 7:6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu TT, Reynolds MM, Hodge DO, Smith WM. Epidemiology and clinical characteristics of episcleritis and scleritis in Olmsted County, MN. Am J Ophthalmol 2020; 217:317–324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abd El Latif E, Seleet MM, El Hennawi H, et al. Pattern of scleritis in an Egyptian cohort. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2019; 27:890–896.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn SJ, Oh JY, Kim MK, Lee JH, Wee WR. Clinical features, predisposing factors, and treatment outcomes of scleritis in the Korean population. Korean J Ophthalmol KJO 2010; 24:331–335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
