<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33301509</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>12</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>PloS one</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Structure of the pecten neuropil pathway and its innervation by bimodal peg afferents in two scorpion species.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0243753</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0243753</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0243753</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0243753</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The pectines of scorpions are comb-like structures, located ventrally behind the fourth walking legs and consisting of variable numbers of teeth, or pegs, which contain thousands of bimodal peg sensillae. The associated neuropils are situated ventrally in the synganglion, extending between the second and fourth walking leg neuromeres. While the general morphology is consistent among scorpions, taxon-specific differences in pecten and neuropil structure remain elusive but are crucial for a better understanding of chemosensory processing. We analysed two scorpion species (Mesobuthus eupeus and Heterometrus petersii) regarding their pecten neuropil anatomy and the respective peg afferent innervation with anterograde and lipophilic tracing experiments, combined with immunohistochemistry and confocal laser-scanning microscopy. The pecten neuropils consisted of three subcompartments: a posterior pecten neuropil, an anterior pecten neuropil and a hitherto unknown accessory pecten neuropil. These subregions exhibited taxon-specific variations with regard to compartmentalisation and structure. Most notable were structural differences in the anterior pecten neuropils that ranged from ovoid shape and strong fragmentation in Heterometrus petersii to elongated shape with little compartmentalisation in Mesobuthus eupeus. Labelling the afferents of distinct pegs revealed a topographic organisation of the bimodal projections along a medio-lateral axis. At the same time, all subregions along the posterior-anterior axis were innervated by a single peg's afferents. The somatotopic projection pattern of bimodal sensillae appears to be common among arachnids, including scorpions. This includes the structure and organisation of the respective neuropils and the somatotopic projection patterns of chemosensory afferents. Nonetheless, the scorpion pecten pathway exhibits unique features, e.g. glomerular compartmentalisation superimposed on somatotopy, that are assumed to allow high resolution of substrate-borne chemical gradients.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Drozd</LastName>
            <ForeName>Denise</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2751-2690</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neurobiology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wolf</LastName>
            <ForeName>Harald</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neurobiology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stemme</LastName>
            <ForeName>Torben</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neurobiology, University of Ulm, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002628" MajorTopicYN="N">Chemoreceptor Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019581" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropil</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012605" MajorTopicYN="N">Scorpions</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="Y">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301509</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7728269</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0243753</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-20-21246</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dethier VG. Chemical Insect Attractants and Repellents. Rev Entomol. 1947;1: 181–202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hildebrand JG, Shepherd GM. Mechanism of olfactory discrimination: converging evidence for common principles across phyla. Annu Rev Neurosci. 1997;20: 595–631. 10.1146/annurev.neuro.20.1.595
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.neuro.20.1.595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9056726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisthen HL. Why Are Olfactory Systems of Different Animals So Similar?
Brain Behav Evol. 2002;59: 273–293. 10.1159/000063564
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000063564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12207084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zacharuk RY. Ultrastructure and Function of Insect Chemosensilla. Rev Entomol. 1980;25: 27–47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinbrecht RA. Functional morphology of pheromone-sensitive sensilla In Prestwich GD, Blomquist GJ, editors. Pheromone Biochemistry. Academic Press; 
1987.  p. 353–384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tichy H, Barth FG. Fine structure of olfactory sensilla in myriapods and arachnids. Microsc Res Tech. 1992;22: 372–391. 10.1002/jemt.1070220406
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.1070220406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1392066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Homberg U, Christensen TA, Hildebrand JG. Structure and function of the deutocerebrum in insects. Rev Entomol. 1989;34: 477–501. 10.1146/annurev.en.34.010189.002401
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.en.34.010189.002401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2648971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson BS, Christensen TA. Functional characteristics of the antennal lobe In: Hansson BS, editor. Insect Olfaction. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 1999.  pp.125–161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ignell R, Anton S, Hansson BS. The antennal lobe of Orthoptera–Anatomy and Evolution. Brain Behav Evol. 2001;57: 1–17. 10.1159/000047222
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000047222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11359044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loesel R, Wolf H, Kenning M, Harzsch S, Sombke A. Architectural principles and evolution of the arthropod central nervous system In: Minelli A, Boxshall G, Fusco G, editors. Arthropod Biology and Evolution: Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2013.  pp. 299–342.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf H. The pectine organs of the scorpion, Vaejovis spinigerus: Structure and (glomerular) central projections. Arthropod Struct Dev. 2008;37: 67–80. 10.1016/j.asd.2007.05.003
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2007.05.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18089128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke A, Klann AE, Lipke E, Wolf H. Primary processing neuropils associated with the malleoli of camel spiders (Arachnida, Solifugae): a re-evaluation of axonal pathways. Zool Lett. 2019;5: 26
10.1186/s40851-019-0137-z
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40851-019-0137-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6679463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31388441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke A, Harzsch S, Hansson BS. Organization of deutocerebral neuropils and olfactory behavior in the centipede Scutigera coleoptrata (Linnaeus, 1758) (Myriapoda: Chilopoda). Chem Senses. 2011;36: 43–61. 10.1093/chemse/bjq096
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/chemse/bjq096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20962283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke A, Lipke E, Kenning M, Müller CHG, Hansson BS. Comparative analysis of deutocerebral neuropils in Chilopoda (Myriapoda): implications for the evolution of the arthropod olfactory system and support for the Mandibulata concept. BMC Neurosci. 2012;13: 1
10.1186/1471-2202-13-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2202-13-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3320525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22214384</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schachtner J, Schmidt M, Homberg U. Organization and evolutionary trends of primary olfactory brain centers in Tetraconata (Crustacea + Hexapoda). Arthropod Struct Dev. 2005;34: 257–299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stemme T, Iliffe TM, Bicker G, Harzsch S, Koenemann S. Serotonin immunoreactive interneurons in the brain of the Remipedia: new insights into the phylogenetic affinities of an enigmatic crustacean taxon. BMC Evol Biol. 2012;12: 168
10.1186/1471-2148-12-168
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2148-12-168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3497878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22947030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stegner MEJ, Richter S. Morphology of the brain in Hutchinsoniella macracantha (Cephalocarida, Crustacea). Arthropod Struct Dev. 2011;40: 221–243. 10.1016/j.asd.2011.04.001
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2011.04.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21679884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch S, Krieger J. Crustacean olfactory systems: A comparative review and a crustacean perspective on olfaction in insects. Prog Neurobiol. 2018;161: 23–60. 10.1016/j.pneurobio.2017.11.005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pneurobio.2017.11.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson BS, Anton S. Function and Morphology of the Antennal Lobe: New Developments. Annu Rev Entomol. 2000;45: 203–231. 10.1146/annurev.ento.45.1.203
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.ento.45.1.203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10761576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld NJ, Hildebrand JG. Olfactory systems: common design, uncommon origins?
Curr Opin Neurol. 1999;9: 634–639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10508748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ache BW, Young JM. Olfaction: Diverse Species, Conserved Principles. Neuron. 2005;48: 417–430. 10.1016/j.neuron.2005.10.022
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2005.10.022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anton S, Barth FG. Central nervous projection patterns of trichobothria and other cuticular sensilla in the wandering spider Cupiennius salei (Arachnida, Araneae). Zoomorphology. 1993;113: 21–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorb SN, Anton S, Barth FG. Central projections of cheliceral mechanoreceptors in the spider Cupiennius salei (Arachnida, Araneae). J Morphol. 1993;217: 129–136. 10.1002/jmor.1052170202
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.1052170202</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29865459</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babu KS, Barth FG. Central nervous projections of mechanoreceptors in the spider Cupiennius salei Keys. Cell Tissue Res. 1989;258: 69–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babu KS, Sreenivasulu K, Sekhar V. Sensory projections of identified coxal hair sensilla of the scorpion Heterometrus fulvipes (Scorpionidae). J Biosci. 1993;18: 247–259.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen Duy-Jacquemin M, Arnold G. Spatial organization of the antennal lobe in Cylindroiulus punctatus (Leach) (Myriapoda: Diplopoda), Int J Insect Morphol Embryo. 1991;20: 205–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt M, Van Ekeris L, Ache BW. Antennular projections to the midbrain of the spiny lobster. I. Sensory innervation of the lateral and medial antennular neuropils. J Comp Neurol. 1992;318: 277–290. 10.1002/cne.903180305
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.903180305</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1583163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuchina O, Koczan S, Harzsch S, Rybak J, Wolff G, Strausfeld NJ, et al.
Central projections of antennular chemosensory and mechanosensory afferents in the brain of the terrestrial hermit crab (Coenobita clypeatus; Coenobitidae, Anomura). Front Neuroanat. 2015;9: 94
10.3389/fnana.2015.00094
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnana.2015.00094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4502362</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26236202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derby CD, Kozma MT, Senatore A, Schmidt M. Molecular Mechanisms of Reception and Perireception in Crustacean Chemoreception: A Comparative Review. Chem Senses. 2016;4: 381–398. 10.1093/chemse/bjw057
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/chemse/bjw057</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27107425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghysen A. The Projection of Sensory Neurons in the Central Nervous System of Drosophila: Choice of the Appropriate Pathway. Dev Biol. 1980;78: 521–541. 10.1016/0012-1606(80)90351-6
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0012-1606(80)90351-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7409313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levine RB, Pak C, Linn D. The structure, function and metamorphic reorganisation of somatotopically projecting sensory neurons of Manduca sexta larvae. J Comp Physiol A. 1985;157: 1–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent KS, Levine RB. Neural control of leg movements in a metamorphic insect: Sensory and motor elements of the larval thoracic legs in Manduca sexta. J Comp Neurol. 1988;271: 559–576. 10.1002/cne.902710407
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.902710407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3385017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pflüger H.-j, Bräunig P, Hustert R. The organization of mechanosensory neuropiles in locust thoracic ganglia. Phil Trans R Soc Lond B. 1988;321: 1–26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson BA, Weeks JC. Somatotopic mapping of sensory neurons innervating mechanosensory hairs on the larval prolegs of Manduca sexta. J Comp Neurol. 1988;275: 128–144. 10.1002/cne.902750111
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.902750111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3170788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newland PL. Morphology and somatotopic organisation of the central projections of afferents from tactile hairs on the hind leg of the locust. J Comp Neurol. 1991;312: 493–508. 10.1002/cne.903120402
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.903120402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1761738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newland PL, Rogers SM, Gaaboub I, Matheson T. Parallel somatotopic maps of gustatory and mechanosensory neurons in the central nervous system of an insect. J Comp Neurol. 2000;425: 82–96. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10940944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foelix RF, Schabronath J. The fine structure of scorpion sensory organs. I. Tarsal sensilla. Bull Br Arachnol Soc. 1983;6: 53–67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edgecombe RS, Murdock LL. Central projections of axons from taste hairs on the labellum and tarsi of the blowfly, Phormia regina Meigen. J Comp Neurol. 1992;315: 431–444. 10.1002/cne.903150406
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.903150406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1373158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stocker RF. The organization of the chemosensory system in Drosophila melanogaster: a review. Cell Tissue Res. 1994;275: 3–26. 10.1007/BF00305372
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00305372</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8118845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Brito Sanchez MG, Lorenzo E, Songkung S, Liu F, Giurfa M. The tarsal taste of honey bees: behavioral and electrophysiological analyses. Front Behav Neurosci. 2014;8: 25
10.3389/fnbeh.2014.00025
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnbeh.2014.00025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913880</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellon DF. Smelling, feeling, tasting and touching: behavioral and neural integration of antennular chemosensory and mechanosensory inputs in the crayfish. J Exp Biol. 2012;215: 2163–2172. 10.1242/jeb.069492
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/jeb.069492</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22675176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers SM, Newland PL. The neurobiology of taste in insects In: Simpson SJ, editor. Advances in insect physiology. Elsevier Academic Press; 2003;31: pp.141–204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell BK, Itagaki H, Rivet MP. Peripheral and central structures involved in insect gustation. Microsc Res Tech. 1999;47: 401–415. 10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19991215)47:6&amp;lt;401::AID-JEMT4&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-7
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19991215)47:6&amp;lt;401::AID-JEMT4&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10607380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kvello P, Jørgensen K, Mustaparta H. Central Gustatory Neurons Integrate Taste Quality Information From Four Appendages in the Moth Heliothis virescens. J Neurophysiol. 2010;103: 2965–2981. 10.1152/jn.00985.2009
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00985.2009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20220075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishino H, Nishikawa M, Yokohari F, Mizunami M. Dual, multilayered somatosensory maps formed by antennal tactile and contact chemosensory afferents in an insect brain. J Comp Neurol. 2005;493: 291–308. 10.1002/cne.20757
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.20757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16255033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ai H, Nishino H, Itoh T. Topographic organization of sensory afferents of Johnston's organ in the honeybee brain. J Comp Neurol. 2007;502: 1030–1046. 10.1002/cne.21341
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.21341</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17444491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foelix RF. Mechano- and chemoreceptive sensilla In: Barth FG, editor. Neurobiology of arachnids. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 1985.  p. 118–137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anton S, Tichy H. Hygro- and thermoreceptors in tip-pore sensilla of the tarsal organ of the spider Cupiennius salei: innervation and central projection. Cell Tissue Res. 1994;278: 399–407.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barth FG. Spider mechanoreceptors. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2004;14: 415–422. 10.1016/j.conb.2004.07.005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conb.2004.07.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15321061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obenchain FD. Structure and anatomical relationships of the synganglion in the American dog tick, Dermacentor variabilis (Acari: Ixodiadae). J Morphol. 1974;142: 205–223. 10.1002/jmor.1051420207
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.1051420207</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30326679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willemart RH, Gnaspini P. Comparative Density of Hair Sensilla on the Legs of Cavernicolous and Epigean Harvestmen (Arachnida: Opiliones). Zool Anz. 2004;242: 353–365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willemart RH, Farine JP, Gnaspini P. Sensory biology of Phalangida harvestmen (Arachnida, Opiliones): a review, with new morphological data on 18 species. Acta Zool. 2009;90: 209–227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haupt J. Hair regeneration in a solfugid chemotactile sensillum. Roux`s Archives of Developtmental Biology. 1982;191: 137–142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28305100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauchhenss E. Morphology and ultrastructure of sensilla ampullaceal in Solifugae (chelicerata: arachnida). Int J Insect Morphol Embryol. 1983;12: 129–138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cushing PE, Casto P. Preliminary survey of the setal and sensory structures on the pedipalps of camel spiders (Arachnida: Solifugae). J Arachnol. 2012;40:123–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenbeis G, Wichard W. Atlas on the biology of soil arthropods
Berlin and New York: Springer; 1987.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Igelmund P. Morphology, sense organs, and regeneration of the forelegs (whips) of the whip spider Heterophrynus elaphus (Arachnida, Amblypygi). J Morphol. 1987;193: 75–89. 10.1002/jmor.1051930108
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.1051930108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29921113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schultz JW. Morphology of locomotor appendages in Arachnida: evolutionary trends and phylogenetic implications. Zool J Linnean Soc. 1989;97: 1–56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Igelmund P, Wendler G. The giant fiber system in the forelegs (whips) of the whip spider Heterophrynus elaphus Pocock (Arachnida: Amblypygi). J Comp Physiol A. 1991;168: 63–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Igelmund P, Wendler G. Morphology and physiology of peripheral giant interneurons in the forelegs (whips) of the whip spider Heterophrynus elaphus Pocock (Arachnida: Amblypygi). J Comp Physiol A. 1991;168: 75–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weygoldt P. Whip Spiders
Their Biology, Morphology and Systematics (Chelicerata: Amblypygi. Stenstrup: Apollo Books; 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foelix RF, Hebets E. Sensory Biology of Whip Spiders (Arachnida, Amblypygi). Andrias. 2001;129–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moro SD, Geethabali. Distribution of cuticular sensory hairs on the legs and whip of Thelyphonus indicus stoliczka (Arachnida Uropygi). Ital J Zool. 1985;19: 207–218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brownell PH, Farley RD. The organization of the malleolar sensory system in the solpugid, Chanbria sp. Tissue Cell.1974;6: 471–485. 10.1016/0040-8166(74)90039-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0040-8166(74)90039-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4432235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carthy JD. Fine structure and function of the sensory pegs on the scorpion pecten. Experientia. 1966;22: 89–91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brownell PH. Properties and function of the pectine chemosensory system of scorpions. Chem Senses. 1988;13: 677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson GJ. Chaetotaxy and setal morphology of the palps and first tarsi of Phytoseiulus persimilis A.H. (Acarina: Phytoseiidae). Acarologia. 1974;16: 583–594.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jagers op Akkerhuis G, Sabelis MW, Tjallingi WF. Ultrastructure of chemoreceptors on the pedipalps and first tarsi of Phytoseiulus persimilis. Exp Appl Acarol. 1985;1: 235–251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Wijk M, Wadman WJ, Sabelis MW. Morphology of the olfactory system in the predatory mite Phytoseiulus Persimilis. Exp Appl Acarol. 2006;40: 217–229. 10.1007/s10493-006-9038-x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10493-006-9038-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17245560</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hummel NA, Li AY, Witt CM. Serotonin-like immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of two ixodid tick species. Exp Appl Acarol. 2007;43: 265–278. 10.1007/s10493-007-9120-z
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10493-007-9120-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18040871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rühlemann H. Über die Fächerorgane, sog. Malleoli oder Raquettes coxales, des vierten Beinpaares der Solpugiden. Zeitschrift fuer wiss Zoologie. 1908;91: 599–641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babu K.S. Anatomy of the central nervous system of arachnids. Zool Jb Anat. 1965;82: 1–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brownell PH. Glomerular Cytoarchitectures in Chemosensory Systems of Arachnids. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1998;855: 502–507. 10.1111/j.1749-6632.1998.tb10614.x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1998.tb10614.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melville JM. The pectines of scorpions: analysis of structure and function. Dissertation. Corvallis: Oregon State University; 2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foelix RF, Müller-Vorholt G. The fine structure of scorpion sensory organs. II. Pecten sensilla. Bull Br Arachnol Soc. 1983;6: 68–74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD, Brownell PH. Evidence of Chemical Signaling in the Sand Scorpion, Paruroctonus mesaensis (Scorpionida: Vaejovida). Ethology.1992;91: 59–69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf H. Scorpions pectines—Idiosyncratic chemo- and mechanosensory organs. Arthropod Struct Dev. 2017;46: 753–764. 10.1016/j.asd.2017.10.002
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2017.10.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29061448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ivanov VP, Balashov YS. The structural and functional organization of the pectine in a scorpion, Buthus eupeus, studied by electron microscopy In: Balashov YS, editor. The fauna and ecology of Arachnida. Leningrad: Tr Zool Inst Leningr; 
1979;85: 73–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fet V, Polis GA, Sissom WD. Life in sandy deserts: the scorpion model. J Arid Environ. 1998;39: 609–622.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jędrzejowska I, Szymusiak K, Mazurkiewicz-Kania M, Garbiec A. Scorpion katoikogenic ovariuterus- much more alike to apoikogenic type than it seemed to be. Arthropod Struct Dev. 2016;45: 488–495. 10.1016/j.asd.2016.09.001
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2016.09.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27645113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kladt N, Wolf H, Heinzel H. Mechanoreception by cuticular sensilla on the pectines of the scorpion Pandinus cavimanus. J Comp Physiol A. 2007;193: 1033–1043. 10.1007/s00359-007-0254-6
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00359-007-0254-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17713768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slifer EH. The Structure of Arthropod Chemoreceptors. Rev Entomol. 1970;15: 121–142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD. Chemosensory physiology and behavior of the desert sand scorpion, Paruroctonus Mesaensis. [Dissertation]. Corvallis: Oregon State University; 1994.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallberg E, Hansson BS. Arthropod sensilla: Morphology and phylogenetic considerations. Microsc Res Tech. 1999;47: 428–439. 10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19991215)47:6&amp;lt;428::AID-JEMT6&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-P
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19991215)47:6&amp;lt;428::AID-JEMT6&amp;gt;3.0.CO;2-P</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10607382</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foelix RF. Structure and function of tarsal sensilla in the spider Araneus diadematus. J Exp Zool. 1970;175: 99–124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krapf D. Contact Chemoreception of Prey in Hunting Scorpions (Arachnida: Scorpiones). Zool Anz. 1986;217: 119–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD, Brownell PH. Chemosensory behaviour and physiology In: Scorpion Biology and Research. Brownell PH, Polis GA, editors. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2001.  pp. 184–203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melville JM, Tallarovic K, Brownell PH. Evidence of Mate Trailing in the Giant Hairy Desert Scorpion, Hadrurus arizonensis (Scorpionida, Iuridae). J Insect Behav. 2003;16: 97–115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinmetz SB, Bost KC, Gaffin DD. Response of Male Centruroides vittatus (Scorpiones: Buthidae) to Aerial and Substrate-Borne Chemical Signals. Euscorpius. 2004;12: 1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD, Bumm LA, Taylor MS, Popokina NV, Mann S. Scorpion fluorescence and reaction to light. Anim Behav. 2012;83: 429–436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prévost ED, Stemme T. Non-visual homing and the current status of navigation in scorpions. Anim Cogn. 2020; 10.1007/s10071-020-01386-z
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10071-020-01386-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7700070</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32350712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD, Brayfield BP. Exploring the chemo-textural familiarity hypothesis for scorpion navigation. J Arachnol. 2017;45: 265–270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musaelian A, Gaffin DD. High-throughput simulations indicate feasibility of navigation by familiarity with a local sensor such as scorpion pectines. BioRxiv. 2020. 
10.1101/2020.06.17.156612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.06.17.156612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drozd D. Topographic Organization of the Pectine Neuropils in Scorpions: An Analysis of Chemosensory Afferents and the Projection Pattern in the Central Nervous. Wiesbaden: Springer Spectrum; 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsubayashi Y, Iwai L, Kawasakia H. Fluorescent doublelabeling with carbocyanine neuronal tracing and immunohistochemistry using a cholesterol-specific detergent digitonin. J Neurosci Methods. 2008;174: 71–81. 10.1016/j.jneumeth.2008.07.003
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneumeth.2008.07.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18674563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klagges BRE, Heimbeck G, Godenschwege TA, Hofbauer A, Pflugfelder GO, Reifegerste R, et al.
Invertebrate Synapsins: A Single Gene Codes for Several Isoforms in Drosophila. J Neurosci.1996;16: 3154–3165. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.16-10-03154.1996
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.16-10-03154.1996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6579133</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8627354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch S, Hansson BS. Brain architecture in the terrestrial hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomura, Coenobitidae), a crustacean with a good aerial sense of smell. BMC Neurosci. 2008;9: 58
10.1186/1471-2202-9-58
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2202-9-58</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2459186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18590553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Groh C, Rössler W. Comparison of microglomerular structures in the mushroom body calyx of neopteran insects. Arthropod Struct Dev. 2010;40: 358–367. 10.1016/j.asd.2010.12.002
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2010.12.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21185946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stemme T, Iliffe TM, von Reumont B M, Koenemann S, Harzsch S, Bicker G. Serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in the ventral nerve cord of Remipedia (Crustacea): support for a sister group relationship of Remipedia and Hexapoda?
BMC Evol Biol. 2013;13: 119
10.1186/1471-2148-13-119
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2148-13-119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3687579</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23758940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabian-Fine R, Volknandt W, Seyfarth E. Peripheral synapses at identifiable mechanosensory neurons in the spider Cupiennius salei: synapsin-like immunoreactivity. Cell Tissue Res. 1999;295: 13–19. 10.1007/s004410051208
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s004410051208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9931349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurer M, Hladik J, Iliffe TM, Stemme T. Histaminergic interneurons in the ventral nerve cord: assessment of their value for Euarthropod phylogeny. Zool Lett. 2019;5: 36
10.1186/s40851-019-0151-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40851-019-0151-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6929356</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreis TE. Microtubules containing detyrosinated tubulin are less dynamic. EMBO J. 1987;6: 2597–2606. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC553680</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3315650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cloudsley-Thompson JL. On the function of the pectines of scorpions. Mag Nat Hist Alternative. 1955;2: 556–560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD, Brownell PH. Response properties of chemosensory peg sensilla on the pectines of scorpions. J Comp Physiol A. 1997;181: 291–300. 10.1007/s003590050115
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s003590050115</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9309869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mineo MF, Claro DK. Mechanoreceptive function of pectines in the Brazilian yellow scorpion Tityus serrulatus: perception of substrate-borne vibrations and prey detection. Acta Ethol. 2006;9: 79–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaffin DD. Electrophysiological analysis of synaptic interactions within peg sensilla of scorpion pectines. Microsc Res Tech. 2002;58: 325–334. 10.1002/jemt.10140
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.10140</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12214299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knowlton ED, Gaffin DD. Functionally redundant peg sensilla on the scorpion pecten. J Comp Physiol A. 2011;197: 895–902. 10.1007/s00359-011-0650-9
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00359-011-0650-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf H, Harzsch S. Serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in scorpion pectine neuropils: similarities to insect and crustacean primary olfactory centres?
Zoology. 2012;115: 151–159. 10.1016/j.zool.2011.10.002
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.zool.2011.10.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22445574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes KL, Gaffin DD. Investigating sensory processing in the pectines of the striped bark scorpion, Centruroides vittatus. Invert Neurosci. 2019;19: 9
10.1007/s10158-019-0228-8
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10158-019-0228-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31367776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma PP, Fernández R, Esposito LA, Gonzalez-Santillan E, Monod L. Phylogenomic resolution of scorpions reveals multilevel discordance with morphological phylogenetic signal. Proc R Soc Lond. 2015;282: 2014–2953. 10.1098/rspb.2014.2953
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1098/rspb.2014.2953</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4375871</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25716788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babu KS. Patterns of Arrangement and Connectivity in the Central Nervous System of Arachnids In: Barth FG, editor. Neurobiology of Arachnids. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer;1985; pp. 3–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld N, Reisenman CE. Dimorphic Olfactory Lobes in the Arthropoda. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2009;1170: 487–496. 10.1111/j.1749-6632.2009.04020.x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2009.04020.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2801554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19686183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Punzo F. Natural history and life cycle of the solifuge Eremobates marathoni Muma &amp; Brookhart (Solifugae, Eremobatidae). Bull Br Arachnol Soc. 1998;11: 111–118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fet V, Soleglad ME, Brewer MS. Laterobasal Aculear Serrations (LAS) in Scorpion Family Vaejovidae (Scorpiones: Chactoidea). Euscorpius. 2006;45: 1–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fet V, Brewer MS, Soleglad ME, Neff DPA. Constellation Array: a new sensory structure in scorpions (Arachnida: Scorpiones). Bol SEA. 2006;38: 269–278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klann AE, Gromov AV, Cushing PE, Peretti AV, Alberti G. The anatomy and ultrastructure of the suctorial organ of Solifugae (Arachnida). Arthropod Struct Dev. 2008;37: 3–12. 10.1016/j.asd.2007.04.001
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2007.04.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18089124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruano F, Tinaut A, Soler JJ. High surface temperatures select for individual foraging in ants. Behav Ecol. 2000;1: 396–404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polis GA, McCormick SJ. Intraguild Predation and Competition Among Desert Scorpions. Ecology. 1987;68: 332–343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahsberg D.
Brood care and family cohesion in the tropical scorpion Pandinus imperator (Koch) (Scorpiones: Scorpionidae). Acta Zool Fennica. 1990;190: 267–272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willemart RH, Chelini MC. Experimental demonstration of close-range olfaction and contact chemoreception in the Brazilian harvestman, Iporangaia pustulosa. Entomol Exp Appl. 2007;123: 73–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gainett G, Michalik P, Müller CHG, Giribet G, Talarico G, Willemart RH. Ultrastructure of chemoreceptive tarsal sensilla in an armored harvestman and evidence of olfaction across Laniatores (Arachnida, Opiliones). Arthropod Struct Dev. 2017;46: 178–195. 10.1016/j.asd.2016.12.005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asd.2016.12.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28017815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borges LMF, Li AY, Olafson PU, Renthal R, Bauchan GR, Lohmeyer KH, et al.
Neuronal projections from the Haller’s organ and palp sensilla to the synganglion of Amblyomma americanum. Rev Bras Parasitol Vet. 2016;25: 1984–2961. 10.1590/S1984-29612016039
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1984-29612016039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27334823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia CG, Menzel R. Odour perception in honeybees: coding information in glomerular patterns. Curr Opin Neurbiol. 2000;10: 504–510. 10.1016/s0959-4388(00)00109-4
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0959-4388(00)00109-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10981621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia CG, Menzel R. The role of glomeruli in the neural representation of odours: results from optical recording studies. J Insect Physiol. 2001;47: 115–130. 10.1016/s0022-1910(00)00106-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-1910(00)00106-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11064019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson BS, Stensmyr MC. Evolution of Insect Olfaction. Cell Press, Neuron Review. 2011;72: 698–711. 10.1016/j.neuron.2011.11.003
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2011.11.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22153368</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barth FG. The Central Nervous System In: A Spider’s World. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger J, Braun P, Rivera NT, Schubart CD, Müller CHG, Harzsch S. Comparative analyses of olfactory systems in terrestrial crabs (Brachyura): evidence for aerial olfaction?
PeerJ. 2015;3:e1433
10.7717/peerj.1433
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.1433</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4690415</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26713228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
