<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33331989</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1950</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>81</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Drugs</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Drugs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Updated Overall Survival in a Randomized Study Comparing Dacomitinib with Gefitinib as First-Line Treatment in Patients with Advanced Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer and EGFR-Activating Mutations.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>257</StartPage>
          <EndPage>266</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>257-266</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40265-020-01441-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ARCHER 1050, an ongoing, randomized, open-label, phase III trial of dacomitinib versus gefitinib in newly diagnosed patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC) and an EGFR-activating mutation, reported significant improvement in overall survival (OS) with dacomitinib.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This paper reports an updated OS analysis of ARCHER 1050 after an extended follow-up.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this multinational, multicenter trial, adults (aged ≥ 18 years or ≥ 20 years in Japan and Korea) with newly diagnosed NSCLC and EGFR mutation (exon 19 deletion or exon 21 L858R substitution), and no history of central nervous system metastases, were randomized 1:1 to receive dacomitinib 45 mg/day (n = 227) or gefitinib 250 mg/day (n = 225). Randomization was stratified by race and EGFR mutation type. An ad hoc updated analysis of OS was conducted at the protocol-defined cut-off of 48 months from first dosing of the last enrolled patient (13 May 2019).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After a median follow-up of 47.9 months, 133 (58.6%) patients had died in the dacomitinib arm and 152 (67.6%) in the gefitinib arm. The hazard ratio (HR) for OS was 0.748 (95% CI 0.591-0.947; two-sided P = 0.0155); median OS was 34.1 months with dacomitinib versus 27.0 months with gefitinib. The HR for OS in patients with dose reduction(s) in the dacomitinib arm (n = 154) compared with all patients in the gefitinib arm was 0.554 (95% CI 0.420-0.730); median OS was 42.5 months for patients with dose reduction(s) in the dacomitinib arm. The most common adverse events were diarrhea (87.7%), paronychia (61.7%), dermatitis acneiform (49.3%), and stomatitis (43.6%) with dacomitinib, and diarrhea (55.8%) and alanine aminotransferase increased (40.2%) with gefitinib.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The OS benefit from first-line treatment with dacomitinib versus gefitinib was maintained after extended follow-up in patients with advanced NSCLC with EGFR-activating mutations. CLINICALTRIALS.GOV: NCT01774721 (registered 24 January 2013).</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mok</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tony S</ForeName>
            <Initials>TS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Translational Oncology, Department of Clinical Oncology, Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Jilin Provincial Cancer Hospital, Changchun, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiangdong</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital of Third Military Medical University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ki Hyeong</ForeName>
            <Initials>KH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Chungbuk National University Hospital, Chungbuk National University College of Medicine, Cheongju, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakagawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kindai University Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Niho</LastName>
            <ForeName>Seiji</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chawla</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alka</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>SFJ Pharmaceuticals®, Pleasanton, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rosell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rafael</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Catalan Institute of Oncology, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Corral</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jesus</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hospital Universitario Virgen del Rocio, Seville, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Migliorino</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria Rita</ForeName>
            <Initials>MR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pulmonary Oncology Unit, San Camillo-Forlanini Hospital, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pluzanski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adam</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Maria Sklodowska-Curie National Research Institute of Oncology, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Noonan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kay</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pfizer Inc., Groton, CT, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yiyun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pfizer Oncology, La Jolla, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pastel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Malaika</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pfizer Oncology, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wilner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Keith D</ForeName>
            <Initials>KD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pfizer Oncology, La Jolla, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi-Long</ForeName>
            <Initials>YL</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3611-0258</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Lung Cancer Institute, Guangdong General Hospital and Guangdong Academy of Medical Sciences, 106 Zhongshan Er Rd, Guangzhou, Guangdong, 510080, China. syylwu@live.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT01774721</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Drugs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7600076</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0012-6667</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D047428">Protein Kinase Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D052999">Quinazolinones</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>5092U85G58</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C525726">dacomitinib</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C512478">EGFR protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D066246">ErbB Receptors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>S65743JHBS</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077156">Gefitinib</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="N">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="N">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004305" MajorTopicYN="N">Dose-Response Relationship, Drug</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D066246" MajorTopicYN="N">ErbB Receptors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077156" MajorTopicYN="N">Gefitinib</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D047428" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Kinase Inhibitors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D052999" MajorTopicYN="N">Quinazolinones</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016019" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Tony Mok: grant/research funding (paid to institution): AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Clovis Oncology, G1 Therapeutics, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Merck Serono, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche, SFJ, Takeda, and XCovery; speaker’s fees: ACEA Pharma, Alpha Biopharma Co., Ltd., Amgen, Amoy Diagnostics Co., LTD., AstraZeneca (before Jan 2019), Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, InMed Medical Communication, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Pfizer, PrIME Oncology, Roche/Genentech, Taiho, and Takeda Oncology; honoraria for consultation services: Abbvie Inc., ACEA Pharma (since Aug 2018), Alpha Biopharma Co., Ltd., Amgen, Amoy Diagnostics Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca (before Jan 2019), Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Blueprint Medicines Corporation, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, CStone Pharmaceuticals, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Fishawack Facilitate Ltd., Hengrui Therapeutics Inc., Ignyta, Inc., Incyte Corporation, InMed Medical Communication, IQVIA, Janssen, Loxo-Oncology, Merck Serono, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, MoreHealth, Novartis, OncoGenex Pharmaceuticals, Inc., OrigiMed, PeerVoice, Pfizer, PrIME Oncology, Roche/Genentech, Sanofi-Aventis R&amp;D, SFJ Pharmaceutical Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceuticals HK Ltd., Vertex Pharmaceuticals, Yuhan Corporation, Medscape/WebMD (medical education/CME activities), PeerVoice (independent medical education), Prime Oncology (medical education); stock shareholder/option: Clearbridge Biomedics (now Biolidics Ltd.), Hutchison Chi-Med, Loxo-Oncology, OrigiMed Co. Ltd., Sanomics Ltd., and Virtus Medical Group; advisory board: Abbvie Inc., ACEA Pharma, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Blueprint Medicines Corporation, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Cirina, CStone Pharmaceuticals, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Fishawack Facilitate Ltd., G1 Therapeutics, Inc., geneDecode Co., Ltd. (uncompensated), Hengrui Therapeutics Inc., Hutchison Chi-Med, Ignyta, Inc., Incyte Corporation, IQVIA, Janssen, Loxo-Oncology, Lunit, Inc., Merck Serono, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, OncoGenex Technologies Inc., OrigiMed, Pfizer, Roche/Genentech, Sanofi-Aventis R&amp;D, SFJ Pharmaceutical, Takeda Oncology, Vertex Pharmaceuticals, Virtus Medical Group, and Yuhan Corporation; board of directors/leadership (remunerated): AstraZeneca and Hutchison Chi-Med; board of directors/leadership (non-remunerated): American Society of Clinical Oncology (ASCO), Asian Thoracic Oncology Research Group (ATORG), Chinese Lung Cancer Research Foundation Limited (CLCRF), Chinese Society of Clinical Oncology (CSCO), Hong Kong Cancer Fund (HKCF), Hong Kong Cancer Therapy Society (HKCTS), International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer (IASLC; term ended Apr 2019), and St. Stephen’s College &amp; Prep. School. Kazuhiko Nakagawa: grants: MSD K.K., A2 Healthcare Corp., inVentiv Health Japan Astellas Pharm Inc., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Novarits Pharma K.K., AbbVie Inc., Quintiles Inc., IQVIA Services JAPAN K.K., ICON Japan K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., EP-CRSU CO., LTD., GRITSONE ONCOLOGY.INC, Linical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Eisai Co., Ltd., Bristol-Myers Squibb, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Onc., PAREXEL International Corp., SymBio Pharmaceuticals Limited, Ono Pharmacuetical Co., Ltd., Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation, Bayer Yakuhin Ltd., Syneos Health, EPS International Co., Ltd., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; honoraria: AstraZeneca K.K., Nichi-Iko Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Astellas Pharma Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., MSD K.K., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bristol-Myers Squibb, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Novartis Pharma K.K., SymBio Pharmaceuticals Limited, Pfizer Japan Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Clinical Trial Co., Ltd., NANZANDO Co., Ltd., MEDICUS SHUPPAN Publishers Co., Ltd., YODOSHA CO., LTD., Care Net Inc., Nikkei Business Publications Inc., Reno Medical K.K., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., KYORIN Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Thermo Fisher Scientific K.K., Medical Review Co., Ltd., YOMIURI TELECASTING CORPORATION, Roche Diagnostics K.K., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Medical Mobile Communications Co., Ltd., AbbVie Inc., 3H Clinical Trial Inc. Seiji Niho: grants: AstraZeneca, Pfizer, Merck Biopharma, Eli Lilly, MSD, and Chugai; honoraria: AstraZeneca, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, Chugai, Taiho, MSD, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Novartis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, Ono, and Shionogi. Alka Chawla: former employee of SFJ Pharmaceuticals. Jesus Corral: Education grants, provided consultation, attended advisory boards and/or provided lectures for Pfizer, AstraZeneca, Roche, Eli Lilly, MSD, and Bristol-Myers Squibb. Adam Pluzanski: lecture fees and travel grants: Pfizer. Kay Noonan, Yiyun Tang, Malaika Pastel, and Keith Wilner: Pfizer employees and stockholders. Yi-Long Wu: grants (to institute): AstraZeneca, BMS, Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, and Roche; honoraria: AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, MSD, and Roche; lectures/speakers bureaus: AstraZeneca, BMS, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, MSD, Pfizer, and Roche. Ying Cheng, Xiangdong Zhou, Ki Hyeong Lee, Rafael Rosell, and Maria Rita Migliorino: no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33331989</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7932969</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-020-01441-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40265-020-01441-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maemondo M, Inoue A, Kobayashi K, Sugawara S, Oizumi S, Isobe H, et al.  Gefitinib or chemotherapy for non-small-cell lung cancer with mutated EGFR. N Engl J Med. 2010;362(25):2380–2388. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa0909530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0909530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20573926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosell R, Carcereny E, Gervais R, Vergnenegre A, Massuti B, Felip E, et al.  Erlotinib versus standard chemotherapy as first-line treatment for European patients with advanced EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer (EURTAC): a multicentre, open-label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2012;13(3):239–246. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(11)70393-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(11)70393-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22285168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YL, Zhou C, Liam CK, Wu G, Liu X, Zhong Z, et al.  First-line erlotinib versus gemcitabine/cisplatin in patients with advanced EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer: analyses from the phase III, randomized, open-label. ENSURE study. Ann Oncol. 2015;26(9):1883–1889. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdv270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdv270</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26105600</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou C, Wu YL, Chen G, Feng J, Liu XQ, Wang C, et al.  Final overall survival results from a randomised, phase III study of erlotinib versus chemotherapy as first-line treatment of EGFR mutation-positive advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (OPTIMAL, CTONG-0802) Ann Oncol. 2015;26(9):1877–1883. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdv276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdv276</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26141208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuoka M, Wu YL, Thongprasert S, Sunpaweravong P, Leong SS, Sriuranpong V, et al.  Biomarker analyses and final overall survival results from a phase III, randomized, open-label, first-line study of gefitinib versus carboplatin/paclitaxel in clinically selected patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer in Asia (IPASS) J Clin Oncol. 2011;29(21):2866–2874. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2010.33.4235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2010.33.4235</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21670455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue A, Kobayashi K, Maemondo M, Sugawara S, Oizumi S, Isobe H, et al.  Updated overall survival results from a randomized phase III trial comparing gefitinib with carboplatin-paclitaxel for chemo-naive non-small cell lung cancer with sensitive EGFR gene mutations (NEJ002) Ann Oncol. 2013;24(1):54–59. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mds214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mds214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22967997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshioka H, Shimokawa M, Seto T, Morita S, Yatabe Y, Okamoto I, et al.  Final overall survival results of WJTOG3405, a randomized phase III trial comparing gefitinib versus cisplatin with docetaxel as the first-line treatment for patients with stage IIIB/IV or postoperative recurrent EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2019;30(12):1978–1984. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdz399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdz399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31553438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YL, Cheng Y, Zhou X, Lee KH, Nakagawa K, Niho S, et al.  Dacomitinib versus gefitinib as first-line treatment for patients with EGFR-mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer (ARCHER 1050): a randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2017;18(11):1454–1466. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30608-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30608-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28958502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corral J, Mok TS, Nakagawa K, Rosell R, Lee KH, Migliorino MR, et al.  Effects of dose modifications on the safety and efficacy of dacomitinib for EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer. Future Oncol. 2019;15(24):2795–2805. doi: 10.2217/fon-2019-0299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fon-2019-0299</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31313942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok TS, Cheng Y, Zhou X, Lee KH, Nakagawa K, Niho S, et al.  Improvement in overall survival in a randomized study that compared dacomitinib with gefitinib in patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer and EGFR-activating mutations. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36(22):2244–2250. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2018.78.7994.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2018.78.7994</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29864379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis LM, Bernstein DS, Voest EE, Berlin JD, Sargent D, Cortazar P, et al.  American Society of Clinical Oncology perspective: raising the bar for clinical trials by defining clinically meaningful outcomes. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(12):1277–1280. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2013.53.8009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2013.53.8009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24638016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramalingam SS, Vansteenkiste J, Planchard D, Cho BC, Gray JE, Ohe Y, et al.  Overall survival with osimertinib in untreated, EGFR-mutated advanced NSCLC. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(1):41–50. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1913662.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1913662</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31751012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paz-Ares L, Tan EH, O’Byrne K, Zhang L, Hirsh V, Boyer M, et al.  Afatinib versus gefitinib in patients with EGFR mutation-positive advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: overall survival data from the phase IIb LUX-Lung 7 trial. Ann Oncol. 2017;28(2):270–277. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdw611.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdw611</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5391700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28426106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park K, Tan EH, O’Byrne K, Zhang L, Boyer M, Mok T, et al.  Afatinib versus gefitinib as first-line treatment of patients with EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer (LUX-Lung 7): a phase 2B, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17(5):577–589. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30033-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30033-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27083334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Q, Wu YL, Corral J, Nakagawa K, Garon EB, Sbar EI, et al.  Management of common adverse events related to first-line dacomitinib use in EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer: a pooled safety analysis. Future Oncol. 2019;15(13):1481–1491. doi: 10.2217/fon-2018-0944.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/fon-2018-0944</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30839234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan A, Mok T, Kim D, Yang JC, Lee C, Soo R, et al. ATORG-003: dacomitinib with or without dose titration as first-line therapy for metastatic EGFR mutant non-small cell lung cancer. J Thorac Oncol. 2019;14(10 (Supplement)):S836–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janne PA, Ou SI, Kim DW, Oxnard GR, Martins R, Kris MG, et al.  Dacomitinib as first-line treatment in patients with clinically or molecularly selected advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: a multicentre, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2014;15(13):1433–1441. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(14)70461-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(14)70461-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
