<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33355985</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-2165</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of cosmetic dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Cosmet Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The relationship between lichen planus and metabolic syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2635</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2639</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2635-2639</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocd.13905</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Lichen planus (LP) is an idiopathic, chronic inflammatory disease. Chronic inflammatory diseases can cause metabolic complications. In the literature, data related to the relationship between lichen planus and metabolic syndrome (MS) are limited. We aimed to evaluate the relationship between MS and lichen planus with disease activity.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The patients diagnosed with lichen planus at the dermatology outpatient clinic between January 2018 and January 2020 were retrospectively analyzed. 98 lichen planus cases, age- and sex-matched 99 controls, 197 cases in total were included in the study.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 98 lichen planus cases included in the study, 60 (61%) were women. The mean age of the patients was 49.3 ± 14.4, and the average disease duration was 33.5 ± 31.4 months. 55 (55%) of the patients in the control group were female, and the mean age of the control group was 50 ± 13.2. The body mass index of LP cases was 29.5 ± 5.8, in the control group was 25.8 ± 3.7. Metabolic syndrome was found in 47 (48%) of 98 cases with lichen planus and 32.3% in the control group. MS in the lichen planus group was significantly higher than the control group (P = .025). Metabolic syndrome was detected in the oral lichen planus at the rate of 60% (12 cases). Although the incidence of MS was more common in the oral lichen planus, it was not statistically significant (P = .29). While no significant relationship was found between oral disease severity and metabolic syndrome (P = .19), a significant correlation was found between cutaneous disease severity and metabolic syndrome (P = .023).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The risk of mucosal malignancy that can occur when following LP cases has been known for a long time. According to our results, caution should be taken in terms of metabolic complications in the follow-up of LP cases, especially oral LP cases.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Daye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Munise</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6614-1821</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Necmettin Erbakan University Meram Medical Faculty, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Temiz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Selami Aykut</ForeName>
            <Initials>SA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4878-0045</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinic of Dermatology, Konya Ereğli State Hospital, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Isık</LastName>
            <ForeName>Begüm</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1462-3869</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Necmettin Erbakan University Meram Medical Faculty, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Cosmet Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101130964</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1473-2130</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lichen Planus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017676" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lichen Planus, Oral</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D024821" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metabolic Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lichen planus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolic syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mucosal involvement / disease severity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33355985</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocd.13905</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lehman JS, Tollefson MM, Gibson LE. Lichen planus. Int J Dermatol. 2009;48(7):682-694.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engin B, Özkoca D, Kutlubay Z, Serdaroğlu S. Metabolic syndrome in dermatology: treatment and management for dermatologists. Dermatol Ther. 2019;32(2):e12812.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eckel RH, Alberti KG, Grundy SM, Zimmet PZ. The metabolic syndrome. Lancet. 2010;375(9710):181-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baykal L, Arıca DA, Yaylı S, et al. Prevalence of metabolic syndrome in patients with mucosal lichen planus: A case-control study. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2015;16(5):439-445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escudier M, Ahmed N, Shirlaw P, et al. A scoring system for mucosal disease severity with special reference to oral lichen planus. Br J Dermatol. 2007;157(4):765-770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karıncaoğlu Y, Kandi B, Eşrefoğlu M. Liken Planusta Oral Asitretin Tedavisinin Klinik Etkinliği ve Remisyon Süresine Etkisi. J Inonu University Medical Faculty. 2010;9(1):41-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kar BR, Panda M, Patro N. Metabolic derangements in lichen planus-A case control study. J Clin Diag Res. 2016;10(11):WC01.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arias-Santiago S, Buendía-Eisman A, Aneiros-Fernández J, et al. Cardiovascular risk factors in patients with lichen planus. Am J Med. 2011;124(6):543-548.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreiher J, Shapiro J, Cohen AD. Lichen planus and dyslipidaemia: a case-control study. Br J Dermatol. 2009;161(3):626-629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geetharani G, Sumithra S, Devaprabha S, Kothandaramasamy R. Eruptive lichen planus, a marker of metabolic syndrome. Indian J Dermatol. 2019;64(4):299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anbar TE, Barakat M, Ghannam SF. A clinical and epidemiological study of lichen planus among Egyptians of al-Minya province. Dermatol Online J. 2005;11(2):4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>TickooU BAK, Subramanyam S, Veeraraghavan M, Rangarajan S, Sankarasubramanian A. A clinicopathologic study of lichen planus at a tertiary health care centre in South India. Pigment Intern. 2016;3(2):96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Bachir M, Bakir MA. Predictive value of body mass index to metabolic syndrome risk factors in Syrian adolescents. J Pakistan Assoc Dermatol. 2017;11(1):170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seyhan M, Ozcan H, Sahin I, Bayram N, Karincaoglu Y. High prevalence of glucose metabolism disturbance in patients with lichen planus. Diab Res Clin Prac. 2007;77:198-202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuntoji V, Kudligi C, Bhagwat PV, et al. Dyslipidemia and metabolic syndrome in patients with lichen planus: A case-control study. J Pakistan Assoc Dermatol. 2017;26(4):290-297.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saleh N, Samir N, Megahed H, Farid E. Homocysteine and other cardiovascular risk factors in patients with lichen planus. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2014;28:1507-1513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Özkur E, Uğurer E, Kıvanç AI. Dyslipidemia in lichen planus: a case-control study. Medical Bulletin of Sisli Etfal Hospital. 2020;54(1):62-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hashba H, Bifi J, Thyvalappil A, Sridharan R, Sreenivasan A, Mathew P. Prevalence of metabolic syndrome in patients with lichen planus: A cross-sectional study from a tertiary care center. Indian Dermatol Online J. 2018;9:304-308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishnamoorthy B, Suma GN, Mamatha NS, Sowbhagya MB, Garlapati K. Lipid profile and metabolic syndrome status in patients with oral lichen planus, oral lichenoid reaction and healthy individuals attending a dental college in northern India-a descriptive study. J Clin Diag Res. 2014;8(11):ZC92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pakfetrat A, Dalirsani Z, Nematy M, Esmaily H, Pishbin A, Sheikhveysi M. Association between dietary patterns and oral lichen planus. J Biochem Tech. 2019;2 (Special Issue 2):176-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mushtaq S, Dogra D, Dogra N, et al. Cardiovascular and metabolic risk assessment in patients with lichen planus: A tertiary care hospital-based study from Northern India. Indian Dermatol Online J. 2020;11(2):158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salihbegovic EM, Hadzigrahic N, Cickusic AJ. Psoriasis and metabolic syndrome. Medical Arch. 2015;69(2):85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwager Z, Stern M, Cohen J, Femia A. Clinical epidemiology and treatment of lichen planus: A retrospective review of 2 tertiary care centers. J Am Acade Dermatol. 2019;81(6):1397-1399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
