<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33394604</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6963</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in rheumatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Cellular aspects of the pathogenesis of lupus nephritis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>197</StartPage>
          <EndPage>204</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>197-204</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000777</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Lupus nephritis is a common severe manifestation of systemic lupus erythematosus. Despite recent advances in therapeutics and understanding of its pathogenesis, there are still substantial unmet needs. This review discusses recent discoveries in these areas, especially the role of tubulointerstitial inflammation (TII) in lupus nephritis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Non-white ethnicity is still a major risk and poor prognostic factor in lupus nephritis. TII and fibrosis have been found to be associated with worse renal outcome but the current lupus nephritis treatment guidelines and trials are based on the degree of glomerular inflammation. In combination with mycophenolate mofetil, a B-cell-targeted therapy (belimumab) and a calcineurin inhibitor (voclosporin) have shown efficacy in recent lupus nephritis trials. However, response rates have been modest. While lupus glomerulonephritis results from immune complex deposition derived from systemic autoantibodies, TII arises from complex processes associated with in situ adaptive cell networks. These include local antibody production, and cognate or antigen-induced interactions between T follicular helper cells, and likely other T-cell populations, with antigen presenting cells including B cells, myeloid dendritic cells and plasmacytoid dendritic cells.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Better understanding of the pathogenesis of TII will identify novel therapeutic targets predicted to improve outcomes in our patients with lupus nephritis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2020 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anthony</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Clark</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcus R</ForeName>
            <Initials>MR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine and Gwenn Knapp Center for Lupus and Immunology Research, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ko</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kichul</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine and Gwenn Knapp Center for Lupus and Immunology Research, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AR055646</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>U19 AI082724</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9000851</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1040-8711</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008180" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008181" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lupus Nephritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest. AC is a consultant and on the speaker’s bureau for Alexion Pharmaceuticals Inc.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>16</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33394604</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1665348</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905798</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BOR.0000000000000777</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00002281-202103000-00013</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alarcon GS, McGwin G Jr., Petri M, Reveille JD, Ramsey-Goldman R, Kimberly RP, et al.
Baseline characteristics of a multiethnic lupus cohort: PROFILE. Lupus. 2002;11(2):95–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11958584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastian HM, Roseman JM, McGwin G Jr., Alarcon GS, Friedman AW, Fessler BJ, et al.
Systemic lupus erythematosus in three ethnic groups. XII. Risk factors for lupus nephritis after diagnosis. Lupus. 2002;11(3):152–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12004788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok CC, Wong RW, Lau CS. Lupus nephritis in Southern Chinese patients: clinicopathologic findings and long-term outcome. Am J Kidney Dis. 1999;34(2):315–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10430980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanly JG, O’Keeffe AG, Su L, Urowitz MB, Romero-Diaz J, Gordon C, et al.
The frequency and outcome of lupus nephritis: results from an international inception cohort study. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2016;55(2):252–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4939728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26342222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seligman VA, Lum RF, Olson JL, Li H, Criswell LA. Demographic differences in the development of lupus nephritis: a retrospective analysis. Am J Med. 2002;112(9):726–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12079714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiraki LT, Benseler SM, Tyrrell PN, Harvey E, Hebert D, Silverman ED. Ethnic differences in pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus. J Rheumatol. 2009;36(11):2539–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19833755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tektonidou MG, Dasgupta A, Ward MM. Risk of End-Stage Renal Disease in Patients With Lupus Nephritis, 1971–2015: A Systematic Review and Bayesian Meta-Analysis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2016;68(6):1432–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5071782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26815601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faurschou M, Dreyer L, Kamper AL, Starklint H, Jacobsen S. Long-term mortality and renal outcome in a cohort of 100 patients with lupus nephritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2010;62(6):873–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ward MM. Changes in the incidence of endstage renal disease due to lupus nephritis in the United States, 1996–2004. J Rheumatol. 2009;36(1):63–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2679678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19004042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korbet SM, Schwartz MM, Evans J, Lewis EJ, Collaborative Study G. Severe lupus nephritis: racial differences in presentation and outcome. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2007;18(1):244–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok CC, Kwok RC, Yip PS. Effect of renal disease on the standardized mortality ratio and life expectancy of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2013;65(8):2154–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23754671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernatsky S, Boivin JF, Joseph L, Manzi S, Ginzler E, Gladman DD, et al.
Mortality in systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54(8):2550–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16868977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan TC, Fang H, Magder LS, Petri MA. Differences between male and female systemic lupus erythematosus in a multiethnic population. J Rheumatol. 2012;39(4):759–69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3605704</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22382348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy G, Isenberg D. Effect of gender on clinical presentation in systemic lupus erythematosus. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2013;52(12):2108–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23641038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahajan A, Amelio J, Gairy K, Kaur G, Levy RA, Roth D, et al.
Systemic lupus erythematosus, lupus nephritis and end-stage renal disease: a pragmatic review mapping disease severity and progression. Lupus. 2020;29(9):1011–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adler M, Chambers S, Edwards C, Neild G, Isenberg D. An assessment of renal failure in an SLE cohort with special reference to ethnicity, over a 25-year period. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2006;45(9):1144–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16527882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Contreras G, Lenz O, Pardo V, Borja E, Cely C, Iqbal K, et al.
Outcomes in African Americans and Hispanics with lupus nephritis. Kidney Int. 2006;69(10):1846–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16598205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barr RG, Seliger S, Appel GB, Zuniga R, D’Agati V, Salmon J, et al.
Prognosis in proliferative lupus nephritis: the role of socio-economic status and race/ethnicity. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2003;18(10):2039–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13679478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bajema IM, Wilhelmus S, Alpers CE, Bruijn JA, Colvin RB, Cook HT, et al.
Revision of the International Society of Nephrology/Renal Pathology Society classification for lupus nephritis: clarification of definitions, and modified National Institutes of Health activity and chronicity indices. Kidney Int. 2018;93(4):789–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill GS, Delahousse M, Nochy D, Tomkiewicz E, Remy P, Mignon F, et al.
A new morphologic index for the evaluation of renal biopsies in lupus nephritis. Kidney Int. 2000;58(3):1160–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10972679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsieh C, Chang A, Brandt D, Guttikonda R, Utset TO, Clark MR. Predicting outcomes of lupus nephritis with tubulointerstitial inflammation and scarring. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63(6):865–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3106120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21309006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broder A, Mowrey WB, Khan HN, Jovanovic B, Londono-Jimenez A, Izmirly P, et al.
Tubulointerstitial damage predicts end stage renal disease in lupus nephritis with preserved to moderately impaired renal function: A retrospective cohort study. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2018;47(4):545–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5927553</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28803673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Londono Jimenez A, Mowrey WB, Putterman C, Buyon J, Goilav B, Broder A. Brief Report: Tubulointerstitial Damage in Lupus Nephritis: A Comparison of the Factors Associated With Tubulointerstitial Inflammation and Renal Scarring. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2018;70(11):1801–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6203636</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29851285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hahn BH, McMahon MA, Wilkinson A, Wallace WD, Daikh DI, Fitzgerald JD, et al.
American College of Rheumatology guidelines for screening, treatment, and management of lupus nephritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2012;64(6):797–808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3437757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22556106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Austin HA 3rd, Klippel JH, Balow JE, le Riche NG, Steinberg AD, Plotz PH, et al.
Therapy of lupus nephritis. Controlled trial of prednisone and cytotoxic drugs. N Engl J Med. 1986;314(10):614–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3511372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houssiau FA, Vasconcelos C, D’Cruz D, Sebastiani GD, Garrido Ed Ede R, Danieli MG, et al.
Immunosuppressive therapy in lupus nephritis: the Euro-Lupus Nephritis Trial, a randomized trial of low-dose versus high-dose intravenous cyclophosphamide. Arthritis Rheum. 2002;46(8):2121–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12209517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginzler EM, Dooley MA, Aranow C, Kim MY, Buyon J, Merrill JT, et al.
Mycophenolate mofetil or intravenous cyclophosphamide for lupus nephritis. N Engl J Med. 2005;353(21):2219–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16306519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appel GB, Contreras G, Dooley MA, Ginzler EM, Isenberg D, Jayne D, et al.
Mycophenolate mofetil versus cyclophosphamide for induction treatment of lupus nephritis. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2009;20(5):1103–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathi M, Goyal A, Jaryal A, Sharma A, Gupta PK, Ramachandran R, et al.
Comparison of low-dose intravenous cyclophosphamide with oral mycophenolate mofetil in the treatment of lupus nephritis. Kidney Int. 2016;89(1):235–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26489028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dooley MA, Jayne D, Ginzler EM, Isenberg D, Olsen NJ, Wofsy D, et al.
Mycophenolate versus azathioprine as maintenance therapy for lupus nephritis. N Engl J Med. 2011;365(20):1886–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22087680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houssiau FA, D’Cruz D, Sangle S, Remy P, Vasconcelos C, Petrovic R, et al.
Azathioprine versus mycophenolate mofetil for long-term immunosuppression in lupus nephritis: results from the MAINTAIN Nephritis Trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2010;69(12):2083–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3002764</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20833738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trotter K, Clark MR, Liarski VM. Overview of pathophysiology and treatment of human lupus nephritis. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2016;28(5):460–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4965286</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27341623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parikh SV, Almaani S, Brodsky S, Rovin BH. Update on Lupus Nephritis: Core Curriculum 2020. Am J Kidney Dis. 2020;76(2):265–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32220510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok CC, Ying KY, Yim CW, Siu YP, Tong KH, To CH, et al.
Tacrolimus versus mycophenolate mofetil for induction therapy of lupus nephritis: a randomised controlled trial and long-term follow-up. Ann Rheum Dis. 2016;75(1):30–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25550339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Zhang H, Liu Z, Xing C, Fu P, Ni Z, et al.
Multitarget therapy for induction treatment of lupus nephritis: a randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(1):18–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rovin BH, Furie R, Latinis K, Looney RJ, Fervenza FC, Sanchez-Guerrero J, et al.
Efficacy and safety of rituximab in patients with active proliferative lupus nephritis: the Lupus Nephritis Assessment with Rituximab study. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64(4):1215–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22231479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rekvig OP. The dsDNA, Anti-dsDNA Antibody, and Lupus Nephritis: What We Agree on, What Must Be Done, and What the Best Strategy Forward Could Be. Front Immunol. 2019;10:1104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6529578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mjelle JE, Rekvig OP, Fenton KA. Nucleosomes possess a high affinity for glomerular laminin and collagen IV and bind nephritogenic antibodies in murine lupus-like nephritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2007;66(12):1661–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2095330</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17504842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fenton KA, Tømmerås B, Marion TN, Rekvig OP. Pure anti-dsDNA mAbs need chromatin structures to promote glomerular mesangial deposits in BALB/c mice. Autoimmunity. 2010;43(2):179–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19835488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winfield JB, Faiferman I, Koffler D. Avidity of anti-DNA antibodies in serum and IgG glomerular eluates from patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. Association of high avidity antinative DNA antibody with glomerulonephritis. J Clin Invest. 1977;59(1):90–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC333335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">299748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie C, Liang Z, Chang S, Mohan C. Use of a novel elution regimen reveals the dominance of polyreactive antinuclear autoantibodies in lupus kidneys. Arthritis Rheum. 2003;48(8):2343–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12905490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ehrenstein MR, Katz DR, Griffiths MH, Papadaki L, Winkler TH, Kalden JR, et al.
Human IgG anti-DNA antibodies deposit in kidneys and induce proteinuria in SCID mice. Kidney Int. 1995;48(3):705–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7474655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishnan MR, Wang C, Marion TN. Anti-DNA autoantibodies initiate experimental lupus nephritis by binding directly to the glomerular basement membrane in mice. Kidney Int. 2012;82(2):184–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3343188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22297676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lou H, Wojciak-Stothard B, Ruseva MM, Cook HT, Kelleher P, Pickering MC, et al.
Autoantibody-dependent amplification of inflammation in SLE. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11(9):729.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7481301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32908129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolas-Avila JA, Adrover JM, Hidalgo A. Neutrophils in Homeostasis, Immunity, and
Cancer. Immunity. 2017;46(1):15–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28099862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wigerblad G, Kaplan MJ. NETs spread ever wider in rheumatic diseases. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2020;16(2):73–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31853047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Romo GS, Caielli S, Vega B, Connolly J, Allantaz F, Xu Z, et al.
Netting neutrophils are major inducers of type I IFN production in pediatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Sci Transl Med. 2011;3(73):73ra20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3143837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21389264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lood C, Blanco LP, Purmalek MM, Carmona-Rivera C, De Ravin SS, Smith CK, et al.
Neutrophil extracellular traps enriched in oxidized mitochondrial DNA are interferogenic and contribute to lupus-like disease. Nat Med. 2016;22(2):146–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4742415</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26779811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang X, Li J, Dorta-Estremera S, Di Domizio J, Anthony SM, Watowich SS, et al.
Neutrophils Regulate Humoral Autoimmunity by Restricting Interferon-gamma Production via the Generation of Reactive Oxygen Species. Cell Rep. 2015;12(7):1120–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4545388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26257170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banchereau R, Hong S, Cantarel B, Baldwin N, Baisch J, Edens M, et al.
Personalized Immunomonitoring Uncovers Molecular Networks that Stratify Lupus Patients. Cell. 2016;165(3):551–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5426482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27040498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SJ, Lee K, Diamond B. Follicular Helper T Cells in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Front Immunol. 2018;9:1793.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6085416</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30123218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi JY, Ho JH, Pasoto SG, Bunin V, Kim ST, Carrasco S, et al.
Circulating follicular helper-like T cells in systemic lupus erythematosus: association with disease activity. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67(4):988–99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4450082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25581113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Silva NS, Klein U. Dynamics of B cells in germinal centres. Nature reviews Immunology. 2015;15(3):137–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4399774</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25656706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Victora GD, Schwickert TA, Fooksman DR, Kamphorst AO, Meyer-Hermann M, Dustin ML, et al.
Germinal center dynamics revealed by multiphoton microscopy with a photoactivatable fluorescent reporter. Cell. 2010;143(4):592–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3035939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21074050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morita R, Schmitt N, Bentebibel S-E, Ranganathan R, Bourdery L, Zurawski G, et al.
Human blood CXCR5+CD4+ T cells are counterparts of T follicular cells and contain specific subsets that differentially support antibody secretion. Immunity. 2011;34:108–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046815</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21215658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liarski V, Kaverina N, Chang A, Brand D, Carlesso G, Utset TO, et al.
Quantitative cell distance mapping in human nephritis reveals organization of in situ adaptive immune responses. Sci Trans Med. 2014;6(230):230ra46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark MR, Trotter K, Chang A. The pathogenesis and therapeutic implications of tubulointerstitial inflammation in human lupus nephritis. Seminars in nephrology. 2015;35(5):455–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4653081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang A, Henderson SG, Brandt D, Liu N, Guttikonda R, Hsieh C, et al.
In situ B cell-mediated immune responses and tubulointerstitial inflammation in human lupus nephritis. J Immunol. 2011;186(3):1849–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3124090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21187439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kinloch AJ, Chang A, Ko K, Henry Dunand CJ, Henderson S, Maienschein-Cline M, et al.
Vimentin is a dominant target of in situ humoral immunity in human lupus tubulointerstitial nephritis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2014;66(12):3359–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4264660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25306868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colucci-Guyon E, Portier MM, Dunia I, Paulin D, Pournin S, Babinet C. Mice lacking vimentin develop and reproduce without an obvious phenotype. Cell. 1994;79:670–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7954832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mor-Vaknin N, Punturieri A, Sitwala K, Markovitz DM. Vimentin is secreted by activated macrophages. Nat Cell Biol. 2003;5:59–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12483219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiagarajan PS, Yakubenko VP, Elsori DH, Yadav SP, Willard B, Tan CD, et al.
Vimentin is an endogenous ligand for the pattern recognition receptor Dectin-1. Cardiovasc Res. 2013;99(3):494–504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3718321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23674515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen SR, Shupe J, Nickerson K, Kashgarian M, Flavell RA, Shlomchik MJ. Toll-like receptor 7 and TLR9 dictate autoantibody specificity and have opposing inflammatory and regulatory roles in a murine model of lupus. Immunity. 2006;25(3):417–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao DA, Gurish MF, Marshall JL, Slowikowski K, Fonseka CY, Liu Y, et al.
Pathologically expanded peripheral T helper cell subset drives B cells in rheumatoid arthritis. Nature. 2017;542(7639):110–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bocharnikov AV, Keegan J, Wacleche VS, Cao Y, Fonseka CY, Wang G, et al.
PD-1hiCXCR5- T peripheral helper cells promote B cell responses in lupus via MAF and IL-21. JCI Insight. 2019;4(20).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6824311</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31536480</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knox JJ, Myles A, Cancro MP. T-bet(+) memory B cells: Generation, function, and fate. Immunol Rev. 2019;288(1):149–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6626622</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenks SA, Cashman KS, Zumaquero E, Marigorta UM, Patel AV, Wang X, et al.
Distinct Effector B Cells Induced by Unregulated Toll-like Receptor 7 Contribute to Pathogenic Responses in Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Immunity. 2018;49(4):725–39.e6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6217820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Neill SK, Veselits ML, Zhang M, Labno C, Cao Y, Finnegan A, et al.
Endocytic sequestration of the B cell antigen receptor and toll-like receptor 9 in anergic B cells. Proc Nat Acad Sci, USA. 2009;106:6262–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19332776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villani AC, Satija R, Reynolds G, Sarkizova S, Shekhar K, Fletcher J, et al.
Single-cell RNA-seq reveals new types of human blood dendritic cells, monocytes, and progenitors. Science (New York, NY). 2017;356(6335):273–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5775029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28428369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen PM, Wilson PC, Shyer JA, Veselits M, Steach HR, Cui C, et al.
Kidney tissue hypoxia dictates T cell-mediated injury in murine lupus nephritis. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12(538).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8055156</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32269165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
