<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33419442</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6963</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>21</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMC health services research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Health Serv Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Evaluation of a training program for life skills education and financial literacy to community health workers in India: a quasi-experimental study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>46</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>46</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">46</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12913-020-06025-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Accredited Social Health Activists (ASHA) are community health workers responsible for improving the health status of people by facilitating their access to healthcare services. The life skills of ASHA are known to be effective in negotiating behaviour change in the community; however, there has been a meagre focus towards improving them. Considering this gap, we adopted a comprehensive training program, known as Personal Advancement and Career Enhancement (P.A.C.E.), to empower ASHAs on life skills and financial literacy. The present study intends to assess the training program in two districts of Uttar Pradesh, India, by examining changes in knowledge, perceptions, and practices of ASHAs about life skills and financial literacy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a quasi-experimental, non-randomized, controlled study with pre-and post-test assessments. Data were collected on socio-demographic characteristics, knowledge, and practices related to life skills (communication skills, self-confidence, problem-solving and decision-making skills, time and stress management skills) and financial literacy. Additionally, change perceptions on gender-, life skills-, and savings-related practices at the personal, community, and workplace levels were assessed in the intervention group. Factor analysis was performed to obtain the change patterns by assessing the degree to which the four life skills, financial literacy, and change perceptions on practices were correlated. A general linear regression model was performed to assess associations among change pattern scores and socio-demographic variables.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We analyzed the data of 171 ASHAs (intervention group:86 and control group:85). There was a significant improvement in the average post-test scores of all the life skills and financial literacy in the intervention group (p &lt; 0.001). Three distinct change patterns were found post-training in the intervention group. Factor 1 (high loadings for change perceptions on practices) was positively associated with ASHAs aged 38 and above and with experience of ≤12 years. On the contrary, the change in financial literacy and self-confidence scores was common among ASHAs with more than 12 years of experience.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The P.A.C.E training program was found effective in improving the life skills and financial literacy of ASHAs in India.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sharma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shantanu</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, Lund University, Skåne University Hospital, S-20502 Malmö, Sweden &amp; Assistant Director, MAMTA Health Institute for Mother and Child, Delhi, India. shantanusharma145@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arora</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kanishtha</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn, Child and Adolescent Health Division, MAMTA Health Institute for Mother and Child, Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chandrashekhar</LastName>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MAMTA Health Institute for Mother and Child, Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sinha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rajesh Kumar</ForeName>
            <Initials>RK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn, Child and Adolescent Health Division, MAMTA Health Institute for Mother and Child, Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Akhtar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Faiyaz</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn, Child and Adolescent Health Division, MAMTA Health Institute for Mother and Child, Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mehra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sunil</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MAMTA Health Institute for Mother and Child, Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D018848">Controlled Clinical Trial</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMC Health Serv Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101088677</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1472-6963</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003150" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community Health Workers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000067010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Literacy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communication</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community health workers</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Decision making</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Problem solving</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Research</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Time management</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Training support</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>26</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33419442</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7796593</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-020-06025-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12913-020-06025-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hogan MC, Foreman KJ, Magahi M, Han SY, Wang M, Makela SM, et al.  Maternal mortality for 181 countries, 1980-2008: a systematic analysis of progress towards millennium development goal 5. Lancet. 2010;375:1609–1623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. India has achieved groundbreaking success in reducing maternal mortality. https://www.who.int/southeastasia/news/detail/10-06-2018-india-has-achieved-groundbreaking-success-in-reducing-maternal-mortality. Accessed 12 March 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal S, Curtis SL, Angeles G, Speizer IS, Singh K, Thomas JC. The impact of India’s accredited social health activist (ASHA) program on the utilization of maternity services: a nationally representative longitudinal modelling study. Hum Resour Health. 2019;17:68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701148</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31426801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health and Family Welfare, Government of India. https://nhm.gov.in/index1.php?lang=1&amp;level=1&amp;sublinkid=150&amp;lid=226. Accessed 20 December 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Health Mission, Government of India. https://nhm.gov.in/index1.php?lang=1&amp;level=3&amp;sublinkid=184&amp;lid=257. Accessed 10 April 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panwar DS, Naidu V, Das E, Verma S, Khan AA. Strengthening support mechanisms for Accredited Social Health Activists in order to improve home-based newborn care in Uttar Pradesh, India. BMC Proc. 2012;6:O33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rama S, Sarada S. Role of self-esteem and self-efficacy on competence-a conceptual framework. J Humanit Soc Sci. 2017;22(2):33–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gap Inc. P.A.C.E.- Empowering women. https://www.gapincsustainability.com/people/pace-changing-one-million-lives. Accessed 10 November 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goel AD, Gosain M, Amarchand R, Sharma H, Rai S, Kapoor SK, Krishnan A. Effectiveness of a quality improvement program using difference-in-difference analysis for home based newborn care–results of a community intervention trial. Indian J Pediatr. 2019;86(11):1028–1035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31325100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarin E, Lunsford SS. How female community health workers navigate work challenges and why there are still gaps in their performance: a look at female community health workers in maternal and child health in two Indian districts through a reciprocal determinism framework. Hum Resour Health. 2017;15:44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5493888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28666447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IIPS  . (International Institute for Population Sciences) &amp; macro international. National Family Health Survey (NFHS-4), 2015–16: India, volume I. Mumbai: IIPS; 2017. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohli C, Kishore J, Sharma S, Nayak H. Knowledge and practice of accredited social health activists for maternal healthcare delivery in Delhi. J Fam Med Prim Care. 2015;4:359–363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4535095</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26288774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health and Family Welfare. Guidelines on accredited social health activists (ASHA). https://nhm.gov.in/images/pdf/communitisation/task-group-reports/guidelines-on-asha.pdf. Accessed 12 April 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarma H, Tariqujjaman M, Mbuya MN, Askari S, Banwell C, Bossert TJ, et al.  Factors associated with home visits by volunteer community health workers to implement a home-fortification intervention in Bangladesh: a multilevel analysis. Public Health Nutr. 2020;27:1–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31983364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>kane S, Radkar A, Gadgil M, McPake B. Community health workers as influential health system actors and not "just another pair of hands". Int J Health Policy Manag. 2020. 10.34172/ijhpm.2020.58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32610755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sagorika S, Hasegawa S.  The 13th International Conference on Knowledge, Information and Creativity Support Systems (KICSS 2018) 2018. Designing a Soft-skill Cultivation Platform for Health Care Professionals (HCPs)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kok MC, Broerse JE, Theobald S, Ormel H, Dieleman M, Taegtmeyer M. Performance of community health workers: situating their intermediary position within complex adaptive health systems. Hum Resour Health. 2017;15(1):59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5581474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28865471</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>KPMG. Human resource and skill requirement in the healthcare sector (2013–17 and 2017–22). National Skill Development Corporation and Government of India. Available from: http://hdl.voced.edu.au/10707/445385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balachander S, Jayam R. A study on the “soft skill requirements” and suggested training for student community at colleges in today’s context. Int J Manag Soc Sci Res Rev. 2015;1(10):228–232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nanda P, Mishra A, Walia S, Sharma S, Weiss E, Abrahamson J.  Advancing Women, Changing Lives: An Evaluation of Gap Inc.’s P.A.C.E. Program. Washington, DC: International Center for Research on Women; 2013. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medical Indemnity Protection Society. Financial literacy of healthcare professionals. https://www.mips.com.au/articles/financial-literacy-of-healthcare-professionals. Accessed 10 April 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>PM360. Healthcare’s financial literacy gap. https://www.pm360online.com/healthcares-financial-literacy-gap. Accessed 1 April 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora A. Assessment of financial literacy amongst working Indian women. Bus Anal. 2016;36:219–237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekar M, Gowri M. A study on financial security and its determinants among gen Y experience. Amity Bus Rev. 2014;15(1):134–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fino Payment Bank. https://www.finobank.com/about-us/news-media/press-release/2016/fino-facilitates-largest-financial-literacy-project-in-bihar-to-train-asha-workers/. Accessed 12 April 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crispin N, Wamae A, Ndirangu M, Wamalwa D, Wangalwa G, Watako P, et al.  Effects of selected socio-demographic characteristics of community health workers on performance of home visits during pregnancy: a cross-sectional study in Busia District, Kenya. Global J Health Sci. 2012;4(5):78–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4776911</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22980380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sany SBT, Peyman N, Behzhad F, Esmaeily H, Taghipoor A, Ferns G. Health providers’ communication skills training affects hypertension outcomes. Med Teach. 2018;40(2):154–163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29183178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-All M, Putica B, Praveen D, Abimbola S, Joshi R. Effectiveness of community health worker training programmes for cardiovascular disease management in low-income and middle-income countries: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2017;7:e015529.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5695434</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29101131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>David M, Bennett S, Witter S, Pond B, Baker B, Gow J, et al.  Salaries and incomes of health Workers in sub-Saharan Africa. Lancet. 2008;371(9613):675–681.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18295025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripathy JP, Goel S, Kumar AMV. Measuring and understanding motivation among community health workers in rural health facilities in India-a mixed method study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2016;16:366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4977615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27507034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sany SB, Behzhad F, Ferns G, Peyman N. Communication skills training for physicians improves health literacy and medical outcomes among patients with hypertension: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1):60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6979365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31973765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khorasani EC, Sany SB, Orooji A, Ferns G, Peyman N. Health literacy in Iranian women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Iran J Public Health. 2020;49(5):860–874.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7475634</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32953674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charoensap-Kelly P, Broussard L, Lindsly M, Troy M. Evaluation of a soft skills training program. Bus Prof Commun Q. 2016;79(2):154–179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
