<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33534195</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility : the official journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Gastric accumulation of enteral nutrition reduces pressure changes induced by phasic contractility in an isovolumetric intragastric balloon.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14088</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14088</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.14088</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">An isovolumetric intragastric balloon to continuously measure gastric phasic contractility was recently developed by us. We aimed to investigate the readout of this technique in relation to gastric content and gastric emptying.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">In this crossover investigation, the VIPUN<sup>TM</sup> Gastric Monitoring System, which comprises a double lumen nasogastric feeding tube with integrated intragastric balloon, was used to assess phasic gastric contractility by interpretation of the pressure in an isovolumetric balloon in 10 healthy subjects. Balloon pressure was recorded in fasted state, during a 2-hour intragastric nutrient infusion (1 kcal/ml at 25, 75, or 250 ml/h) and 4 hours post-infusion, and quantified as Gastric Balloon Motility Index (GBMI), ranging from 0 (no contractility) to 1 (maximal contractility). Gastric accumulation was quantified with magnetic resonance imaging and gastric emptying with a<sup>13</sup> C-breath test. Results are expressed as mean(SD).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS">GBMI was significantly lower during infusion at 250 ml/h compared to baseline (0.13(0.05) versus 0.46(0.12)) and compared to infusion at 25 (0.54(0.21)) and 75 ml/h (0.43(0.20)), all P &lt; 0.005. Gastric content volume was larger after infusion at 250 versus 75 ml/h (P &lt; 0.001). Half-emptying time and accumulation were both negatively correlated with postprandial contractility. Postprandial GBMI was significantly lower when GCV&gt;0 ml compared to when the stomach was empty.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND INFERENCES">Enteral nutrition dose-dependently decreased the contractility readout. This decrease was linked to gastric accumulation of enteral nutrition.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Goelen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nick</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7812-1740</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Translational Research Center for Gastrointestinal Disorders, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Doperé</LastName>
            <ForeName>Glynnis</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Translational Research Center for Gastrointestinal Disorders, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Byloos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kris</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University Hospital Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghysels</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University Hospital Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Putzeys</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guido</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University Hospital Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vandecaveye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vincent</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University Hospital Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morales</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering ESAT, Signal Processing and Data Analytics, STADIUS Center for Dynamical Systems, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Van Huffel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sabine</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Electrical Engineering ESAT, Signal Processing and Data Analytics, STADIUS Center for Dynamical Systems, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tack</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Translational Research Center for Gastrointestinal Disorders, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Janssen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pieter</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1792-953X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Translational Research Center for Gastrointestinal Disorders, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VIPUN Medical, Mechelen, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004750" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enteral Nutrition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015905" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastric Balloon</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005746" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastric Emptying</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008365" MajorTopicYN="N">Manometry</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="Y">instrumentation</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013270" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stomach</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">enteral nutrition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gastric content volume</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gastric emptying</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gastric motility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">medical device</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>17</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33534195</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14088</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tack J, Demedts I. Role of nitric oxide in the gastric accommodation reflex and in meal induced satiety in humans. Gut. 2002;51(2):219-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goelen N, de Hoon J, Morales JF, et al. Codeine delays gastric emptying through inhibition of gastric motility as assessed with a novel diagnostic intragastric balloon catheter. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;32:e13733.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simren M, Vos R, Janssens J, Tack J. Unsuppressed postprandial phasic contractility in the proximal stomach in functional dyspepsia: relevance to symptoms. Am J Gastroenterol. 2003;98(10):2169-2175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grover M, Farrugia G, Stanghellini V. Gastroparesis: a turning point in understanding and treatment. Gut. 2019;68(12):2238-2250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwiatek MA, Menne D, Steingoetter A, et al. Effect of meal volume and calorie load on postprandial gastric function and emptying: studies under physiological conditions by combined fiber-optic pressure measurement and MRI. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2009;297(5):G894-901.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansen MB. Neurohumoral control of gastrointestinal motility. Physiol Res. 2003;52(1):1-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camilleri M. Integrated upper gastrointestinal response to food intake. Gastroenterology. 2006;131(2):640-658.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goyal RK, Guo Y, Mashimo H. Advances in the physiology of gastric emptying. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2019;31(4):e13546.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Indireshkumar K, Brasseur JG, Faas H, et al. Relative contributions of "pressure pump" and "peristaltic pump" to gastric emptying. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2000;278:G604-G616.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leiper JB. Fate of ingested fluids: factors affecting gastric emptying and intestinal absorption of beverages in humans. Nutr Rev. 2015;73(suppl 2):57-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dooley CP, Reznick J, Valenzuela J. Variations in gastric and duodenal motility during gastric empyting of liquid meals in humans. Gastroenterology. 1984;87:1114-1119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heddle R, Dent J, Read NW, et al. Antropyloroduodenal motor responses to intraduodenal lipid infusion in healthy volunteers. Am J Physiol. 1988;254(5 Pt 1):G671-679.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edelbroek M, Sun WM, Horowitz M, Dent J, Smout A, Akkermans L. Stereospecific effects of intraduodenal tryptophan on pyloric and duodenal motility in humans. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1994;29(12):1088-1095.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camilleri M, Malagelada JR, Brown ML, Becker G, Zinsmeister AR. Relation between antral motility and gastric emptying of solids and liquids in humans. Am J Physiol. 1985;249(5 Pt 1):G580-585.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vella A, Camilleri M. The gastrointestinal tract as an integrator of mechanical and hormonal response to nutrient ingestion. Diabetes. 2017;66(11):2729-2737.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer P, Blaser AR, Berger MM, et al. ESPEN guideline on clinical nutrition in the intensive care unit. Clin Nutr. 2019;38(1):48-79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts S, Brody R, Rawal S, Byham-Gray L. Volume-based vs rate-based enteral nutrition in the intensive care unit: impact on nutrition delivery and glycemic control. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2019;43(3):365-375.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rice TW, Wheeler AP, Thompson BT, et al. Initial trophic vs full enteral feeding in patients with acute lung injury: the EDEN randomized trial. JAMA. 2012;307(8):795-803.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cadena AJ, Habib S, Rincon F, Dobak S. The benefits of parenteral nutrition (PN) versus enteral nutrition (EN) among adult critically Ill patients: what is the evidence? a literature review. J Intensive Care Med. 2019;885066619843782.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deane AM, Chapman MJ, Reintam Blaser A, McClave SA, Emmanuel A. Pathophysiology and treatment of gastrointestinal motility disorders in the acutely Ill. Nutr Clin Pract. 2019;34(1):23-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deane AM, Rayner CK, Keeshan A, et al. The effects of critical illness on intestinal glucose sensing, transporters, and absorption. Crit Care Med. 2014;42(1):57-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman M, Fraser R, Vozzo R, et al. Antro-pyloro-duodenal motor responses to gastric and duodenal nutrient in critically ill patients. Gut. 2005;54(10):1384-1390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McClave SA, Taylor BE, Martindale RG, et al. Guidelines for the Provision and Assessment of Nutrition Support Therapy in the Adult Critically Ill Patient: Society of Critical Care Medicine (SCCM) and American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (A.S.P.E.N.). JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2016;40(2):159-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poulard F, Dimet J, Martin-Lefevre L, et al. Impact of not measuring residual gastric volume in mechanically ventilated patients receiving early enteral feeding A prospective before after study. J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2010;34(2):125-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rice TW. Gastric residual volume: end of an era. JAMA. 2013;309(3):283-284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szarka LA, Camilleri M. Methods for measurement of gastric motility. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2009;296(3):G461-475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman MJ, Besanko LK, Burgstad CM, et al. Gastric emptying of a liquid nutrient meal in the critically ill: relationship between scintigraphic and carbon breath test measurement. Gut. 2011;60(10):1336-1343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghoos YF, Maes BD, Geypens BJ, et al. Measurement of gastric emptying rate of solids by means of a carbon-labeled octanoic acid breath test. Gastroenterology. 1993;104(6):1640-1647.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calbet JA, MacLean DA. Role of caloric content on gastric emptying in humans. J Physiol. 1997;498(Pt 2):553-559.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goelen N, Tack J, Janssen P. Erythromycin stimulates phasic gastric contractility as assessed with an isovolumetric intragastric balloon pressure measurement. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;(n/a):e13991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goelen N, Janssen P, Tack J, et al. Continuous assessment of gastric motility and its relation to gastric emptying in adult critically ill patients. JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costill DL, Saltin B. Factors limiting gastric emptying during rest and exercise. J Appl Physiol. 1974;37(5):679-683.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tack J, Ly HG, Carbone F, et al. Efficacy of mirtazapine in patients with functional dyspepsia and weight loss. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;14(3):385-392 e384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carbone F, Tack J, Hoffman I. The intragastric pressure measurement: a novel method to assess gastric accommodation in functional dyspepsia children. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2017;64(6):918-924.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deane AM, Besanko LK, Burgstad CM, Chapman MJ, Horowitz M, Fraser RJ. Modulation of individual components of gastric motor response to duodenal glucose. World J Gastroenterol. 2013;19(35):5863-5869.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alkhawaja S, Martin C, Butler RJ, Gwadry-Sridhar F. Post-pyloric versus gastric tube feeding for preventing pneumonia and improving nutritional outcomes in critically ill adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;(8):CD008875.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moxon TE, Nimmegeers P, Telen D, Fryer PJ, Van Impe J, Bakalis S. Effect of chyme viscosity and nutrient feedback mechanism on gastric emptying. Chem Eng Sci. 2017;171:318-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parker H, Hoad CL, Tucker E, et al. Gastric motor and sensory function in health assessed by magnetic resonance imaging: Establishment of reference intervals for the Nottingham test meal in healthy subjects. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;30(12):e13463.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feinle C, Kunz P, Boesiger P, Fried M, Schwizer W. Scintigraphic validation of a magnetic resonance imaging method to study gastric emptying of a solid meal in humans. Gut. 1999;44(1):106-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khalaf A, Hoad CL, Blackshaw E, et al. Simultaneous measurement of gastric emptying of a soup test meal using MRI and gamma scintigraphy. Diagnostics (Basel). 2020;10(3):170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoad CL, Parker H, Hudders N, et al. Measurement of gastric meal and secretion volumes using magnetic resonance imaging. Phys Med Biol. 2015;60(3):1367-1383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tougas G, Eaker EY, Abell TL, et al. Assessment of gastric emptying using a low fat meal: establishment of international control values. Am J Gastroenterol. 2000;95(6):1456-1462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goelen N, Doperé G, Morales J, Van Huffel S, Tack J, Janssen P. Enteral nutrition dose- dependently inhibits phasic gastric motility. Paper presented at: European Society of Neurogastroenterology and Motility meeting; September 5-7, 2019, 2019; Lisbon.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
