<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33595848</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0501</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>32</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical oral implants research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Oral Implants Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparing effectiveness of rubber dam and gingival displacement cord with copy abutment in reducing residual cement in cement-retained implant crowns: A crossover RCT.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>549</StartPage>
          <EndPage>558</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>549-558</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/clr.13724</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the amount of residual cement after cementation of implant crown abutments with rubber dam and retraction cord with copy abutments techniques.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Thirty single posterior metal-ceramic implant-supported restorations were delivered to 20 patients. The crowns were fabricated with occlusal openings obturated with composite, and then luted with resin-reinforced glass-ionomer cement on customised standard abutments. The cementation procedure was performed twice in the same specimens using rubber dam (group 1) and retraction cord with copy abutment (group 2). If no cement remnants were seen on periapical radiographs after cleaning, the crown-abutment unit was dismounted. All quadrants of the specimens were photographed to calculate the percentage proportions of residual cement area. Mann-Whitney and Kruskal-Wallis tests were used for statistical analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In each group, 120 measurements were performed (30 implants, 4 surfaces each). The median percentage ratio with interquartile range (IQR) between the cement remnant area and total specimen area was 1.39% (IQR 0.77%-2.29%) and 0.58% (IQR 0.31%-1.33%) in groups 1 and 2, respectively. Lesser cement remnants were found in group 2 with a statistically significant difference (p &lt; .001). The comparison of the mesial, distal, buccal, and lingual surfaces in each group showed no statistically significant differences between them (group 1, p = .482; group 2, p = .330).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The retraction cord and copy abutment reduced the excess cement more efficiently than the rubber dam did. Notwithstanding, undetected cement remnants were observed with both methods, and neither should be considered reliable in clinical applications.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Andrijauskas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paulius</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Odontology, Faculty of Medicine, Vilnius University, Vilnius, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zukauskas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Saulius</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Odontology, Faculty of Medicine, Vilnius University, Vilnius, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alkimavicius</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonas</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Odontology, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Vilnius Research Group, Vilnius, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peciuliene</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vytaute</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Odontology, Faculty of Medicine, Vilnius University, Vilnius, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Linkevicius</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tomas</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9587-5560</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Odontology, Faculty of Medicine, Vilnius University, Vilnius, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Vilnius Research Group, Vilnius, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Denmark</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Oral Implants Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9105713</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0905-7161</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003738">Dental Cements</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015921">Dental Implants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005899">Glass Ionomer Cements</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002484" MajorTopicYN="N">Cementation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003442" MajorTopicYN="N">Crowns</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000044" MajorTopicYN="N">Dental Abutments</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003738" MajorTopicYN="N">Dental Cements</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dental Implants</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019094" MajorTopicYN="N">Dental Prosthesis, Implant-Supported</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005899" MajorTopicYN="N">Glass Ionomer Cements</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016733" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rubber Dams</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33595848</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/clr.13724</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agar, J. R., Cameron, S. M., Hughbanks, J. C., &amp; Parker, M. H. (1997). Cement removal from restorations luted to titanium abutments with simulated subgingival margins. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 78(1), 43-47. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3913(97)70086-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Ani, A., Bennani, V., Chandler, N. P., Lyons, K. M., &amp; Thomson, W. M. (2010). New Zealand dentists’ use of gingival retraction techniques for fixed prosthodontics and implants. The New Zealand Dental Journal, 106(3), 92-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhushan, P., Aras, M. A., Chitre, V., Mysore, A. R., &amp; Daswani, S. R. (2017). A novel universal cementation technique for implant-supported crowns with subgingival margins. Journal of Prosthodontics, 26(7), 628-632. https://doi.org/10.1111/jopr.12450</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canullo, L., Cocchetto, R., Marinotti, F., Oltra, D. P., Diago, M. P., &amp; Loi, I. (2016). Clinical evaluation of an improved cementation technique for implant-supported restorations: A randomized controlled trial. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 27(12), 1492-1499. https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12589</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caudry, S., Chvartszaid, D., &amp; Kemp, N. (2009). A simple cementation method to prevent material extrusion into the periimplant tissues. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 102(2), 130-131. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3913(09)60126-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chee, W. W. L., Duncan, J., Afshar, M., &amp; Moshaverinia, A. (2013). Evaluation of the amount of excess cement around the margins of cement-retained dental implant restorations: The effect of the cement application method. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 109(4), 216-221. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3913(13)60047-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frisch, E., Ratka-Krüger, P., Weigl, P., &amp; Woelber, J. (2015). Minimizing excess cement in implant-supported fixed restorations using an extraoral replica technique: A prospective 1-year study. The International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants, 30(6), 1355-1361. https://doi.org/10.11607/jomi.3967</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galván, G., Kois, J. C., Chaiyabutr, Y., &amp; Kois, D. (2015). Cemented implant restoration: A technique for minimizing adverse biologic consequences. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 114(4), 482-485. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2014.10.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hess, T. A. (2014). A technique to eliminate subgingival cement adhesion to implant abutments by using polytetrafluoroethylene tape. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 112(2), 365-368. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2013.06.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jimenez, R. A., &amp; Vargas-Koudriavtsev, T. (2016). Effect of preseating, screw access opening, and vent holes on extrusion of excess cement at the crown-abutment margin and associated tensile force for cement-retained implant restorations. The International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants, 31(4), 807-812. https://doi.org/10.11607/jomi.4143</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korsch, M., Marten, S.-M., Walther, W., Vital, M., Pieper, D. H., &amp; Dötsch, A. (2018). Impact of dental cement on the peri-implant biofilm-microbial comparison of two different cements in an in vivo observational study. Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research, 20(5), 806-813. https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12650</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, J. H., Park, I. S., &amp; Sohn, D. S. (2016). A digital approach to fabricating an abutment replica to control cement volume in a cement-retained implant prosthesis. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 116(1), 25-28. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2016.01.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, T., Hu, X., Zhu, L., Pan, X., Zhou, Y., &amp; Liu, J. (2016). Comparative in vitro study of cementing techniques for implant-supported restorations. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 116(1), 59-66. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2016.01.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linkevicius, T., Puisys, A., Vindasiute, E., Linkeviciene, L., &amp; Apse, P. (2013). Does residual cement around implant-supported restorations cause peri-implant disease? A retrospective case analysis. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 24(11), 1179-1184. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0501.2012.02570.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linkevicius, T., Vindasiute, E., Puisys, A., Linkeviciene, L., Maslova, N., &amp; Puriene, A. (2013). The influence of the cementation margin position on the amount of undetected cement. A prospective clinical study. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 24(1), 71-76. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0501.2012.02453.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linkevicius, T., Vindasiute, E., Puisys, A., &amp; Peciuliene, V. (2011). The influence of margin location on the amount of undetected cement excess after delivery of cement-retained implant restorations. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 22(12), 1379-1384. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0501.2010.02119.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalakis, K. X., Hirayama, H., &amp; Garefis, P. D. (2003). Cement-retained versus screw-retained implant restorations: A critical review. The International Journal of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Implants, 18(5), 719-728.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nematollahi, F., Beyabanaki, E., &amp; Alikhasi, M. (2016). Cement selection for cement-retained implant-supported prostheses: A literature review. Journal of Prosthodontics, 25(7), 599-606. https://doi.org/10.1111/jopr.12361</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pesce, P., Canullo, L., Grusovin, M. G., de Bruyn, H., Cosyn, J., &amp; Pera, P. (2015). Systematic review of some prosthetic risk factors for peri-implantitis. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 114(3), 346-350. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2015.04.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pette, G. A., Ganeles, J., &amp; Norkin, F. J. (2013). Radiographic appearance of commonly used cements in implant dentistry. The International Journal of Periodontics &amp; Restorative Dentistry, 33(1), 61-68. https://doi.org/10.11607/prd.1466</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quaranta, A., Lim, Z. W., Tang, J., Perrotti, V., &amp; Leichter, J. (2017). The impact of residual subgingival cement on biological complications around dental implants: A systematic review. Implant Dentistry, 26(3), 465-474. https://doi.org/10.1097/ID.0000000000000593</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajan, M., &amp; Gunaseelan, R. (2004). Fabrication of a cement- and screw-retained implant prosthesis. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 92(6), 578-580. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022391304006092</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rayyan, M. M., &amp; Makarem, H. A. (2016). A modified technique for preventing excess cement around implant supported restoration margins. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 116(6), 840-842. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2016.04.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sancho-Puchades, M., Crameri, D., Özcan, M., Sailer, I., Jung, R. E., Hämmerle, C. H. F., &amp; Thoma, D. S. (2017). The influence of the emergence profile on the amount of undetected cement excess after delivery of cement-retained implant reconstructions. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 28(12), 1515-1522. https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seo, C. W., &amp; Seo, J. M. (2017). A technique for minimizing subgingival residual cement by using rubber dam for cement-retained implant crowns. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 117(2), 327-328. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.prosdent.2016.08.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staubli, N., Walter, C., Schmidt, J. C., Weiger, R., &amp; Zitzmann, N. U. (2017). Excess cement and the risk of peri-implant disease - A systematic review. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 28(10), 1278-1290. https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.12954</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vindasiute, E., Puisys, A., Maslova, N., Linkeviciene, L., Peciuliene, V., &amp; Linkevicius, T. (2015). Clinical factors influencing removal of the cement excess in implant-supported restorations. Clinical Implant Dentistry and Related Research, 17(4), 771-778. https://doi.org/10.1111/cid.12170</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wadhwani, C., Hess, T., Faber, T., Piñeyro, A., &amp; Chen, C. S. K. (2010). A descriptive study of the radiographic density of implant restorative cements. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 103(5), 295-302. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3913(10)60062-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wadhwani, C., &amp; Piñeyro, A. (2009). Technique for controlling the cement for an implant crown. The Journal of Prosthetic Dentistry, 102(1), 57-58. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3913(09)60102-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber, H. P., Kim, D. M., Ng, M. W., Hwang, J. W., &amp; Fiorellini, J. P. (2006). Peri-implant soft-tissue health surrounding cement- and screw-retained implant restorations: A multi-center, 3-year prospective study. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 17(4), 375-379. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0501.2005.01232.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, T. G. (2009). The positive relationship between excess cement and peri-implant disease: A prospective clinical endoscopic study. Journal of Periodontology, 80(9), 1388-1392. https://doi.org/10.1902/jop.2009.090115</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuzbasioglu, E. (2014). A modified technique for extraoral cementation of implant retained restorations for preventing excess cement around the margins. The Journal of Advanced Prosthodontics, 6(2), 146-149. https://doi.org/10.4047/jap.2014.6.2.146</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaugg, L. K., Zehnder, I., Rohr, N., Fischer, J., &amp; Zitzmann, N. U. (2018). The effects of crown venting or pre-cementing of CAD/CAM-constructed all-ceramic crowns luted on YTZ implants on marginal cement excess. Clinical Oral Implants Research, 29(1), 82-90. https://doi.org/10.1111/clr.13071</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
