<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33613932</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2040-6207</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Therapeutic advances in hematology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Hematol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The role of acalabrutinib in adults with chronic lymphocytic leukemia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2040620721990553</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2040620721990553</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2040620721990553</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2040620721990553</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The treatment landscape of chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) has significantly changed in the past decade. This paradigm shift is due to the introduction of novel agents to the field. The two major classes of drugs that have contributed to this dramatic evolution include the Bruton tyrosine kinase (BTK) inhibitors and BCL2 inhibitors. Ibrutinib was the first-in-class drug which was initially approved by the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of patients with relapsed/refractory and later for patients with treatment-naïve CLL. Despite encouraging efficacy outcomes, its use has been associated with cardiovascular and gastrointestinal toxicities likely due to off-target inhibition of ITK, TEC and EGFR family kinases. The next generation of BTK inhibitors was developed to be more selective with less off-target inhibition with the prospect to improve tolerability without compromising efficacy. Acalabrutinib, a selective covalent BTK inhibitor, is a second generation BTK inhibitor. The focus of this review is on two major phase III trials that resulted in the FDA approval of acalabrutinib in 2019. The ELEVATE TN trial investigated acalabrutinib with or without obintuzumab <i>versus</i> chlorambucil-obinutuzumab in older and frail patients with previously untreated CLL. The ASCEND trial explored acalabrutinib <i>versus</i> chemoimmunotherapy in patients with relapsed/refractory CLL. Both trials demonstrated superiority of the acalabrutinib-containing arms in terms of both efficacy and tolerability. Unfortunately, the availability of new generation BTK inhibitors has not resulted in mitigating the financial toxicities associated with these potentially life-long treatments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s), 2021.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fakhri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bita</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2124-7243</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Hematology/Blood and Marrow Transplantation, University of California, 400 Parnassus Avenue, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Andreadis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Charalambos</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Hematology/Blood and Marrow Transplantation, University of California, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ther Adv Hematol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101549589</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2040-6207</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BTK inhibitors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acalabrutinib</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic lymphocytic leukemia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ibrutinib</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small lymphocytic lymphoma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: The authors declare that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>55</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33613932</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871059</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2040620721990553</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2040620721990553</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Byrd JC, Brown JR, O’Brien S, et al.
Ibrutinib versus ofatumumab in previously treated chronic lymphoid leukemia. N Engl J Med
2014; 371: 213–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24881631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Byrd JC, Hillmen P, O’Brien S, et al.
Long-term follow-up of the RESONATE phase 3 trial of ibrutinib vs ofatumumab. Blood
2019; 133: 2031–2042.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6509542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30842083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Munir T, Brown JR, O’Brien S, et al.
Final analysis from RESONATE: up to six years of follow-up on ibrutinib in patients with previously treated chronic lymphocytic leukemia or small lymphocytic lymphoma. Am J Hematol
2019; 94: 1353–1363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6899718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31512258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Burger JA, Tedeschi A, Barr PM, et al.
Ibrutinib as initial therapy for patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia. N Engl J Med
2015; 373: 2425–2437.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4722809</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26639149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Barr PM, Robak T, Owen C, et al.
Sustained efficacy and detailed clinical follow-up of first-line ibrutinib treatment in older patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia: extended phase 3 results from RESONATE-2. Haematologica
2018; 103: 1502–1510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6119145</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29880603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Burger JA, Barr PM, Robak T, et al.
Long-term efficacy and safety of first-line ibrutinib treatment for patients with CLL/SLL: 5 years of follow-up from the phase 3 RESONATE-2 study. Leukemia. Epub ahead of print 18
October
2019.  DOI: 10.1038/s41375-019-0602-x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41375-019-0602-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7214263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Woyach JA, Ruppert AS, Heerema NA, et al.
Ibrutinib regimens versus chemoimmunotherapy in older patients with untreated CLL. N Engl J Med
2018; 379: 2517–2528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6325637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30501481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shanafelt TD, Wang XV, Kay NE, et al.
Ibrutinib–rituximab or chemoimmunotherapy for chronic lymphocytic leukemia. N Engl J Med
2019; 381: 432–443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Moreno C, Greil R, Demirkan F, et al.
Ibrutinib plus obinutuzumab versus chlorambucil plus obinutuzumab in first-line treatment of chronic lymphocytic leukaemia (iLLUMINATE): a multicentre, randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol
2019; 20: 43–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mato AR, Nabhan C, Thompson MC, et al.
Toxicities and outcomes of 616 ibrutinib-treated patients in the United States: a real-world analysis. Haematologica
2018; 103: 874–879.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5927982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29419429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Byrd JC, Harrington B, O’Brien S, et al.
Acalabrutinib (ACP-196) in relapsed chronic lymphocytic leukemia. N Engl J Med
2016; 374: 323–332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4862586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26641137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Herman SEM, Montraveta A, Niemann CU, et al.
The Bruton Tyrosine Kinase (BTK) inhibitor acalabrutinib demonstrates potent on-target effects and efficacy in two mouse models of chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Clin Cancer Res
2017; 23: 2831–2841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5548968</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27903679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brown JR.
How I treat CLL patients with ibrutinib. Blood
2018; 131: 379–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29255067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lipsky AH, Farooqui MZ, Tian X, et al.
Incidence and risk factors of bleeding-related adverse events in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia treated with ibrutinib. Haematologica
2015; 100: 1571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666333</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26430171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang A, Yan XE, Wu H, et al.
Ibrutinib targets mutant-EGFR kinase with a distinct binding conformation. Oncotarget
2016; 7: 69760–69769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5342513</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27626175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Awan FT, Schuh A, Brown JR, et al.
Acalabrutinib monotherapy in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia who are intolerant to ibrutinib. Blood Adv
2019; 3: 1553–1562.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6517672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Advani RH, Buggy JJ, Sharman JP, et al.
Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor ibrutinib (PCI-32765) has significant activity in patients with relapsed/refractory B-cell malignancies. J Clin Oncol
2013; 31: 88–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5505166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23045577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sun C, Nierman P, Kendall EK, et al.
Clinical and biological implications of target occupancy in CLL treated with the BTK inhibitor acalabrutinib. Blood
2020; 136: 93–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332900</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32202637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sharman JP, Banerji V, Fogliatto LM, et al.
ELEVATE TN: phase 3 study of acalabrutinib combined with Obinutuzumab (O) or alone vs o plus Chlorambucil (Clb) in Patients (Pts) with treatment-naive Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL). Blood
2019; 134 (Suppl. 1): 31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sharman JP, Egyed M, Jurczak W, et al.
Acalabrutinib with or without obinutuzumab versus chlorambucil and obinutuzmab for treatment-naive chronic lymphocytic leukaemia (ELEVATE TN): a randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet
2020; 395: 1278–1291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32305093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ghia P, Pluta A, Wach M, et al.
ASCEND: phase III, randomized trial of acalabrutinib versus idelalisib plus rituximab or bendamustine plus rituximab in relapsed or refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia. J Clin Oncol
2020; 28: 2849–2861.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459600</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Goede V, Fischer K, Busch R, et al.
Obinutuzumab plus chlorambucil in patients with CLL and coexisting conditions. N Engl J Med
2014; 370: 1101–1110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24401022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yazdy MS, Mato AR, Roeker LE, et al.
Toxicities and outcomes of acalabrutinib-treated patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia: a retrospective analysis of real world patients. Blood
2019; 134 (Suppl. 1): 4311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang M, Rule S, Zinzani PL, et al.
Acalabrutinib in relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma (ACE-LY-004): a single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 trial. Lancet
2018; 391: 659–667.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7864374</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29241979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang M, Rule S, Zinzani PL, et al.
Long-term follow-up of acalabrutinib monotherapy in patients with relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma. Blood
2018; 132 (Suppl. 1): 2876.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hillmen P, Brown JR, Byrd JC, et al.
ALPINE: phase III zanubrutinib (BGB-3111) versus ibrutinib in patients with relapsed/refractory (R/R) chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL). J Clin Oncol
2019; 37 (Suppl. 15): TPS7572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Woyach JA, Ruppert AS, Guinn D, et al.
BTK(C481S)-mediated resistance to ibrutinib in chronic lymphocytic leukemia. J Clin Oncol
2017; 35: 1437–1443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5455463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28418267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mato AR, Flinn IW, Pagel JM, et al.
Results from a first-in-human, proof-of-concept phase 1 trial in pretreated B-cell malignancies for Loxo-305, a next-generation, highly selective, non-covalent BTK inhibitor. Blood
2019; 134 (Suppl. 1): 501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fischer K, Al-Sawaf O, Bahlo J, et al.
Venetoclax and obinutuzumab in patients with CLL and coexisting conditions. N Engl J Med
2019; 380: 2225–2236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31166681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Al-Sawaf O, Zhang C, Tandon M, et al.
Venetoclax plus obinutuzumab versus chlorambucil plus obinutuzumab for previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukaemia (CLL14): follow-up results from a multicentre, open-label, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol
2020; 21: 1188–1200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32888452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jain N, Keating M, Thompson P, et al.
Ibrutinib and venetoclax for first-line treatment of CLL. N Engl J Med
2019; 380: 2095–2103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31141631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hillmen P, Schuh A, Eyre TA, et al.
Acalabrutinib monotherapy in patients with richter transformation from the phase 1/2 ACE-CL-001 clinical study. Blood
2016; 128: 60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
