<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">33620821</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK567744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211">Vitamin A Deficiency</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hodge</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Madigan Army Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>USUHS, Madigan Army Medical Center</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>Vitamin A is a fat-soluble vitamin essential in cell development, metabolism, immune competency, vision, and reproductive functions. Vitamin A deficiency (VAD) is a highly prevalent health concern associated with substantial morbidity and mortality, mostly affecting young children in impoverished regions throughout the world. Insufficient intake of absorption leads to deficiency and compromise of essential physiologic processes. Natural sources of vitamin A include dark leafy greens, orange-colored vegetables, milk products, liver, and fish. It is absorbed in the duodenum after hydrolyzation by pancreatic and intestinal enzymes and emulsified with dietary fats and bile acids. The majority is then stored in the hepatic stellate cells. Significant amounts are also stored in adipose tissue and the pancreas. The recommended dietary allowance (RDA) of vitamin A by the Institute of Medicine in healthy adults is 700 micrograms/day for women and 900 micrograms/day for men. For children, pregnant women, and lactating women, the RDA is 300 to 900, 770, and 1300 micrograms/day respectively. The minimum requirement to prevent symptomatic VAD in children 1 to 5 years of age is about 200 micrograms/day. Serum retinol levels are a good marker of vitamin A nutritional status. Deficiency is defined as a retinol concentration of fewer than 20 micrograms/dL.  Vitamin A deficiency-associated ocular symptoms have been shown to develop at concentrations less than 10 micrograms/dL. Dietary vitamin A is ingested as either carotenoid from fruits and vegetables or retinoid from animal products. Carotenoids are a provitamin A, most commonly beta-carotene, and retinoids are active forms of vitamin A, such as retinol and retinyl esters. Retinoids have been shown to have 75% to 100% absorption, whereas carotenoid absorption varies greatly depending on the food matrix and type of carotenoid.  A 12 to 1 ratio of beta-carotene to retinol absorption in a diet of mixed fruits and vegetables is the estimated conversion used by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Many populations in developing countries rarely ingest meat, dairy, or carotenoid-rich vegetables leading to difficulty obtaining sufficient quantities of vitamin A.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s3">Etiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s4">Epidemiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s5">Pathophysiology</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s6">History and Physical</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s7">Evaluation</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s8">Treatment / Management</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s9">Differential Diagnosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s10">Prognosis</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s11">Complications</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s12">Deterrence and Patient Education</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s13">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s14">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-31211" sec="article-31211.s15">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wiseman EM, Bar-El Dadon S, Reifen R. The vicious cycle of vitamin a deficiency: A review. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr. 2017 Nov 22;57(17):3703-3714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27128154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Ambrosio DN, Clugston RD, Blaner WS. Vitamin A metabolism: an update. Nutrients. 2011 Jan;3(1):63-103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3042718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21350678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hombali AS, Solon JA, Venkatesh BT, Nair NS, Peña-Rosas JP. Fortification of staple foods with vitamin A for vitamin A deficiency. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019 May 10;5:CD010068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6509778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31074495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison EH. Mechanisms involved in the intestinal absorption of dietary vitamin A and provitamin A carotenoids. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2012 Jan;1821(1):70-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3525326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21718801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senoo H, Mezaki Y, Fujiwara M. The stellate cell system (vitamin A-storing cell system). Anat Sci Int. 2017 Sep;92(4):387-455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28299597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeed A, Dullaart RPF, Schreuder TCMA, Blokzijl H, Faber KN. Disturbed Vitamin A Metabolism in Non-Alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease (NAFLD). Nutrients. 2017 Dec 29;10(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5793257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29286303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer CM, Sternberg MR, Schleicher RL, Haynes BM, Rybak ME, Pirkle JL. The CDC's Second National Report on Biochemical Indicators of Diet and Nutrition in the U.S. Population is a valuable tool for researchers and policy makers. J Nutr. 2013 Jun;143(6):938S-47S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4822995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23596164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller M, Humphrey J, Johnson E, Marinda E, Brookmeyer R, Katz J. Why do children become vitamin A deficient? J Nutr. 2002 Sep;132(9 Suppl):2867S-2880S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12221263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reboul E. Absorption of vitamin A and carotenoids by the enterocyte: focus on transport proteins. Nutrients. 2013 Sep 12;5(9):3563-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3798921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24036530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haskell MJ. The challenge to reach nutritional adequacy for vitamin A: β-carotene bioavailability and conversion--evidence in humans. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012 Nov;96(5):1193S-203S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23053560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotz C, Chileshe J, Siamusantu W, Palaniappan U, Kafwembe E. Vitamin A intake and infection are associated with plasma retinol among pre-school children in rural Zambia. Public Health Nutr. 2012 Sep;15(9):1688-96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22443986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahman MM, Wahed MA, Fuchs GJ, Baqui AH, Alvarez JO. Synergistic effect of zinc and vitamin A on the biochemical indexes of vitamin A nutrition in children. Am J Clin Nutr. 2002 Jan;75(1):92-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11756065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West CE. Vitamin A and measles. Nutr Rev. 2000 Feb;58(2 Pt 2):S46-54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10748617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoltzfus RJ, Underwood BA. Breast-milk vitamin A as an indicator of the vitamin A status of women and infants. Bull World Health Organ. 1995;73(5):703-11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2486808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8846497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhouri RH, Hashmi H, Baker RD, Gelfond D, Baker SS. Vitamin and mineral status in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2013 Jan;56(1):89-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22832510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min M, Patel B, Han S, Bocelli L, Kheder J, Vaze A, Wassef W. Exocrine Pancreatic Insufficiency and Malnutrition in Chronic Pancreatitis: Identification, Treatment, and Consequences. Pancreas. 2018 Sep;47(8):1015-1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6462188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30074926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kositamongkol S, Suthutvoravut U, Chongviriyaphan N, Feungpean B, Nuntnarumit P. Vitamin A and E status in very low birth weight infants. J Perinatol. 2011 Jul;31(7):471-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21233795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirth JP, Petry N, Tanumihardjo SA, Rogers LM, McLean E, Greig A, Garrett GS, Klemm RD, Rohner F. Vitamin A Supplementation Programs and Country-Level Evidence of Vitamin A Deficiency. Nutrients. 2017 Feb 24;9(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5372853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28245571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abebe Z, Haki GD, Schweigert FJ, Henkel IM, Baye K. Low breastmilk vitamin A concentration is prevalent in rural Ethiopia. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2019 Aug;73(8):1110-1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30297758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laxmaiah A, Nair MK, Arlappa N, Raghu P, Balakrishna N, Rao KM, Galreddy C, Kumar S, Ravindranath M, Rao VV, Brahmam GN. Prevalence of ocular signs and subclinical vitamin A deficiency and its determinants among rural pre-school children in India. Public Health Nutr. 2012 Apr;15(4):568-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21884647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed F. Vitamin A deficiency in Bangladesh: a review and recommendations for improvement. Public Health Nutr. 1999 Mar;2(1):1-14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10452726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venu M, Martin E, Saeian K, Gawrieh S. High prevalence of vitamin A deficiency and vitamin D deficiency in patients evaluated for liver transplantation. Liver Transpl. 2013 Jun;19(6):627-33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3667969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23495130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slater GH, Ren CJ, Siegel N, Williams T, Barr D, Wolfe B, Dolan K, Fielding GA. Serum fat-soluble vitamin deficiency and abnormal calcium metabolism after malabsorptive bariatric surgery. J Gastrointest Surg. 2004 Jan;8(1):48-55; discussion 54-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14746835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curcio CA, Sloan KR, Kalina RE, Hendrickson AE. Human photoreceptor topography. J Comp Neurol. 1990 Feb 22;292(4):497-523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2324310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saari JC. Vitamin A and Vision. Subcell Biochem. 2016;81:231-259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27830507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert C. The eye signs of vitamin A deficiency. Community Eye Health. 2013;26(84):66-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3936686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24782581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelazzo FB, Oliveira JM, Stefanello J, Luzia LA, Rondó PH. The influence of vitamin A supplementation on iron status. Nutrients. 2013 Nov 07;5(11):4399-413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3847738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24212089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghishan FK, Kiela PR. Vitamins and Minerals in Inflammatory Bowel Disease. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2017 Dec;46(4):797-808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6342481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Medeiros PHQS, Pinto DV, de Almeida JZ, Rêgo JMC, Rodrigues FAP, Lima AÂM, Bolick DT, Guerrant RL, Oriá RB. Modulation of Intestinal Immune and Barrier Functions by Vitamin A: Implications for Current Understanding of Malnutrition and Enteric Infections in Children. Nutrients. 2018 Aug 21;10(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6164597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30134532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Surman SL, Penkert RR, Sealy RE, Jones BG, Marion TN, Vogel P, Hurwitz JL. Consequences of Vitamin A Deficiency: Immunoglobulin Dysregulation, Squamous Cell Metaplasia, Infectious Disease, and Death. Int J Mol Sci. 2020 Aug 04;21(15)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7432039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32759702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maronn M, Allen DM, Esterly NB. Phrynoderma: a manifestation of vitamin A deficiency?... The rest of the story. Pediatr Dermatol. 2005 Jan-Feb;22(1):60-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15660900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer A. Vitamin a deficiency and clinical disease: an historical overview. J Nutr. 2008 Oct;138(10):1835-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18806089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanumihardjo SA. Vitamin A: biomarkers of nutrition for development. Am J Clin Nutr. 2011 Aug;94(2):658S-65S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3142734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21715511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imdad A, Mayo-Wilson E, Herzer K, Bhutta ZA. Vitamin A supplementation for preventing morbidity and mortality in children from six months to five years of age. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017 Mar 11;3:CD008524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28282701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballew C, Bowman BA, Sowell AL, Gillespie C. Serum retinol distributions in residents of the United States: third National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 1988-1994. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001 Mar;73(3):586-93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11237936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline: Vitamin A Supplementation in Infants and Children 6–59 Months of Age. World Health Organization; Geneva: 2011. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24575452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline: Vitamin A Supplementation in Pregnant Women. World Health Organization; Geneva: 2011. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26158192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline: Vitamin A Supplementation in Infants 1–5 Months of Age. World Health Organization; Geneva: 2011. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23586125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline: Neonatal Vitamin A Supplementation. World Health Organization; Geneva: 2011. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24575453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline: Vitamin A Supplementation in Postpartum Women. World Health Organization; Geneva: 2011. </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24575454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measles vaccines: WHO position paper. Wkly Epidemiol Rec. 2009 Aug 28;84(35):349-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Via MA, Mechanick JI. Nutritional and Micronutrient Care of Bariatric Surgery Patients: Current Evidence Update. Curr Obes Rep. 2017 Sep;6(3):286-296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28718091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu S, Khanna P, Srivastava R, Kumar A. Oral vitamin A supplementation in very low birth weight neonates: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Pediatr. 2019 Aug;178(8):1255-1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31209560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun H, Cheng R, Wang Z. EARLY VITAMIN A SUPPLEMENTATION IMPROVES THE OUTCOME OF RETINOPATHY OF PREMATURITY IN EXTREMELY PRETERM INFANTS. Retina. 2020 Jun;40(6):1176-1184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7242171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30964778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehra D, Le PH.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Sep 28, Physiology, Night Vision.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31424830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merin S, Auerbach E. Retinitis pigmentosa. Surv Ophthalmol. 1976 Mar-Apr;20(5):303-46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">817406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine RA, Rabb MF. Bitot's spot overlying a pinguecula. Arch Ophthalmol. 1971 Nov;86(5):525-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5315641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bors F, Fells P. Reversal of the complications of self-induced vitamin A deficiency. Br J Ophthalmol. 1971 Mar;55(3):210-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1208224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5575226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crum AR, Srikumaran D, Woreta F. Bitot's Spots following Bariatric Surgery: An Ocular Manifestation of a Systemic Disease. Case Rep Ophthalmol. 2017 Sep-Dec;8(3):581-589.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5836227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29515430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwyer JT, Wiemer KL, Dary O, Keen CL, King JC, Miller KB, Philbert MA, Tarasuk V, Taylor CL, Gaine PC, Jarvis AB, Bailey RL. Fortification and health: challenges and opportunities. Adv Nutr. 2015 Jan;6(1):124-31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4288271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25593151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kassa G, Mesfin A, Gebremedhin S. Uptake of routine vitamin A supplementation for children in Humbo district, southern Ethiopia: community-based cross-sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2020 Oct 02;20(1):1500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7532605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33008352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoddinott J, Ahmed I, Ahmed A, Roy S. Behavior change communication activities improve infant and young child nutrition knowledge and practice of neighboring non-participants in a cluster-randomized trial in rural Bangladesh. PLoS One. 2017;12(6):e0179866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28636674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang G, Qin J, Dolnikowski GG, Russell RM, Grusak MA. Golden Rice is an effective source of vitamin A. Am J Clin Nutr. 2009 Jun;89(6):1776-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2682994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19369372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chitchumroonchokchai C, Diretto G, Parisi B, Giuliano G, Failla ML. Potential of golden potatoes to improve vitamin A and vitamin E status in developing countries. PLoS One. 2017;12(11):e0187102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5678870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29117188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cong L, Wang C, Chen L, Liu H, Yang G, He G. Expression of phytoene synthase1 and carotene desaturase crtI genes result in an increase in the total carotenoids content in transgenic elite wheat (Triticum aestivum L.). J Agric Food Chem. 2009 Sep 23;57(18):8652-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19694433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim MJ, Kim JK, Kim HJ, Pak JH, Lee JH, Kim DH, Choi HK, Jung HW, Lee JD, Chung YS, Ha SH. Genetic modification of the soybean to enhance the β-carotene content through seed-specific expression. PLoS One. 2012;7(10):e48287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3485231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23118971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Wang W, Lian T, Zhang C. Manipulation of Metabolic Pathways to Develop Vitamin-Enriched Crops for Human Health. Front Plant Sci. 2017;8:937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5460589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28634484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Steur H, Demont M, Gellynck X, Stein AJ. The social and economic impact of biofortification through genetic modification. Curr Opin Biotechnol. 2017 Apr;44:161-168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28231514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feroze KB, Kaufman EJ.  StatPearls [Internet] StatPearls Publishing; Treasure Island (FL): 2021. Apr 25, Xerophthalmia.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33620821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
