<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33624254</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1866-3370</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>49</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current topics in behavioral neurosciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Top Behav Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Inflammation, Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder, and Related Disorders.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>31</StartPage>
          <EndPage>53</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>31-53</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/7854_2020_210</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Initial reports supporting the possibility of inflammation in the brain in obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) evolved from the models of Sydenham's Chorea, and Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Disorder Associated with Streptococcus (PANDAS), which implicated excessive autoimmune responses following exposure to group A B-hemolytic streptococcal infections. Subsequently, this model was expanded to Pediatric Autoimmune Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS) which applied the same concept but included other infections. A critical shortcoming of this model was that it was attributable to a small minority of OCD cases. The relationship between inflammation and OCD was more broadly demonstrated through translocator protein (TSPO) positron emission tomography imaging, a method that detects gliosis, an important component of brain inflammation, in neuropsychiatric diseases, including morphological activation and proliferation of microglia and to some extent astroglia. This method identified greater TSPO binding in the cortico-striatal-thalamo-cortical circuit in OCD, providing a direct brain measure of an important component of inflammation. To identify OCD cases with prominent elevations in TSPO binding in clinical research settings with lower cost peripheral markers, a promising approach is to apply blood serum biomarkers of inflammatory molecules produced by activated microglia and astroglia (gliosis). Such measures may aid stratification in future clinical trials. Several inflammatory-modifying interventions, including celecoxib, minocycline, and n-acetylcysteine, have been tested as treatments in randomized double-blind placebo controlled clinical trials and there is a tendency toward positive results, although these medications are not optimized for brain penetration and sample sizes for most trials were small. Future clinical trials of medications that target gliosis in OCD should apply larger sample sizes, ideally incorporating stratification approaches to enrich samples for the presence of gliosis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meyer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Campbell Family Mental Health Research Institute, CAMH, Toronto, ON, Canada. jeffrey.meyer@utoronto.ca.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada. jeffrey.meyer@utoronto.ca.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Top Behav Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101535383</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1866-3370</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018079">Receptors, GABA</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C499229">TSPO protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009771" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018079" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, GABA</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013290" MajorTopicYN="Y">Streptococcal Infections</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gliosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroinflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obsessive-compulsive disorder</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33624254</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2020_210</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams KH, Hansen ES, Pinborg LH, Hasselbalch SG, Svarer C, Holm S, Bolwig TG, Knudsen GM (2005) Patients with obsessive-compulsive disorder have increased 5-HT2A receptor binding in the caudate nuclei. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol 8(3):391–401</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15801987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1461145705005055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Afshar H, Roohafza H, Mohammad-Beigi H, Haghighi M, Jahangard L, Shokouh P, Sadeghi M, Hafezian H (2012) N-acetylcysteine add-on treatment in refractory obsessive-compulsive disorder: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Psychopharmacol 32(6):797–803</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23131885</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCP.0b013e318272677d</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akanuma S, Higuchi T, Higashi H, Ozeki G, Tachikawa M, Kubo Y, Hosoya K (2014) Transporter-mediated prostaglandin E(2) elimination across the rat blood-brain barrier and its attenuation by the activation of N-methyl-D-aspartate receptors. Drug Metab Pharmacokinet 29(5):387–393</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24717839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2133/dmpk.DMPK-14-RG-004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">24717839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akkus F, Terbeck S, Ametamey SM, Rufer M, Treyer V, Burger C, Johayem A, Mancilla BG, Sovago J, Buck A, Hasler G (2014) Metabotropic glutamate receptor 5 binding in patients with obsessive-compulsive disorder. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol 17(12):1915–1922</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24833114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1461145714000716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attwells S, Setiawan E, Wilson AA, Rusjan P, Mizrahi R, Miler L, Xu C, Richter MA, Kahn A, Kish SJ, Houle S, Ravindran L, Meyer JH (2017) Inflammation in the neurocircuitry of obsessive-compulsive disorder. JAMA Psychiat 74:833–840</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.1567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attwells S, Setiawan E, Wilson AA, Rusjan PM, Miler L, Xu C, Hutton C, Husain MI, Kish S, Vasdev N, Houle S, Meyer JH (2020a) Replicating predictive serum correlates of greater translocator protein distribution volume in brain. Neuropsychopharmacology 45(6):925–931</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31683271</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-019-0561-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">31683271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attwells S, Setiawan E, Rusjan PM, Xu C, Hutton C, Rafiei D, Varughese B, Kahn A, Kish SJ, Vasdev N, Houle S, Meyer JH (2020b) Translocator protein distribution volume predicts reduction of symptoms during open-label trial of celecoxib in major depressive disorder. Biol Psychiatry 88(8):649–656. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2020.03.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2020.03.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402468</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">32402468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachen EA, Chesney MA, Criswell LA (2009) Prevalence of mood and anxiety disorders in women with systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum 61:822–829</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19479699</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2763591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.24519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banati R, Myers R, Kreutzberg GW (1997) PK (‘peripheral benzodiazepine’)--binding sites in the CNS indicate early and discrete brain lesions: microautoradiographic detection of [3H]PK11195 binding to activated microglia. J Neurocytol 26:77–82</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9181482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1018567510105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">9181482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banks WA (2015) The blood-brain barrier in neuroimmunology: Tales of separation and assimilation. Brain Behav Immun 44:1–8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25172555</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2014.08.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">25172555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltazar C, Harrison-Brown M, Middleton RJ, Banati R, Liu GJ (2018) Cellular sources and regional variations in the expression of the neuroinflammatory marker translocator protein (TSPO) in the normal brain. Int J Mol Sci 19:E2707</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms19092707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berk M, Malhi GS, Gray LJ, Dean OM (2013) The promise of N-acetylcysteine in neuropsychiatry. Trends Pharmacol Sci 34(3):167–177</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tips.2013.01.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">23369637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhattacharyya S, Khanna S, Chakrabarty K, Mahadevan A, Christopher R, Shankar SK (2009) Anti-brain autoantibodies and altered excitatory neurotransmitters in obsessive-compulsive disorder. Neuropsychopharmacology 34(12):2489–2496</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675532</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2009.77</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bloch MH, Landeros-Weisenberger A, Kelmendi B, Coric V, Bracken MB, Leckman JF (2006) A systematic review: antipsychotic augmentation with treatment refractory obsessive-compulsive disorder. Mol Psychiatry 11(7):622–632</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16585942</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.mp.4001823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Block ML, Zecca L, Hong JS (2007) Microglia-mediated neurotoxicity: uncovering the molecular mechanisms. Nat Rev Neurosci 8(1):57–69</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17180163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">17180163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn2038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown KD, Farmer C, Freeman GM Jr, Spartz EJ, Farhadian B, Thienemann M, Frankovich J (2017) Effect of early and prophylactic nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on flare duration in pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome: an observational study of patients followed by an academic community-based pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome clinic. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol 27(7):619–628</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28696786</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5749580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2016.0193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso F, Vargas AP, Oliveira LD, Guerra AA, Amaral SV (1999) Persistent Sydenham’s chorea. Mov Disord 14(5):805–807</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10495042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1531-8257(199909)14:5&lt;805::AID-MDS1013&gt;3.0.CO;2-P</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">10495042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng S, Hou J, Zhang C, Xu C, Wang L, Zou X, Yu H, Shi Y, Yin Z, Chen G (2015) Minocycline reduces neuroinflammation but does not ameliorate neuron loss in a mouse model of neurodegeneration. Sci Rep 5:10535</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26000566</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4441131</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep10535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark SM, Pocivavsek A, Nicholson JD, Notarangelo FM, Langenberg P, McMahon RP, Kleinman JE, Hyde TM, Stiller J, Postolache TT, Schwarcz R, Tonelli LH (2016) Reduced kynurenine pathway metabolism and cytokine expression in the prefrontal cortex of depressed individuals. J Psychiatry Neurosci 41(6):386–394</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27070351</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5082509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/jpn.150226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Converse AK, Larsen EC, Engle JW, Barnhart TE, Nickles RJ, Duncan ID (2011) 11C-(R)-PK11195 PET imaging of microglial activation and response to minocycline in zymosan-treated rats. J Nucl Med 52(2):257–262</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21233178</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.110.082743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cosco TD, Pillinger T, Emam H, Solmi M, Budhdeo S, Matthew Prina A, Maes M, Stein DJ, Stubbs B, Carvalho AF (2019) Immune aberrations in obsessive-compulsive disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Mol Neurobiol 56(7):4751–4759</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30382535</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12035-018-1409-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cosenza-Nashat M, Zhao ML, Suh HS, Morgan J, Natividad R, Morgello S, Lee SC (2009) Expression of the translocator protein of 18 kDa by microglia, macrophages and astrocytes based on immunohistochemical localization in abnormal human brain. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 35:306–328</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19077109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2990.2008.01006.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cosgrove KP (2013) Personal communication from Hannestad et al. The neuroinflamation marker translocator protein is not elevated in individuals with mild to moderate depression: a [11C]PBR28 PET study. Brain Behav Immun 33:131–138</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2013.06.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa DLC, Diniz JB, Requena G, Joaquim MA, Pittenger C, Bloch MH, Miguel EC, Shavitt RG (2017) Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of N-acetylcysteine augmentation for treatment-resistant obsessive-compulsive disorder. J Clin Psychiatry 78(7):e766–e773</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28617566</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.16m11101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Heyman I, Giovannoni G, Church AW (2005) Incidence of anti-brain antibodies in children with obsessive-compulsive disorder. Br J Psychiatry 187:314–319</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.187.4.314</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">16199788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dantzer R, O’Connor JC, Freund GG, Johnson RW, Kelley KW (2008) From inflammation to sickness and depression: when the immune system subjugates the brain. Nat Rev Neurosci 9(1):46–56</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18073775</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2919277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn2297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dean SL, Singer HS (2017) Treatment of Sydenham’s chorea: a review of the current evidence. Tremor Other Hyperkinet Mov 7:456</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5334/tohm.376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emery ES, Vieco PT (1997) Sydenham chorea: magnetic resonance imaging reveals permanent basal ganglia injury. Neurology 48(2):531–533</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9040753</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.48.2.531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">9040753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enache D, Pariante CM, Mondelli V (2019) Markers of central inflammation in major depressive disorder: a systematic review and meta-analysis of studies examining cerebrospinal fluid, positron emission tomography and post-mortem brain tissue. Brain Behav Immun 81:24–40</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31195092</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2019.06.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esalatmanesh S, Abrishami Z, Zeinoddini A, Rahiminejad F, Sadeghi M, Najarzadegan MR, Shalbafan MR, Akhondzadeh S (2016) Minocycline combination therapy with fluvoxamine in moderate-to-severe obsessive-compulsive disorder: a placebo-controlled, double-blind, randomized trial. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 70(11):517–526</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27488081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pcn.12430</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">27488081</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fettes P, Schulze L, Downar J (2017) Cortico-striatal-thalamic loop circuits of the orbitofrontal cortex: promising therapeutic targets in psychiatric illness. Front Syst Neurosci 11:25</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28496402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5406748</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnsys.2017.00025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galasko D, Montine TJ (2010) Biomarkers of oxidative damage and inflammation in Alzheimer’s disease. Biomark Med 4(1):27–36</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383271</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/bmm.09.89</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">20383271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garrido-Mesa N, Zarzuelo A, Galvez J (2013) Minocycline: far beyond an antibiotic. Br J Pharmacol 169(2):337–352</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23441623</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3651660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bph.12139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gause C, Morris C, Vernekar S, Pardo-Villamizar C, Grados MA, Singer HS (2009) Antineuronal antibodies in OCD: comparisons in children with OCD-only, OCD+chronic tics and OCD+PANDAS. J Neuroimmunol 214(1–2):118–124</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19628285</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2009.06.015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">19628285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghanizadeh A, Mohammadi MR, Bahraini S, Keshavarzi Z, Firoozabadi A, Alavi SA (2017) Efficacy of N-acetylcysteine augmentation on obsessive compulsive disorder: a multicenter randomized double blind placebo controlled clinical trial. Iran J Psychiatry 12(2):134–141</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28659986</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5483239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hagen AA, Gerber JN, Sweeley CC, White RP, Robertson JT (1977) Levels and disappearance of prostaglandin F2alpha in cerebral spinal fluid: a clinical and experimental study. Stroke 8(6):672–675</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">929655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.STR.8.6.672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">929655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hesse S, Stengler K, Regenthal R, Patt M, Becker GA, Franke A, Knupfer H, Meyer PM, Luthardt J, Jahn I, Lobsien D, Heinke W, Brust P, Hegerl U, Sabri O (2011) The serotonin transporter availability in untreated early-onset and late-onset patients with obsessive-compulsive disorder. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol 14(5):606–617</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21232166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1461145710001604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmay MJ, Terpstra M, Coles LD, Mishra U, Ahlskog M, Oz G, Cloyd JC, Tuite PJ (2013) N-acetylcysteine boosts brain and blood glutathione in Gaucher and Parkinson diseases. Clin Neuropharmacol 36(4):103–106</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23860343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3934795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNF.0b013e31829ae713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmes SE, Hinz R, Conen S, Gregory CJ, Matthews JC, Anton-Rodriguez JM, Gerhard A, Talbot PS (2018) Elevated Translocator protein in anterior cingulate in major depression and a role for inflammation in suicidal thinking: a positron emission tomography study. Biol Psychiatry 83(1):61–69</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28939116</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.08.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">28939116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Homsi S, Piaggio T, Croci N, Noble F, Plotkine M, Marchand-Leroux C, Jafarian-Tehrani M (2010) Blockade of acute microglial activation by minocycline promotes neuroprotection and reduces locomotor hyperactivity after closed head injury in mice: a twelve-week follow-up study. J Neurotrauma 27(5):911–921</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20166806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/neu.2009.1223</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">20166806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horti AG, Naik R, Foss CA, Minn I, Misheneva V, Du Y, Wang Y, Mathews WB, Wu Y, Hall A, LaCourse C, Ahn HH, Nam H, Lesniak WG, Valentine H, Pletnikova O, Troncoso JC, Smith MD, Calabresi PA, Savonenko AV, Dannals RF, Pletnikov MV, Pomper MG (2019) PET imaging of microglia by targeting macrophage colony-stimulating factor 1 receptor (CSF1R). Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husby G, van de Rijn I, Zabriskie JB, Abdin ZH, Williams RC Jr (1976) Antibodies reacting with cytoplasm of subthalamic and caudate nuclei neurons in chorea and acute rheumatic fever. J Exp Med 144(4):1094–1110</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">789810</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1084/jem.144.4.1094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">789810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikawa M, Lohith TG, Shrestha S, Telu S, Zoghbi SS, Castellano S, Taliani S, Da Settimo F, Fujita M, Pike VW, Innis RB (2017) Biomarkers consortium Radioligand project T. 11C-ER176, a Radioligand for 18-kDa Translocator protein, has adequate sensitivity to robustly image all three affinity genotypes in human brain. J Nucl Med 58(2):320–325</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27856631</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5288742</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.116.178996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imaizumi M, Kim HJ, Zoghbi SS, Briard E, Hong J, Musachio JL, Ruetzler C, Chuang DM, Pike VW, Innis RB, Fujita M (2007) PET imaging with [11C]PBR28 can localize and quantify upregulated peripheral benzodiazepine receptors associated with cerebral ischemia in rat. Neurosci Lett 411(3):200–205</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17127001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neulet.2006.09.093</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">17127001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalinski P (2012) Regulation of immune responses by prostaglandin E2. J Immunol 188(1):21–28</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22187483</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1101029</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">22187483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiessling LS, Marcotte AC, Culpepper L (1994) Antineuronal antibodies: tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms. J Dev Behav Pediatr 15(6):421–425</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7884013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004703-199412000-00005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim MJ, Shrestha SS, Cortes M, Singh P, Morse C, Liow JS, Gladding RL, Brouwer C, Henry K, Gallagher E, Tye GL, Zoghbi SS, Fujita M, Pike VW, Innis RB (2018) Evaluation of two potent and selective PET radioligands to image COX-1 and COX-2 in rhesus monkeys. J Nucl Med 59(12):1907–1912</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29959215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6278897</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.118.211144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirvan CA, Swedo SE, Heuser JS, Cunningham MW (2003a) Mimicry and autoantibody-mediated neuronal cell signaling in Sydenham chorea. Nat Med 9(7):914–920</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12819778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirvan CA, Swedo SE, Heuser JS, Cunningham MW (2003b) Mimicry and autoantibody-mediated neuronal cell signaling in Sydenham chorea. Nat Med 9:914–920</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12819778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirvan CA, Swedo SE, Kurahara D, Cunningham MW (2006) Streptococcal mimicry and antibody-mediated cell signaling in the pathogenesis of Sydenham’s chorea. Autoimmunity 39(1):21–29</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16455579</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08916930500484757</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi K, Imagama S, Ohgomori T, Hirano K, Uchimura K, Sakamoto K, Hirakawa A, Takeuchi H, Suzumura A, Ishiguro N, Kadomatsu K (2013) Minocycline selectively inhibits M1 polarization of microglia. Cell Death Dis 4:e525</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23470532</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3613832</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cddis.2013.54</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi M, Jiang T, Telu S, Zoghbi SS, Gunn RN, Rabiner EA, Owen DR, Guo Q, Pike VW, Innis RB, Fujita M (2018) 11C-DPA-713 has much greater specific binding to translocator protein 18 kDa (TSPO) in human brain than 11C-( R)-PK11195. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 38:393–403</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0271678X17699223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar JSD, Bai B, Zanderigo F, DeLorenzo C, Prabhakaran J, Parsey RV, Mann JJ (2018) In vivo brain imaging, biodistribution, and radiation dosimetry estimation of [(11)C]Celecoxib, a COX-2 PET ligand, in nonhuman primates. Molecules 23(8)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latimer ME, L’Etoile N, Seidlitz J, Swedo SE (2015) Therapeutic plasma apheresis as a treatment for 35 severely ill children and adolescents with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol 25(1):70–75</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25658452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4340509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2014.0080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JL, Naguwa SM, Cheema GS, Gershwin ME (2009) Acute rheumatic fever and its consequences: a persistent threat to developing nations in the 21st century. Autoimmun Rev 9(2):117–123</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2009.04.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">19386288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, Sagar AP, Keri S (2018) Translocator protein (18kDa TSPO) binding, a marker of microglia, is reduced in major depression during cognitive-behavioral therapy. Prog Neuro-Psychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry 83:1–7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pnpbp.2017.12.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li F, Welling MC, Johnson JA, Coughlin C, Mulqueen J, Jakubovski E, Coury S, Landeros-Weisenberger A, Bloch MH (2020) N-acetylcysteine for pediatric obsessive-compulsive disorder: a small pilot study. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol 30(1):32–37</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31800306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7133418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2019.0041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lisboa BCG, Oliveira KC, Tahira AC, Barbosa AR, Feltrin AS, Gouveia G, Lima L, Feio Dos Santos AC, Martins DC Jr, Puga RD, Moretto AC, De Braganca Pereira CA, Lafer B, Leite REP, Ferretti-Rebustini REL, Farfel JM, Grinberg LT, Jacob-Filho W, Miguel EC, Hoexter MQ, Brentani H (2019) Initial findings of striatum tripartite model in OCD brain samples based on transcriptome analysis. Sci Rep 9(1):3086</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30816141</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6395771</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-38965-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marrie RA, Fisk JD, Tremlett H, Wolfson C, Warren S, Tennakoon A, Leung S, Patten SB, CIHR Team in the Epidemiology and Impact of Comorbidity on Multiple Sclerosis (2015) Differences in the burden of psychiatric comorbidity in MS vs the general population. Neurology 85:1972–1979</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26519542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4664123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin A, Boisgard R, Thézé B, van Camp N, Kuhnast B, Damont A, Kassiou M, Dolié F, Tavitian B (2010) Evaluation of the PBR/TSPO radioligand [(18)F]DPA-714 in a rat model of focal cerebral ischemia. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 30:230–241</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19794397</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jcbfm.2009.205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin A, Boisgard R, Kassiou M, Dolle F, Tavitian B (2011) Reduced PBR/TSPO expression after minocycline treatment in a rat model of focal cerebral ischemia: a PET study using [(18)F]DPA-714. Mol Imaging Biol 13(1):10–15</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20383592</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11307-010-0324-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto R, Ichise M, Ito H, Ando T, Takahashi H, Ikoma Y, Kosaka J, Arakawa R, Fujimura Y, Ota M, Takano A, Fukui K, Nakayama K, Suhara T (2010) Reduced serotonin transporter binding in the insular cortex in patients with obsessive-compulsive disorder: a [11C]DASB PET study. NeuroImage 49(1):121–126</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19660554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2009.07.069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyer J (2017) Novel phenotypes detectable with PET in mood disorders: elevated monoamine oxidase A and Translocator protein level. In: Vasdev N, Alavi A (eds) PET clinics: novel PET radiotracers with potential clinical applications, vol 12. Elsevier, pp 361–371</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyer JH, Cervenka S, Kim M-J, Kreisl WC, Henter ID, Innis RB (2020) Neuroinflammation in psychiatric disorders: PET imaging and promising new targets. Lancet Psychiatry 7(12):1064–1074</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33098761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7893630</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30255-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minghetti L, Polazzi E, Nicolini A, Creminon C, Levi G (1997) Up-regulation of cyclooxygenase-2 expression in cultured microglia by prostaglandin E2, cyclic AMP and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs. Eur J Neurosci 9(5):934–940</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9182946</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1460-9568.1997.tb01444.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narayanaswami V, Dahl K, Bernard-Gauthier V, Josephson L, Cumming P, Vasdev N (2018) Emerging PET radiotracers and targets for imaging of Neuroinflammation in neurodegenerative diseases: outlook beyond TSPO. Mol Imaging 17:1536012118792317</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30203712</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6134492</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1536012118792317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson TR, Ferdinando S, Krishnaiah RB, Anhoury S, Lennox BR, Mataix-Cols D, Cleare A, Veale DM, Drummond LM, Fineberg NA, Church AJ, Giovannoni G, Heyman I (2012) Prevalence of anti-basal ganglia antibodies in adult obsessive-compulsive disorder: cross-sectional study. Br J Psychiatry 200(5):381–386</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22282431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.111.092007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolini H, Lopez Y, Genis-Mendoza AD, Manrique V, Lopez-Canovas L, Niubo E, Hernandez L, Bobes MA, Riveron AM, Lopez-Casamichana M, Flores J, Lanzagorta N, De la Fuente-Sandoval C, Santana D (2015) Detection of anti-streptococcal, antienolase, and anti-neural antibodies in subjects with early-onset psychiatric disorders. Actas Esp Psiquiatr 43(2):35–41</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25812540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owen DR, Narayan N, Wells L, Healy L, Smyth E, Rabiner EA, Galloway D, Williams JB, Lehr J, Mandhair H, Peferoen LA, Taylor PC, Amor S, Antel JP, Matthews PM, Moore CS (2017) Pro-inflammatory activation of primary microglia and macrophages increases 18 kDa translocator protein expression in rodents but not humans. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab 37(8):2679–2690</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28530125</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5536262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0271678X17710182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paydary K, Akamaloo A, Ahmadipour A, Pishgar F, Emamzadehfard S, Akhondzadeh S (2016) N-acetylcysteine augmentation therapy for moderate-to-severe obsessive-compulsive disorder: randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Pharm Ther 41(2):214–219</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26931055</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpt.12370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittenger C, Bloch MH, Williams K (2011) Glutamate abnormalities in obsessive compulsive disorder: neurobiology, pathophysiology, and treatment. Pharmacol Ther 132(3):314–332</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21963369</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3205262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2011.09.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittenger C, Adams TG Jr, Gallezot JD, Crowley MJ, Nabulsi N, James R, Gao H, Kichuk SA, Simpson R, Billingslea E, Hannestad J, Bloch M, Mayes L, Bhagwagar Z, Carson RE (2016) OCD is associated with an altered association between sensorimotor gating and cortical and subcortical 5-HT1b receptor binding. J Affect Disord 196:87–96</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26919057</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4808438</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2016.02.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plane JM, Shen Y, Pleasure DE, Deng W (2010) Prospects for minocycline neuroprotection. Arch Neurol 67(12):1442–1448</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20697034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3127230</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2010.191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pulli B, Chen JW (2014) Imaging Neuroinflammation - from bench to bedside. J Clin Cell Immunol 5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajkowska G, Stockmeier CA (2013) Astrocyte pathology in major depressive disorder: insights from human postmortem brain tissue. Curr Drug Targets 14(11):1225–1236</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23469922</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3799810</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/13894501113149990156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richards EM, Zanotti-Fregonara P, Fujita M, Newman L, Farmer C, Ballard ED, Machado-Vieira R, Yuan P, Niciu MJ, Lyoo CH, Henter ID, Salvadore G, Drevets WC, Kolb H, Innis RB, Zarate CA Jr (2018) PET radioligand binding to translocator protein (TSPO) is increased in unmedicated depressed subjects. EJNMMI Res 8(1):57</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29971587</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6029989</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13550-018-0401-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuni Y, Goldstein S, Dean OM, Berk M (2013) The chemistry and biological activities of N-acetylcysteine. Biochim Biophys Acta 1830(8):4117–4129</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23618697</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbagen.2013.04.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandiego CM, Gallezot JD, Pittman B, Nabulsi N, Lim K, Lin SF, Matuskey D, Lee JY, O’Connor KC, Huang Y, Carson RE, Hannestad J, Cosgrove KP (2015) Imaging robust microglial activation after lipopolysaccharide administration in humans with PET. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 112:12468–12473</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26385967</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4603509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.1511003112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarris J, Oliver G, Camfield DA, Dean OM, Dowling N, Smith DJ, Murphy J, Menon R, Berk M, Blair-West S, Ng CH (2015) N-acetyl cysteine (NAC) in the treatment of obsessive-compulsive disorder: a 16-week, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled study. CNS Drugs 29(9):801–809</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26374743</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-015-0272-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saxena S, Brody AL, Schwartz JM, Baxter LR (1998) Neuroimaging and frontal-subcortical circuitry in obsessive-compulsive disorder. Br J Psychiatry Suppl 35:26–37</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/S0007125000297870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sayyah M, Boostani H, Pakseresht S, Malayeri A (2011) A preliminary randomized double-blind clinical trial on the efficacy of celecoxib as an adjunct in the treatment of obsessive-compulsive disorder. Psychiatry Res 189(3):403–406</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21329988</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2011.01.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">21329988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schou M, Varnas K, Lundquist S, Nakao R, Amini N, Takano A, Finnema SJ, Halldin C, Farde L (2015) Large variation in brain exposure of reference CNS drugs: a PET study in nonhuman primates. Int J Neuropsychopharmacol 18(10):pyv036</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25813017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4648157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ijnp/pyv036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott G, Zetterberg H, Jolly A, Cole JH, De Simoni S, Jenkins PO, Feeney C, Owen DR, Lingford-Hughes A, Howes O, Patel MC, Goldstone AP, Gunn RN, Blennow K, Matthews PM, Sharp DJ (2018) Minocycline reduces chronic microglial activation after brain trauma but increases neurodegeneration. Brain 141(2):459–471</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29272357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awx339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">29272357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seabrook TJ, Jiang L, Maier M, Lemere CA (2006) Minocycline affects microglia activation, Abeta deposition, and behavior in APP-tg mice. Glia 53(7):776–782</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16534778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.20338</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">16534778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setiawan E, Wilson AA, Mizrahi R, Rusjan PM, Miler L, Rajkowska G, Suridjan I, Kennedy JL, Rekkas PV, Houle S, Meyer JH (2015) Role of translocator protein density, a marker of neuroinflammation, in the brain during major depressive episodes. JAMA Psychiat 72(3):268–275</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2014.2427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setiawan E, Attwells S, Wilson AA, Mizrahi R, Rusjan PM, Miler L, Xu C, Sharma S, Kish S, Houle S, Meyer JH (2018) Association of translocator protein total distribution volume with duration of untreated major depressive disorder: a cross-sectional study. Lancet Psychiatry 5(4):339–347</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29496589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(18)30048-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">29496589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shalbafan M, Mohammadinejad P, Shariat SV, Alavi K, Zeinoddini A, Salehi M, Askari N, Akhondzadeh S (2015) Celecoxib as an adjuvant to fluvoxamine in moderate to severe obsessive-compulsive disorder: a double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized trial. Pharmacopsychiatry 48(4–5):136–140</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25959196</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">25959196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Loiselle CR, Lee O, Minzer K, Swedo S, Grus FH (2004) Anti-basal ganglia antibodies in PANDAS. Mov Disord 19(4):406–415</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15077238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.20052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">15077238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA, Lougee L, Slattery M, Grant P, Swedo SE (2005) Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biol Psychiatry 57(7):788–792</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820236</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">15820236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE (1994) Sydenham’s chorea. A model for childhood autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders. JAMA 272(22):1788–1791</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7661914</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.1994.03520220082035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7661914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Garvey M, Mittleman B, Allen AJ, Perlmutter S, Lougee L, Dow S, Zamkoff J, Dubbert BK (1998) Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry 155(2):264–271</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leckman JF, Rose NR (2012a) From research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome). Pediatr Ther 2(2):113</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-0665.1000113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo S, Leckman JF, Rose N (2012b) From research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome). Pediatr Therapeut 2:1–8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-0665.1000113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leckman JF, Rose NR (2012c) From research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome). Pediatr Therapeut 2:1–8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-0665.1000113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tachikawa M, Hosoya K, Terasaki T (2014) Pharmacological significance of prostaglandin E2 and D2 transport at the brain barriers. Adv Pharmacol 71:337–360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25307222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.apha.2014.06.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">25307222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Weehaeghe D, Van Schoor E, De Voch J, Koole M, Attili B, Celen S, Declercq L, Thal DR, Van Damme P, Bormans G, Van Laere K (2020) TSPO versus P2X7 as a target for neuroinflammation – an in vitro and in vivo study. J Nucl Med 61(4):604–607</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31562223</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7198372</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2967/jnumed.119.231985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venneti S, Wang G, Nguyen J, Wiley CA (2008) The positron emission tomography ligand DAA1106 binds with high affinity to activated microglia in human neurological disorders. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol 67:1001–1010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18800007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NEN.0b013e318188b204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">18800007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker KG, Wilmshurst JM (2010) An update on the treatment of Sydenham’s chorea: the evidence for established and evolving interventions. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 3(5):301–309</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21179620</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3002660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756285610382063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang AK, Miller BJ (2018) Meta-analysis of cerebrospinal fluid cytokine and tryptophan Catabolite alterations in psychiatric patients: comparisons between schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, and depression. Schizophr Bull 44(1):75–83</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28338954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sbx035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">28338954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson AA, Garcia A, Parkes J, McCormick P, Stephenson KA, Houle S, Vasdev N (2008) Radiosynthesis and initial evaluation of [18F]-FEPPA for PET imaging of peripheral benzodiazepine receptors. Nucl Med Biol 35(3):305–314</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18355686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nucmedbio.2007.12.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf BJ, Brackhan M, Bascunana P, Leiter I, Langer BLN, Ross TL, Bankstahl JP, Bankstahl M (2020) TSPO PET identifies different anti-inflammatory minocycline treatment response in two rodent models of epileptogenesis. Neurotherapeutics 17(3):1228–1238</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31970667</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7609777</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-020-00834-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong DF, Brasic JR, Singer HS, Schretlen DJ, Kuwabara H, Zhou Y, Nandi A, Maris MA, Alexander M, Ye W, Rousset O, Kumar A, Szabo Z, Gjedde A, Grace AA (2008) Mechanisms of dopaminergic and serotonergic neurotransmission in Tourette syndrome: clues from an in vivo neurochemistry study with PET. Neuropsychopharmacology 33(6):1239–1251</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17987065</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.npp.1301528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
