<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33649113</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-6596</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>65</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Antimicrobial agents and chemotherapy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Human Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Molnupiravir, a Novel Broad-Spectrum Oral Antiviral Agent with Activity Against SARS-CoV-2.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e02428-20</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/AAC.02428-20</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">AAC.02428-20</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Molnupiravir, EIDD-2801/MK-4482, the prodrug of the active antiviral ribonucleoside analog ß-d-N4-hydroxycytidine (NHC; EIDD-1931), has activity against a number of RNA viruses including severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2, severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus, Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus, and seasonal and pandemic influenza viruses.Single and multiple doses of molnupiravir were evaluated in this first-in-human, phase 1, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study in healthy volunteers, which included evaluation of the effect of food on pharmacokinetics.EIDD-1931 appeared rapidly in plasma, with a median time of maximum observed concentration of 1.00 to 1.75 hours, and declined with a geometric half-life of approximately 1 hour, with a slower elimination phase apparent following multiple doses or higher single doses (7.1 hours at the highest dose tested). Mean maximum observed concentration and area under the concentration versus time curve increased in a dose-proportional manner, and there was no accumulation following multiple doses. When administered in a fed state, there was a decrease in the rate of absorption, but no decrease in overall exposure.Molnupiravir was well tolerated. Fewer than half of subjects reported an adverse event, the incidence of adverse events was higher following administration of placebo, and 93.3% of adverse events were mild. One discontinued early due to rash. There were no serious adverse events and there were no clinically significant findings in clinical laboratory, vital signs, or electrocardiography. Plasma exposures exceeded expected efficacious doses based on scaling from animal models; therefore, dose escalations were discontinued before a maximum tolerated dose was reached.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Painter et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Painter</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wendy P</ForeName>
            <Initials>WP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6710-1277</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ridgeback Biotherapeutics LP, 3480 Main Highway, Unit 402, Miami, Florida 33133, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Holman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wayne</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ridgeback Biotherapeutics LP, 3480 Main Highway, Unit 402, Miami, Florida 33133, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bush</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jim A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Covance Clinical Research Unit Limited, Springfield House, Hyde Street, Leeds LS2 9LH, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Almazedi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Firas</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Covance Clinical Research Unit Limited, Springfield House, Hyde Street, Leeds LS2 9LH, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Malik</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hamzah</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Covance Clinical Research Unit Limited, Springfield House, Hyde Street, Leeds LS2 9LH, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eraut</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicola C J E</ForeName>
            <Initials>NCJE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Covance Clinical Research Unit Limited, Springfield House, Hyde Street, Leeds LS2 9LH, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Merribeth J</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ridgeback Biotherapeutics LP, 3480 Main Highway, Unit 402, Miami, Florida 33133, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Szewczyk</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laura J</ForeName>
            <Initials>LJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ridgeback Biotherapeutics LP, 3480 Main Highway, Unit 402, Miami, Florida 33133, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Painter</LastName>
            <ForeName>George R</ForeName>
            <Initials>GR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Chemical Biology, Emory University School of Medicine, 954 Gatewood Road NE, Atlanta, Georgia 30329, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Antimicrob Agents Chemother</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0315061</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0066-4804</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33649113</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092915</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.02428-20</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">AAC.02428-20</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. 2020. Novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) situation report 1. World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheahan TP, Sims AC, Zhou S, Graham RL, Pruijssers AJ, Agostini ML, Leist SR, Schäfer A, Dinnon KH, Stevens LJ, Chappell JD, Lu X, Hughes TM, George AS, Hill CS, Montgomery SA, Brown AJ, Bluemling GR, Natchus MG, Saindane M, Kolykhalov AA, Painter G, Harcourt J, Tamin A, Thornburg NJ, Swanstrom R, Denison MR, Baric RS. 2020. An orally bioavailable broad-spectrum antiviral inhibits SARS-CoV-2 and multiple endemic, epidemic and bat coronavirus. Sci Transl Med
12:eabb5883. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.abb5883.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.abb5883</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32253226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toots M, Yoon J-J, Cox RM, Hart M, Sticher ZM, Makhsous N, Plesker R, Barrena AH, Reddy PG, Mitchell DG, Shean RC, Bluemling GR, Kolykhalov AA, Greninger AL, Natchus MG, Painter GR, Plemper RK. 2019. Characterization of orally efficacious influenza drug with high resistance barrier in ferrets and human airway epithelia. Sci Transl Med
11:eaax5866. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.aax5866.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aax5866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6848974</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31645453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Painter GR, Bowen RA, Bluemling GR, DeBergh J, Edpuganti V, Gruddanti PR, Guthrie DB, Hager M, Kuiper DL, Lockwood MA, Mitchell DG, Natchus MG, Sticher ZM, Kolykhalov AA. 2019. The prophylactic and therapeutic activity of a broadly active ribonucleoside analog in a murine model of intranasal Venezuelan equine encephalitis virus infection. Antiviral Res
171:104597. doi:10.1016/j.antiviral.2019.104597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.antiviral.2019.104597</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31494195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agostini ML, Pruijssers AJ, Chappell JD, Gribble J, Lu X, Andres EL, Bluemling GR, Lockwood MA, Sheahan TP, Sims AC, Natchus MG, Saindane M, Kolykhalov AA, Painter GR, Baric RS, Denison MR. 2019. Small-molecule antiviral β-d-N4-hydroxycytidine inhibits a proofreading-intact coronavirus with a high genetic barrier to resistance. J Virol
93:e01348-19. doi:10.1128/JVI.01348-19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.01348-19</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6880162</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31578288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, Division of AIDS. 2017. Division of AIDS (DAIDS) table for grading the severity of adult and pediatric adverse events. National Institutes of Health, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Bethesda, MD.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez-Santiago BI, Beltran T, Stuyver L, Chu CK, Schinazi RF. 2004. Metabolism of the anti-hepatitis C virus nucleoside beta-d-N4-hydroxycytidine in different liver cells. Antimicrob Agents Chemother
48:4636–4642. doi:10.1128/AAC.48.12.4636-4642.2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.48.12.4636-4642.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC529212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15561837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox RM, Wolf JD, Plemper RK. 2021. Therapeutically administered ribonucleoside analogue MK-4482/EIDD-2801 blocks SARS-CoV-2 transmission in ferrets. Nat Microbiol
6:11–18. doi:10.1038/s41564-020-00835-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41564-020-00835-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755744</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darnowski JW, Handschumacher RE. 1986. Tissue uridine pools: evidence in vivo of a concentrative mechanism for uridine uptake. Cancer Res
46:3490–3494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3708581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng Y, Wang ZV, Gordillo R, An Y, Zhang C, Liang Q, Yoshino J, Cautivo KM, De Brabander J, Elmquist JK, Horton JD, Hill JA, Klein S, Scherer PE. 2017. An adipo-biliary-uridine axis that regulates energy homeostasis. Science
355:eaaf5375. doi:10.1126/science.aaf5375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aaf5375</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5832364</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28302796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karle JM, Anderson LW, Dietrick DD, Cysyk RL. 1980. Determination of serum and plasma uridine levels in mice, rats, and humans by high-pressure liquid chromatography. Anal Biochem
109:41–46. doi:10.1016/0003-2697(80)90007-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0003-2697(80)90007-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7469017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
