<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33661557</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2691-1299</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>1</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current protocols</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Protoc</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Transformation of Borrelia burgdorferi.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e61</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e61</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cpz1.61</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Transformation techniques used to genetically manipulate Borrelia burgdorferi, the agent of Lyme disease, play a critical role in generating mutants that facilitate analyses of the role of genes in the pathophysiology of this bacterium. A number of borrelial mutants have been successfully isolated and characterized since the first electrotransformation procedure was established 25 years ago (Samuels, 1995). This article is directed at additional considerations for transforming infectious B. burgdorferi to generate strains retaining the plasmid profile of the parental strain, enabling analysis of transformants for in vitro and in vivo phenotypes. These methods are built on previously published protocols and are intended to add steps and tips to enhance transformation efficiency and recovery of strains amenable for studies involving colonization, survival, and transmission of B. burgdorferi during the vector and vertebrate phases of infection. © 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC. Basic Protocol 1: Preparation of stock cultures, propagation of spirochetes, and analysis of plasmid profiles Basic Protocol 2: Preparation of plasmid and linear DNA templates for transformation Basic Protocol 3: Transformation of B. burgdorferi Basic Protocol 4: Antibiotic selection of borrelial transformants Basic Protocol 5: Isolation of borrelial transformants in agar overlays Basic Protocol 6: Complementation of mutant borrelial strains in cis or in trans.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Seshu</LastName>
            <ForeName>J</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biology, South Texas Center for Emerging Infectious Diseases, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brian E</ForeName>
            <Initials>BE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biology, South Texas Center for Emerging Infectious Diseases, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ingle</LastName>
            <ForeName>Taylor MacMackin</ForeName>
            <Initials>TM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biology, South Texas Center for Emerging Infectious Diseases, University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R21 AI123837</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Protoc</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101773894</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2691-1299</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D025065" MajorTopicYN="Y">Borrelia burgdorferi</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008193" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lyme Disease</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010957" MajorTopicYN="N">Plasmids</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Borrelia burgdorferi</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lyme disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">circular plasmids</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genetic manipulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">isolation of mutants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">linear plasmids</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transformation methods</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virulence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whole-genome sequencing</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>17</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33661557</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpz1.61</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>Literature Cited</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, W. K., Savage, C. R., Brissette, C. A., Seshu, J., Livny, J., &amp; Stevenson, B. (2016). RNASeq of Borrelia burgdorferi in multiple phases of growth reveals insights into the dynamics of gene expression, transcriptome architecture, and noncoding RNAs. PLoS One, 11(10), e0164165. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0164165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, W. K., Savage, C. R., Lethbridge, K. G., Smith, T. C., 2nd, Brissette, C. A., Seshu, J., &amp; Stevenson, B. (2018). Transcriptomic insights on the virulence-controlling CsrA, BadR, RpoN, and RpoS regulatory networks in the Lyme disease spirochete. PLoS One, 13(8), e0203286. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0203286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blevins, J. S., Revel, A. T., Smith, A. H, Bachlani, G. N., &amp; Norgard, M. V. (2007). Adaptation of a luciferase gene reporter and lac expression system to Borrelia burgdorferi. Applied Environmental Microbiology, 73(5), 1501-1513. doi: 10.1128/AEM.02454-06.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bono, J. L., Elias, A. F., Kupko, J. J., 3rd, Stevenson, B., Tilly, K., &amp; Rosa, P. (2000). Efficient targeted mutagenesis in Borrelia burgdorferi. Journal of Bacteriology, 182(9), 2445-2452. doi: 10.1128/JB.182.9.2445-2452.2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botkin, D. J., Abbott, A. N., Stewart, P. E., Rosa, P. A., Kawabata, H., Watanabe, H., &amp; Norris, S. J. (2006). Identification of potential virulence determinants by Himar1 transposition of infectious Borrelia burgdorferi B31. Infection and Immunity, 74(12), 6690-6699. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00993-06.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bunikis, I., Kutschan-Bunikis, S., Bonde, M., &amp; Bergström, S. (2011). Multiplex PCR as a tool for validating plasmid content of Borrelia burgdorferi. Journal of Microbiological Methods, 86(2), 243-247. Epub 2011 May 12. PMID: 21605603. doi: 10.1016/j.mimet.2011.05.004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drecktrah, D., &amp; Samuels, D. S. (2018). Genetic manipulation of Borrelia spp. Current Topics in Microbiology and Immunology, 415, 113-140. doi: 10.1007/82_2017_51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eggers, C. H., Caimano, M. J., Clawson, M. L., Miller, W. G., Samuels, D. S., &amp; Radolf, J. D., (2002). Identification of loci critical for replication and compatibility of a Borrelia burgdorferi cp32 plasmid and use of a cp32-based shuttle vector for the expression of fluorescent reporters in the Lyme disease spirochaete. Molecular Microbiology, 43(2), 281-295. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2958.2002.02758.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elias, A. F., Bono, J. L., Kupko, J. J., 3rd, Stewart, P. E., Krum, J. G., &amp; Rosa, P. A. (2003). New antibiotic resistance cassettes suitable for genetic studies in Borrelia burgdorferi. Journal of Molecular Microbiology and Biotechnology, 6(1), 29-40. doi: 10.1159/000073406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elias, A. F., Stewart, P. E., Grimm, D., Caimano, M. J., Eggers, C. H., Tilly, K., … Rosa, P. (2002). Clonal polymorphism of Borrelia burgdorferi strain B31 MI: Implications for mutagenesis in an infectious strain background. Infection and Immunity, 70(4), 2139-2150. doi: 10.1128/IAI.70.4.2139-2150.2002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Elliott, N. L., &amp; Seshu, J. (2009). sodA is essential for virulence of Borrelia burgdorferi in the murine model of Lyme disease. Molecular Microbiology, 71(3), 594-612. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2958.2008.06549.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frank, K. L., Bundle, S. F., Kresge, M. E., Eggers, C. H., &amp; Samuels, D. S. (2003). aadA confers streptomycin resistance in Borrelia burgdorferi. Journal of Bacteriology, 185(22), 6723-6727. doi: 10.1128/JB.185.22.6723-6727.2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraser, C. M., Casjens, S., Huang, W. M., Sutton, G. G., Clayton, R., Lathigra, R., … Venter, J. C. (1997). Genomic sequence of a Lyme disease spirochaete, Borrelia burgdorferi. Nature, 390(6660), 580-586. doi: 10.1038/37551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Groshong, A. M., &amp; Blevins, J. S. (2014). Insights into the biology of Borrelia burgdorferi gained through the application of molecular genetics. Advances in Applied Microbiology, 86, 41-143. doi: 10.1016/B978-0-12-800262-9.00002-0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyde, J. A., Weening, E. H., &amp; Skare, J. T. (2011). Genetic transformation of Borrelia burgdorferi. Current Protocols in Microbiology, 20, 12C.4.1-12C.4.17. doi: 10.1002/9780471729259.mc12c04s20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jutras, B. L., Chenail, A. M., Carroll, D. W., Miller, M. C., Zhu, H., Bowman, A., &amp; Stevenson, B. (2013). Bpur, the Lyme disease spirochete's PUR domain protein: Identification as a transcriptional modulator and characterization of nucleic acid interactions. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 288(36), 26220-26234. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M113.491357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jutras, B. L., Savage, C. R., Arnold, W. K., Lethbridge, K. G., Carroll, D. W., Tilly, K., … Stevenson, B. (2019). The Lyme disease spirochete's BpuR DNA/RNA-binding protein is differentially expressed during the mammal-tick infectious cycle, which affects translation of the SodA superoxide dismutase. Molecular Microbiology, 112(3), 973-991. doi: 10.1111/mmi.14336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jutras, B. L., Verma, A., Adams, C. A., Brissette, C. A., Burns, L. H., Whetstine, C. R., … Stevenson, B. (2012). BpaB and EbfC DNA-binding proteins regulate production of the Lyme disease spirochete's infection-associated Erp surface proteins. Journal of Bacteriology, 194(4), 778-786. doi: 10.1128/JB.06394-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karna, S. L., Prabhu, R. G., Lin, Y. H., Miller, C. L., &amp; Seshu, J. (2013). Contributions of environmental signals and conserved residues to the functions of carbon storage regulator A of Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 81(8), 2972-2985. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00494-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karna, S. L., Sanjuan, E., Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Miller, C. L., Maruskova, M., &amp; Seshu, J. (2011). CsrA modulates levels of lipoproteins and key regulators of gene expression critical for pathogenic mechanisms of Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 79(2), 732-744. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00882-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawabata, H., Norris, S. J., &amp; Watanabe, H. (2004). BBE02 disruption mutants of Borrelia burgdorferi B31 have a highly transformable, infectious phenotype. Infection and Immunity, 72(12), 71477154. doi: 10.1128/IAI.72.12.7147-7154.2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labandeira-Rey, M., Seshu, J., &amp; Skare, J. T. (2003). The absence of linear plasmid 25 or 28-1 of Borrelia burgdorferi dramatically alters the kinetics of experimental infection via distinct mechanisms. Infection and Immunity, 71(8), 4608-4613. doi: 10.1128/IAI.71.8.4608-4613.2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labandeira-Rey, M., &amp; Skare, J. T. (2001). Decreased infectivity in Borrelia burgdorferi strain B31 is associated with loss of linear plasmid 25 or 28-1. Infection and Immunity, 69(1), 446-455. doi: 10.1128/IAI.69.1.446-455.2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latham, J. I., &amp; Blevins, J. S. (2018). Generation of conditional mutants in Borrelia burgdorferi. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1690, 225-239. doi: 10.1007/978-1-4939-7383-5_17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawrenz, M. B., Kawabata, H., Purser, J. E., &amp; Norris, S. J. (2002). Decreased electroporation efficiency in Borrelia burgdorferi containing linear plasmids lp25 and lp56: Impact on transformation of infectious B. burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 70(9), 4798-4804. doi: 10.1128/IAI.70.9.4798-4804.2002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, T., Troy, E. B., Hu, L. T., Gao, L., &amp; Norris, S. J. (2014). Transposon mutagenesis as an approach to improved understanding of Borrelia pathogenesis and biology. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 4, 63. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2014.00063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, Y. H., Romo, J. A., Smith, T. C., 2nd, A. N. Reyes, Karna, S. L. R., Miller, C. L., … Seshu, J. (2017). Spermine and spermidine alter gene expression and antigenic profile of Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 85(3), 300684-16. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00684-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez, L. L., Rusconi, B., Gildersleeve, H., Qi, C., McLaughlin, M., Scheetz, M. H., … Eppinger, M. (2016). Genome sequences of five clinical isolates of Klebsiella pneumoniae. Genome Announcements, 4(2), e00040-16. doi: 10.1128/genomeA.00040-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lybecker, M. C., &amp; Samuels, D. S. (2017). Small RNAs of Borrelia burgdorferi: Characterizing functional regulators in a sea of sRNAs. Yale Journal of Biology and Medicine, 90(2), 317-323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maruskova, M., Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Sexton, V. L., &amp; Seshu, J. (2008). Role of the BBA64 locus of Borrelia burgdorferi in early stages of infectivity in a murine model of Lyme disease. Infection and Immunity, 76(1), 391-402. doi: 10.1128/IAI.01118-07.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maruskova, M., &amp; Seshu, J. (2008). Deletion of BBA64, BBA65, and BBA66 loci does not alter the infectivity of Borrelia burgdorferi in the murine model of Lyme disease. Infection and Immunity, 76(11), 5274-5284. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00803-08.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason, C., Liu, X., Prabhudeva, S., &amp; Ouyang, Z. (2019). The CXXC motifs are essential for the function of BosR in Borrelia burgdorferi. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 9, 109. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2019.00109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medina-Perez, D. N., Wager, B., Troy, E., Gao, L., Norris, S. J., Lin, T., … Skare, J. T. (2020). The intergenic small non-coding RNA ittA is required for optimal infectivity and tissue tropism in Borrelia burgdorferi. PLoS Pathogens, 16(5), e1008423. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1008423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller, C. L., Karna, S. L., &amp; Seshu, J. (2013). Borrelia host adaptation regulator (BadR) regulates rpoS to modulate host adaptation and virulence factors in Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 88(1), 105-124. doi: 10.1111/mmi.12171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moriarty, T. J., Norman, M. U., Colarusso, P., Bankhead, T., Kubes, P., &amp; Chaconas, G. (2008). Real-time high resolution 3D imaging of the Lyme disease spirochete adhering to and escaping from the vasculature of a living host. PLoS Pathogens, 4(6), e1000090. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1000090.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phelan, J. P., Kern, A., Ramsey, M. E., Lundt, M. E., Sharma, B., Lin, T., … Hu, L. T. (2019). Genome-wide screen identifies novel genes required for Borrelia burgdorferi survival in its Ixodes tick vector. PLoS Pathogens, 15(5), e1007644. doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1007644.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Purser, J. E., &amp; Norris, S. J. (2000). Correlation between plasmid content and infectivity in Borrelia burgdorferi. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 97(25), 13865-13870. doi: 10.1073/pnas.97.25.13865.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radolf, J. D., Caimano, M. J., Stevenson, B., &amp; Hu, L. T. (2012). Of ticks, mice and men: Understanding the dual-host lifestyle of Lyme disease spirochaetes. Nature Reviews Microbiology, 10(2), 8799. doi: 10.1038/nrmicro2714.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raju, B. V., Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Karna, S. L., Miller, C. L., Van Laar, T. A., &amp; Seshu, J. (2011). Oligopeptide permease A5 modulates vertebrate host-specific adaptation of Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 79(8), 3407-3420. doi: 10.1128/IAI.05234-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosa, P. A., Tilly, K., &amp; Stewart, P. E. (2005). The burgeoning molecular genetics of the Lyme disease spirochaete. Nature Reviews Microbiology, 3(2), 129-143. doi: 10.1038/nrmicro1086.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuels, D. S. (1995). Electrotransformation of the spirochete Borrelia burgdorferi. Methods in Molecular Biology, 47, 253-259. doi: 10.1385/0-89603-310-4:253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuels, D. S. (2011). Gene regulation in Borrelia burgdorferi. Annual Review of Microbiology, 65, 479499. doi: 10.1146/annurev.micro.112408.134040.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuels, D. S., Drecktrah, D., &amp; Hall, L. S. (2018). Genetic transformation and complementation. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1690, 183-200. doi: 10.1007/978-1-4939-7383-5_15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanjuan, E., Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Maruskova, M., &amp; Seshu, J. (2009). Overexpression of CsrA (BB0184) alters the morphology and antigen profiles of Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 77(11), 5149-5162. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00673-09.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savage, C. R., Jutras, B. L., Bestor, A., Tilly, K., Rosa, P. A., Tourand, Y., … Stevenson, B. (2018). Borrelia burgdorferi SpoVG DNA- and RNA-binding protein modulates the physiology of the Lyme disease spirochete. Journal of Bacteriology, 200(12), e00033-18. doi: 10.1128/JB.00033-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seshu, J., Boylan, J. A., Hyde, J. A., Swingle, K. L., Gherardini, F. C., &amp; Skare, J. T. (2004). A conservative amino acid change alters the function of BosR, the redox regulator of Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 54(5), 1352-1363. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2958.2004.04352.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seshu, J., Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Labandeira-Rey, M., Kim, J. H., Trzeciakowski, J. P., Hook, M., &amp; Skare, J. T. (2006). Inactivation of the fibronectin-binding adhesin gene bbk32 significantly attenuates the infectivity potential of Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 59(5), 1591-1601. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2958.2005.05042.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seshu, J., Smith, T. C. 2nd, Lin, Y. H., Karna, S. L. R., Miller, C. L., &amp; Van Laar, T. (2018). Analysis of DNA and RNA binding properties of Borrelia burgdorferi regulatory proteins. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1690, 155-175. doi: 10.1007/978-1-4939-7383-5_13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, T. C. 2nd, Helm, S. M., Chen, Y., Lin, Y. H., Rajasekhar Karna, S. L., &amp; Seshu, J. (2018). Borrelia host adaptation protein (BadP) is required for the colonization of a mammalian host by the agent of Lyme disease. Infection and Immunity, 86(7), e00057-18. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00057-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanek, G., Wormser, G. P., Gray, J., &amp; Strle, F. (2012). Lyme borreliosis. Lancet, 379(9814), 461-473. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60103-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steere, A. C., Strle, F., Wormser, G. P., Hu, L. T., Branda, J. A., Hovius, J. W., … Mead, P. S. (2016). Lyme borreliosis. Nature Reviews Disease Primers, 2, 16090. doi: 10.1038/nrdp.2016.90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevenson, B., Schwan, T. G., &amp; Rosa, P. A. (1995). Temperature-related differential expression of antigens in the Lyme disease spirochete, Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 63(11), 45354539. doi: 10.1128/IAI.63.11.4535-4539.1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevenson, B., &amp; Seshu, J. (2018). Regulation of gene and protein expression in the Lyme disease spirochete. Current Topics in Microbiology and Immunology, 415, 83-112. doi: 10.1007/82_2017_49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart, P. E., Thalken, R., Bono, J. L., &amp; Rosa, P. (2001). Isolation of a circular plasmid region sufficient for autonomous replication and transformation of infectious Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 39(3), 714-721. doi: 10.1046/j.1365-2958.2001.02256.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sultan, S. Z., Pitzer, J. E., Miller, M. R., &amp; Motaleb, M. A. (2010). Analysis of a Borrelia burgdorferi phosphodiesterase demonstrates a role for cyclic-di-guanosine monophosphate in motility and virulence. Molecular Microbiology, 77(1), 128-142. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2958.2010.07191.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takacs, C. N., Kloos, Z. A., Scott, M., Rosa, P. A., &amp; Jacobs-Wagner, C. (2018). Fluorescent proteins, promoters, and selectable markers for applications in the Lyme disease spirochete Borrelia burgdorferi. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 84(24), e01824-18. doi: 10.1128/AEM.01824-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Laar, T. A., Lin, Y. H., Miller, C. L., Karna, S. L., Chambers, J. P., &amp; Seshu, J. (2012). Effect of levels of acetate on the mevalonate pathway of Borrelia burgdorferi. PLoS One, 7(5), e38171. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0038171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
