<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33667026</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1865-1682</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>69</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Transboundary and emerging diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Transbound Emerg Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Diversity of rickettsiae in domestic, synanthropic, and sylvatic mammals and their ectoparasites in a spotted fever-epidemic region at the western US-Mexico border.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>609</StartPage>
          <EndPage>622</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>609-622</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tbed.14027</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Over one hundred cases of human rickettsiosis, many fatal, are reported annually across the US-Mexico transboundary region, representing a likely undercount. Although cases are often attributed to Rickettsia rickettsii, the agent of Rocky Mountain spotted fever, multiple other Rickettsia pathogens are present in North America. We conducted multiple-host surveillance of domestic, synanthropic, and sylvatic mammals and their ectoparasites to investigate the ecology of Rickettsia species in this region. A total of 499 mammals, including 83 dogs, 23 wild carnivores, five lagomorphs, and 388 rodents were sampled, and 413 fleas and 447 ticks belonging to 15 and 4 species, respectively, were collected during 2017 and 2018. We detected Rickettsia spp. DNA in one blood sample of coyote (Canis latrans), 11 ear tissues of rodents (10.6%), and 79 ectoparasites (9.5%). Of the 64 Rickettsia-positive fleas, 54 were Echidnophaga gallinacea and 10 were Pulex simulans, while of the 15 ticks, 11 were Rhipicephalus sanguineus s.l. and four Ixodes pacificus. The DNA sequence alignment of gltA and ompB regions revealed one and ten genetic variants of Rickettsia spp., respectively. These variants were clustered in clades of zoonotic species (R. felis, R. massiliae, R. parkeri, R. rickettsii, and R. typhi) and organisms of unknown pathogenic significance (R. asembonensis and Candidatus Rickettsia tarasevichiae). The finding of a coyote infected with R. rickettsii and the multiple zoonotic SFG rickettsial agents in the study area suggest that: 1) wild canids could serve as an amplifying host for RMSF, an alternate host for Rh. sanguineus s.l. ticks, and a means to spread infection and ticks over large areas; and 2) at least some of the human rickettsiosis cases attributed to R. rickettsii could be caused by other Rickettsia species. This study strongly supports the importance of multiple-host and vector eco-epidemiological studies and the One Health approach to better understand disease in a RMSF-epidemic region.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>López-Pérez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrés M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5726-7943</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Epidemiology, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of California, Davis, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Ciudad de México, México.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chaves</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrea</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6237-0678</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Epidemiology, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of California, Davis, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sánchez-Montes</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sokani</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6316-2187</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Facultad de Ciencias Biológicas y Agropecuarias, región Tuxpan, Universidad Veracruzana, Veracruz, México.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>División de Investigación, Facultad de Medicina, Centro de Medicina Tropical, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Ciudad de México, México.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Foley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Patrick</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Sacramento State University, Sacramento, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Uhart</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcela</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Karen C. Drayer Wildlife Health Center, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of California, Davis, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barrón-Rodríguez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julio</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Ciudad de México, México.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Becker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ingeborg</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Facultad de Ciencias Biológicas y Agropecuarias, región Tuxpan, Universidad Veracruzana, Veracruz, México.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suzán</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gerardo</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Facultad de Medicina Veterinaria y Zootecnia, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Ciudad de México, México.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Foley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Janet</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Epidemiology, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of California, Davis, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Transbound Emerg Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101319538</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1865-1674</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002335" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carnivora</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008800" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Mexico</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D048508" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rhipicephalus sanguineus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012281" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rickettsia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000073605" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spotted Fever Group Rickettsiosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Rickettsia
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">One Health</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">US-Mexico border</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diversity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fleas</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mammal hosts</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ticks</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33667026</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14027</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acosta, R., &amp; Morrone, J. J. (2003). Clave ilustrada para la identificacion de los taxones supraespecificos de Siphonaptera de Mexico. Acta Zoologica Mexicana Nueva Serie, 89, 39-53. https://doi.org/10.21829/azm.2003.89891773</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams, J. R., Schmidtmann, E. T., &amp; Azad, A. F. (1990). Infection of colonized cat fleas, Ctenocephalides felis (Bouche), with a Rickettsia-like microorganism. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 43, 400-409. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.1990.43.400</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar-Domínguez, M., Sánchez-Montes, S., Esteve-Gassent, M. D., Barrientos-Salcedo, C., Pérez de León, A., &amp; Romero-Salas, D. (2019). Genetic structure analysis of Amblyomma mixtum populations in Veracruz State, Mexico. Ticks and Tick-borne Diseases, 10, 86-92. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ttbdis.2018.09.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander, S. M., &amp; Quinn, M. S. (2011). Coyote (Canis latrans) interactions with humans and pets reported in the Canadian print media (1995-2010). Human Dimensions of Wildlife, 16, 345-359. https://doi.org/10.1080/10871209.2011.599050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Álvarez-Hernández, G., Roldán, J. F. G., Milan, N. S. H., Lash, R. R., Behravesh, C. B., &amp; Paddock, C. D. (2017). Rocky Mountain spotted fever in Mexico: Past, present, and future. The Lancet Infectious Diseases, 17, e189-e196. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1473-3099(17)30173-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beati, L., &amp; Raoult, D. (1993). Rickettsia massiliae, a new spotted fever group Rickettsia. International Journal of Systematic Bacteriology, 43, 839-840. https://doi.org/10.1099/00207713-43-4-839</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beeler, E., Abramowicz, K. F., Zambrano, M. L., Sturgeon, M. M., Khalaf, N., Hu, R., Dasch, G. A., &amp; Eremeeva, M. E. (2011). A focus of dogs and Rickettsia massiliae-infected Rhipicephalus sanguineus in California. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 84, 244-249. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.2011.10-0355</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermúdez, S. E., Gottdenker, N., Krishnvajhala, A., Fox, A., Wilder, H. K., González, K., Smith, D., López, M., Perea, M., Rigg, C., Montilla, S., Calzada, J. E., Saldaña, A., Caballero, C. M., &amp; Lopez, J. E. (2017). Synanthropic mammals as potential hosts of tick-borne pathogens in Panama. PLoS One, 14, e0226195. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0169047</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggs, H. M., Behravesh, C. B., Bradley, K. K., Dahlgren, F. S., Drexler, N. A., Dumler, J. S., Folk, S. M., Kato, C. Y., Lash, R. R., Levin, M. L., Massung, R. F., Nadelman, R. B., Nicholson, W. L., Paddock, C. D., Pritt, B. S., &amp; Traeger, M. S. (2016). Diagnosis and management of tick-borne rickettsial Diseases: Rocky Mountain spotted fever and other spotted fever group rickettsioses, ehrlichioses, and anaplasmosis - United States. MMWR. Recommendations and Reports, 65, 1-44. https://doi.org/10.15585/mmwr.rr6502a1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bitam, I., Dittmar, K., Parola, P., Whiting, M. F., &amp; Raoult, D. (2010). Fleas and flea-borne diseases. International Journal of Infectious Diseases, 14, e667-e676. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2009.11.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown, L. D., &amp; Macaluso, K. R. (2016). Rickettsia felis, an Emerging Flea-Borne Rickettsiosis. Current Tropical Medicine Reports, 3, 27-39. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40475-016-0070-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgdorfer, W. (1975). A review of Rocky Mountain spotted fever (tick borne typhus), its agent, and its tick vectors in the United States. Journal of Medical Entomology, 12, 269-278. https://doi.org/10.1093/jmedent/12.3.269</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bustamante, M., &amp; Varela, G. (1943). Una nueva rickettsiosis en México. Existencia de la fiebre manchada Americana en los estados de Sinaloa y Sonora. Revista Del Instituto De Salubridad Y Enfermedades Tropicales, 4, 189-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ceballos, G., Davidson, A., List, R., Pacheco, J., Manzano-Fischer, P., Santos-Barrera, G., &amp; Cruzado, J. (2010). Rapid decline of a grassland system and its ecological and conservation implications. PLoS One, 5, e8562. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0008562</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark, T. R., Noriea, N. F., Bublitz, D. A. C., Ellison, D. W., Martens, C., Lutter, E. I., &amp; Hackstadt, T. (2015). Comparative genome sequencing of Rickettsia rickettsii strains that differ in virulence. Infection and Immunity, 83, 1568-1576. https://doi.org/10.1128/IAI.03140-14</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooley, R. A. (1946). The genera Boophilus, Rhipicephalus, and Haemaphysalis (Ixodidae) of the New World. National Institute of Health Bulletin, 187, 1-54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dantas-Torres, F. (2010). Biology and ecology of the brown dog tick, Rhipicephalus sanguineus. Parasites and Vectors, 3, 1-26. https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-3305-3-26</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darriba, D., Taboada, G. L., Doallo, R., &amp; Posada, D. (2012). JModelTest 2: More models, new heuristics and parallel computing. Nature Methods, 9, 772. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.2109</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delgado-De la Mora, J., Sánchez-Montes, S., Licona-Enríquez, J. D., Delgado-De la Mora, D., Paddock, C. D., Beati, L., Colunga-Salas, P., Guzmán-Cornejo, C., Zambrano, M. L., Karpathy, S. E., López-Pérez, A. M., &amp; Álvarez-Hernández, G. (2019). Rickettsia parkeri and Candidatus Rickettsia andeanae in ticks of the Amblyomma maculatum group, Mexico. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 25, 836-838. https://doi.org/10.3201/EID2504.181507</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demma, L. J., Eremeeva, M., Nicholson, W. L., Traeger, M., Blau, D., Paddock, C., Levin, M., Dasch, G., Cheek, J., Swerdlow, D., &amp; McQuiston, J. (2006). An outbreak of rocky mountain spotted fever associated with a novel tick vector, Rhipicephalus sanguineus, in Arizona, 2004: Preliminary report. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1078, 342-343. https://doi.org/10.1196/annals.1374.066</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisen, R. J., &amp; Gage, K. L. (2012). Transmission of flea-borne zoonotic agents. Annual Review of Entomology, 57, 61-82. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-ento-120710-100717</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisen, R. J., Kugeler, K. J., Eisen, L., Beard, C. B., &amp; Paddock, C. D. (2017). Tick-borne zoonoses in the United States: Persistent and emerging threats to human health. ILAR Journal, 58, 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1093/ilar/ilx005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eldin, C., Virgili, G., Attard, L., Edouard, S., Viale, P., Raoult, D., &amp; Parola, P. (2018). Rickettsia massiliae infection after a tick bite on the eyelid. Travel Medicine and Infectious Disease, 26, 66-68. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tmaid.2018.08.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eremeeva, M. E., Bosserman, E. A., Demma, L. J., Zambrano, M. L., Blau, D. M., &amp; Dasch, G. A. (2006). Isolation and identification of Rickettsia massiliae from Rhipicephalus sanguineus ticks collected in Arizona. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 72, 5569-5577. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.00122-06</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eremeeva, M. E., &amp; Dasch, G. A. (2015). Challenges posed by tick-borne rickettsiae: Eco-epidemiology and public health implications. Frontiers in Public Health, 3, 1-17. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2015.00055</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eremeeva, M. E., Karpathy, S. E., Krueger, L., Hayes, E. K., Williams, A. M., Zaldivar, Y., Bennett, S., Cummings, R., Tilzer, A., Velten, R. K., Kerr, N., Dasch, G. A., &amp; Hu, R. (2012). Two pathogens and one disease: Detection and identification of flea-borne rickettsiae in areas endemic for murine typhus in California. Journal of Medical Entomology, 49, 1485-1494. https://doi.org/10.1603/ME11291</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estrada, I., Balagot, C., Fierro, M., Kriner, P., Iniguez-Stevens, E., Kjemtrup, A., &amp; Foley, J. (2020). Spotted fever group rickettsiae canine serosurveillance near the US-Mexico border in California. Zoonoses and Public Health, 67, 148-155. https://doi.org/10.1111/zph.12666</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foley, J., Tinoco-Gracia, L., Rodriguez-Lomelí, M., Estrada-Guzmán, J., Fierro, M., Mattar-Lopez, E., Peterson, A., Pascoe, E., Gonzalez, Y., Hori-Oshima, S., Armstrong, P. A., Lopez, G., Jacome-Ibarra, M., Paddock, C. D., &amp; Zazueta, O. E. (2019). Unbiased assessment of abundance of Rhipicephalus sanguineus sensu lato ticks, canine exposure to spotted fever group rickettsia, and risk factors in Mexicali, México. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 101, 22-32. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.18-0878</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Folkema, A. M., Holman, R. C., McQuiston, J. H., &amp; Cheek, J. E. (2012). Trends in clinical diagnoses of rocky mountain spotted fever among American Indians, 2001-2008. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 86, 152-158. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.2012.11-0269</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green, E. N., Porter, W. T., Howard, A. L., Yaglom, H., Benford, R., Busch, J. D., &amp; Nieto, N. C. (2020). Coyotes (Canis latrans) in Arizona, USA, exhibit immune and genetic evidence of rickettsial infections. Journal of Wildlife Diseases, 56, 261-269. https://doi.org/10.7589/2019-01-012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guégan, J. F., Ayouba, A., Cappelle, J., &amp; De Thoisy, B. (2020). Forests and emerging infectious diseases: Unleashing the beast within. Environmental Research Letters, 15, 1-21. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ab8dd7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henning, T. C., Orr, J. M., Smith, J. D., Arias, J. R., &amp; Norris, D. E. (2014). Spotted fever group rickettsiae in multiple hard tick species from fairfax county, Virginia. Vector-Borne and Zoonotic Diseases, 14, 482-485. https://doi.org/10.1089/vbz.2013.1534</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubbard, C. A. (1947). Fleas of Western North America: Their Relation to the Public Health. The Iowa State College Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karpathy, S. E., Hayes, E. K., Williams, A. M., Hu, R., Krueger, L., Bennett, S., Tilzer, A., Velten, R. K., Kerr, N., Moore, W., &amp; Eremeeva, M. E. (2009). Detection of Rickettsia felis and Rickettsia typhi in an area of California endemic for murine typhus. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 15, 218-219. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-0691.2008.02140.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keirans, J. E., &amp; Clifford, C. M. (1978). The genus Ixodes in the United States: A scanning electron microscope study and key to the adults. Journal of Medical Entomology Supplemental, 2, 1-149. https://doi.org/10.1093/jmedent/15.suppl2.1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolbe, J. A., &amp; Squires, J. R. (2005). Long distance movement by a coyote within the rocky mountains. Northwest Science, 78, 344-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreeger, T. J., &amp; Arnemo, J. M. (2012). Handbook of Wildlife Chemical Immobilization (4th edn.). : Terry J. Kreeger.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, S., Stecher, G., &amp; Tamura, K. (2016). MEGA7: Molecular evolutionary genetics analysis version 7.0 for bigger datasets. Molecular Biology and Evolution, 33, 1870-1874. https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msw054</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levin, M. L., Killmaster, L. F., Zemtsova, G. E., Ritter, J. M., &amp; Langham, G. (2014). Clinical presentation, convalescence, and relapse of rocky mountain spotted fever in dogs experimentally infected via tick bite. PLoS One, 9, e115105. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0115105</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis, R. (2000). A taxonomic review of the North American genus Orchopeas Jordan, 1933 (Siphonaptera: Ceratophyllidae: Ceratophyllinae). Journal of Vector Ecology, 25, 164-189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis, R. (2002). A review of the North American species of Oropsylla Wagner and Ioff, 1926 (Siphonaptera: Ceratophyllidae: Ceratophyllinae). Journal of Vector Ecology, 27, 184-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, W., Li, H., Bin Lu, Q., Cui, N., Yang, Z. D., Hu, J. G., Di Fan, Y., Guo, C. T., Li, X. K., Wang, Y. W., Liu, K., Zhang, X. A., Yuan, L., Zhao, P. Y., Qin, S. L., &amp; Cao, W. C. (2016). Candidatus Rickettsia tarasevichiae infection in Eastern Central China: A case series. Annals of Internal Medicine, 164, 641-648. https://doi.org/10.7326/M15-2572</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Pérez, A. M., Sánchez-Montes, S., Foley, J., Guzmán-Cornejo, C., Colunga-Salas, P., Pascoe, E., Becker, I., Delgado-de la Mora, J., Licona-Enriquez, J. D., &amp; Suzan, G. (2019). Molecular evidence of Borrelia burgdorferi sensu stricto and Rickettsia massiliae in ticks collected from a domestic-wild carnivore interface in Chihuahua, Mexico. Ticks and Tick-borne Diseases, 10, 1118-1123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ttbdis.2019.05.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundgren, D. L., Ushijima, R. N., &amp; Sidwell, R. W. (1963). Studies on infectious diseases in wild animals in Utah. V. Experimental rocky mountain spotted fever in the coyote. Canis Latrans Lestes Merriam. Zoonoses Research, 2, 124-134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maina, A. N., Fogarty, C., Krueger, L., MacAluso, K. R., Odhiambo, A., Nguyen, K., Farris, C. M., Luce-Fedrow, A., Bennett, S., Jiang, J., Sun, S., Cummings, R. F., &amp; Richards, A. L. (2016). Rickettsial infections among Ctenocephalides felis and host animals during a flea-borne rickettsioses outbreak in orange county, California. Plos One, 11, e0160604. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0160604</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maina, A. N., Jiang, J., Luce-Fedrow, A., St, H. K., John, C. M. F., &amp; Richards, A. L. (2019). Worldwide presence and features of flea-borne Rickettsia asembonensis. Frontiers in Veterinary Science, 5, 1-8. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2018.00334</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maxey, E. E. (1899). Some observations on the so-called spotted fever of Idaho. Medical Sentinel, 7, 432-438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morand, S., Chaisiri, K., Kritiyakan, A., &amp; Kumlert, R. (2020). Disease ecology of rickettsial species: A data science approach. Tropical Medicine and Infectious Disease, 5, 1-14. https://doi.org/10.3390/tropicalmed5020064</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson, W. L., Allen, K. E., McQuiston, J. H., Breitschwerdt, E. B., &amp; Little, S. E. (2010). The increasing recognition of rickettsial pathogens in dogs and people. Trends in Parasitology, 26, 205-212. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pt.2010.01.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieri-Bastos, F. A., Marcili, A., de Sousa, R., Paddock, C. D., &amp; Labruna, M. B. (2018). Phylogenetic evidence for the existence of multiple strains of Rickettsia parkeri in the New World. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 84, e02872-e2917. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.02872-17</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Openshaw, J. J., Swerdlow, D. L., Krebs, J. W., Holman, R. C., Mandel, E., Harvey, A., Haberling, D., Massung, R. F., &amp; McQuiston, J. H. (2010). Rocky mountain spotted fever in the United States, 2000-2007: Interpreting contemporary increases in incidence. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 83, 174-182. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.2010.09-0752</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paddock, C. D., Allerdice, M. E. J., Karpathy, S. E., Nicholson, W. L., Levin, M. L., Smith, T. C., Becker, T., Delph, R. J., Knight, R. N., Ritter, J. M., Sanders, J. H., &amp; Goddard, J. (2017). Unique strain of Rickettsia parkeri associated with the hard tick Dermacentor parumapertus Neumann in the western United States. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 83, e03463-e3516. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.03463-16</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paddock, C. D., Denison, A. M., Lash, R. R., Liu, L., Bollweg, B. C., Dahlgren, F. S., Kanamura, C. T., Angerami, R. N., Dos Santos, F. C. P., Martines, R. B., &amp; Karpathy, S. E. (2014). Phylogeography of Rickettsia rickettsii genotypes associated with fatal rocky mountain spotted fever. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 91, 589-597. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.14-0146</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paddock, C. D., &amp; Goddard, J. (2015). The evolving medical and veterinary importance of the gulf coast tick (Acari: Ixodidae). Journal of Medical Entomology, 52, 230-252. https://doi.org/10.1093/jme/tju022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paddock, C. D., Sumner, J. W., Comer, J. A., Zaki, S. R., Goldsmith, C. S., Goddard, J., McLellan, S. L. F., Tamminga, C. L., &amp; Ohl, C. A. (2004). Rickettsia parkeri: A newly recognized cause of spotted fever rickettsiosis in the United States. Clinical Infectious Diseases, 38, 805-811. https://doi.org/10.1086/381894</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parker, R., Philip, C., &amp; Jellison, W. (1933). Potentialities of tick transmission in relation to geographical occurrence in the United States. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 13, 341-379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parola, P. (2011). Rickettsia felis: From a rare disease in the USA to a common cause of fever in sub-Saharan Africa. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 17, 996-1000. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-0691.2011.03516.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parola, P., Paddock, C. D., Socolovschi, C., Labruna, M. B., Mediannikov, O., Kernif, T., Abdad, M. Y., Stenos, J., Bitam, I., Fournier, P. E., &amp; Raoult, D. (2013). Update on tick-borne rickettsioses around the world: A geographic approach. Clinical Microbiology Reviews, 26, 657-702. https://doi.org/10.1128/CMR.00032-13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peniche Lara, G., Dzul Rosado, K. R., Zavala Velásquez, J. E., &amp; Zavala-Castro, J. (2012). Murine typhus: Clinical and epidemiological aspects. Colombia Medica, 43, 175-180. https://doi.org/10.25100/cm.v43i2.1147</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pieracci, E. G., De La Rosa, J. D. P., Rubio, D. L., Perales, M. E. S., Contreras, M. V., Drexler, N. A., Nicholson, W. L., De La Rosa, J. J. P., Chung, I. H., Kato, C., Barton Behravesh, C., Enríquez, M. A. G., Roldan, J. F. G., &amp; Villarino, M. E. (2019). Seroprevalence of spotted fever group rickettsiae in canines along the United States-Mexico border. Zoonoses and Public Health, 66, 918-926. https://doi.org/10.1111/zph.12642</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piranda, E. M., Faccini, J. L. H., Pinter, A., Pacheco, R. C., Cançado, P. H. D., &amp; Labruna, M. B. (2011). Experimental infection of Rhipicephalus sanguineus ticks with the bacterium Rickettsia rickettsii, using experimentally infected dogs. Vector-Borne and Zoonotic Diseases, 11, 29-36. https://doi.org/10.1089/vbz.2009.0250</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitt, J., Luecke, D. F., Cohen, M. J., Glenn, E. P., &amp; Valdes-Casillas, C. (2000). Two nations, one river: Managing ecosystem conservation in the Colorado River delta. Natural Resources Journal, 40, 819-864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roux, V., &amp; Raoult, D. (2000). Phylogenetic analysis of members of the genus Rickettsia using the gene encoding the outer-membrane protein rOmpB (ompB). International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology, 50, 1449-1455. https://doi.org/10.1099/00207713-50-4-1449</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sánchez-Montes, S., Guzmán-Cornejo, C., Martínez-Nájera, Y., Becker, I., Venzal, J. M., &amp; Labruna, M. B. (2016). Rickettsia lusitaniae associated with Ornithodoros yumatensis (Acari: Argasidae) from two caves in Yucatan, Mexico. Ticks and Tick-borne Diseases, 7, 1097-1101. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ttbdis.2016.09.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sánchez-Montes, S., López-Pérez, A. M., Guzmán-Cornejo, C., Colunga-Salas, P., Becker, I., Mora, J. D., Licona-enríquez, J. D., Mora, D. D., Karpathy, S. E., Paddock, C. D., &amp; Suzán, G. (2018). Rickettsia parkeri in Dermacentor parumapertus ticks, Mexico. Emerging Infectiuos Diseases, 24, 1108-1111. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2406.180058</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shpynov, S. N., Fournier, P. E., Pozdnichenko, N. N., Gumenuk, A. S., &amp; Skiba, A. A. (2018). New approaches in the systematics of rickettsiae. New Microbes and New Infections, 23, 93-102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nmni.2018.02.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shuford, J., Hunt, P., &amp; Mayes, B. (2018). Changing epidemiology of murine typhus in Texas. Open Forum Infectious Diseases, 5, S242. https://doi.org/10.1093/ofid/ofy210.676</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva-Goytia, R., &amp; Elizondo, A. (1952). Estudios sobre fiebre manchada en Mexico. IV. Caracteristicas epidemiológicas de casos de fiebre manchada ocurridos en la Laguna. Medicina Revista Mexicana, 32, 569-579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, S., Chen, C., Yang, M., Zhao, S., Wang, B., Hornok, S., Makhatov, B., Rizabek, K., &amp; Wang, Y. (2018). Diversity of Rickettsia species in border regions of northwestern China. Parasites and Vectors, 11, 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-018-3233-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stark, H. E. (1958). The Siphonaptera of Utah: Their Taxonomy, Distribution, Host Relations, and Medical Importance. U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Communicable Disease Center.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Starkey, L. A., West, M. D., Barrett, A. W., Saucier, J. M., O’Connor, T. P., Paras, K. L., Reiskind, M. H., Reichard, M. V., &amp; Little, S. E. (2013). Prevalence of antibodies to spotted fever group Rickettsia spp. and Ehrlichia spp. in coyotes (Canis latrans) in Oklahoma and Texas, USA. Journal of Wildlife Diseases, 49, 670-673. https://doi.org/10.7589/2012-08-215</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swei, A., Couper, L. I., Coffey, L. L., Kapan, D., &amp; Bennett, S. (2020). Patterns, drivers, and challenges of vector-borne disease emergence. Vector-Borne and Zoonotic Diseases, 20, 159-170. https://doi.org/10.1089/vbz.2018.2432</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tinoco-Gracia, L., Lomelí, M. R., Hori-Oshima, S., Stephenson, N., &amp; Foley, J. (2018). Molecular confirmation of rocky mountain spotted fever epidemic agent in Mexicali, Mexico. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 24, 1723-1725. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2409.171523</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varela-Stokes, A. S., Paddock, C. D., Engber, B., &amp; Toliver, M. (2011). Rickettsia parkeri in Amblyomma maculatum ticks, North Carolina, USA, 2009-2010. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 17, 2350-2353. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid1712.110789</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamson, P. C., Billingsley, P. M., Teltow, G. J., Seals, J. P., Turnbough, M. A., &amp; Atkinson, S. F. (2010). Borrelia, Ehrlichia, and Rickettsia spp. in ticks removed from persons, Texas, USA. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 16, 441-446. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid1603.091333</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolbach, S. B. (1919). Studies on Rocky Mountain spotted Fever. The Journal of Medical Research, 41, 1-198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaglom, H. D., Casal, M., Carson, S., O’Grady, C. L., Dominguez, V., Singleton, J., Chung, I., Lodge, H., &amp; Paddock, C. D. (2020). Expanding recognition of Rickettsia parkeri rickettsiosis in southern Arizona, 2016-2017. Vector-Borne and Zoonotic Diseases, 20, 82-87. https://doi.org/10.1089/vbz.2019.2491</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yunker, C. E., Keirans, J. E., Clifford, C. M., &amp; Easton, E. R. (1986). Dermacentor ticks (Acari: Ixodoidea: Ixodidae) of the New World: A scanning electron microscope atlas. Proceedings of the Entomological Society of Washington, 88, 609-627. https://doi.org/10.1039/p19880000157</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
