<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33728754</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1865-1682</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>69</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Transboundary and emerging diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Transbound Emerg Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Human brucellosis epidemiology in the pastoral area of Hulun Buir city, Inner Mongolia autonomous region, China, between 2003 and 2018.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1155</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1165</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1155-1165</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tbed.14075</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Human brucellosis represents a serious public health concern in Hulun Buir and requires a comprehensive epidemiologic analysis to define adapted control measures. The present study describes the case numbers, constituent ratios and incidence rate of human brucellosis. Conventional biotyping, that is abortus, melitensis, ovis and suis (AMOS)-PCR and multi-locus variable-number tandem repeat analysis (MLVA) were used to characterize the Brucella strains. Between 2003 and 2018, a total of 23,897 human brucellosis cases were reported, with an incidence rate of 56.03/100,000, which is 20 times higher than the country's average incidence. This incidence rate increased year after year, culminating in 2005 and decreased between 2011 and 2018. Because Hulun Buir relies on a nomadic livestock rearing system, brucellosis spreads easily among different animal species and humans. In Xin Barag Left Banner and Xin Barag Right Banner, the incidence rates were, respectively, 226.54/100,000 and 199.10/100,000, exceeding those observed in other areas. Most of the cases occurred in the 25- to 45-year-old group, accounting for 65.74% of the cases (15,709/23,897), and among farmers, accounting for 66.71% (15,942/23,897). The male to female incidence ratio was 2.67:1. The higher incidence in younger people and the large gender ratio reflected the unique traditional production and lifestyle of nomads. Most reported cases were observed from April to June, indicating that more than 40% of the cases were related to the delivery of domestic livestock. The biotyping showed that the 44 isolated strains were all B. melitensis, including 12 Brucella melitensis biovar (bv) 1 and 32 B. melitensis bv. 3. The strains displayed a genetic similarity of 80%-100%. Our hypothesis is that human brucellosis outbreak in this region may be originating from a limited source of infection, so further investigation is necessary. The epidemic situation of human brucellosis in Hulun Buir is extremely serious, strengthened surveillance and control in animals' brucellosis should be priority.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhiguo</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4904-4878</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Infectious Disease Prevention and Control, National Institute for Communicable Disease Control and Prevention, Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Central for Comprehensive Disease Control and Prevention, Huhhot, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dongyan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hulun Buir City Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Hulun Buir, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Miao</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ulanqab Central for Endemic Disease Control and Prevention, Ulanqab, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhenjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Infectious Disease Prevention and Control, National Institute for Communicable Disease Control and Prevention, Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Transbound Emerg Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101319538</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1865-1674</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002002" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brucella</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017347" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brucella melitensis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002006" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brucellosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002681" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">China</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005838" MajorTopicYN="N">Genotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018598" MajorTopicYN="N">Minisatellite Repeats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058885" MajorTopicYN="N">Multilocus Sequence Typing</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012756" MajorTopicYN="N">Sheep</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012757" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sheep Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Brucella
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brucellosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hulun Buir</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiological characteristics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genotypes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33728754</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14075</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bat-Erdene, D., Chuang, Y. C., &amp; Chuang, K. Y. (2019). Brucellosis knowledge and preventive practices among herders in Western Mongolia. Zoonoses Public Health, 66(1), 133-139. https://doi.org/10.1111/zph.12545</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgess, T. L., Johnson, C. K., Burdin, A., Gill, V. A., Doroff, A. M., Tuomi, P., Smith, W. A., &amp; Goldstein, T. (2017). Brucella infection in Asian sea otters (Enhydra lutris lutris) on Bering Island, Russia. Journal of Wildlife Diseases, 53(4), 864-868. https://doi.org/10.7589/2016-09-220</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, J.-D., Ke, C.-W., Deng, X., Jiang, S., Liang, W., Ke, B.-X., Li, B., Tan, H., &amp; Liu, M. (2013). Brucellosis in Guangdong Province, people's republic of China, 2005-2010. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 19(5), 817-818. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid1905.120146</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daugaliyeva, А., Sultanov, A., Usserbayev, B., Baramova, S., Modesto, P., Adambayeva, A., Acutis, P. L., &amp; Peletto, S. (2018). Genotyping of Brucella melitensis and brucella abortus strains in Kazakhstan using MLVA-15. Infection, Genetics and Evolution, 58, 135-144. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meegid.2017.12.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denk, A., Demirdag, K., Kalkan, A., Ozden, M., Cetinkaya, B., &amp; Kilic, S. S. (2015). In vitro activity of Brucella melitensis isolates to various antimicrobials in Turkey. Infectious Diseases (London), 47(6), 364-369. https://doi.org/10.3109/00365548.2014.988748</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, S. N., Wang, Z. J., Yu, G. W., Cui, Y. L., Chen, J. J., Hu, N., &amp; Liu, Z. G. (2020). Epidemiological characteristics of human brucellosis in Tongliao city of Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, 2004-2018. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi, 41(7), 1063-1067. https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.cn112338-20190901-00642</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edelsten, R. M. (1988). Techniques for the brucellosis laboratory. Veterinary Research Communications, 13, 420. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00402562</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreira, A. C., Chambel, L., Tenreiro, T., Cardoso, R., Flor, L., Dias, I. T., Pacheco, T., Garin-Bastuji, B., Le Flèche, P., Vergnaud, G., Tenreiro, R., &amp; de Sá, M. I. C. (2012). MLVA16 typing of Portuguese human and animal Brucella melitensis and brucella abortus isolates. PLoS One, 7(8), e42514. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0042514</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galińska, E. M., &amp; Zagórski, J. (2013). Brucellosis in humans-etiology, diagnostics, clinical forms. Annals of Agricultural and Environmental Medicine, 20(2), 233-238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garofolo, G., Di Giannatale, E., De Massis, F., Zilli, K., Ancora, M., Cammà, C., Calistri, P., &amp; Foster, J. T. (2013). Investigating genetic diversity of Brucella abortus and Brucella melitensis in Italy with MLVA-16. Infection, Genetics and Evolution, 19, 59-70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.meegid.2013.06.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godfroid, J., Al Dahouk, S., Pappas, G., Roth, F., Matope, G., Muma, J., Marcotty, T., Pfeiffer, D., &amp; Skjerve, E. (2013). A "One Health" surveillance and control of brucellosis in developing countries: Moving away from improvisation. Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 36(3), 241-248. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2012.09.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janowicz, A., De Massis, F., Zilli, K., Ancora, M., Tittarelli, M., Sacchini, F., Di Giannatale, E., Sahl, J. W., Foster, J. T., &amp; Garofolo, G. (2020). Evolutionary history and current distribution of the West Mediterranean lineage of Brucella melitensis in Italy. Microbial Genomics, 6(11), mgen000446. https://doi.org/10.1099/mgen.0.000446</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang, W., Chen, J., Li, Q., Jiang, L., Huang, Y., Lan, Y., &amp; Li, Y. (2019). Epidemiological characteristics, clinical manifestations and laboratory findings in 850 patients with brucellosis in Heilongjiang Province, China. BMC Infectious Diseases, 19(1), 439. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12879-019-4081-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang, S.-I., Her, M., Erdenebaataar, J., Vanaabaatar, B., Cho, H., Sung, S.-R., Lee, J. J., Jung, S. C., Park, Y. H., &amp; Kim, J.-Y. (2017). Molecular epidemiological investigation of Brucella melitensis circulating in Mongolia by MLVA16. Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 50, 16-22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2016.11.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kulakov Iu, K., Erdenbaator, J., Zheludkov, M. M., &amp; Korenberg, E. I. (2011). Genetic characterization of the Brucella melitensis isolates from Mongolia, Russia, and Azerbaijan. Molekuliarnaia Genetika, Mikrobiologiia I Virusologiia, 2, 8-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai, S., Zhou, H., Xiong, W., Gilbert, M., Huang, Z., Yu, J., Yin, W., Wang, L., Chen, Q., Li, Y. U., Mu, D. I., Zeng, L., Ren, X., Geng, M., Zhang, Z., Cui, B., Li, T., Wang, D., Li, Z., … Yu, H. (2017). Changing epidemiology of human brucellosis, China, 1955-2014. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 23(2), 184-194. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2302.151710</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, M. T., Sun, G. Q., Zhang, W. Y., &amp; Jin, Z. (2017). Model-based evaluation of strategies to control brucellosis in China. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 14(3), 295. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph14030295</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, C., Wei, W., Liang, X., De, E., &amp; Zheng, B. (2019). Spinal brucellosis in Hulunbuir, China, 2011-2016. Infection and Drug Resistance, 12, 1565-1571. https://doi.org/10.2147/idr.S202440</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, P. F., Zhao, Y., Zhao, J. H., Pan, D. F., &amp; Guo, Z. Q. (2020). Human distribution and spatial-temporal clustering analysis of human brucellosis in China from 2012 to 2016. Infectious Diseases of Poverty, 9(1), 142. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40249-020-00754-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, F., Wang, D., Yang, S.-C., Zhu, J.-H., Li, J.-M., Shi, K., Du, R., &amp; Zhao, Q. (2019). Prevalence and risk factors of brucellosis, toxoplasmosis, and neosporosis among yanbian yellow cattle in Jilin province, China. Vector Borne Zoonotic Diseases, 19(3), 217-221. https://doi.org/10.1089/vbz.2018.2288</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Z.-G., Di, D.-D., Wang, M., Liu, R.-H., Zhao, H.-Y., Piao, D.-R., Tian, G.-Z., Fan, W.-X., Jiang, H., Cui, B.-Y., &amp; Xia, X.-Z. (2017). MLVA genotyping characteristics of human Brucella melitensis isolated from Ulanqab of Inner Mongolia, China. Frontiers in Microbiology, 8, 6. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2017.00006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Z., Wang, C., Wei, K., Zhao, Z., Wang, M., Li, D., Wang, H., Wei, Q., &amp; Li, Z. (2020). Investigation of genetic relatedness of Brucella strains in countries along the silk road. Frontiers in Veterinary Science, 7, 539444. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2020.539444</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Z. G., Wang, M., Ta, N., Fang, M. G., Mi, J. C., Yu, R. P., &amp; Li, Z. J. (2020). Seroprevalence of human brucellosis and molecular characteristics of Brucella strains in Inner Mongolia Autonomous region of China, from 2012 to 2016. Emerging Microbes and Infections, 9(1), 263-274. https://doi.org/10.1080/22221751.2020.1720528</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Z. G., Wang, M., Zhan, Z. F., Cui, B. Y., &amp; Li, Z. J. (2019). Epidemiology of human brucellosis and source of Brucella isolates in Hunan province. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi, 40(9), 1150-1154. https://doi.org/10.3760/cma.j.issn.0254-6450.2019.09.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Massis, F. D., Girolamo, A. D., Petrini, A., Pizzigallo, E., &amp; Giovannini, A. (2005). Correlation between animal and human brucellosis in Italy during the period 1997-2002. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 11(8), 632-636. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-0691.2005.01204.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shevtsova, E., Shevtsov, A., Mukanov, K., Filipenko, M., Kamalova, D., Sytnik, I., Syzdykov, M., Kuznetsov, A., Akhmetova, A., Zharova, M., Karibaev, T., Tarlykov, P., &amp; Ramanculov, E. (2016). Epidemiology of Brucellosis and genetic diversity of Brucella abortus in Kazakhstan. PLoS One, 11(12), e0167496. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0167496</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shevtsova, E., Vergnaud, G., Shevtsov, A., Shustov, A., Berdimuratova, K., Mukanov, K., Syzdykov, M., Kuznetsov, A., Lukhnova, L., Izbanova, U., Filipenko, M., &amp; Ramankulov, Y. (2019). Genetic diversity of Brucella melitensis in Kazakhstan in relation to world-wide diversity. Frontiers in Microbiology, 10, 1897. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2019.01897</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swai, E. S., &amp; Schoonman, L. (2011). Microbial quality and associated health risks of raw milk marketed in the Tanga region of Tanzania. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Biomedicine, 1(3), 217-222. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2221-1691(11)60030-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsend, S., Baljinnyam, Z., Suuri, B., Dashbal, E., Oidov, B., Roth, F., Zinstag, J., Schelling, E., &amp; Dambadarjaa, D. (2014). Seroprevalence survey of brucellosis among rural people in Mongolia. Western Pacific Surveillance and Response Journal, 5(4), 13-20. https://doi.org/10.5365/wpsar.2014.5.1.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, T., Wang, X., Tie, P., Bai, Y., Zheng, Y., Yan, C., Chai, Z., Chen, J., Rao, H., Zeng, L., Chen, L., &amp; Qiu, L. (2018). Spatio-temporal cluster and distribution of human brucellosis in Shanxi province of China between 2011 and 2016. Scientific Reports, 8(1), 16977. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-34975-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y. U., Wang, Y., Zhang, L., Wang, A., Yan, Y. U., Chen, Y., Li, X., Guo, A., &amp; Robertson, I. D. (2020). An epidemiological study of brucellosis on mainland China during 2004-2018. Transboundary and Emerging Diseases, https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.13896</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan, H. T., Wang, C. L., Liu, L. N., Wang, D., Li, D., Li, Z. J., &amp; Liu, Z. G. (2020). Epidemiologically characteristics of human brucellosis and antimicrobial susceptibility pattern of Brucella melitensis in Hinggan League of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, China. Infectious Diseases of Poverty, 9(1), 79. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40249-020-00697-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng, J. Y., Robertson, I. D., Ji, Q. M., Dawa, Y. L., &amp; Bruce, M. (2019). Evaluation of the economic impact of brucellosis in domestic yaks of Tibet. Transboundary and Emerging Diseases, 66(1), 476-487. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.13049</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng, R., Xie, S., Lu, X., Sun, L., Zhou, Y., Zhang, Y., &amp; Wang, K. (2018). A systematic review and meta-analysis of epidemiology and clinical manifestations of human brucellosis in China. BioMed Research International, 2018, 5712920. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/5712920</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong, Z., Yu, S., Wang, X., Dong, S., Xu, J., Wang, Y., Chen, Z., Ren, Z., &amp; Peng, G. (2013). Human brucellosis in the people's republic of China during 2005-2010. International Journal of Infectious Diseases, 17(5), e289-e292. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2012.12.030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, L., Fan, M., Hou, Q., Jin, Z., &amp; Sun, X. (2018). Transmission dynamics and optimal control of brucellosis in Inner Mongolia of China. Mathematical Biosciences and Engineering, 15(2), 543-567. https://doi.org/10.3934/mbe.2018025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu, X., Zhao, Z., Ma, S., Guo, Z., Wang, M., Li, Z., &amp; Liu, Z. (2020). Brucella melitensis, a latent "travel bacterium," continual spread and expansion from Northern to Southern China and its relationship to worldwide lineages. Emerging Microbes &amp; Infection, 9(1), 1618-1627. https://doi.org/10.1080/22221751.2020.1788995</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zolzaya, B., Selenge, T., Narangarav, T., Gantsetseg, D., Erdenechimeg, D., Zinsstag, J., &amp; Schelling, E. (2014). Representative seroprevalences of human and livestock brucellosis in two Mongolian provinces. EcoHealth, 11(3), 356-371. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10393-014-0962-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
