<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33763903</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-3083</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>35</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology : JEADV</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Nondermatophyte mould onychomycosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1628</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1641</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1628-1641</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jdv.17240</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Nondermatophyte moulds (NDMs) onychomycosis is often difficult to diagnose as NDMs have been considered contaminants of nails. There are several diagnostic methods used to identify NDMs, however, repeated laboratory isolation is recommended to validate pathogenicity. With NDM and mixed infection (dermatophytes plus NDM) onychomycosis on the rise, accurate clinical diagnosis along with mycological tests is recommended. Systemic antifungal agents such as itraconazole and terbinafine (e.g. pulse regimen: 1 pulse = every day for one week, followed by no treatment for three weeks) have shown efficacy in treating onychomycosis caused by various NDMs such as Aspergillus spp., Fusarium spp., Scopulariopsis brevicaulis, and Onychocola canadensis. Studies investigating topical therapy and devices for NDM onychomycosis are limited. The emergence of antifungal resistance necessitates the incorporation of antifungal susceptibility testing into diagnosis when possible, for the management of recalcitrant infections. Case studies documented in the literature show newer azoles such as posaconazole and voriconazole as sometimes effective in treating resistant NDM onychomycosis. Treatment with broad-spectrum antifungal agents (e.g. itraconazole and efinaconazole) and other combination therapy (oral + oral and/or oral + topical) may be considerations in the management of NDM onychomycosis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gupta</LastName>
            <ForeName>A K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8664-7723</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Summerbell</LastName>
            <ForeName>R C</ForeName>
            <Initials>RC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sporometrics, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dalla Lana School of Public Health, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Venkataraman</LastName>
            <ForeName>M</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Quinlan</LastName>
            <ForeName>E M</ForeName>
            <Initials>EM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9216037</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0926-9959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>304NUG5GF4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017964">Itraconazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>G7RIW8S0XP</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077291">Terbinafine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000661753">Arachnomyces nodosetosus</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017964" MajorTopicYN="N">Itraconazole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014009" MajorTopicYN="Y">Onychomycosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020036" MajorTopicYN="N">Onygenales</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077291" MajorTopicYN="N">Terbinafine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>49</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33763903</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.17240</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Summerbell RC. Onychomycosis: a critical study of techniques and criteria for confirming the etiologic significance of nondermatophytes. Med Mycol 2005; 43: 39-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno G, Arenas R. Other fungi causing onychomycosis. Clin Dermatol 2010; 28: 160-163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramani R, Srinivas CR, Ramani A, Kumari TG, Shivananda PG. Molds in onychomycosis. Int J Dermatol 1993; 32: 877-878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Drummond-Main C, Cooper EA, Brintnell W, Piraccini BM, Tosti A. Systematic review of nondermatophyte mold onychomycosis: diagnosis, clinical types, epidemiology, and treatment. J Am Acad Dermatol 2012; 66: 494-502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scher RK, Rich P, Pariser D, Elewski B. The epidemiology, etiology, and pathophysiology of onychomycosis. Semin Cutan Med Surg 2013; 32(2 Suppl 1): S2-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Mays RR, Versteeg SG et al. Global perspectives for the management of onychomycosis. Int J Dermatol 2019; 58: 1118-1129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas J, Jacobson GA, Narkowicz CK, Peterson GM, Burnet H, Sharpe C. Toenail onychomycosis: An important global disease burden. J Clin Pharm and Therapeut 2010; 35: 497-519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghavendra KR, Yadav D, Kumar A, Sharma M, Bhuria J, Chand AE. The nondermatophyte molds: Emerging as leading cause of onychomycosis in south-east Rajasthan. Indian Dermatol Online J 2015; 6: 92-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Ryder JE, Baran R, Summerbell RC. Non-dermatophyte onychomycosis. Dermatol Clin 2003; 21: 257-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Taborda V, Taborda P, Shemer A, Summerbell R, Nakrieko K. High prevalence of mixed infections in global onychomycosis. PLoS One 2020; 15: e0239648.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>English MP. Nails and fungi. Br J Dermatol 1976; 94: 697-701.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Summerbell RC. Epidemiology and ecology of onychomycosis. Dermatology (Basel) 1997; 194(Suppl 1): 32-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Straten MRV, Balkis MM, Ghannoum MA. The role of nondermatophyte molds in onychomycosis: diagnosis and treatment. Dermatol Ther 2002; 15: 89-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA, MacDonald P, Summerbell RC. Utility of inoculum counting (Walshe and English criteria) in clinical diagnosis of onychomycosis caused by nondermatophytic filamentous fungi. J Clin Microbiol 2001; 39: 2115-2121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>English M, Wethered R, Duncan E. Studies in the epidemiology of tinea pedis: VIII. Fungal infection in a long-stay hospital. Br Med J 1967;3:136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Davidovici B, Grunwald Mh, Trau H, Amichai B. New criteria for the laboratory diagnosis of nondermatophyte moulds in onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2009; 160: 37-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noguchi H, Matsumoto T, Kimura U et al. Non-dermatophyte mould onychomycosis in Japan. Med Mycol J 2020; 61: 23-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassagne C, Normand A-C, L’Ollivier C, Ranque S, Piarroux R. Performance of MALDI-TOF MS platforms for fungal identification. Mycoses 2016; 59: 678-690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Konnikov N, Lynde CW et al. Onychomycosis: predisposed populations and some predictors of suboptimal response to oral antifungal agents. Eur J Dermatol 1999; 9: 633-638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Mays R. The impact of onychomycosis on quality of life: a systematic review of the available literature. Skin Appendage Disorders 2018; 4: 208-216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westerberg DP, Voyack MJ. Onychomycosis: Current trends in diagnosis and treatment. Am Fam Physician 2013; 88: 762-770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Tosti A. Risk factors and comorbidities for onychomycosis: implications for treatment with topical therapy. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol 2015; 8: 38-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Daigle D, Foley KA. The prevalence of culture-confirmed toenail onychomycosis in at-risk patient populations. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2015; 29: 1039-1044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bongomin F, Batac CR, Richardson MD, Denning DW. A review of onychomycosis due to Aspergillus species. Mycopathologia 2018; 183: 485-493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee MH, Hwang SM, Suh MK, Ha GY, Kim H, Park JY. Onychomycosis caused by Scopulariopsis brevicaulis: report of two cases. Ann Dermatol 2012; 24: 209-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Hay R, Arenas-Guzmán R. Patients at risk of onychomycosis-risk factor identification and active prevention. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2005; 19(Suppl 1): 13-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK. Onychomycosis in the elderly. Drugs Aging 2000; 16: 397-407.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG, Shear NH. Onychomycosis in the 21st century: an update on diagnosis, epidemiology, and treatment. J Cutan Med Surg 2017; 21: 525-539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hope YM, Clayton YM, Hay RJ, Noble WC, Elder-Smith JG. Foot infection in coal miners: a reassessment. Br J Dermatol 1985; 112: 405-413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaias N, Escovar SX, Rebell G. Opportunistic toenail onychomycosis. The fungal colonization of an available nail unit space by non-dermatophytes is produced by the trauma of the closed shoe by an asymmetric gait or other trauma. A plausible theory. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2014; 28: 1002-1006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaias N, Rebell G, Casal G, Appel J. The asymmetric gait toenail unit sign. Skinmed 2012; 10: 213-217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R ed. Baran &amp; Dawber’s diseases of the nails and their management, 5th edn. Hoboken, NJ, Wiley-Blackwell, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Berker D. Nail anatomy. Clin Dermatol 2013; 31: 509-515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez-Flores A, Saeb-Lima M, Martínez-Nova A. Histopathology of the nail unit. Rom J Morphol Embryol 2014; 27: 235-256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Lynde CW, Jain HC et al. A higher prevalence of onychomycosis in psoriatics compared with non-psoriatics: a multicentre study. Br J Dermatol 1997; 136: 786-789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Konnikov N, MacDonald P et al. Prevalence and epidemiology of toenail onychomycosis in diabetic subjects: a multicentre survey. Br J Dermatol 1998; 139: 665-671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Hatmi AMS, Bonifaz A, Calderón L et al. Proximal subungual onychomycosis caused by Fusarium falciforme successfully cured with posaconazole. Br J Dermatol 2015; 173: 253-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R, McLoone N, Hay RJ. Could proximal white subungual onychomycosis be a complication of systemic spread? The lessons to be learned from Maladie Dermatophytique and other deep infections. Br J Dermatol 2005; 153: 1023-1025.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaias N. Onychomycosis. Arch Dermatol 1972; 105: 263-274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R, Hay RJ, Tosti A, Haneke E. A new classification of onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 1998; 139: 567-571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Baran R, Piraccini BM, Fanti PA. “Endonyx” onychomycosis: a new modality of nail invasion by dermatophytes. Acta Derm Venereol 1999; 79: 52-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hay RJ, Baran R. Onychomycosis: a proposed revision of the clinical classification. J Am Acad Dermatol 2011; 65: 1219-1227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Summerbell RC. Combined distal and lateral subungual and white superficial onychomycosis in the toenails. J Am Acad Dermatol 1999; 41: 938-944.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R, Hay R, Perrin C. Superficial white onychomycosis revisited. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2004; 18: 569-571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Elewski BE. Nondermatophyte causes of onychomycosis and superficial mycoses. Curr Top Med Mycol 1996; 7: 87-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Lorenzi S, Tosti A. “Deep” white superficial onychomycosis due to molds. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2002; 16: 532-533.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Alessandrini A. Onychomycosis: a review. J Fungi (Basel) 2015; 1: 30-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Tosti A. White superficial onychomycosis: Epidemiological, clinical, and pathological study of 79 patients. Arch Dermatol 2004; 140: 696-701.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM. Proximal subungual onychomycosis due to Aspergillus niger: report of two cases. Br J Dermatol 1998; 139: 156-157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniel CR, 3rd, Norton LA, Scher RK. The spectrum of nail disease in patients with human immunodeficiency virus infection. J Am Acad Dermatol 1992; 27: 93-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan MH, Sadick N, McNutt NS, Meltzer M, Sarngadharan MG, Pahwa S. Dermatologic findings and manifestations of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). J Am Acad Dermatol 1987; 16(3 Pt 1): 485-506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baran R, Tosti A, Piraccini BM. Uncommon clinical patterns of Fusarium nail infection: report of three cases. Br J Dermatol 1997; 136: 424-427.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falahati M, Ghojoghi A, Abastabar M et al. The first case of total dystrophic onychomycosis caused by Aspergillus clavatus resistant to antifungal drugs. Mycopathologia 2016; 181: 273-277.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM, Stinchi C, Lorenzi S. Onychomycosis due to Scopulariopsis brevicaulis: clinical features and response to systemic antifungals. Br J Dermatol 1996; 135: 799-802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Stec N, Summerbell RC et al. Onychomycosis: a review. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2020; 34: 1972-1990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leelavathi M, Tzar M. Brief report: nail sampling technique and its interpretation. Malays Fam Physician 2011; 6: 58-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>St-Germain G, Summerbell R. Identifying Filamentous Fungi: A Clinical Laboratory Handbook. 1st ed. Vol. 45. Belmont, CA: Star Publishing Company; 1996. 314 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bitew A, Wolde S. Prevalence, risk factors, and spectrum of fungi in patients with onychomycosis in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia: a prospective study. J Trop Med 2019; 4: 3652634.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walshe MM, English MP. Fungi in nails. Br J Dermatol 1966; 78: 198-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinberg JM, Koestenblatt EK, Tutrone WD, Tishler HR, Najarian L. Comparison of diagnostic methods in the evaluation of onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol 2003; 49: 193-197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung MY, Shim JH, Lee JH et al. Comparison of diagnostic methods for onychomycosis, and proposal of a diagnostic algorithm. Clin Exp Dermatol 2015; 40: 479-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim YJ, Han SS, Yang HJ, Chang SE. Prospective, comparative evaluation of a deep neural network and dermoscopy in the diagnosis of onychomycosis. PLoS One 2020; 15: e0234334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Zaman M, Singh J. Fast and sensitive detection of Trichophyton rubrum DNA from the nail samples of patients with onychomycosis by a double-round polymerase chain reaction-based assay. Br J Dermatol 2007; 157: 698-703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato T, Takayanagi A, Nagao K et al. Simple PCR-Based DNA microarray system to identify human pathogenic fungi in skin. J Clin Microbiol 2010; 48: 2357-2364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verrier J, Monod M. Diagnosis of dermatophytosis using molecular biology. Mycopathologia 2017; 182: 193-202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monod M, Bontems O, Zaugg C, Léchenne B, Fratti M, Panizzon R. Fast and reliable PCR/sequencing/RFLP assay for identification of fungi in onychomycoses. J Med Microbiol 2006; 55: 1211-1216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nouripour-Sisakht S, Mirhendi H, Shidfar MR et al. Aspergillus species as emerging causative agents of onychomycosis. J Mycol Med 2015; 25: 101-107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Nakrieko K-A. Molecular determination of mixed infections of dermatophytes and nondermatophyte molds in individuals with onychomycosis. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2014; 104: 330-336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebihara M, Makimura K, Sato K, Abe S, Tsuboi R. Molecular detection of dermatophytes and nondermatophytes in onychomycosis by nested polymerase chain reaction based on 28S ribosomal RNA gene sequences. Br J Dermatol 2009; 161: 1038-1044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menotti J, Machouart M, Benderdouche M et al. Polymerase chain reaction for diagnosis of dermatophyte and Scytalidium spp. onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2004; 15: 518-519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Bruni F, Starace M. Dermoscopy of non-skin cancer nail disorders. Dermatol Ther 2012; 25: 594-602.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nada EE-DA, El Taieb MA, El-Feky MA et al. Diagnosis of onychomycosis clinically by nail dermoscopy versus microbiological diagnosis. Arch Dermatol Res 2020; 312: 207-212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piraccini BM, Balestri R, Starace M, Rech G. Nail digital dermoscopy (onychoscopy) in the diagnosis of onychomycosis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2013; 27: 509-513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bet DL, dos Reis AL, Chiacchio ND, Belda Junior W. Dermoscopy and Onychomycosis: guided nail abrasion for mycological samples. An Bras Dermatol 2015; 90: 904-906.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Hoshy KH, Abdel Hay RM, El-Sherif RH, Salah Eldin M, Moussa MF. Nail dermoscopy is a helpful tool in the diagnosis of onychomycosis: A case control study. Eur J Dermatol 2015; 25: 494-495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos Pinheiro R, Dias Domingues T, Sousa V, Galhardas C, Apetato M, Lencastre A. A comparative study of onychomycosis and traumatic toenail onychodystrophy dermoscopic patterns. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2019; 33: 786-792.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlahovic. Can dermoscopy be beneficial for point of care diagnosis of onychomycosis? Podiatry Today 2020; 33: 34-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdallah NA, Said M, Mahmoud MT, Omar MA. Onychomycosis: Correlation between the dermoscopic patterns and fungal culture. J Cosmet Dermatol 2020; 19: 1196-1204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaya islamoğlu zeynep gizem. Nail digital dermoscopy in onychomycosis: correlation with clinical type, gender and culture examination. Erciyes Med J 2019; 41: 288-294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaias N, Rebell G, Escovar S. Asymmetric gait nail unit syndrome: the most common worldwide toenail abnormality and onychomycosis. Skinmed 2014; 12: 217-223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaias N, Escovar SX, Zaiac MN et al. Onychomycosis, the active invasion of a normal nail unit by a dermatophytic versus the colonization of an existing abnormal nail unit by environmental fungus. Skinmed 2020; 18: 18-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore MK. Morphological and physiological studies of isolates of Hendersonula toruloidea Nattrass cultured from human skin and nail samples. J Med Vet Mycol 1988; 26: 25-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris-Jones R, Youngchim S, Hextall JM et al. Scytalidium dimidiatum causing recalcitrant subcutaneous lesions produces melanin. J Clin Microbiol 2004; 42: 3789-3794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madrid H, Ruíz-Cendoya M, Cano J, Stchigel A, Orofino R, Guarro J. Genotyping and in vitro antifungal susceptibility of Neoscytalidium dimidiatum isolates from different origins. Int J Antimicrob Agents 2009; 34: 351-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Jain HC, Lynde CW, Watteel GN, Summerbell RC. Prevalence and epidemiology of unsuspected onychomycosis in patients visiting dermatologists’ offices in Ontario, Canada-a multicenter survey of 2001 patients. Int J Dermatol 1997; 36: 783-787.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Doncker PRG, Scher RK, Baran RL et al. Itraconazole therapy is effective for pedal onychomycosis caused by some nondermatophyte molds and in mixed infection with dermatophytes and molds: A multicenter study with 36 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol 1997; 36: 173-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godoy-Martinez P, Nunes FG, Tomimori-Yamashita J et al. Onychomycosis in São Paulo, Brazil. Mycopathologia 2009; 168: 111-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvarado Z, Pereira C. Fungal diseases in children and adolescents in a referral centre in Bogota, Colombia. Mycoses 2018; 61: 543-548.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guilhermetti E, Takahachi G, Shinobu CS, Svidzinski TIE. Fusarium spp. as agents of onychomycosis in immunocompetent hosts. Int J Dermatol 2007; 46: 822-826.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maraki S, Mavromanolaki VE. Epidemiology of onychomycosis in Crete, Greece: a 12-year study. Mycoses 2016; 59: 798-802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubljanin E, Džamić A, Vujčić I et al. Epidemiology of onychomycosis in Serbia: a laboratory-based survey and risk factor identification. Mycoses 2017; 60: 25-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gianni C, Cerri A, Crosti C. Non-dermatophytic onychomycosis. An understimated entity? A study of 51 cases. Mycoses 2000; 43: 29-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ioannidou DJ, Maraki S, Krasagakis SK, Tosca A, Tselentis Y. The epidemiology of onychomycoses in Crete, Greece, between 1992 and 2001. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2006; 20: 170-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini BM, Lorenzi S. Onychomycosis caused by nondermatophytic molds: clinical features and response to treatment of 59 cases. J Am Acad Dermatol 2000; 42(2 Pt 1): 217-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregoriou S, Mpali N, Vrioni G, Hatzidimitriou E, Chryssou S-E, Rigopoulos D. Epidemiology of onychomycosis in an academic nail unit in south Greece during a three-year period. Skin Appendage Disord 2020; 6: 102-107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vella Zahra L, Gatt P, Boffa MJ et al. Characteristics of superficial mycoses in Malta. Int J Dermatol 2003; 42: 265-271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bokhari MA, Hussain I, Jahangir M, Haroon TS, Aman S, Khurshid K. Onychomycosis in Lahore, Pakistan. Int J Dermatol 1999; 38: 591-595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salakshna N, Bunyaratavej S, Matthapan L, Lertrujiwanit K, Leeyaphan C. A cohort study of risk factors, clinical presentations and outcomes for dermatophyte, non-dermatophyte and mixed toenail infections. J Am Acad Dermatol 2018; 79: 1145-1146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youssef AB, Kallel A, Azaiz Z et al. Onychomycosis: which fungal species are involved? Experience of the laboratory of parasitology-mycology of the Rabta hospital of Tunis. J Mycol Med 2018; 28: 651-654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal R, Shemer A, Hochberg M et al. Onychomycosis in Israel: epidemiological aspects. Mycoses 2015; 58: 133-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>del Palacio A, Cuétara M-S, Garau M, Perea S. Onychomycosis: a prospective survey of prevalence and etiology in Madrid. Int J Dermatol 2006; 45: 874-876.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erbagci Z, Tuncel A, Zer Y, Balci I. A prospective epidemiologic survey on the prevalence of onychomycosis and dermatophytosis in male boarding school residents. Mycopathologia 2005; 159: 347-352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Horgan-Bell CB, Summerbell RC. Onychomycosis associated with Onychocola canadensis: ten case reports and a review of the literature. J Am Acad Dermatol 1998; 39: 410-417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Donoghue NB, Moore MK, Creamer D. Onychomycosis due to Onychocola canadensis. Clin Exp Dermatol 2003; 28: 283-284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigler L, Congly H. Toenail infection caused by Onychocola canadensis gen. et sp. nov. J Med Vet Mycol 1990; 28: 405-417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Renaud HJ, Quinlan EM, Shear NH, Piguet V. The growing problem of antifungal resistance in onychomycosis and other superficial mycoses. Am J Clin Dermatol 2021; 22: 149-157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pai V, Ganavalli A, Kikkeri NN. Antifungal resistance in dermatology. Indian J Dermatol 2018; 63: 361-368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saunte DML, Hare RK, Jørgensen KM et al. Emerging terbinafine resistance in Trichophyton: clinical characteristics, squalene epoxidase gene mutations, and a reliable EUCAST method for detection. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2019; 63: e01126-e1219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada T, Maeda M, Alshahni MM et al. Terbinafine resistance of Trichophyton clinical isolates caused by specific point mutations in the squalene epoxidase gene. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2017; 61: e00115-e117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh A, Masih A, Khurana A et al. High terbinafine resistance in Trichophyton interdigitale isolates in Delhi, India harbouring mutations in the squalene epoxidase gene. Mycoses 2018; 61: 477-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Paquet M. Management of Onychomycosis in Canada in 2014. J Cutan Med Surg 2015; 19: 260-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jo Siu WJ, Tatsumi Y, Senda H et al. Comparison of in vitro antifungal activities of efinaconazole and currently available antifungal agents against a variety of pathogenic fungi associated with onychomycosis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2013; 57: 1610-1616.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamura T, Asahara M, Yamamoto M et al. In vitro susceptibility of dermatomycoses agents to six antifungal drugs and evaluation by fractional inhibitory concentration index of combined effects of amorolfine and itraconazole in dermatophytes. Microbiol Immunol 2014; 58: 1-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curatolo R, Juricevic N, Leong C, Bosshard PP. Antifungal susceptibility testing of dermatophytes: Development and evaluation of an optimised broth microdilution method. Mycoses 2021; 64: 282-291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfaller MA. Antifungal drug resistance: mechanisms, epidemiology, and consequences for treatment. Am J Med. 2012; 125(1 Suppl): S3-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanguinetti M, Posteraro B. New approaches for antifungal susceptibility testing. Clin Microbiol Infect 2017; 23: 931-934.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arendrup MC, Kahlmeter G, Guinea J, Meletiadis J. Subcommittee on Antifungal Susceptibility Testing (AFST) of the ESCMID European Committee for Antimicrobial Susceptibility Testing (EUCAST). How to: perform antifungal susceptibility testing of microconidia-forming dermatophytes following the new reference EUCAST method E.Def 11.0, exemplified by Trichophyton. Clin Microbiol Infect 2021; 27: 55-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arendrup MC, Meletiadis J, Mouton JW, Lagrou K, Hamal P, Guinea J. Eucast Definitive Document E.DEF 9.3.2. 2020; 23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander BD. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute. Reference method for broth dilution antifungal susceptibility testing of filamentous fungi. 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reference method for broth dilution antifungal susceptibility testing of filamentous fungi. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute.; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novartis Pharmaceuticals Canada Inc. LAMISIL* (terbinafine hydrochloride) 250 mg tablets Product Monograph [Internet]; 2016 [cited 2020 Dec 10]. Available from: http://www.ask.novartispharma.ca/download.htm?res=lamisil_scrip_e.pdf&amp;resTitleId=728</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bausch Health Companies Inc. JUBLIA® (efinaconazole) topical solution [Internet]. Drugs@FDA; 2020 [cited 2020 Dec 2]. Available from: https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2020/203567s009lbl.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfizer Canada Inc. DIFLUCAN 150* Fluconazole Capsule 150 mg Product Monograph [Internet]. 2019 [cited 2020 Dec 10]. Available from: http://www.pfizer.ca/en/our_products/products/monograph/178</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Ryder JE, Summerbell RC. The diagnosis of nondermatophyte mold onychomycosis. Int J Dermatol 2003; 42: 272-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hwang SM, Suh MK, Ha GY. Onychomycosis due to nondermatophytic molds. Ann Dermatol 2012; 24: 175-180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Gregurek-Novak T, Konnikov N, Lynde CW, Hofstader S, Summerbell RC. Itraconazole and terbinafine treatment of some nondermatophyte molds causing onychomycosis of the toes and a review of the literature. J Cutan Med Surg 2001; 5: 206-210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gianni C, Romano C. Clinical and histological aspects of toenail onychomycosis caused by Aspergillus spp.: 34 cases treated with weekly intermittent terbinafine. Dermatology (Basel) 2004; 209: 104-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Gregurek-Novak T. Efficacy of itraconazole, terbinafine, fluconazole, griseofulvin and ketoconazole in the treatment of Scopulariopsis brevicaulis causing onychomycosis of the toes. Dermatology (Basel) 2001; 202: 235-238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolting S, Brautigam M, Weidinger G. Terbinafine in onychomycosis with involvement by non-dermatophytic fungi. Br J Dermatol 1994; 130(Suppl 43): 16-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Gupta AK, Kamshov S et al. Continuous terbinafine and pulse itraconazole for the treatment of non-dermatophyte mold toenail onychomycosis. J Dermatolog Treat 2019; 1-4. https://doi.org/10.1080/09546634.2019.1654598</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacroix C, de Chauvin MF. In vitro activity of amphotericin B, itraconazole, voriconazole, posaconazole, caspofungin and terbinafine against Scytalidium dimidiatum and Scytalidium hyalinum clinical isolates. J Antimicrob Chemother 2008; 61: 835-837.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janssen Pharmaceutica. Sporanox. Package Insert (Itraconazole) Capsules, 100 mg [Internet]. Drugs@FDA: FDA Approved Drug Products. 2009 [cited 2020 Dec 10]. Available from: https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2009/020083s040s041s044lbl.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilaberte Y, Aspiroz C, Martes MP, Alcalde V, Espinel-Ingroff A, Rezusta A. Treatment of refractory fingernail onychomycosis caused by nondermatophyte molds with methylaminolevulinate photodynamic therapy. J Am Acad Dermatol 2011; 65: 669-671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zotti M, Machetti M, Perotti M, Barabino G, Persi A. A new species, Aspergillus persii, as an agent of onychomycosis. Med Mycol 2010; 48: 656-660.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ameen M, Lear JT, Madan V, Mohd Mustapa MF, Richardson M. British Association of Dermatologists’ guidelines for the management of onychomycosis 2014. Br J Dermatol 2014; 171: 937-958.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novartis. LAMISIL (terbinafine hydrochloride) Tablets, 250 mg [Internet]. Drugs@FDA; [cited 2020 Dec 10]. Available from: http://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2012/020539s021lbl.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE. Onychomycosis: pathogenesis, diagnosis, and management. Clin Microbiol Rev 1998; 11: 415-429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis DH, Watson AB, Marley JE, Williams TG. Non-dermatophytes in onychomycosis of the toenails. Br J Dermatol 1997; 136: 490-493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lurati M, Baudraz-Rosselet F, Vernez M et al. Efficacious treatment of non-dermatophyte mould onychomycosis with topical amphotericin B. Dermatology 2011; 223: 289-292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
