<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">33771955</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9235</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>98</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Optometry and vision science : official publication of the American Academy of Optometry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Optom Vis Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Gas-Permeable Contact Lenses and Water Exposure: Practices and Perceptions.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>258</StartPage>
          <EndPage>265</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>258-265</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/OPX.0000000000001660</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE">This study provides insight into the current recommendations, clinical behaviors, and risk assessments of eye care professionals on the topic of rigid contact lens exposure to tap water. This knowledge may motivate professional organizations to develop initiatives to educate eye care professionals on the dangers of contact lens exposure to water.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">The purpose of this study was to investigate the practice patterns and risk perceptions of eye care professionals regarding gas-permeable contact lens exposure to tap water.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">A branched-logic survey was started by 320 clinicians, vision scientists, and industry personnel and was fully completed by 272 participants. The survey queried participants about their current practices, recommendations, and perceptions of risk regarding exposure of gas-permeable contact lenses to tap water.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of those who prescribe gas-permeable contact lenses, 57.4% reported rinsing lenses with tap water, whereas only 32.7% reported engaging in this same behavior in front of patients. Of those who reported never rinsing lenses with tap water, 85.6% indicated that rinsing lenses with water increases infection risk, whereas 52.1% of those who rinse lenses with water reported the same perceived risk (P &lt; .001). Of all participants, 60% indicated that wearing contact lenses while showering increases infection risk, and 50.2% of all participants advised patients to avoid this behavior.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A discrepancy exists between perceptions of risk concerning exposure of contact lenses to water and both clinical practices and patient education provided by professionals.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 American Academy of Optometry.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Steele</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kelsy R</ForeName>
            <Initials>KR</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wagner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heidi</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Ohio State University, College of Optometry, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicky</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Ohio State University, College of Optometry, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zimmerman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aaron B</ForeName>
            <Initials>AB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Ohio State University, College of Optometry, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Optom Vis Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8904931</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1040-5488</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018639">Contact Lens Solutions</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>059QF0KO0R</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014867">Water</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018639" MajorTopicYN="N">Contact Lens Solutions</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003261" MajorTopicYN="N">Contact Lenses</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000469" MajorTopicYN="N">parasitology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015817" MajorTopicYN="N">Eye Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="Y">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015438" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Behavior</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006306" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Surveys</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011364" MajorTopicYN="N">Professional Practice</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017755" MajorTopicYN="N">Prosthesis Fitting</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014867" MajorTopicYN="N">Water</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest Disclosure: None of the authors have reported a financial conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>54</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33771955</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/OPX.0000000000001660</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006324-202103000-00012</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cope JR, Collier SA, Rao MM, et al. Contact Lens Wearer Demographics and Risk Behaviors for Contact Lens–related Eye Infections—United States, 2014. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2015;64:865–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efron N, Morgan PB, Woods CA; International Contact Lens Prescribing Survey Consortium. International Survey of Rigid Contact Lens Fitting. Optom Vis Sci 2013;90:113–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Legarreta JE, Nau AC, Dhaliwal DK. Acanthamoeba Keratitis Associated with Tap Water Use during Contact Lens Cleaning: Manufacturer Guidelines Need to Change. Eye Contact Lens 2013;39:158–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Jonckheere JF. Ecology of Acanthamoeba. Rev Infect Dis 1991;13(Suppl. 5):S385–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stehr-Green JK, Bailey TM, Visvesvara GS. The Epidemiology of Acanthamoeba Keratitis in the United States. Am J Ophthalmol 1989;107:331–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown AC, Ross J, Jones DB, et al. Risk Factors for Acanthamoeba Keratitis—A Multistate Case-control Study, 2008–2011. Eye Contact Lens 2018;44(Suppl. 1):S173–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schaumberg DA, Snow KK, Dana MR. The Epidemic of Acanthamoeba Keratitis: Where Do We Stand?Cornea 1998;17:3–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radford CF, Minassian DC, Dart JK. Acanthamoeba Keratitis in England and Wales: Incidence, Outcome, and Risk Factors. Br J Ophthalmol 2002;86:536–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoder JS, Verani J, Heidman N, et al. Acanthamoeba Keratitis: The Persistence of Cases Following a Multistate Outbreak. Ophthalmic Epidemiol 2012;19:221–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McAllum P, Bahar I, Kaiserman I, et al. Temporal and Seasonal Trends in Acanthamoeba Keratitis. Cornea 2009;28:7–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKelvie J, Alshiakhi M, Ziaei M, et al. The Rising Tide of Acanthamoeba Keratitis in Auckland, New Zealand: A 7-year Review of Presentation, Diagnosis and Outcomes (2009–2016). Clin Experiment Ophthalmol 2018;46:600–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cope JR, Collier SA, Schein OD, et al. Acanthamoeba Keratitis among Rigid Gas Permeable Contact Lens Wearers in the United States, 2005 through 2011. Ophthalmology 2016;123:1435–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kam KW, Yung W, Li GKH, et al. Infectious Keratitis and Orthokeratology Lens Use: A Systematic Review. Infection 2017;45:727–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watt K, Swarbrick HA. Microbial Keratitis in Overnight Orthokeratology: Review of the First 50 Cases. Eye Contact Lens 2005;31:201–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilvington S, Gray T, Dart J, et al. Acanthamoeba Keratitis: The Role of Domestic Tap Water Contamination in the United Kingdom. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2004;45:165–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnt NA, Subedi D, Connor S, et al. The Relationship between Environmental Sources and the Susceptibility of Acanthamoeba Keratitis in the United Kingdom. PLoS One 2020;15:e0229681.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joslin CE, Tu EY, McMahon TT, et al. Epidemiological Characteristics of a Chicago-area Acanthamoeba Keratitis Outbreak. Am J Ophthalmol 2006;142:212–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmerman AB, Richdale K, Mitchell GL, et al. Water Exposure Is a Common Risk Behavior among Soft and Gas-permeable Contact Lens Wearers. Cornea 2017;36:995–1001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Water and Contact Lenses; 2020. Available at: http://www.cdc.gov/contactlenses/water-and-contact-lenses.html. Accessed February 22, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Optometric Association (AOA). Lens Care. Available at: https://www.aoa.org/patients-and-public/caring-for-your-vision/contact-lenses/lens-care. Accessed April 20, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Contact Lens Risks; 2018. Available at: https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/contact-lenses/contact-lens-risks. Accessed April 20, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnt N, Stapleton F. Strategies for the Prevention of Contact Lens–related Acanthamoeba Keratitis: A Review. Ophthalmic Physiol Opt 2016;36:77–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arshad M, Carnt N, Tan J, et al. Compliance Behaviour Change in Contact Lens Wearers: A Randomised Controlled Trial. Eye (Lond) 2021;35:988–95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein D, Guenther C, Ross S. Do as I Say, Not as I Do. Can Fam Physician 2016;62:e393–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Logan DE, Mastroleo NR, Wood MD, et al. Do as I Say, Not as I Do. J Drug Educ 2016;46:15–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone E, Allgaier L. A Social Values Analysis of Self-other Differences in Decision Making Involving Risk. Basic Appl Soc Psych 2008;30:114–29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ubel PA, Angott AM, Zikmund-Fisher BJ. Physicians Recommend Different Treatments for Patients Than They Would Choose for Themselves. Arch Intern Med 2011;171:630–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Retamero R, Galesic M. Doc, What Would You Do if You Were Me? On Self-other Discrepancies in Medical Decision Making. J Exp Psychol Appl 2012;18:38–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta DM, Boland RJ Jr., Aron DC. The Physician's Experience of Changing Clinical Practice: A Struggle to Unlearn. Implement Sci 2017;12:28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ubel PA, Asch DA. Creating Value in Health by Understanding and Overcoming Resistance to De-innovation. Health Aff (Millwood) 2015;34:239–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris ZS, Wooding S, Grant J. The Answer Is 17 Years, What Is the Question: Understanding Time Lags in Translational Research. J R Soc Med 2011;104:510–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harthan J, Nau CB, Barr J, et al. Scleral Lens Prescription and Management Practices: The SCOPE Study. Eye Contact Lens 2018;44(Suppl. 1):S228–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paugh JR, Chen E, Heinrich C, et al. Silicone Hydrogel and Rigid Gas-permeable Scleral Lens Tear Exchange. Eye Contact Lens 2018;44:97–101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tse V, Tan B, Kim YH, et al. Tear Dynamics under Scleral Lenses. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2019;42:43–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bullimore MA, Sinnott LT, Jones-Jordan LA. The Risk of Microbial Keratitis with Overnight Corneal Reshaping Lenses. Optom Vis Sci 2013;90:937–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan PB, Efron N, Woods CA, et al. International Survey of Orthokeratology Contact Lens Fitting. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2019;42:450–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michaud L, van der Worp E, Brazeau D, et al. Predicting Estimates of Oxygen Transmissibility for Scleral Lenses. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2012;35:266–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lum E, Swarbrick HA. Lens Dk/T Influences the Clinical Response in Overnight Orthokeratology. Optom Vis Sci 2011;88:469–75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnston SP, Sriram R, Qvarnstrom Y, et al. Resistance of Acanthamoeba Cysts to Disinfection in Multiple Contact Lens Solutions. J Clin Microbiol 2009;47:2040–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abjani F, Khan NA, Jung SY, et al. Status of the Effectiveness of Contact Lens Disinfectants in Malaysia against Keratitis-causing Pathogens. Exp Parasitol 2017;183:187–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boost MV, Shi GS, Lai S, et al. Amoebicidal Effects of Contact Lens Disinfecting Solutions. Optom Vis Sci 2012;89:44–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shoff ME, Joslin CE, Tu EY, et al. Efficacy of Contact Lens Systems against Recent Clinical and Tap Water Acanthamoeba Isolates. Cornea 2008;27:713–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nichols JJ, Chalmers RL, Dumbleton K, et al. The Case for Using Hydrogen Peroxide Contact Lens Care Solutions: A Review. Eye Contact Lens 2019;45:69–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim CH, Carnt NA, Farook M, et al. Risk Factors for Contact Lens–related Microbial Keratitis in Singapore. Eye (Lond) 2016;30:447–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szczotka-Flynn LB, Imamura Y, Chandra J, et al. Increased Resistance of Contact Lens–related Bacterial Biofilms to Antimicrobial Activity of Soft Contact Lens Care Solutions. Cornea 2009;28:918–26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Optometric Association (AOA). Contact Lens Case Care. Available at: https://www.aoa.org/patients-and-public/caring-for-your-vision/contact-lenses/case-care. Accessed January 22, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Focusing on Contact Lens Safety. Available at: https://www.fda.gov/consumers/consumer-updates/focusing-contact-lens-safety. Accessed April 30, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YT, Zhu H, Harmis NY, et al. Profile and Frequency of Microbial Contamination of Contact Lens Cases. Optom Vis Sci 2010;87:E152–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devonshire P, Munro FA, Abernethy C, et al. Microbial Contamination of Contact Lens Cases in the West of Scotland. Br J Ophthalmol 1993;77:41–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larkin DF, Kilvington S, Easty DL. Contamination of Contact Lens Storage Cases by Acanthamoeba and Bacteria. Br J Ophthalmol 1990;74:133–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stapleton F, Arshad M, Carnt N, et al. The Effect of Water Exposure on Contact Lens Storage Case Contamination. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2019;42:e34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ustunturk M, Zeybek Z. Microbial Contamination of Contact Lens Storage Cases and Domestic Tap Water of Contact Lens Wearers. Wien Klin Wochenschr 2012;124(Suppl. 3):17–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tilia D, Lazon de la Jara P, Zhu H, et al. The Effect of Compliance on Contact Lens Case Contamination. Optom Vis Sci 2014;91:262–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YT, Zhu H, Willcox M, et al. Removal of Biofilm from Contact Lens Storage Cases. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2010;51:6329–33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choo J, Vuu K, Bergenske P, et al. Bacterial Populations on Silicone Hydrogel and Hydrogel Contact Lenses After Swimming in a Chlorinated Pool. Optom Vis Sci 2005;82:134–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radford CF, Lehmann OJ, Dart JK. Acanthamoeba Keratitis: Multicentre Survey in England 1992–6. National Acanthamoeba Keratitis Study Group. Br J Ophthalmol 1998;82:1387–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stehr-Green JK, Bailey TM, Brandt FH, et al. Acanthamoeba Keratitis in Soft Contact Lens Wearers. A Case-control Study. JAMA 1987;258:57–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arance-Gil Á, Gutiérrez-Ortega ÁR, Villa-Collar C, et al. Corneal Cross-linking for Acanthamoeba Keratitis in an Orthokeratology Patient After Swimming in Contaminated Water. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2014;37:224–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnt N, Hoffman JJMBBS, Verma S, et al. Acanthamoeba Keratitis: Confirmation of the UK Outbreak and a Prospective Case-control Study Identifying Contributing Risk Factors. Br J Ophthalmol 2018;102:1621–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YT, Tran J, Truong M, et al. Do Swimming Goggles Limit Microbial Contamination of Contact Lenses?Optom Vis Sci 2011;88:456–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stapleton F, Keay L, Jalbert I, et al. The Epidemiology of Contact Lens Related Infiltrates. Optom Vis Sci 2007;84:257–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hassan F, Bhatti A, Desai R, et al. Analysis from a Year of Increased Cases of Acanthamoeba Keratitis in a Large Teaching Hospital in the UK. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2019;42:506–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stapleton F, Naduvilath T, Keay L, et al. Risk Factors and Causative Organisms in Microbial Keratitis in Daily Disposable Contact Lens Wear. PLoS One 2017;12:e0181343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verani JR, Lorick SA, Yoder JS, et al. National Outbreak of Acanthamoeba Keratitis Associated with Use of a Contact Lens Solution, United States. Emerg Infect Dis 2009;15:1236–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sorbara L, Zimmerman AB, Mitchell GL, et al. Multicenter Testing of a Risk Assessment Survey for Soft Contact Lens Wearers with Adverse Events: A Contact Lens Assessment in Youth Study. Eye Contact Lens 2018;44:21–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robertson DM, Cavanagh HD. Non-compliance with Contact Lens Wear and Care Practices: A Comparative Analysis. Optom Vis Sci 2011;88:1402–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breiman RF, Fields BS, Sanden GN, et al. Association of Shower Use with Legionnaires' Disease. Possible Role of Amoebae. JAMA 1990;263:2924–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joslin CE, Tu EY, Shoff ME, et al. The Association of Contact Lens Solution Use and Acanthamoeba Keratitis. Am J Ophthalmol 2007;144:169–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
