<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">33788998</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1934-6638</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>129</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cancer cytopathology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cancer Cytopathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Analysis of the risk of malignancy associated with the basaloid and oncocytic subtypes of the salivary gland neoplasm of unknown malignant potential (SUMP) category in the Milan system.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>603</StartPage>
          <EndPage>611</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>603-611</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cncy.22427</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The salivary gland neoplasm of unknown malignant potential (SUMP) category reflects the cytomorphologic overlap and complexity of reporting salivary gland cytology in the Milan system. It includes neoplasms for which a diagnosis of a specific entity cannot be made and, more importantly, for which a carcinoma cannot be entirely excluded. For risk stratification, the subcategorization of SUMP based on the predominant cell type is recommended. This study was aimed at evaluating the risk of neoplasm (RON) and the risk of malignancy (ROM) of the basaloid and oncocytic subtypes of the SUMP category.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective analysis of 482 salivary gland fine-needle aspirations from 2012 to 2019 resulted in 48 SUMP cases. The cytology of these cases was reviewed and reclassified as the basaloid or oncocytic subtype. Surgical follow-up was available for 36 cases. The RON and ROM for each subtype were calculated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The RON and ROM were 100% and 23%, respectively, for monomorphic basaloid tumors and 88% and 58.8%, respectively, for monomorphic oncocytic tumors. The ROM for basaloid tumors was 8.3% without matrix/with minimal matrix and 60% with an nonfibrillary matrix. The ROM for oncocytic tumors was 50% without a cystic background and 60% with a cystic or mucinous background. The difference was not statistically significant for either of the subgroups.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Even though statistically not significant in our study, the differential ROMs within the oncocytic and basaloid subgroups help in the risk stratification of SUMP cases. Further subcategorization based on the stroma and background helps in limiting the differential diagnosis but does not necessarily add to the value of the risk stratification.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American Cancer Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manucha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Varsha</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3943-635X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Mississippi Medical Center, Jackson, Mississippi.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gonzalez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria F</ForeName>
            <Initials>MF</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2804-4104</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Mississippi Medical Center, Jackson, Mississippi.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Akhtar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Israh</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Mississippi Medical Center, Jackson, Mississippi.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cancer Cytopathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101499453</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1934-662X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D044963" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy, Fine-Needle</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D024862" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxyphil Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012468" MajorTopicYN="Y">Salivary Gland Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012469" MajorTopicYN="N">Salivary Glands</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology (MSRSGC)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">basaloid</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">fine-needle aspiration (FNA)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">oncocytic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">salivary gland neoplasm of unknown malignant potential (SUMP)</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33788998</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncy.22427</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faquin WC, Rossi ED, Baloch Z, et al. The Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology. 1st ed. Springer International Publishing AG; 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farahani SJ, Baloch Z. Retrospective assessment of the effectiveness of the Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytology: a systematic review and meta-analysis of published literature. Diagn Cytopathol. 2019;47:67-87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jalaly JB, Farahani SJ, Baloch ZW. The Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology: a comprehensive review of the literature. Diagn Cytopathol. 2020;48:880-889.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossi ED, Faquin WC. The Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology: the clinical impact so far. Considerations from theory to practice. Cytopathology. 2020;31:181-184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffith CC, Pai RK, Schneider F, et al. Salivary gland tumor fine-needle aspiration cytology: a proposal for a risk stratification classification. Am J Clin Pathol. 2015;143:839-853.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffith CC, Schmitt AC, Pantanowitz L, Monaco SE. A pattern-based risk-stratification scheme for salivary gland cytology: a multi-institutional, interobserver variability study to determine applicability. Cancer Cytopathol. 2017;125:776-785.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chowsilpa S, An D, Lose H, Huang X, Nayar R, Maleki Z. Risk of malignancy associated with cytomorphology subtypes in the salivary gland neoplasm of uncertain malignant potential (SUMP) category in the Milan system: a bi-institutional study. Cancer Cytopathol. 2019;127:377-389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hang JF, Alruwaii F, Zeng BR, Lai CR, Wu HH. Subtyping salivary gland neoplasm of uncertain malignant potential based on cell type demonstrates differential risk of malignancy. Cancer Cytopathol. 2018;126:924-933.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu H, Ljungren C, Lin F, Zarka MA, Chen L. Analysis of histologic follow-up and risk of malignancy for salivary gland neoplasm of uncertain malignant potential proposed by the Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology. Cancer Cytopathol. 2018;126:490-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gargano SM, Sebastiano C, Solomides CC, Griffith CC, HooKim K. Cytohistologic correlation of basaloid salivary gland neoplasms: can cytomorphologic classification be used to diagnose and grade these tumors? Cancer Cytopathol. 2020;128:92-99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lubin DJ, Griffith CC, Buonocore DJ, Wei XJ, Lin O. Putting morphology to the test: an established classification scheme reliably stratifies salivary gland cytology by risk of malignancy with substantial interobserver agreement. Cancer Cytopathol. Published online November 2, 2020. doi:10.1002/cncy.22382</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Layfield LJ, Esebua M, Yang Z, Vatzmitsel M, Giorgadze T, Schmidt R. The Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology: a study of inter-observer reproducibility. Diagn Cytopathol. 2019;47:765-768.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elsheikh TM, Bernacki EG. Fine needle aspiration cytology of cellular pleomorphic adenoma. Acta Cytol. 1996;40:1165-1175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabatabai ZL, Auger M, Kurtycz DF, et al. Performance characteristics of adenoid cystic carcinoma of the salivary glands in fine-needle aspirates: results from the College of American Pathologists Nongynecologic Cytology Program. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2015;139:1525-1530.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cantley RL. Fine-needle aspiration cytology of cellular basaloid neoplasms of the salivary gland. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2019;143:1338-1345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chowsilpa S, An D, Maleki Z. Adenoid cystic carcinoma cytology: salivary gland and nonsalivary gland. Diagn Cytopathol. 2020;48:1282-1289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maleki Z, Allison DB, Butcher M, Kawamoto S, Eisele DW, Pantanowitz L. Application of the Milan System for Reporting Salivary Gland Cytopathology to cystic salivary gland lesions. Cancer Cytopathol. Published online October 1, 2020. doi:10.1002/cncy.22363</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salehi S, Maleki Z. Diagnostic challenges and problem cases in salivary gland cytology: a 20-year experience. Cancer Cytopathol. 2018;126:101-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sučić M, Ljubić N, Perković L, et al. Cytopathology and diagnostics of Warthin's tumour. Cytopathology. 2020;31:193-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shafique K, Zhang PJ, Montone KT, Song S, Livolsi VA, Baloch Z. Pathologic grading of mucoepidermoid carcinomas of the salivary gland and its effect on clinicopathologic follow-up: an institutional experience. Hum Pathol. 2020;98:89-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamamoto Y, Harada H, Kohara M, Honma K, Nakatsuka SI, Morii E. Usefulness of immunohistochemistry to distinguish between secretory carcinoma and acinic cell carcinoma in the salivary gland. Med Mol Morphol. Published June 1, 2020. doi:10.1007/s00795-020-00256-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skaugen JM, Seethala RR, Chiosea SI, Landau MS. Evaluation of NR4A3 immunohistochemistry (IHC) and fluorescence in situ hybridization and comparison with DOG1 IHC for FNA diagnosis of acinic cell carcinoma. Cancer Cytopathol. Published online August 18, 2020. doi:10.1002/cncy.22338</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
