<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33827169</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1042-7260</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>52</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of zoo and wildlife medicine : official publication of the American Association of Zoo Veterinarians</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Zoo Wildl Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>SAFETY OF MULTIPLE-DOSE INTRAMUSCULAR KETOPROFEN TREATMENT IN LOGGERHEAD TURTLES (<i>CARETTA CARETTA</i>).</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>126</StartPage>
          <EndPage>132</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>126-132</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1638/2020-0159</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Sea turtles are frequently presented for rehabilitation with injuries for which analgesic treatment is warranted. Ketoprofen is a nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug (NSAID) widely used in clinical veterinary medicine for musculoskeletal pain relief. Pharmacokinetics of 2 mg/kg IM have been studied in loggerhead sea turtles (<i>Caretta caretta</i>) as a single and a repeated dose q24hr for 3 days. Safety of longer term administration has not been performed, however, and NSAID use carries a risk of potential complications, including gastrointestinal ulceration, kidney damage, and bleeding. The objective of the current study was to determine the effects of a 5-day course of ketoprofen on thromboelastography (TEG) and hematological (including thrombocytes) and plasma biochemical analytes in loggerheads. A secondary objective was to determine 24-hr trough concentrations of ketoprofen after 5 days of treatment. Eight loggerheads were treated with ketoprofen 2 mg/kg IM q24hr for 5 days, and TEG, hematology, and plasma biochemistry panels were performed before and at the conclusion of treatment. Eight controls were treated with an equivalent volume of saline intramuscularly. Virtually no changes were detected before and after treatment or between treatment and control groups in any of the 24 endpoints evaluated, and marginal differences were not considered clinically relevant. Plasma ketoprofen concentrations after 5 days of treatment indicated no accumulation over that duration. Ketoprofen at 2 mg/kg IM q24hr for up to 5 days in loggerheads appears safe with respect to blood clotting and blood data, although other potential effects were not evaluated.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Harms</LastName>
            <ForeName>Craig A</ForeName>
            <Initials>CA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27606, USA, caharms@ncsu.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Marine Sciences and Technology, North Carolina State University, Morehead City, NC 28557, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ruterbories</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laura K</ForeName>
            <Initials>LK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27606, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stacy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicole I</ForeName>
            <Initials>NI</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Comparative, Diagnostic, and Population Medicine, College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Florida, Gainesville, FL 32608, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Christiansen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emily F</ForeName>
            <Initials>EF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27606, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Marine Sciences and Technology, North Carolina State University, Morehead City, NC 28557, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>North Carolina Aquariums, Raleigh, NC 27604, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Papich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mark G</ForeName>
            <Initials>MG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular and Biomedical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27606, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lynch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alex M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27606, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barratclough</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ashley</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Marine Mammal Foundation, San Diego, CA 92106, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Serrano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria E</ForeName>
            <Initials>ME</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Sciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC 27606, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Marine Sciences and Technology, North Carolina State University, Morehead City, NC 28557, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000081262">Randomized Controlled Trial, Veterinary</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Zoo Wildl Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8915208</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1042-7260</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000894">Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>90Y4QC304K</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007660">Ketoprofen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000894" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Inflammatory Agents, Non-Steroidal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004334" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Administration Schedule</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007660" MajorTopicYN="N">Ketoprofen</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013916" MajorTopicYN="N">Thrombelastography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014426" MajorTopicYN="N">Turtles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827169</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1638/2020-0159</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barratclough A, Hanel R, Stacy N, Ruterbories L, Christiansen E, Harms C. Establishing a protocol for thromboelastography in sea turtles. Vet Rec Open [Internet]. 2018;5:e000240. doi:10.1136/vetreco-2017-000240</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barratclough A, Tuxbury K, Hanel R, Stacy NI, Ruterbories L, Christiansen E, Harms CA. Baseline plasma thromboelastography in Kemp's ridley (<i>Lepidochelys kempii</i>), green (<i>Chelonia mydas</i>) and loggerhead (<i>Caretta caretta</i>) sea turtles and its use to diagnose coagulopathies in cold-stunned Kemp's ridley and green sea turtles. J Zoo Wildl Med. 2019;50(1):62–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brainard BM, Meredith CP, Callan MB, Budsberg SC, Shofer FS, Driessen B, Otto CM. Changes in platelet function, hemostasis, and prostaglandin expression after treatment with nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs with various cyclooxygenase selectivities in dogs. Am J Vet Res. 2007;68(3):251–257.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Claus C, Papich MG, Coy S, Hernandez-Divers S, Berzins IK, Budsberg SC. Pharmacokinetics of meloxicam in loggerhead sea turtles (<i>Caretta caretta</i>) after single dose intravenous administration. In: Proc Int Assoc Aquat Anim Med; 2007. 38:228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franzen-Klein D, Burkhalter B, Sommer R, Weber M, Zirkelbach B, Norton T. Diagnosis and management of marine debris ingestion and entanglement by using advanced imaging and endoscopy in sea turtles. J Herp Med Surg. 2020;30(2):74–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Innis CJ., Staggs LA. Cold stunning. In: Manire CA, Norton TM, Stacy BA, Innis CJ, Harms CA (eds.). Sea turtle health and rehabilitation. Plantation (FL): J Ross Publishing; 2017. p. 675–687.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>KuKanich B, Bidgood T, Knesl O. Clinical pharmacology of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs in dogs. Vet Anaesth Analg 2012;39(1):69–90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar KR, Vennila R, Kanchana S, Arumugam M, Balasubramaniam T. Fibrinogenolytic and anticoagulant activities in the tissue covering the stingers of marine stingrays <i>Dasyatis sephen</i> and <i>Aetobatis narinari</i>. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2011;31(4):464–471.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai OR, Di Bello S, Soloperto S, Freggi, D, Marzano G, Cavaliere L, Crescenzo G. Pharmacokinetic behavior of meloxicam in loggerhead sea turtles (<i>Caretta caretta</i>) after intramuscular and intravenous administration. J Wildl Dis. 2015;51(2):509–512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewbart G, Roe S, Sharp N, Love N, Harms C, Burkart M, Beasley J. Clinical management of a severe skull fracture in a loggerhead sea turtle (<i>Caretta caretta</i>). In: Proc Int Assoc Aquat Anim Med; 2001. 32:64–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mettee NS, Norton TN. Trauma and wound care. In: Manire CA, Norton TM, Stacy BA, Innis CJ, Harms CA (eds.). Sea turtle health and rehabilitation. Plantation (FL): J Ross Publishing; 2017. p. 657–674.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore N, Pollack C, Butkerait P. Adverse drug reactions and drug-drug interactions with over-the-counter NSAIDs. Ther Clin Risk Manag 2015;11: 1061–1075.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norton TM, Mosley CI, Sladky KK, Rousselet E, Walsh MT, Manire CA, Zachariah TT. Analgesia and anesthesia. In: Manire CA, Norton TM, Stacy BA, Innis CJ, Harms CA (eds.). Sea turtle health and rehabilitation. Plantation (FL): J Ross Publishing; 2017. p. 527–550.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plessers E, Watteyn A, Wyns H, Pardon B, De Baere S, De Backer P, Croubels S. Enantioselective pharmacokinetics of ketoprofen in calves after intramuscular administration of a racemic mixture. J Vet Pharmacol Ther. 2014;38(4):410–413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rice WR. Analyzing tables of statistical tests. Evolution. 1989;43(1):223–225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Royal LW, Lascelles D, Lewbart GA, Correa MT, Jones SL. Evaluation of cyclooxygenase protein expression in traumatized versus normal tissues from eastern box turtles (<i>Terrapene carolina carolina</i>). J Zoo Wildl Med. 2012;43(2):289–295.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadler RA, Schumacher J, Rathore K, Newkirk KM, Cole G, Seibert R, Cekanova M. Evaluation of the role of the cyclooxygenase signaling pathway during inflammation in skin and muscle tissues of ball pythons (<i>Python regiu</i>s). Am J Vet Res. 2016;77(5):487–494.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schafer AI. Effects of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs on platelet function and systemic hemostasis. J Clin Pharmacol. 1995;35(3):209–219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sladky KK. Analgesia. In: Mader DR, Divers S (eds.). Current therapy in reptile medicine and surgery. 3rd ed. St. Louis (MO): Elsevier-Saunders; 2014. p. 217–228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soslau G, Prest PJ, Class R, George R, Paladino F, Violetta G. Comparison of sea turtle thrombocyte aggregation to human platelet aggregation in whole blood. Comp Biochem Physiol B Biochem Mol Biol. 2005;142(3):353–360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stacy NI, Innis CJ. Clinical pathology. In: Manire CA, Norton TM, Stacy BA, Innis CJ, Harms CA (eds.). Sea turtle health and rehabilitation. Plantation (FL): J Ross Publishing; 2017. p. 147–207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson KA, Papich MG, Higgins B, Flanagan J, Christiansen E, Harms CA. Ketoprofen pharmacokinetics of <i>R</i>- and <i>S</i>-isomers in juvenile loggerhead sea turtles (<i>Caretta caretta</i>) after single intravenous and single and multiple-dose intramuscular administration. J Vet Pharmacol Ther. 2018;41(2): 340–348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuttle AD, Papich M, Lewbart GA, Christian S, Gunkel C, Harms CA. Pharmacokinetics of ketoprofen in the green iguana (<i>Iguana iguana</i>) following single intravenous and intramuscular injections. J Zoo Wildl Med. 2006;37(4):567–570.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wyneken J, Mader DR, Webber ES 3rd, Merigo C. Medical care of sea turtles. In: Mader DR (ed.). Reptile medicine and surgery. 2nd ed. St. Louis (MO): Saunders Elsevier; 2006. p. 972–1007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
