<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33856061</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0801</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>35</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Biomedical chromatography : BMC</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Chromatogr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Development, validation, and application of a simple UPLC-MS/MS method for simultaneous quantification of five traditional antipsychotics in human plasma.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e5143</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e5143</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bmc.5143</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>A UPLC-MS/MS method was developed to determine the levels of five traditional antipsychotics (APs) (chlorprothixene, perphenazine, fluphenazine, thioridazine, and promethazine) in human plasma with carbamazepine as the internal standard. Samples were extracted using simple liquid-liquid extraction (ethyl acetate/methyl tert-butyl ether, 2:3 v/v); then the analytes were subjected to gradient elution chromatography with a mobile phase composed of 0.1% formic acid in water and acetonitrile. The analytes were separated using a Waters XBridge BEH C<sub>18</sub> column (100 × 2.1 mm, 2.5 μm). The linear ranges of chlorprothixene, perphenazine, fluphenazine, thioridazine, and promethazine are 2-250 ng/mL, r &gt; 0.995. The limit of quantitation is 2 ng/mL, and the limit of detection is in the range of 0.1-0.5 ng/mL. The inter-day and intra-day relative standard deviations are less than 10%, and the relative errors are in the range of -5.70 to 7.20%. The recoveries of the five drugs are in the range of 70-109%. The results of methodology verification indicate that this method is simple, economical, sensitive, and suitable for the simultaneous quantification of five traditional APs in human plasma.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Liju</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4844-018X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Graduate Studies, Hebei Medical University, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Department, Hebei General Hospital, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>An</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Department, Hebei General Hospital, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cui</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yanjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Graduate Studies, Hebei Medical University, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Department, Hebei General Hospital, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhanjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Graduate Studies, Hebei Medical University, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Department, Hebei General Hospital, Shijiazhuang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Biomed Chromatogr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8610241</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0269-3879</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014150">Antipsychotic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014150" MajorTopicYN="N">Antipsychotic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002851" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromatography, High Pressure Liquid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057230" MajorTopicYN="N">Limit of Detection</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016014" MajorTopicYN="N">Linear Models</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059625" MajorTopicYN="N">Liquid-Liquid Extraction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053719" MajorTopicYN="N">Tandem Mass Spectrometry</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UPLC-MS/MS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liquid-liquid extraction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plasma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traditional antipsychotics</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856061</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bmc.5143</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruijnzeel, D., Suryadevara, U., &amp; Tandon, R. (2014). Antipsychotic treatment of schizophrenia: An update. Asian Journal of Psychiatry, 11, 3-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajp.2014.08.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz-Vera, M., Lucena, R., Cardenas, S., &amp; Valcarcel, M. (2009). Determination of phenothiazine derivatives in human urine by using ionic liquid-based dynamic liquid-phase microextraction coupled with liquid chromatography. Journal of Chromatography. B, Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 877(1-2), 37-42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2008.11.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis, C., &amp; Fenimore, D. (1983). Determination of fluphenazine in plasma by high-performance thin-layer chromatography. Journal of Chromatography, 272, 157-165. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0378-4347(00)86112-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falkai, P., Wobrock, T., Lieberman, J., Glenthoj, B., Gattaz, W. F., &amp; Moller, H. J. (2005). World Federation of Societies of biological psychiatry (WFSBP) guidelines for biological treatment of schizophrenia, part 1: Acute treatment of schizophrenia. The World Journal of Biological Psychiatry, 6(3), 132-191. https://doi.org/10.1080/15622970510030090</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gradinaru, J., Vullioud, A., Eap, C. B., &amp; Ansermot, N. (2014). Quantification of typical antipsychotics in human plasma by ultra-high performance liquid chromatography tandem mass spectrometry for therapeutic drug monitoring. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 88, 36-44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpba.2013.07.041</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiemke, C., Baumann, P., Bergemann, N., Conca, A., Dietmaier, O., Egberts, K., Fric, M., Gerlach, M., Greiner, C., Gründer, G., &amp; Haen, E. (2011). AGNP consensus guidelines for therapeutic drug monitoring in psychiatry: Update 2011. Pharmacopsychiatry, 44(6), 195-235. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0031-1286287</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juenke, J. M., Brown, P. I., Urry, F. M., Johnson-Davis, K. L., &amp; McMillin, G. A. (2013). Simultaneous UPLC-MS/MS assay for the detection of the traditional antipsychotics haloperidol, fluphe nazine, perphenazine, and thiothixene in serum and plasma. Clinica Chimica Acta, 423, 32-34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2013.04.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirchherr, H., &amp; Kuhn-Velten, W. N. (2006). Quantitative determination of forty-eight antidepressants and antipsychotics in human serum by HPLC tandem mass spectrometry: A multi-level, single-sample approach. Journal of Chromatography. B, Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 843(1), 100-113. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2006.05.031</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, J., An, J., &amp; Jiang, Y. (2020). Development of a method of hollow fiber-based solid-phase microextraction followed by ultra performance liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry for determination of five antipsychotics in human whole blood and urine. Journal of Chromatography. A, 1620, 461000. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chroma.2020.461000</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mandal, T. K., &amp; Ace, L. N. (1993). High-performance liquid chromatographic determination of perphenazine in plasma. Joumal of Chnical Pharmacy and Therapeutics, 18, 205-208. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2710.1993.tb00614.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meltzer, H. (2000). An atypical compound by any other name is still a. Psychopharmacology, 148, 16-19. https://doi.org/10.1007/s002130050018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyamoto, S., Duncan, G. E., Marx, C. E., &amp; Lieberman, J. A. (2005). Treatments for schizophrenia: A critical review of pharmacology and mechanisms of action of antipsychotic drugs. Molecular Psychiatry, 10(1), 79-104. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.mp.4001556</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mobed, A., Ahmadalipour, A., Fakhari, A., Kazem, S. S., &amp; Saadi, G. K. (2020). Bioassay: A novel approach in antipsychotic pharmacology. Clinica Chimica Acta, 509, 30-35. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2020.05.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mounsey, A. S., Strachan, D., Rowell, F. J., &amp; Tyson, J. D. (1996). Direct determination of some phenothiazine sedatives in greyhound urine by fluoroimmunoassay. Analyst, 121, 955-958. https://doi.org/10.1039/an9962100955</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parsy, C. B., Chapman, C. J., Barnes, A. C., Robertson, J. F., &amp; Murray, A. (2007). Two-step method to isolate target recombinant protein from co-purified bacterial contaminant SlyD aft er immobilised metal affinity chromatography. Journal of Chromatography. B, Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 853(1-2), 314-319. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2007.03.046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patteet, L., Morrens, M., Maudens, K. E., &amp; Neels, H. (2012). Therapeutic drug monitoring of common antipsychotics. Therapeutic Drug Monitoring, 34(6), 629-651. https://doi.org/10.1097/FTD.0b013e3182708ec5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedernera, C., Ruiz, J. L., Castells, G., Manteca, X., &amp; Cristofol, C. (2007). HPLC quantification of perphenazine in sheep plasma: Application to a pharmacokinetic study. Journal of Chromatography. B, Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 854(1-2), 308-312. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2007.04.038</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proenca, P., Monteiro, C., Mustra, C., Claro, A., Franco, J., &amp; Real, F. C. (2020). Identification and quantification of antipsychotics in blood samples by LC-MS-MS: Case reports and data from three years of routine analysis. Journal of Analytical Toxicology, 44, 915-922. https://doi.org/10.1093/jat/bkaa100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pujadas, M., Pichini, S., Civit, E., Santamariña, E., Perez, K., &amp; de la Torre, R. (2007). A simple and reliable procedure for the determination of psychoactive drugs in oral fluid by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 44(2), 594-601. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpba.2007.02.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roman, M. K., Kronstrand, R., Lindstedt, D., &amp; Josefsson, M. (2008). Quantitation of seven low-dosage antipsychotic drugs in human postmortem blood using LC-MS-MS. Journal of Analytical Toxicology, 32, 147-155. https://doi.org/10.1093/jat/32.2.147</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosado, T., Oppolzer, D., Cruz, B., Barroso, M., Varela, S., Oliveira, V., &amp; Gallardo, E. (2018). Development and validation of a gas chromatography/tandem mass spectrometry method for simultaneous quantitation of several antipsychotics in human plasma and oral fluid. Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry, 32(23), 2081-2095. https://doi.org/10.1002/rcm.8087</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Safdarian, M., Ramezani, Z., &amp; Ghadiri, A. A. (2016). Facile synthesis of magnetic molecularly imprinted polymer: Perphenazine template and its application in urine and plasma analysis. Journal of Chromatography a, 1455, 28-36. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chroma.2016.05.083</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saracino, M. A., Amore, M., Baioni, E., Petio, C., &amp; Raggi, M. A. (2008). Determination of selected phenothiazines in human plasma by solid-phase extraction and liquid chromatography with coulometric detection. Analytica Chimica Acta, 624(2), 308-316. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aca.2008.06.040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seeman, P. (2002). Atypical antipsychotics: Mechanism of action. Canadian Journal of Psychiatry, 47, 27-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sempio, C., Morini, L., Vignali, C., &amp; Groppi, A. (2014). Simple and sensitive screening and quantitative determination of 88 psychoactive drugs and their metabolites in blood through LC-MS/MS: Application on postmortem samples. Journal of Chromatography. B, Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 970, 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2014.08.039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shamsayei, M., Yamini, Y., &amp; Asiabi, H. (2018). Electrochemically controlled fiber-in-tube solid-phase microextraction method for the determination of trace amounts of antipsychotic drugs in biological samples. Journal of Separation Science, 41(18), 3598-3606. https://doi.org/10.1002/jssc.201800417</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi, F. S., Liu, J., Zhang, L., Liu, J. X., &amp; Wang, J. P. (2016). Development of an enzyme linked immunosorbent assay for the determination of phenothiazine drugs in meat and animal feeds. Journal of Environmental Science and Health, Part B, 51(10), 715-721. https://doi.org/10.1080/03601234.2016.1191919</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka, E., Nakamura, T., Terada, M., Shinozuka, T., Hashimoto, C., Kurihara, K., &amp; Honda, K. (2007). Simple and simultaneous determination for 12 phenothiazines in human serum by reversed-phase high-performance liquid chromatography. Journal of Chromatography B, 854(1-2), 116-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2007.04.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urinovska, R., Brozmanova, H., Sistik, P., Silhan, P., Kacirova, I., Lemr, K., &amp; Grundmann, M. (2012). Liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry method for determination of five antidepressants and four atypical antipsychotics and their main metabolites in human serum. Journal of Chromatography. B, Analytical Technologies in the Biomedical and Life Sciences, 907, 101-107. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2012.09.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallerstedt, S. L., &amp; Lindh, J. D. (2015). Prevalence of therapeutic drug monitoring for antidepressants and antipsychotics in Stockholm, Sweden: A longitudinal analysis. Therapeutic Drug Monitoring, 37, 461-465. https://doi.org/10.1097/FTD.0000000000000167</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, X. C., Cai, X., &amp; Zhang, X. (2010). Rapid simultaneous determination of 42 psychoactive drugs and their metabolites in human plasma and urine by ultra performance liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry. Chinese Journal of Chromatography, 28, 23-33. https://doi.org/10.3724/sp.j.1123.2010.00023</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
