<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33891370</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4930</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>99</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cytometry. Part A : the journal of the International Society for Analytical Cytology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cytometry A</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Detecting cells rotations for increasing the robustness of cell sizing by impedance measurements, with or without machine learning.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>977</StartPage>
          <EndPage>986</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>977-986</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cyto.a.24356</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The Coulter principle is a widespread technique for sizing red blood cells (RBCs) in hematological analyzers. It is based on the monitoring of the electrical perturbations generated by cells passing through a micro-orifice, in which a concentrated electrical field is imposed by two electrodes. However, artifacts associated with near-wall passages in the sensing region are known to skew the statistics for RBCs sizing. This study presents numerical results that emphasize the link between the cell flow-induced rotation in the detection area and the error in its measured volume. Based on these observations, two methods are developed to identify and reject pulses impaired by cell rotation. In the first strategy, the filtering is allowed by a metric computed directly from the waveform. In the second, a numerical database is employed to train a neural network capable of detecting if the cell has experienced a rotation, given its electrical pulse. Detecting and rejecting rotation-associated pulses are shown to provide results comparable to hydrodynamical focusing, which enforces cells to flow in the center of the orifice, the gold standard implementation of the Coulter principle.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 International Society for Advancement of Cytometry.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Taraconat</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pierre</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6847-0856</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Horiba Medical, Parc Euromédecine, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut Montpelliérain Alexander, Grothendieck, CNRS, Univ. Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gineys</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean-Philippe</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Horiba Medical, Parc Euromédecine, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Isèbe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Damien</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Horiba Medical, Parc Euromédecine, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nicoud</LastName>
            <ForeName>Franck</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0006-8422</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut Montpelliérain Alexander, Grothendieck, CNRS, Univ. Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mendez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simon</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0863-2024</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut Montpelliérain Alexander, Grothendieck, CNRS, Univ. Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cytometry A</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101235694</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1552-4922</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D048429" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Size</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017097" MajorTopicYN="N">Electric Impedance</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004566" MajorTopicYN="N">Electrodes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004912" MajorTopicYN="Y">Erythrocytes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Machine Learning</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Coulter principle</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">computational fluid dynamics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">hydrodynamic focusing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">neural network</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pulse editing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">red blood cells</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33891370</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cyto.a.24356</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coulter WH. Means for counting particles suspended in a fluid.US Patent 2,656,508. 1953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans TC, Jehle D. The red blood cell distribution width. J Emerg Med. 1991;9:71-4. https://doi.org/10.1016/0736-4679(91)90592-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salvagno GL, Sanchis-Gomar F, Picanza A, Lippi G. Red blood cell distribution width: a simple parameter with multiple clinical applications. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci. 2014;52(2):86-105. https://doi.org/10.3109/10408363.2014.992064.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kachel V. Sizing of cells by the electrical resistance pulse technique: methodology and application in cytometric systems. Cell Analysis. 1982;1:195-331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohandas N, Clark MR, Kissinger S, Bayer C, Shohet SB. Inaccuracies associated with the automated measurement of mean cell hemoglobin concentration in dehydrated cells. Blood. 1981;56(1):125-128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strauchen JA, Alston W, Anderson J, Gustafson Z, Fajardo LF. Inaccuracy in automated measurement of hematocrit and corpuscular indices in the presence of severe hyperglycemia. Blood. 1981;57(6):1065-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brian SB. On the distribution of red cell volumes. Blood. 1968;31:503-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waterman CS, Atkinson EEJ, Wilkins BJ, Fischer CL, Kimzey SL. Improved measurement of erythrocyte volume distribution by aperture-counter signal analysis. Clin Chem. 1975;21(9):1201-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price-Jones C. The diameters of red cells in pernicious anaemia and in anaemia following haemorrhage. J Pathol Bacteriol. 1922;25(4):487-504. https://doi.org/10.1002/path.1700250410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grover NB, Naaman J, Ben-Sasson S, Doljanski F. Electrical sizing of particles in suspensions: III. Rigid spheroids and red blood cells. Biophys J. 1972;12(9);1099-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kachel V. Electrical resistance pulse sizing: Coulter sizing. In: Melamed MR, Lindmo T, Mendelsohn ML, eds. Flow Cytometry and Sorting, 2nd ed. New York: Wiley-Liss, Inc.; 1990.p. 45-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isèbe D, Nérin P. Numerical simulation of particle dynamics in an orifice-electrode system. Application to counting and sizing by impedance measurement. Int J Numer Method Biomed Eng. 2013;29(4):462-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golibersuch D. Observation of Aspherical particle rotation in Poiseuille flow via the resistance pulse technique: I application to human erythrocytes. Biophys J. 1973;13(3):265-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taraconat P, Gineys JP, Isebe D, Nicoud F, Mendez S. Numerical simulation of deformable particles in a Coulter counter. Int J Numer Method Biomed Eng. 2019;35:e3243. https://doi.org/10.1002/cnm.3243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spielman LGSL. Improving resolution in Coulter counting by hydrodynamic focusing. J Colloid Interface Sci. 1968;26:175-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tatsumi N, Tsuda I, Fujimoto K, Matsumoto H. Evaluation of a new blood cell counter with sheath flow system. Cytometry. 1985;6(5):395-400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunstan HJ, Harfield JG, Knight P, Podgorney HJ. Method and apparatus for editing particle produced electrical pulses.US Patent 4,797,624. 1989.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lombarts AJPF, Koevoet AL, Leijnse B. Basic principles and problems of Haemocytometry. Ann Clin Biochem. 1986;23(4):390-404. https://doi.org/10.1177/000456328602300404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishizuka K, Matsubayashi H, Nishimori M. Particle counting method and particle counting apparatus.WO Patent 2015099116 A1. 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Zheng M, Lin D, Huo Z. Systems and methods for particle counting.US Patent 7,457,709 B2. 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donnenberg AD, Donnenberg VS. Rare-event analysis in flow cytometry. Clin Lab Med. 2007;27(3):627-52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cll.2007.05.013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lippi G, Pavesi F, Bardi M, Pipitone S. Lack of harmonization of red blood cell distribution width (RDW). Evaluation of four hematological analyzers. Clin Biochem. 2014;47(12):1100-3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2014.06.003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behrens WV, Edmondson S. Comparison of techniques improving the resolution of standard Coulter cell sizing systems. J Histochem Cytochem. 1976;24(1):247-56. https://doi.org/10.1177/24.1.1254920.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taraconat P, Isebe D, Mendez S, Nicoud F. Device for medical analyses with impedance signal processing.WO Patent 2020216952. 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanotte L, Mauer J, Mendez S, Fedosov DA, Fromental JM, Claveria V, et al. Red cells' dynamic morphologies govern blood shear thinning under microcirculatory flow conditions. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(47):13289-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigüenza J, Mendez S, Nicoud F. How should the optical tweezers experiment be used to characterize the red blood cell membrane mechanics? Biomech Model Mechanobiol. 2017;16:1645-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendez S, Abkarian M. In-plane elasticity controls the full dynamics of red blood cells in shear flow. Phys Rev Fluids. 2018;3:101101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans EA, Fung YC. Improved measurements of the erythrocyte geometry. Microvasc Res. 1972;4:335-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skalak R, Tozeren A, Zarda RP, Chien S. Strain energy function of red blood cell membranes. Biophys J. 1973;13:245-64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helfrich W. Elastic properties of lipid bilayers: theory and possible experiments. Z Naturforsch. 1973;28 c:693-703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abkarian M, Viallat A. Fluid-structure interactions in Low-Reynolds-Number Flows. On the importance of red blood cells deformability in blood flow. London: Royal Society of Chemistry; 2016. p. 347-462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendez S, Abkarian M. Single red blood cell dynamics in shear flow and their role in hemorheology. In: Dynamics of blood cell suspensions in microflows, Boca Raton FL: CRC Press; 2019:125-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abadi M, Agarwal A, Barham P, et al. TensorFlow: a system for large-scale machine learning. Proc. 12th USENIX Conf. Operating Systems Design and Implementation. 2016:265-283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grover NB, Naaman J, Ben-Sasson S, Doljanski F. Electrical sizing of particles in suspensions: I Theory. Biophys J. 1969;9:1398-414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loken MR, Parks DR, Herzenberg LA. Identification of cell asymmetry and orientation by light scattering. J Histochem Cytochem. 1977;25(7):790-5. https://doi.org/10.1177/25.7.330730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stovel R, Sweet R, Herzenberg L. A means for orienting flat cells in flow systems. Biophys J. 1978;23(1):1-5. https://doi.org/10.1016/S00063495(78)85427-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
