<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated">
      <PMID Version="1">33901345</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1934-6638</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>129</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cancer cytopathology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cancer Cytopathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of molecular testing on detecting mimics of oncocytic neoplasms in thyroid fine-needle aspirates diagnosed as follicular neoplasm of Hürthle cell (oncocytic) type.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>788</StartPage>
          <EndPage>797</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>788-797</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cncy.22439</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Some thyroid nodules cytologically presenting as follicular neoplasm, Hürthle cell (Oncocytic) type (FNHCT), are not oncocytic tumors and represent autonomously functioning thyroid nodules (AFTNs) with TSHR, GNAS, and EZH1 mutations or oncocytic metaplasia. A to be defined subset of FNHCT harbors genome haploidisation-type DNA copy number alterations (GH-CNA). Molecular profiling of FNHCT may distinguish oncocytic neoplasms from its mimics.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Consecutive fine-needle aspirates of 180 thyroid nodules over 37 months diagnosed as FNHCT and tested by ThyroSeq v3 were identified. Histologic follow-up was available for 79 of 180 nodules (44%).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">No molecular alterations were found in 76 of 180 nodules (42%), of which 15 were resected (oncocytic metaplasia, n = 7; follicular oncocytic adenoma, n = 8). Of nodules followed without surgery, 17 of 101 (17%) showed TSHR, EZH1, and GNAS mutations of AFTNs. Papillary thyroid carcinoma was identified by BRAF V600E (n = 2) and hyalinizing trabecular adenoma by PAX8-GLIS3 (n = 1). GH-CNA alone was detected in 42 of 180 FNHCT nodules (23%), of which 29 were resected and histologically diagnosed as follicular oncocytic neoplasms. All remaining resected nodules were histologically proven oncocytic neoplasms: 1) RAS-like alterations without GH-CNA (n = 25) and 2) TERT and/or TP53 mutations co-occurring with GH-CNA (n = 6), including anaplastic thyroid carcinoma arising from follicular oncocytic carcinoma with TP53, TERT mutations with GH-CNA (n = 2).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">A proportion of FNHCT nodules are AFTNs and oncocytic metaplasias, which can be suspected based on characteristic mutations or lack of alterations on molecular testing. Among resected FNHCTs, GH-CNAs characterize approximately half of histologically confirmed follicular oncocytic neoplasms.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American Cancer Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Landau</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael S</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2871-5409</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC), Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nikiforov</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuri E</ForeName>
            <Initials>YE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2239-1095</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC), Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ohori</LastName>
            <ForeName>N Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>NP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3280-0534</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC), Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chiosea</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simion I</ForeName>
            <Initials>SI</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5766-8779</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC), Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cancer Cytopathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101499453</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1934-662X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D044963" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy, Fine-Needle</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008679" MajorTopicYN="N">Metaplasia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D025202" MajorTopicYN="N">Molecular Diagnostic Techniques</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D024862" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oxyphil Cells</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013964" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thyroid Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016606" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thyroid Nodule</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">
EZH1
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">
PAX8-GLIS3
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">
RAS
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">
THSR
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">DNA copy-number alterations</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">autonomously functioning thyroid nodule</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">biopsy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">fine-needle aspiration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">follicular adenoma thyroid cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">follicular oncocytic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">papillary</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">thyroid neoplasms</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901345</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncy.22439</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bongiovanni M, Spitale A, Faquin WC, Mazzucchelli L, Baloch ZW. The Bethesda System for Reporting Thyroid Cytopathology: a meta-analysis. Acta Cytol. 2012;56:333-339. doi:10.1159/000339959</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong KS, Angell TE, Barletta JA, Krane JF. Hurthle cell lesions of the thyroid: Progress made and challenges remaining. Cancer Cytopathol. 2020. doi:10.1002/cncy.22375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali SZ, Cibas ES. The Bethesda System for Reporting Thyroid Cytopathology. Vol 11. Springer; 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jalaly JB, Baloch ZW. Hurthle-cell neoplasms of the thyroid: an algorithmic approach to pathologic diagnosis in light of molecular advances. Semin Diagn Pathol. 2020;37:234-242. doi:10.1053/j.semdp.2020.03.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corver WE, van Wezel T, Molenaar K, et al. Near-haploidization significantly associates with oncocytic adrenocortical, thyroid, and parathyroid tumors but not with mitochondrial DNA mutations. Genes Chromosomes Cancer. 2014;53:833-844. doi:10.1002/gcc.22194</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gopal RK, Kubler K, Calvo SE, et al. Widespread chromosomal losses and mitochondrial DNA alterations as genetic drivers in Hurthle cell carcinoma. Cancer Cell. 2018;34:242-255 e5. doi:10.1016/j.ccell.2018.06.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corver WE, Ruano D, Weijers K, et al. Genome haploidisation with chromosome 7 retention in oncocytic follicular thyroid carcinoma. PLoS One. 2012;7:e38287. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0038287</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganly I, Ricarte Filho J, Eng S, et al. Genomic dissection of Hurthle cell carcinoma reveals a unique class of thyroid malignancy. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;98:E962-E972. doi:10.1210/jc.2012-3539</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganly I, Makarov V, Deraje S, et al. Integrated genomic analysis of Hürthle cell cancer reveals oncogenic drivers, recurrent mitochondrial mutations, and unique chromosomal landscapes. Cancer Cell. 2018;34:256-270.e5. doi:10.1016/j.ccell.2018.07.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doerfler WR, Nikitski A, Morariu EM, et al. Molecular alterations in Hürthle cell nodules and preoperative cancer risk. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2021;ERC-20-0435.R1. doi:10.1530/ERC-20-0435</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforova MN, Nikitski A, Tebbets J, et al. Impact of nodule size on the probability of Hurthle cell carcinoma and other cancers in thyroid nodules with multiple chromosomal copy number alterations. J Endocr Soc. 2020;4(suppl 1):OR21-02.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephenson A, Eszlinger M, Stewardson P, et al. Sensitive sequencing analysis suggests thyrotropin receptor and guanine nucleotide-binding protein G subunit alpha as sole driver mutations in hot thyroid nodules. Thyroid. 2020;30:1482-1489. doi:10.1089/thy.2019.0648</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mon SY, Riedlinger G, Abbott CE, et al. Cancer risk and clinicopathological characteristics of thyroid nodules harboring thyroid-stimulating hormone receptor gene mutations. Diagn Cytopathol. 2018;46:369-377. doi:10.1002/dc.23915</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calebiro D, Grassi ES, Eszlinger M, et al. Recurrent EZH1 mutations are a second hit in autonomous thyroid adenomas. J Clin Invest. 2016;126:3383-3388. doi:10.1172/JCI84894</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guan H, Matonis D, Toraldo G, Lee SL. Clinical significance of thyroid-stimulating hormone receptor gene mutations and/or sodium-iodine symporter gene overexpression in indeterminate thyroid fine needle biopsies. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2018;9:566. doi:10.3389/fendo.2018.00566</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo D, Wong MG, Costante G, et al. A Val 677 activating mutation of the thyrotropin receptor in a Hurthle cell thyroid carcinoma associated with thyrotoxicosis. Thyroid. 1999;9:13-17. doi:10.1089/thy.1999.9.13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esapa C, Foster S, Johnson S, Jameson JL, Kendall-Taylor P, Harris PE. G protein and thyrotropin receptor mutations in thyroid neoplasia. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 1997;82:493-496. doi:10.1210/jcem.82.2.3719</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforova MN, Mercurio S, Wald AI, et al. Analytical performance of the ThyroSeq v3 genomic classifier for cancer diagnosis in thyroid nodules. Cancer. 2018;124:1682-1690. doi:10.1002/cncr.31245</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haugen BR, Alexander EK, Bible KC, et al. 2015 American Thyroid Association Management Guidelines for Adult Patients with Thyroid Nodules and Differentiated Thyroid Cancer: The American Thyroid Association Guidelines Task Force on Thyroid Nodules and Differentiated Thyroid Cancer. Thyroid. 2016;26:1-133. doi:10.1089/thy.2015.0020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cibas ES, Ali SZ. The 2017 Bethesda System for Reporting Thyroid Cytopathology. Thyroid. 2017;27:1341-1346. doi:10.1089/thy.2017.0500</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lloyd RV, Osamura RY, Klöppel G, et al. WHO Classification of Tumours of Endocrine Organs. International Agency for Research on Cancer; 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steward DL, Carty SE, Sippel RS, et al. Performance of a multigene genomic classifier in thyroid nodules with indeterminate cytology: a prospective blinded multicenter study. JAMA oncology. 2019;5:204-212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohori NP, Landau MS, Carty SE, et al. Benign call rate and molecular test result distribution of ThyroSeq v3. Cancer Cytopathol. 2019;127:161-168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu B, Reznik E, Tuttle RM, et al. Outcome and molecular characteristics of non-invasive encapsulated follicular variant of papillary thyroid carcinoma with oncocytic features. Endocrine. 2019;64:97-108. doi:10.1007/s12020-019-01848-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takashima S, Matsuzuka F, Nagareda T, Tomiyama N, Kozuka T. Thyroid nodules associated with Hashimoto thyroiditis: assessment with US. Radiology. 1992;185:125-130. doi:10.1148/radiology.185.1.1523294</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoo SK, Lee S, Kim SJ, et al. Comprehensive analysis of the transcriptional and mutational landscape of follicular and papillary thyroid cancers. PLoS Genet. 2016;12:e1006239. doi:10.1371/journal.pgen.1006239</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trulzsch B, Krohn K, Wonerow P, et al. Detection of thyroid-stimulating hormone receptor and Gsalpha mutations: in 75 toxic thyroid nodules by denaturing gradient gel electrophoresis. J Mol Med (Berl). 2001;78:684-691. doi:10.1007/s001090000170</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye L, Zhou X, Huang F, et al. The genetic landscape of benign thyroid nodules revealed by whole exome and transcriptome sequencing. Nat Commun. 2017;8:15533. doi:10.1038/ncomms15533</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung CK, Kim Y, Jeon S, Jo K, Lee S, Bae JS. Clinical utility of EZH1 mutations in the diagnosis of follicular-patterned thyroid tumors. Hum Pathol. 2018;81:9-17. doi:10.1016/j.humpath.2018.04.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung SH, Kim MS, Jung CK, et al. Mutational burdens and evolutionary ages of thyroid follicular adenoma are comparable to those of follicular carcinoma. Oncotarget. 2016;7:69638-69648. doi:10.18632/oncotarget.11922</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cancer Genome Atlas Research N. Integrated genomic characterization of papillary thyroid carcinoma. Cell. 2014;159:676-690. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2014.09.050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforova MN, Nikitski AV, Panebianco F, et al. GLIS rearrangement is a genomic hallmark of hyalinizing trabecular tumor of the thyroid gland. Thyroid. 2019;29:161-173. doi:10.1089/thy.2018.0791</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bo W, Schoedel KE, Carty SE, et al. Incidental diagnosis of parathyroid lesions by preoperative use of next-generation molecular testing. World J Surg. 2018;42:2840-2845. doi:10.1007/s00268-018-4548-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong KS, Jo VY, Lowe AC, et al. Malignancy risk for solitary and multiple nodules in Hurthle cell-predominant thyroid fine-needle aspirations: a multi-institutional study. Cancer Cytopathol. 2020;128:68-75. doi:10.1002/cncy.22213</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melo M, da Rocha AG, Vinagre J, et al. TERT promoter mutations are a major indicator of poor outcome in differentiated thyroid carcinomas. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014;99:E754-E765. doi:10.1210/jc.2013-3734</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
