<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33926048</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>21</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>26</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Exploring Equity in Public Transportation Planning Using Smart Card Data.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3039</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s21093039</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Existing public transport (PT) planning methods use a trip-based approach, rather than a user-based approach, leading to neglecting equity. In other words, the impacts of regular users-i.e., users with higher trip rates-are overrepresented during analysis and modelling because of higher trip rates. In contrast to the existing studies, this study aims to show the actual demand characteristic and users' share are different in daily and monthly data. For this, 1-month of smart card data from the Kocaeli, Turkey, was evaluated by means of specific variables, such as boarding frequency, cardholder types, and the number of users, as well as a breakdown of the number of days traveled by each user set. Results show that the proportion of regular PT users to total users in 1 workday, is higher than the monthly proportion of regular PT users to total users. Accordingly, users who have 16-21 days boarding frequency are 16% of the total users, and yet they have been overrepresented by 39% in the 1-day analysis. Moreover, users who have 1-6 days boarding frequency, have a share of 66% in the 1-month dataset and are underrepresented with a share of 22% in the 1-day analysis. Results indicated that the daily travel data without information related to the day-to-day frequency of trips and PT use caused incorrect estimation of real PT demand. Moreover, user-based analyzing approach over a month prepares the more realistic basis for transportation planning, design, and prioritization of transport investments.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghasemlou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kiarash</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate School of Science, Engineering and Technology, Istanbul Technical University, 34467 Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ergun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Murat</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Civil Engineering Faculty, Istanbul Technical University, 34467 Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dadashzadeh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nima</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5425-0572</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Civil and Geodetic Engineering, University of Ljubljana, 1000 Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cost benefit analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">equity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">human centric planning</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobility pattern</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">public transportation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smart card data</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transport planning</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">travel behavior</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33926048</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8123666</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21093039</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">s21093039</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banister D. The sustainable mobility paradigm. Transp. Policy. 2008;15:73–80. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2007.10.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2007.10.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OECD Improving Transport Accessibility for All: Guide to Good Practice. European Conference of Ministers of Transport (ECMT) Publications; Paris, France: 2006. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadashzadeh N., Ergun M. Spatial bus priority schemes, implementation challenges and needs: An overview and directions for future studies. Public Transp. 2018;10:545–570. doi: 10.1007/s12469-018-0191-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12469-018-0191-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadashzadeh N.  Effects of Bus PRIORITY Methods on Adjacent Mixed Traffic. Istanbul Technical University; Istanbul, Turkey: 2019. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beyazit E. Evaluating Social Justice in Transport: Lessons to be Learned from the Capability Approach. Transp. Rev. 2011;31:117–134. doi: 10.1080/01441647.2010.504900.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01441647.2010.504900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanoutrive T., Cooper E. How just is transportation justice theory? The issues of paternalism and production. Transp. Res. Part A Policy Pract. 2019;122:112–119. doi: 10.1016/j.tra.2019.02.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tra.2019.02.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martens K.  Transport Justice: Designing Fair Transportation Systems. Routledge Taylor &amp; Francis Group; New York, NY, USA: 2017. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Ciommo F., Shiftan Y. Transport equity analysis. Transp. Rev. 2017;37:139–151. doi: 10.1080/01441647.2017.1278647.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01441647.2017.1278647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelobonye K., Zhou H., McCarney G., Xia J. Measuring the accessibility and spatial equity of urban services under competition using the cumulative opportunities measure. J. Transp. Geogr. 2020;85:102706. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2020.102706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2020.102706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martens K., Di Ciommo F. Travel time savings, accessibility gains and equity effects in cost–benefit analysis. Transp. Rev. 2017;37:152–169. doi: 10.1080/01441647.2016.1276642.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01441647.2016.1276642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martens K. Substance precedes methodology: On cost-benefit analysis and equity. Transportation. 2011;38:959–974. doi: 10.1007/s11116-011-9372-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11116-011-9372-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koutsopoulos H.N., Ma Z., Noursalehi P., Zhu Y.  Transit Data Analytics for Planning, Monitoring, Control, and Information. In: Antoniou C., Dimitriou L., Pereira F., editors. Mobility Patterns, Big Data and Transport Analytics. Elsevier B.V.; Amsterdam, The Netherlands: 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu W., Bai H., Chen J., Yan X. Anomaly Detection of Passenger OD on Nanjing Metro Based on Smart Card Big Data. IEEE Access. 2019;7:138624–138636. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2943598.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2943598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X., Wang Q. PeopleVis: A visual analysis system for mining travel behavior; Proceedings of the 2017 IEEE 21st International Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work in Design; Wellington, New Zealand. 26–28 April 2017; pp. 463–468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee I.  Ph.D. Thesis. Seoul National University; Seoul, Korea: Aug, 2019. Estimating of Bus-Trip Destinations Using Temporal Travel patterns of Smart Card Data.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali A.A., Eliasson J. Dynamic origin-destination estimation using smart card data: An entropy maximisation approach. arXiv. 20191909.02826</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alsger A., Tavassoli A., Mesbah M., Ferreira L., Hickman M. Public transport trip purpose inference using smart card fare data. Transp. Res. Part C Emerg. Technol. 2018;87:123–137. doi: 10.1016/j.trc.2017.12.016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trc.2017.12.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu C., He Z.C. Analysing the spatial-temporal characteristics of bus travel demand using the heat map. J. Transp. Geogr. 2017;58:247–255. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2016.11.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2016.11.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tavassoli A., Mesbah M., Hickman M. Application of smart card data in validating a large-scale multi-modal transit assignment model. Public Transp. 2018;10:1–21. doi: 10.1007/s12469-017-0171-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12469-017-0171-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litman T.  Proceedings of the Transport and Social Exclusion G7 Comparison Seminar. Transport Studies Group of the University of Westminster; London, UK: 2003. Social Inclusion as A Transport Planning Issue in Canada; pp. 6–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litman T. Evaluating Transportation Equity: Guidance for Incorporating Distributional Impacts in Transportation Planning.  [(accessed on 26 April 2021)]; Available online:  https://www.vtpi.org/equity.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira R.H.M., Schwanen T., Banister D. Distributive justice and equity in transportation. Transp. Rev. 2017;37:170–191. doi: 10.1080/01441647.2016.1257660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01441647.2016.1257660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camporeale R., Caggiani L., Fonzone A., Ottomanelli M. Quantifying the impacts of horizontal and vertical equity in transit route planning. Transp. Plan. Technol. 2017;40:28–44. doi: 10.1080/03081060.2016.1238569.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03081060.2016.1238569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McArthur J., Robin E., Smeds E. Socio-spatial and temporal dimensions of transport equity for London’s night time economy. Transp. Res. Part A Policy Pract. 2019;121:433–443. doi: 10.1016/j.tra.2019.01.024.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tra.2019.01.024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boisjoly G., Serra B., Oliveira G., El-Geneidy A. Inequity in transit: Evaluating public transport distribution through accessibility measurements in São Paulo, Rio de Janeiro, Curitiba and Recife, Brazil. J. Transp. Geogr. 2020;82:1–11. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2019.102551.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2019.102551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palm M., Farber S., Shalaby A., Young M. Equity Analysis and New Mobility Technologies: Toward Meaningful Interventions. J. Plan. Lit. 2020;36:31–45. doi: 10.1177/0885412220955197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0885412220955197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Rashid M.A., Goh H.C., Harumain Y.A.S., Ali Z., Campisi T., Mahmood T. Psychosocial barriers of public transport use and social exclusion among older adults: Empirical evidence from Lahore, Pakistan. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2021;18:185.  doi: 10.3390/ijerph18010185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18010185</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7794845</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33383763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martens K. Accessibility and potential mobility as a guide for policy action. Transp. Res. Rec. 2015;2499:18–24. doi: 10.3141/2499-03.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3141/2499-03</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Currie G. Quantifying spatial gaps in public transport supply based on social needs. J. Transp. Geogr. 2010;18:31–41. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2008.12.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2008.12.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United Nations  . Cost Benefit Analysis of Transport Infrastructure Projects. United Nations; Geneva, Switzerland: 2003. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomopoulos N., Grant-Muller S., Tight M.R. Incorporating equity considerations in transport infrastructure evaluation: Current practice and a proposed methodology. Eval. Program Plann. 2009;32:351–359. doi: 10.1016/j.evalprogplan.2009.06.013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.evalprogplan.2009.06.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19647318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Topuz Kiremitçi S.  A Model for Accessibility and Affordability in Urban Transportation: Istanbul Case. Istanbul Technical University; Istanbul, Turkey: 2017. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelletier M.P., Trépanier M., Morency C. Smart card data use in public transit: A literature review. Transp. Res. Part C Emerg. Technol. 2011;19:557–568. doi: 10.1016/j.trc.2010.12.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trc.2010.12.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syarif M., Widyawan , Adji T.B. Big data analytics: Estimation of destination for users of bus rapid transit (brt) public transportation in Jakarta; Proceedings of the 2019 International Conference of Artificial Intelligence and Information Technology (ICAIIT); Yogyakarta, Indonesia. 13–15 March 2019; pp. 209–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma X., Ji Y., Yuan Y., Van Oort N., Jin Y., Hoogendoorn S. A comparison in travel patterns and determinants of user demand between docked and dockless bike-sharing systems using multi-sourced data. Transp. Res. Part A Policy Pract. 2020;139:148–173. doi: 10.1016/j.tra.2020.06.022.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tra.2020.06.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J., Shen D., Tu L., Zhang F., Xu C., Wang Y., Tian C., Li X., Huang B., Li Z. A real-time passenger flow estimation and prediction method for urban bus transit systems. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 2017;18:3168–3178. doi: 10.1109/TITS.2017.2686877.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2017.2686877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian X., Zheng B. Study Group Travel Behaviour Patterns from Large-Scale Smart Card Data; Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Big Data; Los Angeles, CA, USA. 9–12 December 2019; pp. 1232–1237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian X., Zheng B. Using Smart Card Data to Model Commuters’ Responses Upon Unexpected Train Delays; Proceedings of the 2019 IEEE International Conference on Big Data; Seattle, WA, USA. 10–13 December 2018; pp. 831–840.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J., Tu L., Zhang F., Yin X., Sun J., Chen H.S.T. Flexible Express Bus Line Planning and Operating Based on Passenger Flow Analysis; Proceedings of the 2018 21st International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC); Maui, HI, USA. 4–7 November 2018; pp. 2511–2518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickens M., Hughes-Cromwick M. Leveraging Big Data in the Public Transportation Industry.  [(accessed on 26 April 2021)]; Available online:  https://www.apta.com/wp-content/uploads/Big-Data-Policy-Brief.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basu A., Zhao J., Koutsopoulos H., Mishalani R. Data-driven customer segmentation and personalized information provision in public transit; Proceedings of the TransitData 2019: 5th International Workshop and Symposium: Research and Applications on the Use of passive Data from Public Transport; Paris, France. 8–10 July 2019; pp. 2–18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinoza C., Munizaga M., Bustos B., Trépanier M. Assessing the public transport travel behavior consistency from smart card data. Transp. Res. Procedia. 2018;32:44–53. doi: 10.1016/j.trpro.2018.10.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trpro.2018.10.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benenson I., Marinov M., Ben-Elia E. Unexpected flexibility of public transit usage revealed from mining Israel’s smartcard data; Proceedings of the TransitData 2019: 5th International Workshop and Symposium: Research and Applications on the use of Passive Data from Public Transport; Paris, France. 8–10 July 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egu O., Bonnel P. Investigating day-to-day variability of transit usage on a multimonth scale with smart card data. A case study in Lyon. Travel Behav. Soc. 2020;19:112–123. doi: 10.1016/j.tbs.2019.12.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tbs.2019.12.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raux C., Ma T.Y., Cornelis E. Variability in daily activity-travel patterns: The case of a one-week travel diary. Eur. Transp. Res. Rev. 2016;26:8. doi: 10.1007/s12544-016-0213-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12544-016-0213-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S., Yamamoto T., Yao E., Nakamura T. Exploring Travel Pattern Variability of Public Transport Users Through Smart Card Data: Role of Gender and Age. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 2020:1–10. doi: 10.1109/TITS.2020.3043021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2020.3043021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morency C., Trépanier M., Agard B. Measuring transit use variability with smart-card data. Transp. Policy. 2007;14:193–203. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2007.01.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2007.01.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agard B.  Encyclopedia of Data Warehousing and Mining. 2nd ed. IGI Global; Hershey, PA, USA: 2011. Mining Smart Card Data from an Urban Transit Network; pp. 1292–1302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu K., Liu J., Zhou X., Han B. A Review of Big Data Applications in Urban Transit Systems. IEEE Trans. Intell. Transp. Syst. 2020:1–18. doi: 10.1109/TITS.2020.2973365.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TITS.2020.2973365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>KMM Kocaeli Province, Turkey.  [(accessed on 13 December 2020)]; Available online:  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kocaeli_Province.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocaeli Transportation Master Plan and Public Transportation Priority Systems: Updates for 2050. Boğaziçi Proje Engineering Inc.; Kocaeli, Turkey: 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>PTV VISION VISUM: Travel Demand Modeling—User Manuals 2019.  [(accessed on 14 April 2021)]; Available online:  https://www.ptvgroup.com/en/solutions/products/ptv-visum/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li T., Sun D., Jing P., Yang K. Smart card data mining of public transport destination: A literature review. Information. 2018;9:18.  doi: 10.3390/info9010018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/info9010018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith G. European medicines agency guideline on bioanalytical method validation: What more is there to say? Bioanalysis. 2012;4:865–868. doi: 10.4155/bio.12.44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4155/bio.12.44</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22533559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gervasi O., Murgante B., Misra S., Garau C., Blec I., Taniar D., Apduhan B.O., Maria A., Eufemia A.C.R., Goos G.  In: Computational Science and Its Applications—ICCSA 2020. Gervasi O., Murgante B., Misra S., Garau C., Blečić I., Taniar D., Apduhan B.O., Rocha A.M.A.C., Tarantino E., Torre C.M., Karaca Y., editors. Volume 12255. Springer International Publishing; Cham, Switzerland: 2020.  Lecture Notes in Computer Science.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torrisi V., Garau C., Ignaccolo M., Inturri G.  “Sustainable Urban Mobility Plans”: Key Concepts and a Critical Revision on SUMPs Guidelines. In: Gervasi O., Murgante B., Misra S., Garau C., Blečić I., Taniar D., Apduhan B.O., Rocha A.M.A.C., Tarantino E., Torre C.M., et al., editors. Proceedings of the Computational Science and Its Applications—ICCSA 2020. Springer; Cham, Switzerland: 2020. pp. 613–628.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pirra M., Carboni A., Diana M. Assessing gender gaps in educational provision, research and employment opportunities in the transport sector at the european level. Educ. Sci. 2020;10:123.  doi: 10.3390/educsci10050123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/educsci10050123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Rashid M.A., Nahiduzzaman K.M., Ahmed S., Campisi T., Akgün N. Gender-responsive public transportation in the Dammam metropolitan region, Saudi Arabia. Sustainability. 2020;12:9068.  doi: 10.3390/su12219068.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12219068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
