<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33939231</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility : the official journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Role of enteric dopaminergic neurons in regulating peristalsis of rat proximal colon.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14127</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14127</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.14127</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Constipation is commonly seen in patients with Parkinson's disease associated with a loss of dopaminergic neurons in both central and enteric nervous systems. However, the roles of enteric dopaminergic neurons in developing constipation remain to be elucidated. Here, we investigated the roles of enteric dopaminergic neurons in the generation of colonic peristalsis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Cannulated segments of rat proximal colon were situated in the organ bath, abluminally perfused with physiological salt solution and luminally perfused with 0.9% saline. Drugs were applied in the abluminal solution. Changes in diameter along the length of the colonic segment were captured by a video camera and transformed into spatio-temporal maps. Fluorescence immunohistochemistry was also carried out.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS">Blockade of nitrergic neurotransmission prevented oro-aboral propagation of peristaltic waves and caused a colonic constriction without affecting ripples, non-propagating myogenic contractions. Blockade of cholinergic neurotransmission also prevented peristaltic waves but suppressed ripples with a colonic dilatation. Tetrodotoxin (0.6 μM) abolished peristaltic waves and increased ripples with a constriction. SCH 23390 (20 μM), a D<sub>1</sub> -like dopamine receptor antagonist, slowed the peristaltic waves and caused a constriction, while GBR 12909 (1 μM), a dopamine reuptake inhibitor, diminished the peristaltic waves with a dilatation. Bath-applied dopamine (3 μM) abolished the peristaltic waves associated with a colonic dilation in an SCH 23390 (5 μM)-sensitive manner. D<sub>1</sub> receptor immunoreactivity was co-localized to nitrergic and cholinergic neurons.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND INFERENCES">Dopaminergic neurons appear to facilitate nitrergic neurons via D<sub>1</sub> -like receptors to stabilize asynchronous contractile activity resulting in the generation of colonic peristalsis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakamori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0310-4927</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Noda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenta</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mitsui</LastName>
            <ForeName>Retsu</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hashitani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hikaru</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059329" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003106" MajorTopicYN="N">Colon</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059290" MajorTopicYN="N">Dopaminergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017615" MajorTopicYN="N">Enteric Nervous System</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D026602" MajorTopicYN="N">Nitrergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010528" MajorTopicYN="N">Peristalsis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">enteric nervous system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gastrointestinal motility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">parkinson's disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">peristalsis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>49</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939231</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14127</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalia LV, Lang AE. Parkinson's disease. Lancet. 2015;386:896-912.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schapira AHV, Chaudhuri KR, Jenner P. Non-motor features of Parkinson disease. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2017;18:435-450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singaram C, Ashraf W, Gaumnitz EA, et al. Dopaminergic defect of enteric nervous system in Parkinson's disease patients with chronic constipation. Lancet. 1995;346:861-864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anlauf M, Schäfer MK, Eiden L, Weihe E. Chemical coding of the human gastrointestinal nervous system: cholinergic, VIPergic, and catecholaminergic phenotypes. J Comp Neurol. 2003;459:90-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li ZS, Pham TD, Tamir H, Chen JJ, Gershon MD. Enteric dopaminergic neurons: definition, developmental lineage, and effects of extrinsic denervation. J Neurosci. 2004;24:1330-1339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li ZS, Schmauss C, Cuenca A, Ratcliffe E, Gershon MD. Physiological modulation of intestinal motility by enteric dopaminergic neurons and the D2 receptor: analysis of dopamine receptor expression, location, development, and function in wild-type and knock-out mice. J Neurosci. 2006;26:2798-2807.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Guo H, Xu J, et al. Dopamine receptor D1 mediates the inhibition of dopamine on the distal colonic motility. Transl Res. 2012;159:407-414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Li Y, Liu C, et al. Alteration of enteric monoamines with monoamine receptors and colonic dysmotility in 6-hydroxydopamine-induced Parkinson's disease rats. Transl Res. 2015;166:152-162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Missale C, Nash SR, Robinson SW, Jaber M, Caron MG. Dopamine receptors: from structure to function. Physiol Rev. 1998;78:189-225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Auteri M, Zizzo MG, Amato A, Serio R. Dopamine induces inhibitory effects on the circular muscle contractility of mouse distal colon via D1- and D2-like receptors. J Physiol Biochem. 2016;73:395-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar MJ, Estañ L, Martínez-Mir I, Martínez-Abad M, Rubio E, Morales-Olivas FJ. Effects of dopamine in isolated rat colon strips. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2005;83:447-452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zizzo MG, Bellanca A, Amato A, Serio R. Opposite effects of dopamine on the mechanical activity of circular and longitudinal muscle of human colon. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;32:e13811.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurosawa S, Hasler WL, Torres G, Wiley JW, Owyang C. Characterization of receptors mediating the effects of dopamine on gastric smooth muscle. Gastroenterology. 1991;100:1224-1231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa M, Dodds KN, Wiklendt L, Spencer NJ, Brookes SJ, Dinning PG. Neurogenic and myogenic motor activity in the colon of the guinea pig, mouse, rabbit, and rat. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2013;305:G749-G759.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa M, Wiklendt L, Simpson P, Spencer NJ, Brookes SJ, Dinning PG. Neuromechanical factors involved in the formation and propulsion of fecal pellets in the guinea-pig colon. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2015;27:1466-1477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaji I, Akiba Y, Konno K, et al. Neural FFA3 activation inversely regulates anion secretion evoked by nicotinic ACh receptor activation in rat proximal colon. J Physiol. 2016;594:3339-3352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sershen H, Hashim A, Lajtha A. Serotonin-mediated striatal dopamine release involves the dopamine uptake site and the serotonin receptor. Brain Res Bull. 2000;53:353-357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foxx-Orenstein AE, Grider JR. Regulation of colonic propulsion by enteric excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:G433-G437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spencer NJ, Dinning PG, Brookes SJ, Costa M. Insights into the mechanisms underlying colonic motor patterns. J Physiol. 2016;594:4099-4116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuzhikandathil EV, Oxford GS. Classic D1 dopamine receptor antagonist R-(+)-7-chloro-8-hydroxy-3-methyl-1-phenyl-2,3,4,5-tetrahydro-1H-3-benzazepine hydrochloride (SCH23390) directly inhibits G protein-coupled inwardly rectifying potassium channels. Mol Pharmacol. 2002;62:119-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Medina AL, Galligan JJ. Optogenetic analysis of neuromuscular transmission in the colon of ChAT-ChR2-YFP BAC transgenic mice. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2019;317:G569-G579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koh SD, Kim TW, Jun JY, Glasgow NJ, Ward SM, Sanders KM. Regulation of pacemaker currents in interstitial cells of Cajal from murine small intestine by cyclic nucleotides. J Physiol. 2000;527:149-162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez A, Sarna SK. Neural regulation of in vitro giant contractions in the rat colon. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2001;281:G275-G282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu CZ, Zhang XL, Zhou L, et al. Rasagiline, an inhibitor of MAO-B, decreases colonic motility through elevating colonic dopamine content. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;30:e13390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soykan I, Sarosiek I, Shifflett J, Wooten GF, McCallum RW. Effect of chronic oral domperidone therapy on gastrointestinal symptoms and gastric emptying in patients with Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 1997;12:952-957.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bueno L, Gue M, Fabre C, Junien JL. Involvement of central dopamine and D1 receptors in stress-induced colonic motor alterations in rats. Brain Res Bull. 1992;29:135-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naitou K, Nakamori H, Shiina T, et al. Stimulation of dopamine D2-like receptors in the lumbosacral defaecation centre causes propulsive colorectal contractions in rats. J Physiol. 2016;594:4339-4350.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker JK, Gainetdinov RR, Mangel AW, Caron MG, Shetzline MA. Mice lacking the dopamine transporter display altered regulation of distal colonic motility. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2000;279:G311-G318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerra DD, Bok R, Lorca RA, Hurt KJ. Protein kinase A facilitates relaxation of mouse ileum via phosphorylation of neuronal nitric oxide synthase. Br J Pharmacol. 2020;177:2765-2778.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren J, Zhou X, Galligan JJ. 5-HT4 receptor activation facilitates recovery from synaptic rundown and increases transmitter release from single varicosities of myenteric neurons. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2008;294:G1376-G1383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickson EJ, Spencer NJ, Hennig GW, et al. An enteric occult reflex underlies accommodation and slow transit in the distal large bowel. Gastroenterology. 2007;132:1912-1924.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gould TW, Swope WA, Heredia DJ, Corrigan RD, Smith TK. Activity within specific enteric neurochemical subtypes is correlated with distinct patterns of gastrointestinal motility in the murine colon. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2019;317:G210-G221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naitou K, Nakamori H, Horii K, et al. Descending monoaminergic pathways projecting to the spinal defecation center enhance colorectal motility in rats. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2018;315:G631-G637.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamori H, Naitou K, Horii Y, et al. Roles of the noradrenergic nucleus locus coeruleus and dopaminergic nucleus A11 region as supraspinal defecation centers in rats. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2019;317:G545-G555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamori H, Naitou K, Sano Y, Shimaoka H, Shiina T, Shimizu Y. Exogenous serotonin regulates colorectal motility via the 5-HT2 and 5-HT3 receptors in the spinal cord of rats. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;30:e13183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annerino DM, Arshad S, Taylor GM, Adler CH, Beach TG, Greene JG. Parkinson's disease is not associated with gastrointestinal myenteric ganglion neuron loss. Acta Neuropathol. 2012;124:665-680.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian YM, Chen X, Luo DZ, et al. Alteration of dopaminergic markers in gastrointestinal tract of different rodent models of parkinson's disease. Neuroscience. 2008;153:634-644.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blandini F, Balestra B, Levandis G, et al. Functional and neurochemical changes of the gastrointestinal tract in a rodent model of parkinson's disease. Neurosci Lett. 2009;467:203-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chai XY, Diwakarla S, Pustovit RV, et al. Investigation of nerve pathways mediating colorectal dysfunction in Parkinson's disease model produced by lesion of nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurons. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;32:e13893.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fornai M, Pellegrini C, Antonioli L, et al. Enteric dysfunctions in experimental parkinson's disease: alterations of excitatory cholinergic neurotransmission regulating colonic motility in rats. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2016;356:434-444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellegrini C, Antonioli L, Colucci R, et al. Effects of L-DOPA/benserazide co-treatment on colonic excitatory cholinergic motility and enteric inflammation following dopaminergic nigrostriatal neurodegeneration. Neuropharmacology. 2017;123:22-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">33939231</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility : the official journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Role of enteric dopaminergic neurons in regulating peristalsis of rat proximal colon.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14127</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14127</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.14127</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Constipation is commonly seen in patients with Parkinson's disease associated with a loss of dopaminergic neurons in both central and enteric nervous systems. However, the roles of enteric dopaminergic neurons in developing constipation remain to be elucidated. Here, we investigated the roles of enteric dopaminergic neurons in the generation of colonic peristalsis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Cannulated segments of rat proximal colon were situated in the organ bath, abluminally perfused with physiological salt solution and luminally perfused with 0.9% saline. Drugs were applied in the abluminal solution. Changes in diameter along the length of the colonic segment were captured by a video camera and transformed into spatio-temporal maps. Fluorescence immunohistochemistry was also carried out.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS">Blockade of nitrergic neurotransmission prevented oro-aboral propagation of peristaltic waves and caused a colonic constriction without affecting ripples, non-propagating myogenic contractions. Blockade of cholinergic neurotransmission also prevented peristaltic waves but suppressed ripples with a colonic dilatation. Tetrodotoxin (0.6 μM) abolished peristaltic waves and increased ripples with a constriction. SCH 23390 (20 μM), a D<sub>1</sub> -like dopamine receptor antagonist, slowed the peristaltic waves and caused a constriction, while GBR 12909 (1 μM), a dopamine reuptake inhibitor, diminished the peristaltic waves with a dilatation. Bath-applied dopamine (3 μM) abolished the peristaltic waves associated with a colonic dilation in an SCH 23390 (5 μM)-sensitive manner. D<sub>1</sub> receptor immunoreactivity was co-localized to nitrergic and cholinergic neurons.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND INFERENCES">Dopaminergic neurons appear to facilitate nitrergic neurons via D<sub>1</sub> -like receptors to stabilize asynchronous contractile activity resulting in the generation of colonic peristalsis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakamori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0310-4927</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Noda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenta</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mitsui</LastName>
            <ForeName>Retsu</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hashitani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hikaru</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Physiology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059329" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003106" MajorTopicYN="N">Colon</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059290" MajorTopicYN="N">Dopaminergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017615" MajorTopicYN="N">Enteric Nervous System</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D026602" MajorTopicYN="N">Nitrergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010528" MajorTopicYN="N">Peristalsis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">enteric nervous system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gastrointestinal motility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">parkinson's disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">peristalsis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>49</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33939231</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14127</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalia LV, Lang AE. Parkinson's disease. Lancet. 2015;386:896-912.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schapira AHV, Chaudhuri KR, Jenner P. Non-motor features of Parkinson disease. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2017;18:435-450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singaram C, Ashraf W, Gaumnitz EA, et al. Dopaminergic defect of enteric nervous system in Parkinson's disease patients with chronic constipation. Lancet. 1995;346:861-864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anlauf M, Schäfer MK, Eiden L, Weihe E. Chemical coding of the human gastrointestinal nervous system: cholinergic, VIPergic, and catecholaminergic phenotypes. J Comp Neurol. 2003;459:90-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li ZS, Pham TD, Tamir H, Chen JJ, Gershon MD. Enteric dopaminergic neurons: definition, developmental lineage, and effects of extrinsic denervation. J Neurosci. 2004;24:1330-1339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li ZS, Schmauss C, Cuenca A, Ratcliffe E, Gershon MD. Physiological modulation of intestinal motility by enteric dopaminergic neurons and the D2 receptor: analysis of dopamine receptor expression, location, development, and function in wild-type and knock-out mice. J Neurosci. 2006;26:2798-2807.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Guo H, Xu J, et al. Dopamine receptor D1 mediates the inhibition of dopamine on the distal colonic motility. Transl Res. 2012;159:407-414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Li Y, Liu C, et al. Alteration of enteric monoamines with monoamine receptors and colonic dysmotility in 6-hydroxydopamine-induced Parkinson's disease rats. Transl Res. 2015;166:152-162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Missale C, Nash SR, Robinson SW, Jaber M, Caron MG. Dopamine receptors: from structure to function. Physiol Rev. 1998;78:189-225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Auteri M, Zizzo MG, Amato A, Serio R. Dopamine induces inhibitory effects on the circular muscle contractility of mouse distal colon via D1- and D2-like receptors. J Physiol Biochem. 2016;73:395-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar MJ, Estañ L, Martínez-Mir I, Martínez-Abad M, Rubio E, Morales-Olivas FJ. Effects of dopamine in isolated rat colon strips. Can J Physiol Pharmacol. 2005;83:447-452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zizzo MG, Bellanca A, Amato A, Serio R. Opposite effects of dopamine on the mechanical activity of circular and longitudinal muscle of human colon. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;32:e13811.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurosawa S, Hasler WL, Torres G, Wiley JW, Owyang C. Characterization of receptors mediating the effects of dopamine on gastric smooth muscle. Gastroenterology. 1991;100:1224-1231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa M, Dodds KN, Wiklendt L, Spencer NJ, Brookes SJ, Dinning PG. Neurogenic and myogenic motor activity in the colon of the guinea pig, mouse, rabbit, and rat. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2013;305:G749-G759.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa M, Wiklendt L, Simpson P, Spencer NJ, Brookes SJ, Dinning PG. Neuromechanical factors involved in the formation and propulsion of fecal pellets in the guinea-pig colon. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2015;27:1466-1477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaji I, Akiba Y, Konno K, et al. Neural FFA3 activation inversely regulates anion secretion evoked by nicotinic ACh receptor activation in rat proximal colon. J Physiol. 2016;594:3339-3352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sershen H, Hashim A, Lajtha A. Serotonin-mediated striatal dopamine release involves the dopamine uptake site and the serotonin receptor. Brain Res Bull. 2000;53:353-357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foxx-Orenstein AE, Grider JR. Regulation of colonic propulsion by enteric excitatory and inhibitory neurotransmitters. Am J Physiol. 1996;271:G433-G437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spencer NJ, Dinning PG, Brookes SJ, Costa M. Insights into the mechanisms underlying colonic motor patterns. J Physiol. 2016;594:4099-4116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuzhikandathil EV, Oxford GS. Classic D1 dopamine receptor antagonist R-(+)-7-chloro-8-hydroxy-3-methyl-1-phenyl-2,3,4,5-tetrahydro-1H-3-benzazepine hydrochloride (SCH23390) directly inhibits G protein-coupled inwardly rectifying potassium channels. Mol Pharmacol. 2002;62:119-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Medina AL, Galligan JJ. Optogenetic analysis of neuromuscular transmission in the colon of ChAT-ChR2-YFP BAC transgenic mice. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2019;317:G569-G579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koh SD, Kim TW, Jun JY, Glasgow NJ, Ward SM, Sanders KM. Regulation of pacemaker currents in interstitial cells of Cajal from murine small intestine by cyclic nucleotides. J Physiol. 2000;527:149-162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez A, Sarna SK. Neural regulation of in vitro giant contractions in the rat colon. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2001;281:G275-G282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu CZ, Zhang XL, Zhou L, et al. Rasagiline, an inhibitor of MAO-B, decreases colonic motility through elevating colonic dopamine content. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;30:e13390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soykan I, Sarosiek I, Shifflett J, Wooten GF, McCallum RW. Effect of chronic oral domperidone therapy on gastrointestinal symptoms and gastric emptying in patients with Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 1997;12:952-957.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bueno L, Gue M, Fabre C, Junien JL. Involvement of central dopamine and D1 receptors in stress-induced colonic motor alterations in rats. Brain Res Bull. 1992;29:135-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naitou K, Nakamori H, Shiina T, et al. Stimulation of dopamine D2-like receptors in the lumbosacral defaecation centre causes propulsive colorectal contractions in rats. J Physiol. 2016;594:4339-4350.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker JK, Gainetdinov RR, Mangel AW, Caron MG, Shetzline MA. Mice lacking the dopamine transporter display altered regulation of distal colonic motility. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2000;279:G311-G318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerra DD, Bok R, Lorca RA, Hurt KJ. Protein kinase A facilitates relaxation of mouse ileum via phosphorylation of neuronal nitric oxide synthase. Br J Pharmacol. 2020;177:2765-2778.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren J, Zhou X, Galligan JJ. 5-HT4 receptor activation facilitates recovery from synaptic rundown and increases transmitter release from single varicosities of myenteric neurons. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2008;294:G1376-G1383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickson EJ, Spencer NJ, Hennig GW, et al. An enteric occult reflex underlies accommodation and slow transit in the distal large bowel. Gastroenterology. 2007;132:1912-1924.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gould TW, Swope WA, Heredia DJ, Corrigan RD, Smith TK. Activity within specific enteric neurochemical subtypes is correlated with distinct patterns of gastrointestinal motility in the murine colon. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2019;317:G210-G221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naitou K, Nakamori H, Horii K, et al. Descending monoaminergic pathways projecting to the spinal defecation center enhance colorectal motility in rats. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2018;315:G631-G637.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamori H, Naitou K, Horii Y, et al. Roles of the noradrenergic nucleus locus coeruleus and dopaminergic nucleus A11 region as supraspinal defecation centers in rats. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2019;317:G545-G555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamori H, Naitou K, Sano Y, Shimaoka H, Shiina T, Shimizu Y. Exogenous serotonin regulates colorectal motility via the 5-HT2 and 5-HT3 receptors in the spinal cord of rats. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;30:e13183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annerino DM, Arshad S, Taylor GM, Adler CH, Beach TG, Greene JG. Parkinson's disease is not associated with gastrointestinal myenteric ganglion neuron loss. Acta Neuropathol. 2012;124:665-680.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian YM, Chen X, Luo DZ, et al. Alteration of dopaminergic markers in gastrointestinal tract of different rodent models of parkinson's disease. Neuroscience. 2008;153:634-644.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blandini F, Balestra B, Levandis G, et al. Functional and neurochemical changes of the gastrointestinal tract in a rodent model of parkinson's disease. Neurosci Lett. 2009;467:203-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chai XY, Diwakarla S, Pustovit RV, et al. Investigation of nerve pathways mediating colorectal dysfunction in Parkinson's disease model produced by lesion of nigrostriatal dopaminergic neurons. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;32:e13893.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fornai M, Pellegrini C, Antonioli L, et al. Enteric dysfunctions in experimental parkinson's disease: alterations of excitatory cholinergic neurotransmission regulating colonic motility in rats. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2016;356:434-444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellegrini C, Antonioli L, Colucci R, et al. Effects of L-DOPA/benserazide co-treatment on colonic excitatory cholinergic motility and enteric inflammation following dopaminergic nigrostriatal neurodegeneration. Neuropharmacology. 2017;123:22-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
