<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33961299</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-8206</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Fundamental &amp; clinical pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Fundam Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of 27 CYP3A4 protein variants on saxagliptin metabolism in vitro.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>150</StartPage>
          <EndPage>159</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>150-159</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/fcp.12693</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Saxagliptin is a dipeptidyl peptidase 4 (DPP-4) inhibitor widely used in patients with type 2 diabetes. It can increase the amount of insulin after meals and lower blood sugar. CYP450 3A4 (CYP3A4) can metabolize about 30%-40% of therapeutic drugs. Individual differences caused by CYP3A4 genetic polymorphisms can lead to treatment failure, unpredictable side effects, or severe drug toxicity. The aim of this study was to evaluate the catalytic activities of 27 CYP3A4 variants on saxagliptin metabolism in vitro, which were identified in human CYP alleles. We successfully constructed 27 kinds of wild-type and variant vectors of pFast-dual-OR-3A4 by overlap extension PCR and prepared 27 kinds of CYP3A4 highly expressed cell microsomes by baculovirus insect cell expression system. The ultra-performance liquid chromatography tandem mass spectrometry (UPLC-MS/MS) was used to detect the concentrations of the metabolite of saxagliptin (5-hydroxysaxagliptin) and the internal standard. Compared with the wild-type CYP3A4.1, the intrinsic clearance values of most varieties decreased to 1.91%-77.08%. Most of these varieties showed a decrease in V<sub>max</sub> and an increase in Km values compared with wild type. We are the first to report the vitro metabolic data of 27 CYP3A4 variants of the metabolism of saxagliptin which can deepen our understanding of individualized drug use by combining previous studies about the effects of CYP3A4 variants of drug metabolism. With further in vivo studies, we hope it can guide individualized drug use in the clinic when the variants with low metabolic activity to saxagliptin were sequenced in the human body.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Société Française de Pharmacologie et de Thérapeutique.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Key Laboratory of Geriatrics, Beijing Institute of Geriatrics, Beijing Hospital, National Center of Gerontology, National Health Commission, Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ou-Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qiu-Geng</ForeName>
            <Initials>QG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian-Meng</ForeName>
            <Initials>QM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oncology, NHC Key Laboratory of Cancer Proteomics, XiangYa Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiang-Ran</ForeName>
            <Initials>XR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ya-Qing</ForeName>
            <Initials>YQ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Key Laboratory of Geriatrics, Beijing Institute of Geriatrics, Beijing Hospital, National Center of Gerontology, National Health Commission, Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ying-Hui</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ren-Ai</ForeName>
            <Initials>RA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, The First Affiliated Hospital of Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dong-Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>DD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guo-Xin</ForeName>
            <Initials>GX</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5169-4696</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Pharmacy, Wenzhou Medical University, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jian-Ping</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Key Laboratory of Geriatrics, Beijing Institute of Geriatrics, Beijing Hospital, National Center of Gerontology, National Health Commission, Institute of Geriatric Medicine, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Fundam Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8710411</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0767-3981</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D004151">Dipeptides</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>9GB927LAJW</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C502994">saxagliptin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 1.14.14.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051544">Cytochrome P-450 CYP3A</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 1.14.14.55</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C510163">CYP3A4 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>PJY633525U</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000218">Adamantane</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000218" MajorTopicYN="N">Adamantane</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="N">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000493" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacokinetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002853" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromatography, Liquid</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cytochrome P-450 CYP3A</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004151" MajorTopicYN="N">Dipeptides</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053719" MajorTopicYN="N">Tandem Mass Spectrometry</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CYP3A4</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genetic polymorphism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">personalized treatment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">saxagliptin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961299</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/fcp.12693</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Administration F.A.D. FDA drug safety communication: FDA adds warnings about heart failure risk to labels of type 2 diabetes medicines containing saxagliptin and alogliptin; 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Administration F.A.D. FDA drug safety communication: FDA warns that DPP-4 inhibitors for type 2 diabetes may cause severe joint pain; 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim Y, Kim S, Han S, Kim D, Lee K, Kim H. Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitors and the risk of pancreatitis in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus: a population-based cohort study. Journal of diabetes research. 2018;2018:5246976.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su H, Boulton DW, Barros A et al. Characterization of the in vitro and in vivo metabolism and disposition and cytochrome P450 inhibition/induction profile of saxagliptin in human. Drug Metab Dispos. 2012;40:1345-1356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westlind A, Löfberg L, Tindberg N, Andersson T, Ingelman-Sundberg M. Interindividual differences in hepatic expression of CYP3A4: relationship to genetic polymorphism in the 5'-upstream regulatory region. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 1999;259:201-205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mittal B, Tulsyan S, Kumar S, Mittal R, Agarwal G. Cytochrome P450 in cancer susceptibility and treatment. Adv Clin Chem. 2015;71:77-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watkins P. Noninvasive tests of CYP3A enzymes. Pharmacogenetics. 1994;4:171-184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans W, Relling M. Pharmacogenomics: translating functional genomics into rational therapeutics. Science (New York, NY). 1999;286:487-491.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zanger U, Schwab M. Cytochrome P450 enzymes in drug metabolism: regulation of gene expression, enzyme activities, and impact of genetic variation. Pharmacol Ther. 2013;138:103-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu G, Dai D, Wang H et al. Systematic screening for CYP3A4 genetic polymorphisms in a Han Chinese population. Pharmacogenomics. 2017;18:369-379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu R-A, Wen J, Tang P et al. Functional characterization of 22 CYP3A4 protein variants to metabolize ibrutinib in vitro. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol. 2018;122:383-387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang P, Tang P-F, Xu R-A et al. Functional assessment of CYP3A4 allelic variants on lidocaine metabolism in vitro. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2017;11:3503-3510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang C-C, Zheng X, Liu T-H et al. Functional characterization of 21 CYP3A4 variants on amiodarone metabolism in vitro. Xenobiotica. 2019;49:120-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozdemir V, Kalow W, Tang BK et al. Evaluation of the genetic component of variability in CYP3A4 activity: a repeated drug administration method. Pharmacogenetics. 2000;10:373-388.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Corvaisier C, Capelle A, France M, Bourguignon L, Tod M, Goutelle S. Drug interactions between emergency contraceptive drugs and cytochrome inducers: literature review and quantitative prediction. Fundam Clin Pharmacol. 2021;35:208-216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masamrekh RA, Kuzikov AV, Haurychenka YI et al. In vitro interactions of abiraterone, erythromycin, and CYP3A4: implications for drug-drug interactions. Fundam Clin Pharmacol. 2020;34:120-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao J, Shi Z, Zhu S, Li GQ, Yan R, Yao M. Influences of processed rhubarbs on the activities of four CYP isozymes and the metabolism of saxagliptin in rats based on probe cocktail and pharmacokinetics approaches. J Ethnopharmacol. 2013;145:566-572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou X-Y, Hu X-X, Wang C-C et al. Enzymatic activities of CYP3A4 allelic variants on quinine 3-hydroxylation in vitro. Front Pharmacol. 2019;10:591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leow JWH, Chan ECY. Atypical Michaelis-Menten kinetics in cytochrome P450 enzymes: a focus on substrate inhibition. Biochem Pharmacol. 2019;169:113615.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sata F, Sapone A, Elizondo G et al. CYP3A4 allelic variants with amino acid substitutions in exons 7 and 12: evidence for an allelic variant with altered catalytic activity. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2000;67:48-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyazaki M, Nakamura K, Fujita Y, Guengerich FP, Horiuchi R, Yamamoto K. Defective activity of recombinant cytochromes P450 3A4.2 and 3A4.16 in oxidation of midazolam, nifedipine, and testosterone. Drug Metab Dispos. 2008;36:2287-2291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eiselt R, Domanski TL, Zibat A et al. Identification and functional characterization of eight CYP3A4 protein variants. Pharmacogenetics. 2001;11:447-458.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westlindjohnsson A, Hermann R, Huennemeyer A et al. Identification and characterization of CYP3A4*20, a novel rare CYP3A4 allele without functional activity. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2006;79:339-349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai D, Tang J, Rose R et al. Identification of variants of CYP3A4 and characterization of their abilities to metabolize testosterone and chlorpyrifos. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2001;299:825-831.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C-H, Peck K, Huang J-D et al. Screening CYP3A single nucleotide polymorphisms in a Han Chinese population with a genotyping chip. Pharmacogenomics. 2005;6:731-747.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang AN, Yu B-N, Luo C-H et al. Ile118Val genetic polymorphism of CYP3A4 and its effects on lipid-lowering efficacy of simvastatin in Chinese hyperlipidemic patients. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2005;60:843-848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukushima-Uesaka H, Saito Y, Watanabe H et al. Haplotypes of CYP3A4 and their close linkage with CYP3A5 haplotypes in a Japanese population. Hum Mutat. 2004;23:100-.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garsa AA, McLeod HL, Marsh S. CYP3A4 and CYP3A5 genotyping by Pyrosequencing. BMC Med Genet. 2005;6:19-.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apellániz-Ruiz M, Inglada-Pérez L, Naranjo MEG et al. High frequency and founder effect of the CYP3A4*20 loss-of-function allele in the Spanish population classifies CYP3A4 as a polymorphic enzyme. Pharmacogenomics J. 2015;15:288-292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner J. Intrasubject variation in elimination half-lives of drugs which are appreciably metabolized. J Pharmacokinet Biopharm. 1973;1:165-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruguerolle B. Chronopharmacokinetics. Current status. Clin Pharmacokinet. 1998;35:83-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lloberas N, Hesselink D, van Schaik R et al. Detection of a rare CYP3A4 variant in a transplant patient characterized by a tacrolimus poor metabolizer phenotype. Pharmacogenomics. 2018;19:305-310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu JY, Van Hove JL, Huang YS, Chen YT. Expression of catalytically active human multifunctional glycogen-debranching enzyme and lysosomal acid alpha-glucosidase in insect cells. Biochem Mol Biol Int. 1996;39:755-764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachar M, Park CH, Pesco-Koplowitz L, Koplowitz B, McGinn A. Absence of ethnic difference on single-dose pharmacokinetics of rivoceranib between healthy male Caucasian, Japanese, and Chinese subjects. Fundam Clin Pharmacol. 2021;35:485-495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu RA, Wen J, Tang P et al. Functional characterization of 22 CYP3A4 protein variants to metabolize ibrutinib in vitro. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol. 2017;122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
