<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">33997949</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1467-8624</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>92</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Child development</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Child Dev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Peer Effects on Early Language Development in Dual Language Learners.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2153</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2169</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2153-2169</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cdev.13588</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study investigated the vocabulary development of children (N = 547) from linguistically and socioeconomically diverse classrooms in Germany from age 3 in preschool to age 7 in Grade 1. The results showed that for dual language learners (DLLs, n = 107) growth rates in their German majority language skills varied over classrooms. Compared to monolingual children, DLLs improved faster in classrooms with higher peer-level skills in the majority language than DLLs in classrooms with lower peer-level skills (controlling for socioeconomic status and classroom quality). DLLs showed stronger growth dynamics than monolingual children during later preschool stages. The findings highlight the role of preschool peers in DLLs' acquisition of the majority language before entering elementary school.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Author. Child Development published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Society for Research in Child Development.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schmerse</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5799-6724</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Leibniz Institute for Science and Mathematics Education.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Child Dev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372725</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0009-3920</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002663" MajorTopicYN="N">Child Language</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007802" MajorTopicYN="N">Language</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007804" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Development</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007807" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019303" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multilingualism</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014825" MajorTopicYN="N">Vocabulary</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>31</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33997949</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cdev.13588</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkins-Burnett, S., Xue, Y., &amp; Aikens, N. (2017). Peer effects on children’s expressive vocabulary development using conceptual scoring in linguistically diverse preschools. Early Education and Development, 28, 901-920. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2017.1295585</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnett, S. W., Yarosz, D. J., Thomas, J., Jung, K., &amp; Blanco, D. (2007). Two-way and monolingual English immersion in preschool education: An experimental comparison. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 22, 277-293. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2007.03.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bassok, D., &amp; Galdo, E. (2016). Inequality in preschool quality? Community-level disparities in access to high-quality learning environments. Early Education and Development, 27, 128-144. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2015.1057463</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bates, D., Mächler, M., Bolker, B., &amp; Walker, S. (2015). Fitting linear mixed-effects models using lme4. Journal of Statistical Software, 67, 1-48. https://doi.org/10.18637/jss.v067.i01</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker, B., &amp; Schober, P. S. (2017). Not just any child care center? Social and ethnic disparities in the use of early education institutions with a beneficial learning environment. Early Education and Development, 28, 1011-1034. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2017.1320900</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burchinal, M., Zaslow, M., &amp; Tarullo, L. (Eds.). (2016). Quality thresholds, features, and dosage in early care and education: secondary data analyses of child outcomes. Monographs of the Society for Research in Child Development, 81(Serial No. 321). https://doi.org/10.1111/mono.12248</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buysse, V., Peisner-Feinberg, E., Páez, M., Hammer, C. S., &amp; Knowles, M. (2014). Effects of early education programs and practices on the development and learning of dual language learners: A review of the literature. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 29, 765-785. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2013.08.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byers-Heinlein, K. (2013). Parental language mixing: Its measurement and the relation of mixed input to young bilingual children’s vocabulary size. Bilingualism: Language and Cognition, 16, 32-48. https://doi.org/10.1017/S1366728912000120</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caldwell, B. M., &amp; Bradley, R. H. (2003). Home observation for measurement of the environment: Administration manual. Little Rock, AR: University of Arkansas.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, J., Justice, L. M., Tambyraja, S. R., &amp; Sawyer, B. (2020). Exploring the mechanism through which peer effects operate in preschool classrooms to influence language growth. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 53, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2020.02.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi, J. Y., Castle, S., Burchinal, M., Horm, D., Guss, S., &amp; Bingham, G. E. (2018). Peer effects on low-income children's learning and development. Journal of School Psychology, 71, 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsp.2018.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeAnda, S., Poulin-Dubois, D., Zesiger, P., &amp; Friend, M. (2016). Lexical processing and organization in bilingual first language acquisition: Guiding future research. Psychological Bulletin, 142, 655-667. https://doi.org/10.1037/bul0000042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeLay, D., Hanish, L. D., Martin, C. L., &amp; Fabes, R. A. (2016). Peer effects on Head Start children’s preschool competency. Developmental Psychology, 52, 58-70. https://doi.org/10.1037/dev0000066</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duncan, G. J., &amp; Raudenbush, S. W. (1999). Assessing the effects of context in studies of child and youth development. Educational Psychologist, 34, 29-41. https://doi.org/10.1207/s15326985ep3401_3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn, L. M., &amp; Dunn, L. M. (1997). Peabody Picture Vocabulary Test, third edition (PPVT-III). Circle Pines, MN: American Guidance Service.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durán, L., Roseth, C., Hoffman, P., &amp; Robertshaw, M. B. (2013). Spanish-speaking preschoolers’ early literacy development: A longitudinal experimental comparison of predominantly English and transitional bilingual education. Bilingual Research Journal, 36, 6-34. https://doi.org/10.1080/15235882.2012.735213</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebert, S., Lockl, K., Weinert, S., Anders, Y., Kluczniok, K., &amp; Rossbach, H. G. (2013). Internal and external influences on vocabulary development in preschool children. School Effectiveness and School Improvement, 24, 138-154. https://doi.org/10.1080/09243453.2012.749791</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edele, A., &amp; Stanat, P. (2016). The role of first-language listening comprehension in second-language reading comprehension. Journal of Educational Psychology, 108, 163-180. https://doi.org/10.1037/edu0000060</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enders, C. K. (2010). Applied missing data analysis. New York, NY: Guilford.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ertanir, B., Kratzmann, J., Frank, M., Jahreiss, S., &amp; Sachse, S. (2018). Dual language competencies of Turkish-German children growing up in Germany: Factors supportive of functioning dual language development. Frontiers in Psychology, 9, 2261. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.02261</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinosa, L. M., LaForett, D. R., Burchinal, M., Winsler, A., Tien, H. C., Peisner-Feinberg, E. S., &amp; Castro, D. C. (2017). Child care experiences among dual language learners in the United States: Analyses of the Early Childhood Longitudinal Study-Birth Cohort. AERA Open. https://doi.org/10.1177/2332858417699380</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Child Care and Education (ECCE) Study Group. (1999). School-age assessment of child development: Long-term impact of pre-school experiences on school success, and family-school relationships. Final report. Brussels, Belgium: European Union.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Floccia, C., Sambrook, T. D., Delle Luche, C., Kwok, R., Goslin, J., White, L., … Plunkett, K. (2018). III: Analyses and results for study 1: Estimating the effect of linguistic distance on vocabulary development. Monographs of the Society for Research in Child Development, 83(Serial No. 328), 43-60. https://doi.org/10.1111/mono.12350</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster, T. J., Burchinal, M., &amp; Yazejian, N. (2020). The relation between classroom age composition and children’s language and behavioral outcomes: Examining peer effects. Child Development. https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.13410</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox-Boyer, A. V. (2006). TROG-D: Test zur Überprüfung des Grammatikverständnisses [German version of the test for reception of grammar]. Idstein, Germany: Schulz-Kirchner.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franco, X., Bryant, D. M., Gillanders, C., Castro, D. C., Zepeda, M., &amp; Willoughby, M. T. (2019). Examining linguistic interactions of dual language learners using the Language Interaction Snapshot (LISn). Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 48, 50-61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2019.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganzeboom, H. B., &amp; Treiman, D. J. (1996). Internationally comparable measures of occupational status for the 1988 International Standard Classification of Occupations. Social Science Research, 25, 201-239. https://doi.org/10.1006/SSRE.1996.0010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia, E. B. (2018). The classroom language context and English and Spanish vocabulary development among dual language learners attending Head Start. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 42, 148-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2017.09.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grøver, V., Rydland, V., Gustafsson, J. E., &amp; Snow, C. E. (2020). Shared book reading in preschool supports bilingual children’s second-language learning: A cluster-randomized trial. Child Development, 91, 2192-2210. https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.13348</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grund, S., Robitzsch, A., &amp; Lüdtke, O. (2018). mitml: Tools for multiple imputation in multilevel modeling (R package version 0.3-6). https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=mitml</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hachfeld, A., Anders, Y., Kuger, S., &amp; Smidt, W. (2016). Triggering parental involvement for parents of different language backgrounds: The role of types of partnership activities and preschool characteristics. Early Child Development and Care, 186, 190-211. https://doi.org/10.1080/03004430.2015.1007370</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer, C. S., Hoff, E., Uchikoshi, Y., Gillanders, C., Castro, D. C., &amp; Sandilos, L. E. (2014). The language and literacy development of young dual language learners: A critical review. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 29, 715-733. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2014.05.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harms, T., Clifford, R. M., &amp; Cryer, D. (1998). Early Childhood Environment Rating Scale (Rev. ed.). New York, NY: Teachers College Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry, G. T., &amp; Rickman, D. K. (2007). Do peers influence children's skill development in preschool? Economics of Education Review, 26, 100-112. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.econedurev.2005.09.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoff, E. (2013). Interpreting the early language trajectories of children from low-SES and language minority homes: Implications for closing achievement gaps. Developmental Psychology, 49, 4-14. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0027238</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Højen, A., Hoff, E., Bleses, D., &amp; Dale, P. S. (2021). The relation of home literacy environments to language and preliteracy skills in single-and dual-language children in Danish childcare. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 55, 312-325. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2020.12.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hussar, B., Zhang, J., Hein, S., Wang, K., Roberts, A., Cui, J., … Dilig, R. (2020). The condition of education 2020 (NCES 2020-144). U.S. Department of Education. Washington, DC: National Center for Education Statistics. Retrieved from https://nces.ed.gov/pubsearch/pubsinfo.asp?pubid=2020144</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jahreiß, S., Ertanir, B., Sachse, S., &amp; Kratzmann, J. (2018). Language interaction in German early child education and care with a high amount of multilingual children. Forschung Sprache, 6, 32-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Justice, L. M., Petscher, Y., Schatschneider, C., &amp; Mashburn, A. (2011). Peer effects in preschool classrooms: Is children’s language growth associated with their classmates’ skills? Child Development, 82, 1768-1777. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8624.2011.01665.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kachi, Y., Kato, T., &amp; Kawachi, I. (2020). Socio-economic disparities in early childhood education enrollment: Japanese population-based study. Journal of Epidemiology, 30, 143-150. https://doi.org/10.2188/jea.JE20180216</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keys, T. D., Farkas, G., Burchinal, M. R., Duncan, G. J., Vandell, D. L., Li, W., … Howes, C. (2013). Preschool center quality and school readiness: Quality effects and variation by demographic and child characteristics. Child Development, 84, 1171-1190. https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.12048</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y. K., Curby, T. W., &amp; Winsler, A. (2014). Child, family, and school characteristics related to English proficiency development among low-income, dual language learners. Developmental Psychology, 50, 2600-2613. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0038050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohl, K., Willard, J. A., Agache, A., Bihler, L. M., &amp; Leyendecker, B. (2019). Classroom quality, classroom composition, and age at entry: Experiences in early childhood education and care and single and dual language learners’ German vocabulary. AERA Open, 5, 2332858419832513. https://doi.org/10.1177/2332858419832513</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuger, S., Kluczniok, K., Kaplan, D., &amp; Rossbach, H.-G. (2016). Stability and patterns of classroom quality in German early childhood education and care. School Effectiveness and School Improvement, 27, 418-440. https://doi.org/10.1080/09243453.2015.1112815</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuger, S., Pflieger, K., &amp; Roßbach, H. G. (2005). Familieneinschätzskala [Family Assessment Scale]. Bamberg, Germany: University of Bamberg.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larson, A. L., Cycyk, L. M., Carta, J. J., Hammer, C. S., Baralt, M., Uchikoshi, Y., … Wood, C. (2020). A systematic review of language-focused interventions for young children from culturally and linguistically diverse backgrounds. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 50, 157-178. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2019.06.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Limlingan, M. C., McWayne, C. M., Sanders, E. A., &amp; López, M. L. (2020). Classroom language contexts as predictors of Latinx preschool dual language learners’ school readiness. American Educational Research Journal, 57, 339-370. https://doi.org/10.3102/0002831219855694</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lüdecke, D. (2018). sjPlot: Data visualization for statistics in social science (R package version, 2.1). https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=sjPlot</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lüdtke, O., Robitzsch, A., &amp; Grund, S. (2017). Multiple imputation of missing data in multilevel designs: A comparison of different strategies. Psychological Methods, 22, 141-165. https://doi.org/10.1037/met0000096</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marchman, V. A., Martinez, L. Z., Hurtado, N., Greuter, T., &amp; Fernald, A. (2017). Caregiver talk to young Spanish-English bilinguals: Comparing direct observation and parent-report measures of dual language exposure. Developmental Science, 20. https://doi.org/10.1111/desc.12425</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashburn, A. J., Justice, L. M., Downer, J. T., &amp; Pianta, R. C. (2009). Peer effects on children’s language achievement during pre-kindergarten. Child Development, 80, 686-702. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8624.2009.01291.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehta, P. D., &amp; West, S. G. (2000). Putting the individual back into individual growth curves. Psychological Methods, 5, 23-43. https://doi.org/10.1037/1082-989x.5.1.23</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mullis, I. V. S., Martin, M. O., Foy, P., &amp; Hooper, M. (2017). PIRLS 2016 international results in reading. Retrieved from http://timssandpirls.bc.edu/pirls2016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine (NASEM). (2017). Promoting the educational success of children and youth learning English: Promising futures. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OECD. (2016). PISA 2015 results: Policies and practices for successful schools (Vol. II). Paris, France: Author. https://doi.org/10.1787/9789264267510-en</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OECD. (2018). The resilience of students with an immigrant background: Factors that shape well-being. Paris, France: Author. https://doi.org/10.1787/9789264292093-en</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Passaretta, G., &amp; Skopek, J. (Eds.). (2018). Roots and development of achievement gaps. A longitudinal assessment in selected European countries (ISOTIS report D1.3). Dublin, Ireland: Trinity College Dublin.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R Core Team. (2019). R: A language and environment for statistical computing (Version 3.6.0). Vienna, Austria: Foundation for Statistical Computing.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raikes, H. H., White, L., Green, S., Burchinal, M., Kainz, K., Horm, D., … Esteraich, J. (2019). Use of the home language in preschool classrooms and first-and second-language development among dual-language learners. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 47, 145-158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2018.06.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raudenbush, S. W., &amp; Bryk, A. S. (2002). Hierarchical linear models: Applications and data analysis methods (Vol. 1). London, UK: Sage.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reid, J. L., &amp; Ready, D. D. (2013). High-quality preschool: The socioeconomic composition of preschool classrooms and children's learning. Early Education &amp; Development, 24, 1082-1111. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2012.757519</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribeiro, L. A., Zachrisson, H. D., &amp; Dearing, E. (2017). Peer effects on the development of language skills in Norwegian childcare centers. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 41, 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2017.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rice, M. L., &amp; Hoffman, L. (2015). Predicting vocabulary growth in children with and without specific language impairment: A longitudinal study from 2;6 to 21 years of age. Journal of Speech Language and Hearing Research, 58, 345. https://doi.org/10.1044/2015_jslhr-l-14-0150</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez, E. T., &amp; Tamis-LeMonda, C. S. (2011). Trajectories of the home learning environment across the first 5 years: associations with children’s vocabulary and literacy skills at prekindergarten. Child Development, 82, 1058-1075. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-8624.2011.01614.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rydland, V., Grøver, V., &amp; Lawrence, J. F. (2014). The second-language vocabulary trajectories of Turkish immigrant children in Norway from ages five to ten: The role of preschool talk exposure, maternal education, and co-ethnic concentration in the neighborhood. Journal of Child Language, 41, 352-381. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0305000912000712</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sammons, P., Sylva, K., Melhuish, E., Siraj-Blatchford, I., Taggart, B., &amp; Elliot, K. (2002). Measuring the impact of pre-school on children’s cognitive progress over the pre-school period (Technical paper 8a). London, UK: Institute of Education Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawyer, B., Atkins-Burnett, S., Sandilos, L., Scheffner Hammer, C., Lopez, L., &amp; Blair, C. (2018). Variations in classroom language environments of preschool children who are low income and linguistically diverse. Early Education and Development, 29, 398-416. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2017.1408373</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmerse, D., Anders, Y., Flöter, M., Wieduwilt, N., Roßbach, H. G., &amp; Tietze, W. (2018). Differential effects of home and preschool learning environments on early language development. British Educational Research Journal, 44, 338-357. https://doi.org/10.1002/berj.3332</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmerse, D., &amp; Hepach, R. (2021). How socialization goals and peer social climate predict young children's concern for others: Evidence for a development shift between 2 and 4 years of age. Social Development, 30, 239-257. https://doi.org/10.1111/sode.12478</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shager, H. (2012). What role do peer effects play in early childhood education? Evidence from the 2003 Head Start family and child experiences survey (FACES). Unpublished doctoral dissertation, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slavin, R. E., Madden, N., Calderón, M., Chamberlain, A., &amp; Hennessy, M. (2011). Reading and language outcomes of a multiyear randomized evaluation of transitional bilingual education. Educational Evaluation and Policy Analysis, 33, 47-58. https://doi.org/10.3102/0162373711398127</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slot, P. L., Bleses, D., Justice, L. M., Markussen-Brown, J., &amp; Højen, A. (2018). Structural and process quality of Danish preschools: Direct and indirect associations with children’s growth in language and pre-literacy skills. Early Education and Development, 29, 581-602. https://doi.org/10.1080/10409289.2018.1452494</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slot, P. L., Leseman, P. P. M., Verhagen, J., &amp; Mulder, H. (2015). Associations between structural quality aspects and process quality in Dutch early childhood education and care settings. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 33, 64-76. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2015.06.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tietze, W., Schuster, K.-M., Grenner, K., &amp; Roßbach, H.-G. (2007). Kindergarten-Skala Revidierte Fassung (KES-R) [German version of the Early Childhood Environment Rating Scale (Rev. ed.). Weinheim, Germany: Beltz.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker, D., Sepulveda, S. J., Hoff, E., Rowe, M. L., Schwartz, I. S., Dale, P. S., … Wasik, B. H. (2020). Language intervention research in early childhood care and education: A systematic survey of the literature. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 50, 68-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2019.02.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiland, C., &amp; Yoshikawa, H. (2014). Does higher peer socio-economic status predict children's language and executive function skills gains in prekindergarten? Journal of Applied Developmental Psychology, 35, 422-432. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.appdev.2014.07.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinert, S., Roßbach, H.-G., Faust, G., Blossfeld, H.-P., &amp; Artelt, C. (2013). Bildungsprozesse, Kompetenzentwicklung und Selektionsentscheidungen im Vorschul- und Schulalter (BiKS-3-10) [Educational processes, competence development and selection decisions in preschool- and school age]. SUF Version 4. Institute for Educational Quality Improvement (IQB). https://doi.org/10.5159/IQB_BIKS_3_10_v4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilkinson, I. A., Parr, J. M., Fung, I. Y., Hattie, J. A., &amp; Townsend, M. A. (2002). Discussion: Modeling and maximizing peer effects in school. International Journal of Educational Research, 37, 521-535. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0883-0355(03)00018-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willard, J. A., Agache, A., &amp; Leyendecker, B. (2019). Classroom composition, classroom quality and German skills of very young dual language learners and German-only learners. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 49, 269-281. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2019.07.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yazejian, N., Bryant, D., Freel, K., &amp; Burchinal, M.; Educare Learning Network (ELN) Investigative Team. (2015). High-quality early education: Age of entry and time in care differences in student outcomes for English-only and dual language learners. Early Childhood Research Quarterly, 32, 23-39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecresq.2015.02.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaslow, M., Anderson, R., Redd, Z., Wessel, J., Daneri, P., Green, K., … Martinez-Beck, I. (2016). I. Quality thresholds, features, and dosage in early care and education: Introduction and literature review. Monographs of the Society for Research in Child Development, 81(Serial No. 321), 7-26. https://doi.org/10.1111/mono.12236</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
