<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34003546</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-6984</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>56</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of language &amp; communication disorders</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Lang Commun Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Prosodic skills of Spanish-speaking children with developmental language disorder.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>784</StartPage>
          <EndPage>796</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>784-796</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1460-6984.12627</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Phonological difficulties in children with developmental language disorder (DLD) are well documented. However, abilities regarding prosody, the rhythmic and melodic characteristics of language, have been less widely studied, particularly in Spanish. Moreover, the scant research findings that have been reported are contradictory. These considerations justify our new research into the question, focusing on Spanish-speaking children with DLD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS">To examine a wide range of prosodic skills among Spanish-speaking children with DLD. To analyse the relationships between prosody and other language measurements.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS &amp; PROCEDURES">Prosodic skills were assessed through the Spanish version of the Profiling Elements of Prosody in Speech-Communication (PEPS-C) battery. The performance of 19 children aged 5-11 years with DLD was compared with that of a chronological age-matched control group of 19 typically developing children. Language skills were also assessed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES &amp; RESULTS">There were significant differences between the group with DLD and the control group in terms of skills involving prosody functions and forms: turn-end and chunking signalling, contrastive focus and affect expression and understanding, discriminating and the imitation of prosodic patterns in both words and phrases.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS &amp; IMPLICATIONS">Spanish-speaking children with DLD present impairments not only when prosody interacts with language but also in the processing of prosody alone. The study results suggest that prosody is related to lexicon and grammar in children with DLD. The prosodic impairments of Spanish-speaking children with DLD could produce a negative impact on their language functioning and could also relate to their emotional and social difficulties. Consideration should therefore be given to focusing future interventions on prosodic skills in Spanish-speaking children with DLD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="WHAT THIS PAPER ADDS">What is already known on the subject Although deficits in segmental phonology have been extensively studied in DLD, relatively little research has been conducted into supra-segmental phonology, especially among speakers of Spanish. To our knowledge, only one previous study has analysed the prosodic skills of Spanish-speaking children with DLD, and this only focused on prosody while reading. No analysis was made of the use of prosody in language comprehension and expression. What this study adds to existing knowledge This is the first study to analyse competence in a wide range of prosodic skills among Spanish-speaking children with DLD by using the PEPS-C battery. Spanish-speaking children with DLD present impairments in prosody functions and forms, which are related to other language skills. What are the potential or actual clinical implications of this work? Prosodic impairments among Spanish-speaking children with DLD could contribute to explaining both their language difficulties and their socio-emotional problems. The results obtained suggest that Spanish-speaking children with DLD could benefit from interventions focused on prosody.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Calet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nuria</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Developmental and Educational Psychology, Faculty of Educational Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martín-Peregrina</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manuel Ángel</ForeName>
            <Initials>MÁ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Developmental and Educational Psychology, Faculty of Educational Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiménez-Fernández</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gracia</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Developmental and Educational Psychology, Faculty of Educational Sciences, University of Granada, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martínez-Castilla</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pastora</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2369-0641</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Developmental and Educational Psychology, Faculty of Psychology, Universidad Nacional de Educación a Distancia, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Lang Commun Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9803709</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1368-2822</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007802" MajorTopicYN="Y">Language</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Language Development Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007807" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008037" MajorTopicYN="N">Linguistics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013060" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Spanish</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">assessment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">developmental language disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">prosodic skills</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">specific language impairment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">suprasegmental phonology</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>30</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34003546</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1460-6984.12627</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguado, G., Coloma, C.J., Martínez, A.B., Mendoza, E., Montes, A., Navarro, R. &amp; Serra, M. (2015) Documento de consenso elaborado por el comité de expertos en TEL sobre el diagnóstico del trastorno. Revista de Logopedia, Foniatría y Audiología, 35, 147-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop, D. (2003) Test for the reception of grammar. London: Harcourt Assessment.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop, D.V.M., Snowling, M.J., Thompson, P.A. &amp; Greenhalgh, T. The Catalise-2 Consortium. (2017) Phase 2 of CATALISE: a multinational and multidisciplinary Delphi Consensus Study of problems with language development: terminology. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 58, 1068-1080.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caccia, M. &amp; Lorusso, M.L. (2019) When prosody meets syntax: the processing of the syntax-prosody interface in children with developmental dyslexia and developmental language disorder. Lingua, 224, 16-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conti-Ramsden, G. (2013) Commentary: increased risk of later emotional and behavioural problems in children with SLI-reflections on Yew and O'Kearney. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 54, 525-526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cumming, R., Wilson, A., Leong, V., Colling, L.J. &amp; Goswami, U. (2015) Awareness of rhythm patterns in speech and music in children with specific language impairments. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 9, 1-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demouy, J., Plaza, M., XAVIER, J., Ringeval, F., Chetouani, M., Perisse, D., Chauvin, D., Viaux, S., Golse, B., Cohen, D., &amp; Robel, L. (2011) Differential language markers of pathology in autism, pervasive developmental disorder not otherwise specified and specific language impairment. Research in Autism Spectrum Disorders, 5, 1402-1412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn, L.M. &amp; Dunn, L.M. (2010) PPVT-III Peabody: Test de Vocabulario en Imágenes-III (3rd Ed.) [Peabody Picture Vocabulary Test] (Arribas, D., Trans). (Madrid: TEA Ed.) (Original work published 1959).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher, J., Plante, E., Vance, R., Gerken, L. &amp; Glattke, T.J. (2007) Do children and adults with language impairment recognize prosodic cues? Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 50, 746-758.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujiki, M., Spackman, M., Brinton, B. &amp; Illig, T. (2008) Ability of children with language impairment to understand emotion conveyed by prosody in a narrative passage. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 43, 330-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>JordáN, N., Cuetos, F. &amp; Suárez-Coalla, P. (2019) Prosody in the reading of children with specific language impairment. Infancia y Aprendizaje, 42, 87-127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufman, A.S. &amp; Kaufman, N.L. (2000) K-BIT: Test breve de Inteligencia de Kaufman [Kaufman Brief Intelligence Test] ((Cordero, A., &amp; Calonge, I. Trans). Madrid. Spain: TEA Ed. (Original work published 1990).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kauschke, C., Renner, L. &amp; Domahs, U., (2013) Prosodic constraints on inflected words: an area of difficulty for German-speaking children with specific language impairment? Clinical Linguistics &amp; Phonetics, 27, 574-593.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonard, L.B. (2014) Children with specific language impairment. Cambridge, MA: MIT Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall, C.R., Harcourt-Brown, S., RAMUS, F. &amp; VAN DER LELY, H.K.J. (2009) The link between prosody and language skills in children with specific language impairment (SLI) and/or dyslexia. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 44, 466-488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez-Castilla, P. &amp; Peppé, S. (2008a) Developing a test of prosodic ability for speakers of Iberian Spanish. Speech Communication, 50, 900-915.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MartÍnez-Castilla, P. &amp; Peppé, S. (2008b) Intonation features of the expression of emotions in Spanish: preliminary study for a prosody assessment procedure. Clinical Linguistics &amp; Phonetics, 22, 363-370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez-Castilla, P., Stojanovik, V., Setter, J. &amp; Sotillo, M. (2012) Prosodic abilities in Spanish and English children with Williams syndrome: a cross-linguistic study. Applied Psycholinguistics, 33, 1-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mccann, J. &amp; Peppé, S. (2003) Prosody in autistic spectrum disorders: a critical review. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 38, 325-350.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendoza, E., Carballo, G., Muñoz, J. &amp; Fresneda, M.D. (2005) CEG (Test de Comprensión de Estructuras Gramaticales). Madrid: Ediciones TEA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan, J. &amp; Demuth, K., (1996) Signal to syntax. Bootstrapping from speech to grammar in early acquisition. Mahwah: Lawrence Erlbaum.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman, R., Ratner, N.B., Jusczyk, A.M., JUSCZYK, P.W. &amp; Dow, K.A. (2006) Infants’ early ability to segment the conversational speech signal predicts later language development: a retrospective analysis. Developmental Psychology, 42, 643-655.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortega-Llebaria, M. &amp; Prieto, P. (2010) Acoustic correlates of stress in central Catalan and Castilian Spanish. Language and Speech, 54, 73-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pardo, A. &amp; Ruiz, M.A. (2002) SPSS 11. Guía para el análisis de datos. Madrid: McGraw-Hill Interamericana.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peppé, S. (2009) Why is prosody in speech-language therapy so difficult? Scientific forum on prosody in speech-language pathology. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 11, 258-271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peppé, S. &amp; Mccann, J. (2003) Assessing intonation and prosody in children with atypical language development: the PEPS-C test and the revised version. Clinical Linguistics &amp; Phonetics, 17, 345-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peppé, S., Martínez-Castilla, P., COENE, M., Hesling, I., MOEN, I. &amp; Gibbon, F. (2010) Assessing prosodic disorder in five European languages. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 12, 1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peppé, S., Mccann, J., Gibbon, F., O'Hare, A. &amp; Rutherford, M. (2007) Receptive and expressive prosodic ability in children with high-functioning autism. Journal of Speech Language and Hearing Research, 50, 1015-1028.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quilis, A. (1981) Fonética acústica de la lengua española. Madrid: Gredos.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richards, S. &amp; Goswami, U. (2015) Auditory processing in specific language impairment (SLI): relations with the perception of lexical and phrasal stress. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 58, 1292-1305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richards, S. &amp; Goswami, U. (2019) Impaired recognition of metrical and syntactic boundaries in children with developmental language disorders. Brain Sciences, 9, 1-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuelsson, C. &amp; Nettelbladt, U. (2004) Prosodic problems in Swedish children with language impairment: towards a classification of subgroups. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 39, 325-343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semel, E.M., Wiig, E.H., Secord, W. &amp; Langdon, H. (2006) CELF-4, Evaluación clínica de fundamentos del lenguaje. Edición española [CELF-4, Clinical Evaluation of Language Fundamentals. Spanish edition]. (San Antonio, TX: The Psychological Corporation).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snow, D. (1998) Prosodic markers of syntactic boundaries in the speech of 4-year-old children with normal and disordered language development. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 41, 1158-1170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snow, D. (2001) Imitation of intonation contours by children with normal and disordered language development. Clinical Linguistics and Phonetics, 15, 567-584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stojanovik, V. (2011) Prosodic deficits in children with Down syndrome. Journal of Neurolinguistics, 24, 145-155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sundström, S., Lyxell, B. &amp; Samuelsson, C. (2019) Prosodic aspects of repetition in Swedish speaking children with developmental language disorder. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 21, 623-634.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van der Meulen, S., Janssen, P. &amp; Den Os, E. (1997) Prosodic abilities in children with specific language impairment. Journal of Communication Disorders, 30, 155-170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells, B. &amp; Peppé, S. (2003) Intonation abilities of children with speech and language impairments. Journal of Speech, Language and Hearing Research, 46, 5-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells, B., Peppé, S. &amp; Vance, M. (1995) Linguistic Assessment of Prosody. In: K. Grundy (eds), Linguistics in Clinical Practice. 2nd edn. London: Whurr, pp. 234-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiig, E.H., Secord, W.A., Semel, E. &amp; Langdon, H. (2009) CELF Preescolar 2: Evaluación clínica de fundamentos del lenguaje [CELF Preschool 2: Clinical evaluation of language fundamentals preschool -2]. London, UK: Pearson.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Medical Association. (2001) World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki. Ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. Bulletin of the World Health Organization, 79, 373-374.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
