<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34008328</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1708-8240</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of esthetic and restorative dentistry : official publication of the American Academy of Esthetic Dentistry ... [et al.]</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Esthet Restor Dent</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Digital scanning under rubber dam: An innovative method for making definitive impressions in fixed prosthodontics.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>976</StartPage>
          <EndPage>981</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>976-981</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jerd.12787</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To provide a comprehensive protocol for final impressions making under rubber dam isolation by using an intraoral scanner.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL CONSIDERATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Impression making after tooth preparation with rubber dam isolation are impossible with conventional physical impressions, which are not with intraoral scanners. Digital technologies have disrupted dentistry in the last decades, bringing new, straightforward, and more time-efficient protocols for dental practice.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Taking in consideration the beneficial properties of scanning under rubber dam this protocol can be highly recommended for everyday use for making definitive intraoral scans for tooth-supported restorations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The described protocol offers the possibility to make a final impression in a stress-free environment, without blood or saliva, to obtain a better visualization and scanning of the finish line, and the potential of save time on definitive impression making.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Henarejos-Domingo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Víctor</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7215-0292</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Private practice, Barcelona, Spain; and Assistant Professor, Department of Restorative Dentistry, School of Dentistry, International University of Catalunya, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Clavijo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victor</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1346-0631</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Private practice, Indaiatuba, Brazil; and Visiting Professor, Advanced Program in Operative and Adhesive Dentistry, Division of Restorative Sciences, Herman Ostrow School of Dentistry, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Blasi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Álvaro</ForeName>
            <Initials>Á</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5643-6282</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Private practice, Barcelona, Spain; and Adjunct Assistant Professor, Department of Restorative Sciences, Dental College of Georgia at Augusta University, Augusta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Madeira</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sara</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8222-9401</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Private practice, Barcelona, Spain; and Assistant Professor, Department of Integrated Dentistry Department, School of Dentistry, International University of Catalunya, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roig</LastName>
            <ForeName>Miguel</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4872-4118</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Private practice, Barcelona, Spain; and Chairman and Professor, Department of Restorative Dentistry, School of Dentistry, International University of Catalunya, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Esthet Restor Dent</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101096515</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1496-4155</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017076" MajorTopicYN="N">Computer-Aided Design</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003761" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dental Impression Technique</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011476" MajorTopicYN="N">Prosthodontics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016733" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rubber Dams</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CAD/CAM</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital dentistry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">operative dentistry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prosthodontics</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34008328</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jerd.12787</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rekow ED. Digital dentistry: the new state of the art - is it disruptive or destructive? Dent Mater. 2020;36(1):9-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mörmann WH. The evolution of the CEREC system. J Am Dent Assoc. 2006;137:7S-13S.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vandenberghe B. The digital patient - imaging science in dentistry. J Dent. 2018;74(Suppl 1):S21-S26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blatz MB, Conejo J. The current state of Chairside digital dentistry and materials. Dent Clin N Am. 2019;63(2):175-197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen GJ. Impressions are changing: deciding on conventional, digital or digital plus in-office milling. J Am Dent Assoc. 2009;140(10):1301-1304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ting-Shu S, Jian S. Intraoral digital impression technique: a review. J Prosthodont. 2015;24(4):313-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmermann M, Mehl A, Mörmann WH, Reich S. Intraoral scanning systems - a current overview. Int J Comput Dent. 2015;18(2):101-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mangano F, Gandolfi A, Luongo G, Logozzo S. Intraoral scanners in dentistry: a review of the current literature. BMC Oral Health. 2017;17(1):149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joda T, Zarone F, Ferrari M. The complete digital workflow in fixed prosthodontics: a systematic review. BMC Oral Health. 2017;17(1):124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuzbasioglu E, Kurt H, Turunc R, Bilir H. Comparison of digital and conventional impression techniques: evaluation of patients' perception, treatment comfort, effectiveness and clinical outcomes. BMC Oral Health. 2014;14:10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schepke U, Meijer HJ, Kerdijk W, Cune MS. Digital versus analog complete-arch impressions for single-unit premolar implant crowns: operating time and patient preference. J Prosthet Dent. 2015;114(3):403-406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gjelvold B, Chrcanovic BR, Korduner EK, Collin-Bagewitz I, Kisch J. Intraoral digital impression technique compared to conventional impression technique. a randomized clinical trial. J Prosthodont. 2016;25(4):282-287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chochidakis KM, Papaspyridakos P, Geminiani A, et al. Digital versus conventional impressions for fixed prosthodontics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Prosthet Dent. 2016;116(2):184-190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagarkar SR, Perdigão J, Seong WJ, Theis-Mahon N. Digital versus conventional impressions for full-coverage restorations: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Dent Assoc. 2018;149(2):139-147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahlholm P, Sipilä K, Vallittu P, Jakonen M, Kotiranta U. Digital versus conventional impressions in fixed prosthodontics: a review. J Prosthodont. 2018;27(1):35-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Hamad KQ. Learning curve of intraoral scanning by prosthodontic residents. J Prosthet Dent. 2020;123(2):277-283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandiaky ON, Le Bars P, Gaudin A, et al. Comparative assessment of complete-coverage, fixed tooth supported prostheses fabricated form digital scans or conventional impressions: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Prosthet Dent. 2020;3913(20):30498-30504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ender A, Zimmermann M, Attin T, Mehl A. In vivo precision of conventional and digital methods for obtaining quadrant dental impressions. Clin Oral Investig. 2016;20(7):1495-1504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su TS, Sun J. Comparison of marginal and internal fit of 3-unit ceramic fixed dental prostheses made with either a conventional or digital impression. J Prosthet Dent. 2016;116(3):362-367.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christen AG, Sanford C. Barnum, discoverer of the rubber dam. Bull Hist Dent. 1977;25(1):3-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Browet S, Gerdolle D. Precision and security in restorative dentistry: the synergy of isolation and magnification. Int J Esthet Dent. 2017;12(2):172-185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilbert GH, Litaker MS, Pihlstrom DJ, Amundson CW, Gordan VV, DPBRN Collaborative Group. Rubber dam use during routine operative dentistry procedures: findings from the dental PBRN. Tex Dent J. 2013;130(4):337-347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Li C, Yuan H, et al. Rubber dam isolation for restorative treatment in dental patients. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;9(9):CD009858.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Revilla-León M, Jiang P, Sadeghpour M, et al. Intraoral digital scans-part 1: influence of ambient scanning light conditions on the accuracy (trueness and precision) of different intraoral scanners. J Prosthet Dent. 2020;124(3):372-378.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Revilla-León M, Jiang P, Sadeghpour M, et al. Intraoral digital scans: part 2- influence of ambient scanning light conditions on the mesh quality of different intraoral scanners. J Prosthet Dent. 2020;124(5):575-580.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wesemann C, Kienbaum H, Thun M, et al. Does ambient light affect the accuracy and scanning time of intraoral scans? J Prosthet Dent. 2020;3913(20):30239-30240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magne P. Immediate dentin sealing: a fundamental procedure for indirect bonded restorations. J Esthet Restor Dent. 2005;17(3):144-154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magne P, Spreafico R. Deep margin elevation: a paradigm shift. Am J Esthet Dent. 2012;2:86-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reich S, Yatmaz B, Raith S. Do “cut out-rescan” procedures have an impact on the accuracy of intraoral digital scans? J Prosthet Dent. 2020;125(1):89-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
