<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34047430</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-1063</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>31</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Hippocampus</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Hippocampus</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Nitrergic modulation of neuronal excitability in the mouse hippocampus is mediated via regulation of Kv2 and voltage-gated sodium channels.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1020</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1038</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1020-1038</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hipo.23366</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Regulation of neuronal activity is a necessity for communication and information transmission. Many regulatory processes which have been studied provide a complex picture of how neurons can respond to permanently changing functional requirements. One such activity-dependent mechanism involves signaling mediated by nitric oxide (NO). Within the brain, NO is generated in response to neuronal NO synthase (nNOS) activation but NO-dependent pathways regulating neuronal excitability in the hippocampus remain to be fully elucidated. This study was set out to systematically assess the effects of NO on ion channel activities and intrinsic excitabilities of pyramidal neurons within the CA1 region of the mouse hippocampus. We characterized whole-cell potassium and sodium currents, both involved in action potential (AP) shaping and propagation and determined NO-mediated changes in excitabilities and AP waveforms. Our data describe a novel signaling by which NO, in a cGMP-independent manner, suppresses voltage-gated Kv2 potassium and voltage-gated sodium channel activities, thereby widening AP waveforms and reducing depolarization-induced AP firing rates. Our data show that glutathione, which possesses denitrosylating activity, is sufficient to prevent the observed nitrergic effects on potassium and sodium channels, whereas inhibition of cGMP signaling is also sufficient to abolish NO modulation of sodium currents. We propose that NO suppresses both ion channel activities via redox signaling and that an additional cGMP-mediated component is required to exert effects on sodium currents. Both mechanisms result in a dampened excitability and firing ability providing new data on nitrergic activities in the context of activity-dependent regulation of neuronal function following nNOS activation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. Hippocampus published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Scheiblich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hannah</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurodegenerative Disease and Geriatric Psychiatry/Neurology, University of Bonn Medical Center, Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Steinert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Joern R</ForeName>
            <Initials>JR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1640-0845</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Nottingham, School of Life Sciences, Queen's Medical Centre, Nottingham, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>MC_U132681855</GrantID>
            <Acronym>MRC_</Acronym>
            <Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency>
            <Country>United Kingdom</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Hippocampus</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9108167</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1050-9631</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051669">Shab Potassium Channels</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D061566">Voltage-Gated Sodium Channels</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="N">Hippocampus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018408" MajorTopicYN="N">Patch-Clamp Techniques</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051669" MajorTopicYN="N">Shab Potassium Channels</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061566" MajorTopicYN="Y">Voltage-Gated Sodium Channels</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">excitability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">hippocampus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">nitric oxide</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">redox signaling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">voltage-gated potassium channel</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">voltage-gated sodium channel</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34047430</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hipo.23366</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akhtar, M. W., Sunico, C. R., Nakamura, T., &amp; Lipton, S. A. (2012). Redox regulation of protein function via cysteine S-nitrosylation and its relevance to neurodegenerative diseases. International Journal of Cell Biology, 2012, 463756. https://doi.org/10.1155/2012/463756</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Artinian, L., Tornieri, K., Zhong, L., Baro, D., &amp; Rehder, V. (2010). Nitric oxide acts as a volume transmitter to modulate electrical properties of spontaneously firing neurons via apamin-sensitive potassium channels. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30(5), 1699-1711. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4511-09.2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Artinian, L., Zhong, L., Yang, H., &amp; Rehder, V. (2012). Nitric oxide as intracellular modulator: Internal production of NO increases neuronal excitability via modulation of several ionic conductances. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 36(10), 3333-3343. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2012.08260.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asada, K., Kurokawa, J., &amp; Furukawa, T. (2009). Redox- and calmodulin-dependent S-nitrosylation of the KCNQ1 channel. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 284(9), 6014-6020. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M807158200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bae, H., Kim, T., &amp; Lim, I. (2020). Effects of nitric oxide on apoptosis and voltage-gated calcium channels in human cardiac myofibroblasts. Clinical and Experimental Pharmacology &amp; Physiology, 47(1), 16-26. https://doi.org/10.1111/1440-1681.13178</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balez, R., &amp; Ooi, L. (2016). Getting to NO Alzheimer's disease: Neuroprotection versus neurotoxicity mediated by nitric oxide. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2016, 3806157. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/3806157</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batchelor, A. M., Bartus, K., Reynell, C., Constantinou, S., Halvey, E. J., Held, K. F., Dostmann, W. R., Vernon, J., &amp; Garthwaite, J. (2010). Exquisite sensitivity to subsecond, picomolar nitric oxide transients conferred on cells by guanylyl cyclase-coupled receptors. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107(51), 22060-22065. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1013147107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bean, B. P. (2007). The action potential in mammalian central neurons. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 8(6), 451-465. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn2148</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourgognon, J. M., Spiers, J. G., Robinson, S. W., Scheiblich, H., Glynn, P., Ortori, C., Bradley, S. J., Tobin, A. B., &amp; Steinert, J. R. (2021). Inhibition of neuroinflammatory nitric oxide signaling suppresses glycation and prevents neuronal dysfunction in mouse prion disease. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 118(10), e2009579118. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2009579118</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradley, S. A., &amp; Steinert, J. R. (2015). Characterisation and comparison of temporal release profiles of nitric oxide generating donors. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 245, 116-124. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneumeth.2015.02.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradley, S. A., &amp; Steinert, J. R. (2016). Nitric oxide-mediated posttranslational modifications: Impacts at the synapse. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2016, 5681036. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/5681036</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradley, S. J., Bourgognon, J. M., Sanger, H. E., Verity, N., Mogg, A. J., White, D. J., … Tobin, A. B. (2017). M1 muscarinic allosteric modulators slow prion neurodegeneration and restore memory loss. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 127(2), 487-499. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI87526</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brickley, S. G., Revilla, V., Cull-Candy, S. G., Wisden, W., &amp; Farrant, M. (2001). Adaptive regulation of neuronal excitability by a voltage-independent potassium conductance. Nature, 409(6816), 88-92. https://doi.org/10.1038/35051086</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carver, C. M., &amp; Shapiro, M. S. (2019). Gq-coupled muscarinic receptor enhancement of KCNQ2/3 channels and activation of TRPC channels in multimodal control of excitability in dentate gyrus granule cells. The Journal of Neuroscience, 39(9), 1566-1587. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1781-18.2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choudhury, N., Linley, D., Richardson, A., Anderson, M., Robinson, S. W., Marra, V., Ciampani, V., Walter, S. M., Kopp-Scheinpflug, C., Steinert, J. R., &amp; Forsythe, I. D. (2020). Kv3.1 and Kv3.3 subunits differentially contribute to Kv3 channels and action potential repolarization in principal neurons of the auditory brainstem. The Journal of Physiology, 598(11), 2199-2222. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP279668</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung, Y. H., Kim, Y. S., &amp; Lee, W. B. (2004). Distribution of neuronal nitric oxide synthase-immunoreactive neurons in the cerebral cortex and hippocampus during postnatal development. Journal of Molecular Histology, 35(8-9), 765-770. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10735-004-0667-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clementi, E., Brown, G. C., Feelisch, M., &amp; Moncada, S. (1998). Persistent inhibition of cell respiration by nitric oxide: Crucial role of S-nitrosylation of mitochondrial complex I and protective action of glutathione. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 95(13), 7631-7636. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.95.13.7631</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coetzee, W. A., Amarillo, Y., Chiu, J., Chow, A., Lau, D., McCormack, T., … Rudy, B. (1999). Molecular diversity of K+ channels. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 868, 233-285. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1999.tb11293.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cummins, T. R., Rush, A. M., Estacion, M., Dib-Hajj, S. D., &amp; Waxman, S. G. (2009). Voltage-clamp and current-clamp recordings from mammalian DRG neurons. Nature Protocols, 4(8), 1103-1112. https://doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2009.91</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>di Matteo, V., Pierucci, M., Benigno, A., Esposito, E., Crescimanno, G., &amp; di Giovanni, G. (2010). Critical role of nitric oxide on nicotine-induced hyperactivation of dopaminergic nigrostriatal system: Electrophysiological and neurochemical evidence in rats. CNS Neuroscience &amp; Therapeutics, 16(3), 127-136. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1755-5949.2010.00136.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dias, C., Lourenco, C. F., Ferreiro, E., Barbosa, R. M., Laranjinha, J., &amp; Ledo, A. (2016). Age-dependent changes in the glutamate-nitric oxide pathway in the hippocampus of the triple transgenic model of Alzheimer's disease: Implications for neurometabolic regulation. Neurobiology of Aging, 46, 84-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2016.06.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding, L., Chen, H., Diamantaki, M., Coletta, S., Preston-Ferrer, P., &amp; Burgalossi, A. (2020). Structural correlates of CA2 and CA3 pyramidal cell activity in freely-moving mice. The Journal of Neuroscience, 40(30), 5797-5806. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0099-20.2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, C. P., Wang, M., Geng, C., Hu, B., Meng, L., Xu, Y., … Hou, X. Y. (2020). Activity-induced SUMOylation of neuronal nitric oxide synthase is associated with plasticity of synaptic transmission and extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1/2 signaling. Antioxidants &amp; Redox Signaling, 32(1), 18-34. https://doi.org/10.1089/ars.2018.7669</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, J., Haak, L. L., Phillips-Tansey, E., Russell, J. T., &amp; McBain, C. J. (2000). Frequency-dependent regulation of rat hippocampal somato-dendritic excitability by the K+ channel subunit Kv2.1. Journal of Physiology, 522(Pt 1), 19-31. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-7793.2000.t01-2-00019.xm</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, J., Zhang, L., Weiser, M., Rudy, B., &amp; McBain, C. J. (1996). Developmental expression and functional characterization of the potassium-channel subunit Kv3.1b in parvalbumin-containing interneurons of the rat hippocampus. The Journal of Neuroscience, 16(2), 506-518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estes, S., Zhong, L. R., Artinian, L., Tornieri, K., &amp; Rehder, V. (2015). The role of action potentials in determining neuron-type-specific responses to nitric oxide. Developmental Neurobiology, 75(5), 435-451. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22233</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez, F. R., Rahsepar, B., &amp; White, J. A. (2018). Differences in the electrophysiological properties of mouse somatosensory layer 2/3 neurons in vivo and slice stem from intrinsic sources rather than a network-generated high conductance state. eNeuro, 5(2), ENEURO.0447-ENEU17.2018. https://doi.org/10.1523/ENEURO.0447-17.2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French, C. R., Zeng, Z., Williams, D. A., Hill-Yardin, E. L., &amp; O'Brien, T. J. (2016). Properties of an intermediate-duration inactivation process of the voltage-gated sodium conductance in rat hippocampal CA1 neurons. Journal of Neurophysiology, 115(2), 790-802. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.01000.2014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friebe, A., Mullershausen, F., Smolenski, A., Walter, U., Schultz, G., &amp; Koesling, D. (1998). YC-1 potentiates nitric oxide- and carbon monoxide-induced cyclic GMP effects in human platelets. Molecular Pharmacology, 54(6), 962-967. https://doi.org/10.1124/mol.54.6.962</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gamper, N., &amp; Ooi, L. (2015). Redox and nitric oxide-mediated regulation of sensory neuron ion channel function. Antioxidants &amp; Redox Signaling, 22(6), 486-504. https://doi.org/10.1089/ars.2014.5884</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garthwaite, J. (2016). From synaptically localized to volume transmission by nitric oxide. The Journal of Physiology, 594(1), 9-18. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP270297</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garthwaite, J. (2019). NO as a multimodal transmitter in the brain: Discovery and current status. British Journal of Pharmacology, 176(2), 197-211. https://doi.org/10.1111/bph.14532</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garthwaite, J., Southam, E., Boulton, C. L., Nielsen, E. B., Schmidt, K., &amp; Mayer, B. (1995). Potent and selective inhibition of nitric oxide-sensitive guanylyl cyclase by 1H-[1,2,4]oxadiazolo[4,3-a]quinoxalin-1-one. Molecular Pharmacology, 48(2), 184-188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghotbeddin, Z., Heysieattalab, S., Borjkhani, M., Mirnajafi-Zadeh, J., Semnanian, S., Hosseinmardi, N., &amp; Janahmadi, M. (2019). Ca(2+) channels involvement in low-frequency stimulation-mediated suppression of intrinsic excitability of hippocampal CA1 pyramidal cells in a rat amygdala kindling model. Neuroscience, 406, 234-248. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2019.03.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han, T., Tang, Y., Li, J., Xue, B., Gong, L., Li, J., Yu, X., &amp; Liu, C. (2017). Nitric oxide donor protects against acetic acid-induced gastric ulcer in rats via S-nitrosylation of TRPV1 on vagus nerve. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 2063. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-017-02275-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hockley, A., Berger, J. I., Smith, P. A., Palmer, A. R., &amp; Wallace, M. N. (2020). Nitric oxide regulates the firing rate of neuronal subtypes in the Guinea pig ventral cochlear nucleus. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 51(4), 963-983. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.14572</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoiland, R. L., Caldwell, H. G., Howe, C. A., Nowak-Fluck, D., Stacey, B. S., Bailey, D. M., … Ainslie, P. N. (2020). Nitric oxide is fundamental to neurovascular coupling in humans. The Journal of Physiology, 598, 4927-4939. https://doi.org/10.1113/JP280162</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikematsu, N., Dallas, M. L., Ross, F. A., Lewis, R. W., Rafferty, J. N., David, J. A., Suman, R., Peers, C., Hardie, D. G., &amp; Evans, A. M. (2011). Phosphorylation of the voltage-gated potassium channel Kv2.1 by AMP-activated protein kinase regulates membrane excitability. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108(44), 18132-18137. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1106201108</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jan, L. Y., &amp; Jan, Y. N. (2012). Voltage-gated potassium channels and the diversity of electrical signalling. The Journal of Physiology, 590(11), 2591-2599. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2011.224212</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jinno, S., Aika, Y., Fukuda, T., &amp; Kosaka, T. (1999). Quantitative analysis of neuronal nitric oxide synthase-immunoreactive neurons in the mouse hippocampus with optical disector. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 410(3), 398-412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jinno, S., &amp; Kosaka, T. (2002). Patterns of expression of calcium binding proteins and neuronal nitric oxide synthase in different populations of hippocampal GABAergic neurons in mice. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 449(1), 1-25. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10251</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung, H. Y., Mickus, T., &amp; Spruston, N. (1997). Prolonged sodium channel inactivation contributes to dendritic action potential attenuation in hippocampal pyramidal neurons. The Journal of Neuroscience, 17(17), 6639-6646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karimi, S. A., Hosseinmardi, N., Sayyah, M., Hajisoltani, R., &amp; Janahmadi, M. (2020). Enhancement of intrinsic neuronal excitability-mediated by a reduction in hyperpolarization-activated cation current (Ih) in hippocampal CA1 neurons in a rat model of traumatic brain injury. Hippocampus, 31, 156-169. https://doi.org/10.1002/hipo.23270</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawano, T., Zoga, V., Kimura, M., Liang, M. Y., Wu, H. E., Gemes, G., McCallum, J. B., Kwok, W. M., Hogan, Q. H., &amp; Sarantopoulos, C. D. (2009). Nitric oxide activates ATP-sensitive potassium channels in mammalian sensory neurons: Action by direct S-nitrosylation. Molecular Pain, 5, 12. https://doi.org/10.1186/1744-8069-5-12</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirizs, T., Kerti-Szigeti, K., Lorincz, A., &amp; Nusser, Z. (2014). Distinct axo-somato-dendritic distributions of three potassium channels in CA1 hippocampal pyramidal cells. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 39(11), 1771-1783. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.12526</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledo, A., Barbosa, R., Cadenas, E., &amp; Laranjinha, J. (2010). Dynamic and interacting profiles of *NO and O2 in rat hippocampal slices. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 48(8), 1044-1050. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2010.01.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledo, A., Barbosa, R. M., Gerhardt, G. A., Cadenas, E., &amp; Laranjinha, J. (2005). Concentration dynamics of nitric oxide in rat hippocampal subregions evoked by stimulation of the NMDA glutamate receptor. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 102(48), 17483-17488. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0503624102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledo, A., Lourenco, C. F., Caetano, M., Barbosa, R. M., &amp; Laranjinha, J. (2015). Age-associated changes of nitric oxide concentration dynamics in the central nervous system of Fisher 344 rats. Cellular and Molecular Neurobiology, 35(1), 33-44. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10571-014-0115-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, S., Milescu, M., Jung, H. H., Lee, J. Y., Bae, C. H., Lee, C. W., Kim, H. H., Swartz, K. J., &amp; Kim, J. I. (2010). Solution structure of GxTX-1E, a high-affinity tarantula toxin interacting with voltage sensors in Kv2.1 potassium channels. Biochemistry, 49(25), 5134-5142. https://doi.org/10.1021/bi100246u</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lien, C. C., Martina, M., Schultz, J. H., Ehmke, H., &amp; Jonas, P. (2002). Gating, modulation and subunit composition of voltage-gated K(+) channels in dendritic inhibitory interneurones of rat hippocampus. The Journal of Physiology, 538(Pt 2), 405-419. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2001.013066</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipton, S. A., Singel, D. J., &amp; Stamler, J. S. (1994). Neuroprotective and neurodestructive effects of nitric oxide and redox congeners. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 738, 382-387. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1994.tb21826.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, P. W., &amp; Bean, B. P. (2014). Kv2 channel regulation of action potential repolarization and firing patterns in superior cervical ganglion neurons and hippocampal CA1 pyramidal neurons. The Journal of Neuroscience, 34(14), 4991-5002. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1925-13.2014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Z.-B., Liu, C., Zeng, B., Huang, L.-P., &amp; Yao, L.-H. (2017). Modulation effects of cordycepin on voltage-gated sodium channels in rat hippocampal CA1 pyramidal neurons in the presence/absence of oxygen. Neural Plasticity, 2017, 2459053. https://doi.org/10.1155/2017/2459053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourenco, C. F., Ferreira, N. R., Santos, R. M., Lukacova, N., Barbosa, R. M., &amp; Laranjinha, J. (2014). The pattern of glutamate-induced nitric oxide dynamics in vivo and its correlation with nNOS expression in rat hippocampus, cerebral cortex and striatum. Brain Research, 1554, 1-11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2014.01.030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourenco, C. F., Ledo, A., Barbosa, R. M., &amp; Laranjinha, J. (2017). Neurovascular-neuroenergetic coupling axis in the brain: Master regulation by nitric oxide and consequences in aging and neurodegeneration. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 108, 668-682. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2017.04.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourenco, C. F., Santos, R. M., Barbosa, R. M., Cadenas, E., Radi, R., &amp; Laranjinha, J. (2014). Neurovascular coupling in hippocampus is mediated via diffusion by neuronal-derived nitric oxide. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 73, 421-429. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2014.05.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, Y. F., &amp; Hawkins, R. D. (2002). Ryanodine receptors contribute to cGMP-induced late-phase LTP and CREB phosphorylation in the hippocampus. Journal of Neurophysiology, 88(3), 1270-1278. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.2002.88.3.1270</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin, S. J., Shires, K. L., &amp; da Silva, B. M. (2019). Hippocampal lateralization and synaptic plasticity in the intact rat: No left-right asymmetry in electrically induced CA3-CA1 long-term potentiation. Neuroscience, 397, 147-158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2018.11.044</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martina, M., Schultz, J. H., Ehmke, H., Monyer, H., &amp; Jonas, P. (1998). Functional and molecular differences between voltage-gated K+ channels of fast-spiking interneurons and pyramidal neurons of rat hippocampus. The Journal of Neuroscience, 18(20), 8111-8125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Megias, M., Verduga, R., Fernandez-Viadero, C., &amp; Crespo, D. (1997). Neurons co-localizing calretinin immunoreactivity and reduced nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate diaphorase (NADPH-d) activity in the hippocampus and dentate gyrus of the rat. Brain Research, 744(1), 112-120. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-8993(96)01075-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misonou, H., Mohapatra, D. P., Park, E. W., Leung, V., Zhen, D., Misonou, K., Anderson, A. E., &amp; Trimmer, J. S. (2004). Regulation of ion channel localization and phosphorylation by neuronal activity. Nature Neuroscience, 7(7), 711-718. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn1260</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohapatra, D. P., Misonou, H., Pan, S. J., Held, J. E., Surmeier, D. J., &amp; Trimmer, J. S. (2009). Regulation of intrinsic excitability in hippocampal neurons by activity-dependent modulation of the KV2.1 potassium channel. Channels (Austin, Tex.), 3(1), 46-56. https://doi.org/10.4161/chan.3.1.7655</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohapatra, D. P., Park, K. S., &amp; Trimmer, J. S. (2007). Dynamic regulation of the voltage-gated Kv2.1 potassium channel by multisite phosphorylation. Biochemical Society Transactions, 35(Pt 5), 1064-1068. https://doi.org/10.1042/BST0351064</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno, H., Vega-Saenz de Miera, E., Nadal, M. S., Amarillo, Y., &amp; Rudy, B. (2001). Modulation of Kv3 potassium channels expressed in CHO cells by a nitric oxide-activated phosphatase. The Journal of Physiology, 530(Pt 3), 345-358. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-7793.2001.0345k.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Leary, T., van Rossum, M. C., &amp; Wyllie, D. J. (2010). Homeostasis of intrinsic excitability in hippocampal neurones: Dynamics and mechanism of the response to chronic depolarization. The Journal of Physiology, 588(Pt 1), 157-170. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2009.181024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ooi, L., Gigout, S., Pettinger, L., &amp; Gamper, N. (2013). Triple cysteine module within M-type K+ channels mediates reciprocal channel modulation by nitric oxide and reactive oxygen species. The Journal of Neuroscience, 33(14), 6041-6046. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4275-12.2013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palacio, S., Chevaleyre, V., Brann, D. H., Murray, K. D., Piskorowski, R. A., &amp; Trimmer, J. S. (2017). Heterogeneity in Kv2 channel expression shapes action potential characteristics and firing patterns in CA1 versus CA2 hippocampal pyramidal neurons. eNeuro, 4(4), ENEURO.0267-ENEU17.2017. https://doi.org/10.1523/ENEURO.0267-17.2017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Philippides, A., Ott, S. R., Husbands, P., Lovick, T. A., &amp; O'Shea, M. (2005). Modeling cooperative volume signaling in a plexus of nitric-oxide-synthase-expressing neurons. The Journal of Neuroscience, 25(28), 6520-6532. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1264-05.2005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pigott, B. M., &amp; Garthwaite, J. (2016). Nitric oxide is required for L-type Ca(2+) channel-dependent long-term potentiation in the hippocampus. Frontiers in Synaptic Neuroscience, 8, 17. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnsyn.2016.00017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pires da Silva, M., de Almeida Moraes, D. J., Mecawi, A. S., Rodrigues, J. A., &amp; Varanda, W. A. (2016). Nitric oxide modulates HCN channels in magnocellular neurons of the supraoptic nucleus of rats by an S-nitrosylation-dependent mechanism. The Journal of Neuroscience, 36(44), 11320-11330. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1588-16.2016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renganathan, M., Cummins, T. R., &amp; Waxman, S. G. (2001). Contribution of Na(v)1.8 sodium channels to action potential electrogenesis in DRG neurons. Journal of Neurophysiology, 86(2), 629-640. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.2001.86.2.629</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renganathan, M., Cummins, T. R., &amp; Waxman, S. G. (2002). Nitric oxide blocks fast, slow, and persistent Na+ channels in C-type DRG neurons by S-nitrosylation. Journal of Neurophysiology, 87(2), 761-775. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00369.2001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribeiro, M. A., Cabral, H. O., &amp; Costa, P. F. (2007). Modulatory effect of NO on sodium currents in a neuroblastoma cell line: Aspects of cell specificity. Neuroscience Research, 58(4), 361-370. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neures.2007.04.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, S. W., Bourgognon, J. M., Spiers, J. G., Breda, C., Campesan, S., Butcher, A., Mallucci, G. R., Dinsdale, D., Morone, N., Mistry, R., Smith, T. M., Guerra-Martin, M., Challiss, R. A. J., Giorgini, F., &amp; Steinert, J. R. (2018). Nitric oxide-mediated posttranslational modifications control neurotransmitter release by modulating complexin farnesylation and enhancing its clamping ability. PLoS Biology, 16(4), e2003611. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.2003611</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romero, J. M., &amp; Bizzozero, O. A. (2009). Intracellular glutathione mediates the denitrosylation of protein nitrosothiols in the rat spinal cord. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 87(3), 701-709. https://doi.org/10.1002/jnr.21897</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekerli, M., del Negro, C. A., Lee, R. H., &amp; Butera, R. J. (2004). Estimating action potential thresholds from neuronal time-series: New metrics and evaluation of methodologies. IEEE Transactions on Biomedical Engineering, 51(9), 1665-1672. https://doi.org/10.1109/TBME.2004.827531</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sole, L., Wagnon, J. L., &amp; Tamkun, M. M. (2020). Functional analysis of three Nav1.6 mutations causing early infantile epileptic encephalopathy. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta - Molecular Basis of Disease, 1866(12), 165959. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2020.165959</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, D., Wang, D., Yang, Q., Yan, T., Wang, Z., Yan, Y., Zhao, J., Xie, Z., Liu, Y., Ke, Z., Qazi, T. J., Li, Y., Wu, Y., Shi, Q., Lang, Y., Zhang, H., Huang, T., Wang, C., Quan, Z., &amp; Qing, H. (2020). The lateralization of left hippocampal CA3 during the retrieval of spatial working memory. Nature Communications, 11(1), 2901. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-16698-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, J. R., Chernova, T., &amp; Forsythe, I. D. (2010). Nitric oxide signaling in brain function, dysfunction, and dementia. The Neuroscientist, 16(4), 435-452. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073858410366481</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, J. R., Kopp-Scheinpflug, C., Baker, C., Challiss, R. A., Mistry, R., Haustein, M. D., … Forsythe, I. D. (2008). Nitric oxide is a volume transmitter regulating postsynaptic excitability at a glutamatergic synapse. Neuron, 60(4), 642-656. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2008.08.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, J. R., Postlethwaite, M., Jordan, M. D., Chernova, T., Robinson, S. W., &amp; Forsythe, I. D. (2010). NMDAR-mediated EPSCs are maintained and accelerate in time course during maturation of mouse and rat auditory brainstem in vitro. The Journal of Physiology, 588(Pt 3), 447-463. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2009.184317</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinert, J. R., Robinson, S. W., Tong, H., Haustein, M. D., Kopp-Scheinpflug, C., &amp; Forsythe, I. D. (2011). Nitric oxide is an activity-dependent regulator of target neuron intrinsic excitability. Neuron, 71(2), 291-305. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2011.05.037</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stomberski, C. T., Hess, D. T., &amp; Stamler, J. S. (2019). Protein S-nitrosylation: Determinants of specificity and enzymatic regulation of S-nitrosothiol-based signaling. Antioxidants &amp; Redox Signaling, 30(10), 1331-1351. https://doi.org/10.1089/ars.2017.7403</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tozer, A. J., Forsythe, I. D., &amp; Steinert, J. R. (2012). Nitric oxide signalling augments neuronal voltage-gated L-type (Ca(v)1) and P/q-type (Ca(v)2.1) channels in the mouse medial nucleus of the trapezoid body. PLoS One, 7(2), e32256. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0032256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tricoire, L., Pelkey, K. A., Daw, M. I., Sousa, V. H., Miyoshi, G., Jeffries, B., Cauli, B., Fishell, G., &amp; McBain, C. J. (2010). Common origins of hippocampal Ivy and nitric oxide synthase expressing neurogliaform cells. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30(6), 2165-2176. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5123-09.2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trimmer, J. S. (2015). Subcellular localization of K+ channels in mammalian brain neurons: Remarkable precision in the midst of extraordinary complexity. Neuron, 85(2), 238-256. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2014.12.042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turrigiano, G. G. (1999). Homeostatic plasticity in neuronal networks: The more things change, the more they stay the same. Trends in Neurosciences, 22(5), 221-227. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0166-2236(98)01341-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westenbroek, R. E., Merrick, D. K., &amp; Catterall, W. A. (1989). Differential subcellular localization of the RI and RII Na+ channel subtypes in central neurons. Neuron, 3(6), 695-704. https://doi.org/10.1016/0896-6273(89)90238-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams, S. R., &amp; Mitchell, S. J. (2008). Direct measurement of somatic voltage clamp errors in central neurons. Nature Neuroscience, 11(7), 790-798. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2137</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood, K. C., Batchelor, A. M., Bartus, K., Harris, K. L., Garthwaite, G., Vernon, J., &amp; Garthwaite, J. (2011). Picomolar nitric oxide signals from central neurons recorded using ultrasensitive detector cells. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 286(50), 43172-43181. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M111.289777</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, C. C., Ko, F. N., Kuo, S. C., Lee, F. Y., &amp; Teng, C. M. (1995). YC-1 inhibited human platelet aggregation through NO-independent activation of soluble guanylate cyclase. British Journal of Pharmacology, 116(3), 1973-1978. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476-5381.1995.tb16400.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zemankovics, R., Kali, S., Paulsen, O., Freund, T. F., &amp; Hajos, N. (2010). Differences in subthreshold resonance of hippocampal pyramidal cells and interneurons: The role of h-current and passive membrane characteristics. The Journal of Physiology, 588(Pt 12), 2109-2132. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2009.185975</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong, L. R., Estes, S., Artinian, L., &amp; Rehder, V. (2013). Nitric oxide regulates neuronal activity via calcium-activated potassium channels. PLoS One, 8(11), e78727. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0078727</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong, L. R., Estes, S., Artinian, L., &amp; Rehder, V. (2015). Cell-specific regulation of neuronal activity by endogenous production of nitric oxide. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 41(8), 1013-1024. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.12875</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
