<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34055907</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-9195</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>7</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Skin appendage disorders</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Skin Appendage Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Distinctions in the Management, Patient Impact, and Clinical Profiles of Pachyonychia Congenita Subtypes.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>194</StartPage>
          <EndPage>202</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>194-202</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000513340</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pachyonychia congenita (PC) is a rare dermatosis that confers lifelong physical and emotional morbidities in affected patients. However, the clinical findings, treatments, and psychosocial impact of this disease have not been adequately described. The International PC Research Registry (IPCRR), a multinational initiative to collect data on PC patients, has allowed an opportunity to distinguish the salient features of this disease. We aimed to characterize the breadth and extent of nail disease, treatments, and quality of life in PC patients, and to describe any significant differences in clinical presentation or treatment of PC subtypes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The most recent IPCRR patient survey data consisting of an 857-response questionnaire and a 102-response addendum were analyzed in a retrospective analysis. The survey data were collected as part of a multinational, multicenter initiative and comprise the largest representative population of PC to date. Participants (survey respondents) were included in the study based on questionnaire responses and a genetic confirmation of having a PC subtype.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 857 survey responses were collected. Genetic variations among PC subtypes influence nail disease onset and severity of symptoms. Nail disease negatively impacts patients' emotional health, especially during the adolescent and young adult years. Nail treatment tools vary little in terms of effectiveness and acquired infection rates.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION AND DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with different PC subtypes have distinct clinical nail presentations and psychosocial impact. Genetic testing should be used to confirm PC diagnoses. Further characterization of PC, especially the rarer subtypes, may allow for more individualized patient education.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Albert G</ForeName>
            <Initials>AG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>New York Medical College, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lipner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shari R</ForeName>
            <Initials>SR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Skin Appendage Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101670617</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2296-9160</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disease management</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertrophic nail dystrophy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nail disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pachyonychia congenita</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Dr. Lipner and Mr. Wu have no conflicts of interest, relevant financial activities, or relationships which could be perceived to have influenced, or that give the appearance of potentially influencing, what is written in the submitted work, to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34055907</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8138248</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000513340</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">sad-0007-0194</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cammarata-Scalisi F, Natsuga K, Toyonaga E, Nishie W, Shimizu H, Avendaño A, et al.  Early severe pachyonychia congenita subtype PC-K6a with a novel mutation in the KRT6A gene. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2017 Feb;31((2)):e94–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabogal Gómez MV, González V, Martín JM. Facial cystic lesions and onychodystrophy. Pediatr Dermatol. 2018 Jul;35((4)):517–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29984865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brill S, Sprecher E, Smith FJD, Geva N, Gruener H, Nahman-Averbuch H, et al.  Chronic pain in pachyonychia congenita: evidence for neuropathic origin. Br J Dermatol. 2018;179((1)):154–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29210461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rittié L, Kaspar RL, Sprecher E, Smith FJD. Report of the 13th Annual International Pachyonychia congenita consortium symposium. Br J Dermatol. 2017 May;176((5)):1144–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28345191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duverger O, Carlson JC, Karacz CM, Schwartz ME, Cross MA, Marazita ML, et al.  Genetic variants in pachyonychia congenita-associated keratins increase susceptibility to tooth decay. PLoS Genet. 2018 Jan 22 [cited 2019 Jul 23];14((1)):e1007168. Available from:</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5794186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29357356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duverger O, Cross MA, Smith FJD, Morasso MI. Enamel anomalies in a pachyonychia congenita patient with a mutation in KRT16. J Invest Dermatol. 2019 Jan 1;139((1)):238–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinna R, Cocco F, Campus G, Conti G, Milia E, Sardella A, et al.  Genetic and developmental disorders of the oral mucosa: epidemiology; molecular mechanisms; diagnostic criteria; management [Internet] Periodontology 2000. 2019 [cited 2019 Jul 19];80((1)):12–27. Available from:  http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/prd.12261.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/prd.12261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31090139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nico MM, Hammerschmidt M, Lourenço SV. Oral mucosal manifestations in some genodermatoses: correlation with cutaneous lesions. Eur J Dermatol. 2013 Sep;23((5)):581–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24001555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJ, Hansen CD, Hull PR, Kaspar RL, McLean WI, O'Toole E, et al.   Pachyonychia congenita. In: Adam MP, Ardinger HH, Pagon RA, Wallace SE, Bean LJ, Stephens K, et al., editors. GeneReviews® [Internet] Seattle (WA): University of Washington, Seattle; 1993 [cited 2019 Jul 2].  Available from:  http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK1280/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>What is pachyonychia congenita? [Internet]   [cited 2019 Jul 2]. Available from:  https://www.pachyonychia.org/what-is-pc/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallis T, Poole CD, Hoggart B. Can skin disease cause neuropathic pain? A study in pachyonychia congenita. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2016 Jan;41((1)):26–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26358843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan B, Byrnes K, Schwartz M, Hansen CD, Campbell CM, Krupiczojc M, et al.  Peripheral neuropathic changes in pachyonychia congenita: pain. 2016 Dec;157((12)):2843–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27776012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovgren ML, McAleer MA, Irvine AD, Wilson NJ, Tavadia S, Schwartz ME, et al.  Mutations in desmoglein 1 cause diverse inherited palmoplantar keratoderma phenotypes: implications for genetic screening. Br J Dermatol. 2017 May;176((5)):1345–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5485079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27534273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Kane AM, Jackson CP, Mahadevan M, Barber C. Laryngeal manifestations of pachyonychia congenita: a clinical case and discussion on management for the otolaryngologist. J Laryngol Otol. 2017 Jul;131((S2)):S53–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27762179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamiri M, Wilson NJ, O'Toole EA, Smith FJD. Novel mutations in desmoglein 1: focal palmoplantar keratoderma in milder phenotypes. Br J Dermatol. 2019 Sep;181((3)):618–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30822367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJD, Kreuser-Genis IM, Jury CS, Wilson NJ, Terron-Kwiatowski A, Zamiri M. Novel and recurrent mutations in keratin 1 cause epidermolytic ichthyosis and palmoplantar keratoderma. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2019 Jul;44((5)):528–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson NJ, Leachman SA, Hansen CD, McMullan AC, Milstone LM, Schwartz ME, et al.  A large mutational study in pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2011 May 1;131((5)):1018–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21326300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldberg I, Fruchter D, Meilick A, Schwartz ME, Sprecher E. Best treatment practices for pachyonychia congenita. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2014;28((3)):279–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23363249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koren A, Sprecher E, Reider E, Artzi O. A treatment protocol for botulinum toxin injections in the treatment of pachyonychia congenita-associated keratoderma. Br J Dermatol [Internet] 2019 Sep 8 [cited 2019 Oct 18] Available from:  https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/bjd.18169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.18169</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31127950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grando SA, Zachary CB. The non-neuronal and nonmuscular effects of botulinum toxin: an opportunity for a deadly molecule to treat disease in the skin and beyond. Br J Dermatol. 2018 May;178((5)):1011–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29086923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeKlotz CMC, Schwartz ME, Milstone LM. Nail removal in pachyonychia congenita: patient-reported survey outcomes. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017 May 1;76((5)):990–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28411774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ward KM, Cook-Bolden FE, Christiano AM, Çelebi JT. Identification of a recurrent mutation in keratin 6a in a patient with overlapping clinical features of pachyonychia congenita types 1 and 2. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2003;28((4)):434–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12823309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJ, Liao H, Cassidy AJ, Stewart A, Hamill KJ, Wood P, et al.  The genetic basis of pachyonychia congenita. J Investig Dermatol Symp Proc. 2005 Oct;10((1)):21–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16250206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwala MK, Schwartz ME, Smith FJ. Pachyonychia congenita: new classification and diagnosis. Indian J Dermatol. 2016;61((5)):567.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5029248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27688452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathore PK, Khullar V, Das A. Pachyonychia congenita type 1: case report and review of the literature. Indian J Dermatol. 2016;61((2)):196–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4817447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27057022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLean WH, Hansen CD, Eliason MJ, Smith FJ. The phenotypic and molecular genetic features of pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2011 May 1;131((5)):1015–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21430705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leube RE, Schwarz N. Sex matters: interfering with the oxidative stress response in pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2018 May;138((5)):1019–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29681388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerns ML, Hakim JMC, Zieman A, Lu RG, Coulombe PA. Sexual dimorphism in response to an NRF2 inducer in a model for pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2018 May;138((5)):1094–100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5912985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29277538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hobbs RP, DePianto DJ, Jacob JT, Han MC, Chung BM, Batazzi AS, et al.  Keratin-dependent regulation of Aire and gene expression in skin tumor keratinocytes. Nat Genet. 2015 Aug;47((8)):933–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4520766</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26168014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobar-Hoyos LF, Shah R, Roa-Peña L, Vanner EA, Najafian N, Banach A, et al.  Keratin-17 promotes p27KIP1 nuclear export and degradation and offers potential prognostic utility. Cancer Res. 2015 Sep 1;75((17)):3650–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26109559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lehmann SM, Leube RE, Schwarz N. Keratin 6a mutations lead to impaired mitochondrial quality control. Br J Dermatol [Internet] 2020 Mar [cited 2019 Jul 23];182((3)):636–47. Available from:  https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/bjd.18014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.18014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31004504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harmon RM, Simpson CL, Johnson JL, Koetsier JL, Dubash AD, Najor NA, et al.  Desmoglein-1/Erbin interaction suppresses ERK activation to support epidermal differentiation. J Clin Invest. 2013 Apr 1;123((4)):1556–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3613912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23524970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krupiczojc MA, O'Toole EA. Plantar pain in pachyonychia congenita. Br J Dermatol. 2018 Jul;179((1)):11–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30156287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zieman AG, Coulombe PA. Pathophysiology of pachyonychia congenita-associated palmoplantar keratoderma: new insights into skin epithelial homeostasis and avenues for treatment. Br J Dermatol [Internet] 2019 Jul 24 [cited 2019 Oct 18] Available from:  https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/bjd.18033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.18033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6814456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31021398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spaunhurst KM, Hogendorf AM, Smith FJ, Lingala B, Schwartz ME, Cywinska-Bernas A, et al.  Pachyonychia congenita patients with mutations in KRT6A have more extensive disease compared with patients who have mutations in KRT16. Br J Dermatol. 2012;166((4)):875–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22098151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gruber R, Wilson NJ, Smith FJ, Grabher D, Steinwender L, Fritsch PO, et al.  Increased pachyonychia congenita severity in patients with concurrent keratin and filaggrin mutations. Br J Dermatol. 2009 Dec;161((6)):1391–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19785597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou HL, Yang S, Gao M, Zhao XY, Zhu YG, Li W, et al.  A novel missense mutation L468Q of keratin 6a in pachyonychia congenita type 1. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2007;21((3)):351–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17309457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliason MJ, Leachman SA, Feng BJ, Schwartz ME, Hansen CD. A review of the clinical phenotype of 254 patients with genetically confirmed pachyonychia congenita. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2012 Oct 1;67((4)):680–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22264670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJD, McLean WHI. Keratin 6b variant p.Gly499Ser reported in delayed-onset pachyonychia congenita is a non-pathogenic polymorphism. J Dermatol. 2017 Dec;44((12)):e312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5724482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28815691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo K, Xiao S, Geng S, Feng Y, Zhang D, Zhou P, et al.  Delayed-onset pachyonychia congenita caused by a novel mutation in the V2 domain of keratin 6b. J Dermatol. 2014;41((1)):108–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24354895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiráková A, Rajská L, Rob F, Džambová M, Sečníková Z, Göpfertová D, et al.  First case of pachyonychia congenita in the Czech Republic: keratinizing disorder, pachyonychia congenita. Dermatol Ther. 2015 Jan;28((1)):10–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25174302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghazawi FM, Hassani-Ardakani K, Henriques L, Jafarian F. Identification of a novel substitution mutation (R103C) in the rod domain of the keratin 17 gene associated with pachyonychia congenita type 2. Int J Dermatol. 2019 Feb;58((2)):233–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29904921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiriac A, Rusu C, Murgu A, Chiriac AE, Wilson NJ, Smith FJD. First report of Pachyonychia congenita type PC-K6a in the romanian population. p. p. 4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5649033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29090033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Q, Zhang Q, Tang L, Jin L, Wang X, Kan L, et al.  A KRT16 mutation in the first Chinese pedigree with Pachyonychia congenita and review of the literatures. J Cosmet Dermatol [Internet] 2019 Mar 12 [cited 2019 Oct 18] Available from:  http://doi.wiley.com/10.1111/jocd.12905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocd.12905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30859684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terrinoni A, Smith FJ, Didona B, Canzona F, Paradisi M, Huber M, et al.  Novel and recurrent mutations in the genes encoding keratins K6a, K16 and K17 in 13 cases of pachyonychia congenita. J Invest Dermatol. 2001 Dec 1;117((6)):1391–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11886499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leachman SA, Kaspar RL, Fleckman P, Florell SR, Smith FJ, McLean WH, et al.  Clinical and pathological features of pachyonychia congenita. J Investig Dermatol Symp Proc. 2005 Oct 1;10((1)):3–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16250204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tatiane A, Slape D, Lawless R, Frew JW. A systematic review of reported cases of pachyonychia congenita tarda. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2019 Aug;44((6)):606–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31074523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson NJ, O'Toole EA, Milstone LM, Hansen CD, Shepherd AA, Al-Asadi E, et al.  The molecular genetic analysis of the expanding pachyonychia congenita case collection. Br J Dermatol. 2014 Aug;171((2)):343–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4282083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24611874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wee JS, Smith FJ, Wilson NJ, O'Toole EA. Focal PPK secondary to a novel KRT6C mutation (Pachyonychia congenita-K6c) J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2016;30((8)):1415–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26301947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu T, Leachman SA, Wilson NJ, Smith FJ, Schwartz ME, Tang JY. Genotype-phenotype correlations among pachyonychia congenita patients with K16 mutations. J Invest Dermatol. 2011 May;131((5)):1025–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775566</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21160496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vodo D, O'Toole EA, Malchin N, Lahav A, Adir N, Sarig O, et al.  Striate palmoplantar keratoderma resulting from a missense mutation in DSG1. Br J Dermatol. 2018 Sep;179((3)):755–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6035112</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29315490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Onychomycosis: clinical overview and diagnosis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2019 Apr 1;80((4)):835–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29959961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao YA, Hickerson RP, Seegmiller BL, Grapov D, Gross MM, Bessette MR, et al.  Gene expression profiling in pachyonychia congenita skin. J Dermatol Sci. 2015 Mar;77((3)):156–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4374015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25656049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dabbagh B, Cukier O, Yeganeh M, Halal F, dos Santos BF. Pachyonychia congenita associated with a novel variant of KRT17 presenting unusual oral manifestations [internet] 2019 [cited 2019 Jul 23].  Available from:  https://www.ingentaconnect.com/content/aapd/jodc/2019/00000086/00000001/art00009%3bjsessionid=1mq8dbgaaeqm9.x-ic-live-01.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30992103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Scher RK. Onychomycosis: treatment and prevention of recurrence. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2019 Apr 1;80((4)):853–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29959962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwala M, Salphale P, Peter D, Wilson NJ, Pulimood S, Schwartz ME, et al.  Keratin 17 mutations in four families from India with Pachyonychia congenita. Indian J Dermatol. 2017;62((4)):422–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5527726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tariq S, Schmitz ML, Kanjia MK. Chronic foot pain due to pachyonychia congenita in a pediatric patient: a successful management strategy. A A Case Rep. 2016 May;6((10)):305–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah S, Boen M, Kenner-Bell B, Schwartz M, Rademaker A, Paller AS. Pachyonychia congenita in pediatric patients: natural history, features, and impact. JAMA Dermatol. 2014 Feb 1;150((2)):146–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24132595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campanati A, Martina E, Giuliodori K, Consales V, Bobyr I, Offidani A. Botulinum toxin off-label use in dermatology: a review. Skin Appendage Disord. 2017 Mar;3((1)):39–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5465664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28612001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-Ramos J, Sendagorta-Cudós E, González-López G, Mayor-Ibarguren A, Feltes-Ochoa R, Herranz-Pinto P. Efficacy of botulinum toxin in pachyonychia congenita type 1: report of two new cases: efficacy of botulinum toxin in pachyonychia congenita type 1. Dermatol Ther. 2016 Jan;29((1)):32–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan B, Schröder W, Jostock R, Schwartz M, Rosson G, Polydefkis M. Nociceptin/orphanin FQ opioid peptide-receptor expression in pachyonychia congenita. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2018 Dec;23((4)):241–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30255608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teng JMC, Bartholomew FB, Patel V, Sun G. Novel treatment of painful plantar keratoderma in pachyonychia congenita using topical sirolimus. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2018 Dec;43((8)):968–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29882237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdollahimajd F, Rajabi F, Shahidi-Dadras M, Saket S, Youssefian L, Vahidnezhad H, et al.  Pachyonychia congenita: a case report of a successful treatment with rosuvastatin in a patient with a KRT6A mutation. Br J Dermatol. 2019 Sep;181((3)):584–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30307612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Darouti MA, Marzouk SA, Nabil N, Abdel-Halim MRE, El‐Komy MHM, Abdel‐Latif M. Pachyonychia congenita: treatment of the thickened nails and palmoplantar circumscribed callosities with urea 40% paste. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2006;20((5)):615–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16684301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith FJ, Hansen CD, Hull PR, Kaspar RL, McLean WI, O'Toole E, et al.   Pachyonychia congenita. In: Adam MP, Ardinger HH, Pagon RA, Wallace SE, Bean LJ, Stephens K, et al., editors. GeneReviews®. University of Washington, Seattle; 1993. </Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
