<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34053067</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>600</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of physiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Daily changes in neuronal activities of the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus under standard and high-fat diet.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>733</StartPage>
          <EndPage>749</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>733-749</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP281596</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Recently, we found that the dorsal vagal complex displays autonomous circadian timekeeping properties  The dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus (DMV) is an executory part of this complex - a source of parasympathetic innervation of the gastrointestinal tract  Here, we reveal daily changes in the neuronal activities of the rat DMV, including firing rate, intrinsic excitability and synaptic input - all of these peaking in the late day  Additionally, we establish that short term high-fat diet disrupts these daily rhythms, boosting the variability in the firing rate, but blunting the DMV responsiveness to ingestive cues  These results help us better understand daily control over parasympathetic outflow and provide evidence on its dependence on the high-fat diet ABSTRACT: The suprachiasmatic nuclei (SCN) of the hypothalamus function as the brain's primary circadian clock, but circadian clock genes are also rhythmically expressed in several extra-SCN brain sites where they can exert local temporal control over physiology and behaviour. Recently, we found that the hindbrain dorsal vagal complex possesses strong daily timekeeping capabilities, with the area postrema and nucleus of the solitary tract exhibiting the most robust clock properties. The possibility that the executory part of this complex - the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus (DMV) - also exhibits daily changes has not been extensively studied. The DMV is the source of vagal efferent motoneurons that regulate gastric motility and emptying and consequently influence meal size and energy homeostasis. We used a combination of multi-channel electrophysiology and patch clamp recordings to gain insight into effects of time of day and diet on these DMV cells. We found that DMV neurons increase their spontaneous activity, excitability and responsiveness to metabolic neuromodulators at late day and this was paralleled with an enhanced synaptic input to these neurons. A high-fat diet typically damps circadian rhythms, but we found that consumption of a high-fat diet paradoxically amplified daily variation of DMV neuronal activity, while blunting the neurons responsiveness to metabolic neuromodulators. In summary, we show for the first time that DMV neural activity changes with time of day, with this temporal variation modulated by diet. These findings have clear implications for our understanding of the daily control of vagal efferents and parasympathetic outflow.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology © 2021 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chrobok</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lukasz</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0118-2833</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Klich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jasmin D</ForeName>
            <Initials>JD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2951-3582</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jeczmien-Lazur</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jagoda S</ForeName>
            <Initials>JS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3103-2887</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pradel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kamil</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8185-9129</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Palus-Chramiec</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katarzyna</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9870-334X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sanetra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anna M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3070-4688</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Piggins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hugh D</ForeName>
            <Initials>HD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2555-9858</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Physiology, Pharmacology, and Neuroscience, Faculty of Life Sciences, University of Bristol, Bristol, BS8 1TD, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lewandowski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marian H</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1461-9392</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurophysiology and Chronobiology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Jagiellonian University in Krakow, Gronostajowa Street 9, Krakow, 30-387, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001933" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Stem</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059305" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, High-Fat</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009046" MajorTopicYN="N">Motor Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014630" MajorTopicYN="N">Vagus Nerve</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">circadian clock</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">electrophysiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">excitability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">high-fat diet</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">multi-electrode arrays</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">synaptic input</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053067</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP281596</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acuna-Goycolea C &amp; van den Pol AN (2004). Glucagon-like peptide 1 excites hypocretin/orexin neurons by direct and indirect mechanisms: implications for viscera-mediated arousal. J Neurosci 24, 8141-8152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baranauskas G (2007). Ionic channel function in action potential generation: current perspective. Mol Neurobiol 35, 129-150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baron KG &amp; Reid KJ (2014). Circadian misalignment and health. Int Rev Psychiatry 26, 139-154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baron KG &amp; Reid KJ (2015). Relationship between circadian rhythms, feeding, and obesity. In Modulation of Sleep by Obesity, Diabetes, Age, and Diet, pp. 243-253. Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belle MDC, Baño-Otalora B &amp; Piggins HD (2021). Perforated multi-electrode array recording in hypothalamic brain slices. Methods Mol Biol 2130, 263-285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belle MDC &amp; Piggins HD (2017). Circadian regulation of mouse suprachiasmatic nuclei neuronal states shapes responses to orexin. Eur J Neurosci 45, 723-732.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhagat R, Fortna SR &amp; Browning KN (2015). Exposure to a high fat diet during the perinatal period alters vagal motoneurone excitability, even in the absence of obesity. J Physiol 593, 285-303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Browne SH, Kang J, Akk G, Chiang LW, Schulman H, Huguenard JR &amp; Prince DA (2001). Kinetic and pharmacological properties of GABA A receptors in single thalamic neurons and GABA A subunit expression. J Neurophysiol 86, 2312-2322.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Browning KN, Fortna SR &amp; Hajnal A (2013). Roux-en-Y gastric bypass reverses the effects of diet-induced obesity to inhibit the responsiveness of central vagal motoneurones. J Physiol 591, 2357-2372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Browning KN, Renehan WE &amp; Travagli RA (1999). Electrophysiological and morphological heterogeneity of rat dorsal vagal neurones which project to specific areas of the gastrointestinal tract. J Physiol 517, 521-532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Browning KN &amp; Travagli RA (2014). Central nervous system control of gastrointestinal motility and secretion and modulation of gastrointestinal functions. Compr Physiol 4, 1339-1368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Challet E (2013). Circadian clocks, food intake, and metabolism. In Progress in Molecular Biology and Translational Science, pp. 105-135. Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Challet E (2015). Keeping circadian time with hormones. Diabetes, Obes Metab 17, 76-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Challet E (2019). The circadian regulation of food intake. Nat Rev Endocrinol 15, 393-405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrobok L, Jeczmien-Lazur JS, Pradel K, Klich JD, Bubka M, Wojcik M, Kepczynski M &amp; Lewandowski MH (2021a). Circadian actions of orexins on the retinorecipient lateral geniculate complex in rat. J Physiol 599, 231-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrobok L, Klich JD, Sanetra AM, Jeczmien-Lazur JS, Pradel K, Palus-Chramiec K, Kepczynski M, Piggins HD &amp; Lewandowski MH (2021b). Rhythmic neuronal activities of the rat nucleus of the solitary tract are impaired by short-term high fat diet - implications for daily control of satiety by the brainstem. bioRxiv BIORXIV/2021/433567. https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.05.06.442920.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrobok L, Northeast RC, Myung J, Cunningham PS, Petit C &amp; Piggins HD (2020). Timekeeping in the hindbrain: a multi-oscillatory circadian centre in the mouse dorsal vagal complex. Commun Biol 3, 1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrobok L, Wojcik M, Klich JD, Pradel K, Lewandowski MH &amp; Piggins HD (2021c). Phasic neuronal firing in the rodent nucleus of the solitary tract ex vivo. Front Physiol 12, 638695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clyburn C, Howe CA, Arnold AC, Lang CH, Travagli RA &amp; Browning KN (2019). Perinatal high-fat diet alters development of GABA A receptor subunits in dorsal motor nucleus of vagus. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol 317, G40-G50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clyburn C, Travagli RA &amp; Browning KN (2018). Acute high-fat diet upregulates glutamatergic signaling in the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol 314, G623-G634.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Constantinescu M (2016). The enteric nervous system. In Neuro-Immuno-Gastroenterology, pp. 23-38. Springer International Publishing, Switzerland.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz MT, Murphy EC, Sahibzada N, Verbalis JG &amp; Gillis RA (2007). A reevaluation of the effects of stimulation of the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus on gastric motility in the rat. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 292, 291-307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis SF, Derbenev A V., Williams KW, Glatzer NR &amp; Smith BN (2004). Excitatory and inhibitory local circuit input to the rat dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus originating from the nucleus tractus solitarius. Brain Res 1017, 208-217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derbenev A V., Stuart TC &amp; Smith BN (2004). Cannabinoids suppress synaptic input to neurones of the rat dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus nerve. J Physiol 559, 923-938.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engin A. (2017). Circadian rhythms in diet-induced obesity. In Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology, pp. 19-52. Springer International Publishing, Switzerland.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan A, Bechtold DA, Pot GK &amp; Johnston JD (2020). Chrono-nutrition: from molecular and neuronal mechanisms to human epidemiology and timed feeding patterns. J Neurochem 157, 53-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goo RH, Moore JG, Greenberg E &amp; Alazraki NP (1987). Circadian variation in gastric emptying of meals in humans. Gastroenterology 93, 515-518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grijalva CV &amp; Novin D (1990). The role of the hypothalamus and dorsal vagal complex in gastrointestinal function and pathophysiology. Ann N Y Acad Sci 597, 207-222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grill HJ &amp; Hayes MR (2009). The nucleus tractus solitarius: a portal for visceral afferent signal processing, energy status assessment and integration of their combined effects on food intake. Int J Obes 33, S11-S15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grill HJ &amp; Hayes MR (2012). Hindbrain neurons as an essential hub in the neuroanatomically distributed control of energy balance. Cell Metab 16, 296-309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grundy D (2015). Principles and standards for reporting animal experiments in The Journal of Physiology and Experimental Physiology. J Physiol 593, 2547-2549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guilding C &amp; Piggins HD (2007). Challenging the omnipotence of the suprachiasmatic timekeeper: Are circadian oscillators present throughout the mammalian brain?. Eur J Neurosci 25, 3195-3216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han W, Tellez LA, Perkins MH, Perez IO, Qu T, Ferreira J, Ferreira TL, Quinn D, Liu Z-W, Gao X-B, Kaelberer MM, Bohórquez D V., Shammah-Lagnado SJ, de Lartigue G &amp; de Araujo IE (2018). A neural circuit for gut-induced reward. Cell 175, 665-678.e23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hastings MH, Maywood ES &amp; Brancaccio M (2019). The mammalian circadian timing system and the suprachiasmatic nucleus as its pacemaker. Biology (Basel) 8, 13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hay M &amp; Bishop VS (1991). Effects of area postrema stimulation on neurons of the nucleus of the solitary tract. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 260, H1359-H1364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herichová I, Mravec B, Stebelová K, Križanová O, Jurkovičová D, Kvetňanský R &amp; Zeman M (2007). Rhythmic clock gene expression in heart, kidney and some brain nuclei involved in blood pressure control in hypertensive TGR(mREN-2)27 rats. Mol Cell Biochem 296, 25-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hille B (1992). Ionic Channels of Excitable Membranes. Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmes GM, Browning KN, Tong M, Qualls-Creekmore E &amp; Travagli RA (2009). Vagally mediated effects of glucagon-like peptide 1: in vitro and in vivo gastric actions. J Physiol 587, 4749-4759.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itri JN, Vosko AM, Schroeder A, Dragich JM, Michel S &amp; Colwell CS (2010). Circadian regulation of A-type potassium currents in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. J Neurophysiol 103, 632-640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnston JD (2014). Physiological responses to food intake throughout the day. Nutr Res Rev 27, 107-118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaelberer MM, Buchanan KL, Klein ME, Barth BB, Montoya MM, Shen X &amp; Bohórquez D V (2018). A gut-brain neural circuit for nutrient sensory transduction. Science 361, eaat5236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaneko K, Yamada T, Tsukita S, Takahashi K, Ishigaki Y, Oka Y &amp; Katagiri H (2009). Obesity alters circadian expressions of molecular clock genes in the brainstem. Brain Res 1263, 58-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kentish SJ, Christie S, Vincent A, Li H, Wittert GA &amp; Page AJ (2019). Disruption of the light cycle ablates diurnal rhythms in gastric vagal afferent mechanosensitivity. Neurogastroenterol Motil 31, e13711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kentish SJ, Frisby CL, Kennaway DJ, Wittert GA &amp; Page AJ (2013). Circadian variation in gastric vagal afferent mechanosensitivity. J Neurosci 33, 19238-19242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kentish SJ, Vincent AD, Kennaway DJ, Wittert GA &amp; Page AJ (2016). High-fat diet-induced obesity ablates gastric vagal afferent circadian rhythms. J Neurosci 36, 3199-3207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khaliq ZM &amp; Bean BP (2008). Dynamic, nonlinear feedback regulation of slow pacemaking by A-type potassium current in ventral tegmental area neurons. J Neurosci 28, 10905-10917.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konturek PC, Brzozowski T &amp; Konturek SJ (2011). Gut clock: implication of circadian rhythms in the gastrointestinal tract. J Physiol Pharmacol 62, 139-150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishek BJ, Xie X, Blackstone C, Huganir RL, Moss SJ &amp; Smart TG (1994). Regulation of GABAA receptor function by protein kinase C phosphorylation. Neuron 12, 1081-1095.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krowicki ZK, Burmeister MA, Berthoud HR, Scullion RT, Fuchs K &amp; Hornby PJ (2002). Orexins in rat dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus potently stimulate gastric motor function. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol 283, 465-472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kukkonen JP (2016). Orexin/hypocretin signaling. In Current Topics in Behavioral Neurosciences, pp. 17-50. Springer International Publishing, Switzerland.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin S, Storlien LH &amp; Huang XF (2000). Leptin receptor, NPY, POMC mRNA expression in the diet-induced obese mouse brain. Brain Res 875, 89-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luther JA &amp; Tasker JG (2000). Voltage-gated currents distinguish parvocellular from magnocellular neurones in the rat hypothalamic paraventricular nucleus. J Physiol 523, 193-209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMenamin CA, Travagli RA &amp; Browning KN (2018). Perinatal high fat diet increases inhibition of dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus neurons regulating gastric functions. Neurogastroenterol Motil 30, e13150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morest DK (1967). Experimental study of the projections of the nucleus of the tractus solitarius and the area postrema in the cat. J Comp Neurol 130, 277-299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Namvar S, Gyte A, Denn M, Leighton B &amp; Piggins HD (2016). Dietary fat and corticosterone levels are contributing factors to meal anticipation. Am J Physiol Regul Integr Comp Physiol 310, R711-R723.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nobunaga M, Obukuro K, Kurauchi Y, Hisatsune A, Seki T, Tsutsui M &amp; Katsuki H (2014). High fat diet induces specific pathological changes in hypothalamic orexin neurons in mice. Neurochem Int 78, 61-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pachitariu M, Steinmetz N, Kadir S, Carandini M &amp; Harris KD (2016). Kilosort: realtime spike-sorting for extracellular electrophysiology with hundreds of channels. bioRxiv; https://doi.org/10.1101/061481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul JR, Davis JA, Goode LK, Becker BK, Fusilier A, Meador-Woodruff A &amp; Gamble KL (2020). Circadian regulation of membrane physiology in neural oscillators throughout the brain. Eur J Neurosci 51, 109-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paxinos G &amp; Watson C (2007). The Rat Brain in Stereotaxic Coordinates, 6th edn.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pendergast JS, Branecky KL, Yang W, Ellacott KLJ, Niswender KD &amp; Yamazaki S (2013). High-fat diet acutely affects circadian organisation and eating behavior. Eur J Neurosci 37, 1350-1356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raab M &amp; Neuhuber WL (2007). Glutamatergic functions of primary afferent neurons with special emphasis on vagal afferents. In International Review of Cytology, pp. 223-275. Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogers RC, Mctigue DM &amp; Hermann GE (1996). Vagal control of digestion: Modulation by central neural and peripheral endocrine factors. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 20, 57-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro RE &amp; Miselis RR (1985). The central neural connections of the area postrema of the rat. J Comp Neurol 234, 344-364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi JS (2017). Transcriptional architecture of the mammalian circadian clock. Nat Rev Genet 18, 164-179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Travagli RA &amp; Anselmi L (2016). Vagal neurocircuitry and its influence on gastric motility. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol 13, 389-401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ubaldo-Reyes LM, Buijs RM, Escobar C &amp; Ángeles-Castellanos M (2017). Scheduled meal accelerates entrainment to a 6-h phase advance by shifting central and peripheral oscillations in rats. Eur J Neurosci 46, 1875-1886.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang C, Barkholt P, Nielsen JC, Thorbek DD, Rigbolt K, Vrang N, Woldbye DPD &amp; Jelsing J (2020). The dorsomedial hypothalamus and nucleus of the solitary tract as key regulators in a rat model of chronic obesity. Brain Res 1727, 146538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
