<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34096678</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1610-0387</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal der Deutschen Dermatologischen Gesellschaft = Journal of the German Society of Dermatology : JDDG</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Dtsch Dermatol Ges</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Lichen planus - a clinical guide.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>864</StartPage>
          <EndPage>882</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>864-882</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ddg.14565</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Lichen planus (LP) is a chronic lichenoid inflammatory disorder of the skin, mucosa and of the appendages. LP is classically characterized by the presence of a rich infiltration of inflammatory T cells, which migrate in the upper part of the dermis, arranged in a band-like pattern. Different sub types of the disease have been so far described. Albeit LP is clinically well defined, the disease still represents a therapeutic enigma. Especially with regard to mucosal or scalp affecting LP types, which often present a recalcitrant and treatment unresponsive course, efficacious therapeutic options are still lacking. Thus, LP represents a disease with a high psychosocial burden. Yet, development in the deciphering of LP pathogenesis reveals possible new druggable targets, thus paving the way for future therapeutic options. In this clinical guide, we summarize the current clinical knowledge and therapeutic standards and discuss the future perspective for the management of LP.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Deutsche Dermatologische Gesellschaft (DDG). Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Solimani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Farzan</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Allergology, Charité - Universitätsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Forchhammer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University Medical Center, Eberhard Karls University Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schloegl</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University Medical Center, Eberhard Karls University Tübingen, Tübingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghoreschi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kamran</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Allergology, Charité - Universitätsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meier</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katharina</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Venereology and Allergology, Charité - Universitätsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Dtsch Dermatol Ges</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101164708</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1610-0379</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000505" MajorTopicYN="N">Alopecia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lichen Planus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009092" MajorTopicYN="N">Mucous Membrane</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34096678</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ddg.14565</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaghi D, Griffin JR. Defining “Lichen”: From Greek mycology to modern dermatology. JAMA Dermatol 2016; 152(10): 1136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson E. On leichen planus. J Cutan Med Dis Skin 1869; 3: 117-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Cleach L, Chosidow O. Clinical practice. Lichen planus. N Engl J Med 2012; 366(8): 723-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litaiem N, Mansour Y, Jones M, Zeglaoui F. Dermoscopic signs of lichen planus. BMJ Case Rep 2016; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merk HF, Vanstreels L, Megahed M. [Lichenoid drug reactions]. Hautarzt 2018; 69(2): 116-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramirez P, Feito M, Sendagorta E et al. Childhood actinic lichen planus: successful treatment with antimalarials. Australas J Dermatol 2012; 53(1): e10-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alomari A, McNiff JM. The significance of eosinophils in hypertrophic lichen planus. J Cutan Pathol 2014; 41(4): 347-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knackstedt TJ, Collins LK, Li Z et al. Squamous cell carcinoma arising in hypertrophic lichen planus: a review and analysis of 38 cases. Dermatol Surg 2015; 41(12): 1411-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murzaku EC, Bronsnick T, Rao BK. Axillary lichen planus pigmentosus-inversus: dermoscopic clues of a rare entity. Diagnosis: Lichen planus pigmentosus (LPP). J Am Acad Dermatol 2014; 71(4): e119-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pock L, Jelinkova L, Drlik L et al. Lichen planus pigmentosus-inversus. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2001; 15(5): 452-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hübner F, Langan EA, Recke A. Lichen planus pemphigoides: from lichenoid inflammation to autoantibody-mediated blistering. Front Immunol 2019; 10: 1389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matos-Pires E, Campos S, Lencastre A et al. Lichen planus pemphigoides. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2018; 16(3): 335-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irvine C, Irvine F, Champion RH. Long-term follow-up of lichen planus. Acta Derm Venereol 1991; 71(3): 242-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chuang TY, Stitle L, Brashear R, Lewis C. Hepatitis C virus and lichen planus: A case-control study of 340 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol 1999; 41(5 Pt 1): 787-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shengyuan L, Songpo Y, Wen W et al. Hepatitis C virus and lichen planus: a reciprocal association determined by a meta-analysis. Arch Dermatol 2009; 145(9): 1040-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tucker SC, Coulson IH. Lichen planus is not associated with hepatitis C virus infection in patients from north west England. Acta Derm Venereol 1999; 79(5): 378-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubsam K, Schroll A, Weisenseel P et al. Lichen planus and hepatitis virus infections: causal association? J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2011; 9(6): 464-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calista D, Morri M. Lichen planus induced by hepatitis B vaccination: a new case and review of the literature. Int J Dermatol 2004; 43(8): 562-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khenaizan S. Lichen planus occurring after hepatitis B vaccination: a new case. J Am Acad Dermatol 2001; 45(4): 614-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manolache L, Seceleanu-Petrescu D, Benea V. Lichen planus patients and stressful events. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2008; 22(4): 437-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallejo MJ, Huerta G, Cerero R, Seoane JM. Anxiety and depression as risk factors for oral lichen planus. Dermatology 2001; 203(4): 303-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samman PD. The nails in lichen planus. Br J Dermatol 1961; 73: 288-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Ramos-Garcia P, Warnakulasuriya S. An appraisal of highest quality studies reporting malignant transformation of oral lichen planus based on a systematic review. Oral Dis 2020 Dec 3. [Online ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webber NK, Setterfield JF, Lewis FM, Neill SM. Lacrimal canalicular duct scarring in patients with lichen planus. Arch Dermatol 2012; 148(2): 224-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyce AE, Marshman G, Mills RA. Erosive mucosal lichen planus and secondary epiphora responding to systemic cyclosporin A treatment. Australas J Dermatol 2009; 50(3): 190-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kern JS, Technau-Hafsi K, Schwacha H et al. Esophageal involvement is frequent in lichen planus: study in 32 patients with suggestion of clinicopathologic diagnostic criteria and therapeutic implications. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2016; 28(12): 1374-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox LP, Lightdale CJ, Grossman ME. Lichen planus of the esophagus: what dermatologists need to know. J Am Acad Dermatol 2011; 65(1): 175-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schauer F, Monasterio C, Technau-Hafsi K et al. Esophageal lichen planus: towards diagnosis of an underdiagnosed disease. Scand J Gastroenterol 2019; 54(10): 1189-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng YS, Gould A, Kurago Z et al. Diagnosis of oral lichen planus: a position paper of the American Academy of Oral and Maxillofacial Pathology. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol 2016; 122(3): 332-54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McParland H, Warnakulasuriya S. Oral lichenoid contact lesions to mercury and dental amalgam - a review. J Biomed Biotechnol 2012; 2012: 589569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torrente-Castells E, Figueiredo R, Berini-Aytes L, Gay-Escoda C. Clinical features of oral lichen planus. A retrospective study of 65 cases. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal 2010; 15(5): e685-90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vesper M, Riethdorf S, Christoph E et al. [Detection of human papillomavirus (HVP)-DNA in oral manifestation of lichen planus]. Mund Kiefer Gesichtschir 1997; 1(3): 146-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halonen P, Jakobsson M, Heikinheimo O et al. Cancer risk of Lichen planus: A cohort study of 13,100 women in Finland. Int J Cancer 2018; 142(1): 18-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matta M, Kibbi AG, Khattar J et al. Lichen planopilaris: a clinicopathologic study. J Am Acad Dermatol 1990; 22(4): 594-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Handa S, Sahoo B. Childhood lichen planus: a study of 87 cases. Int J Dermatol 2002; 41(7): 423-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bevans SL, Theos AJ, Fowler PG et al. Pediatric ocular lichen planus and lichen planopilaris: One new case and a review of the literature. Pediatr Dermatol 2018; 35(6): 859-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen KN, Lehman JS, Tollefson MM. Pediatric lichen planopilaris: clinicopathologic study of four new cases and a review of the literature. Pediatr Dermatol 2015; 32(5): 621-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chieregato C, Zini A, Barba A et al. Lichen planopilaris: report of 30 cases and review of the literature. Int J Dermatol 2003; 42(5): 342-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan E, Martinka M, Ball N, Shapiro J. Primary cicatricial alopecias: clinicopathology of 112 cases. J Am Acad Dermatol 2004; 50(1): 25-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McPhie ML, Wang A, Molin S, Herzinger T. Lichen planopilaris induced by infliximab: A case report. SAGE Open Med Case Rep 2020; 8: 2050313 × 20901967.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayasekera PS, Walsh ML, Hurrell D, Parslew RA. Case report of lichen planopilaris occurring in a pediatric patient receiving a tumor necrosis factor alpha inhibitor and a review of the literature. Pediatr Dermatol 2016; 33(2): e143-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isaac M, McNeely MC. Dermatitis herpetiformis associated with lichen planopilaris. J Am Acad Dermatol 1995; 33(6): 1050-1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosina P, Chieregato C, Magnanini M, Barba A. Lichen planopilaris and autoimmune thyroiditis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2002; 16(6): 648-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson G, McMichael A, Wang SQ, Lim HW. Sunscreen and frontal fibrosing alopecia: A review. J Am Acad Dermatol 2020; 82(3): 723-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahsavari A, Riley CA, Maughan C. Graham Little Piccardi Lasseur Syndrome. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2021 Jan-. PMID: 30726015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tziotzios C, McGrath JA, Fenton DA. Nail lichen planus. J Am Acad Dermatol 2019; 80(6): e179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishizawa A, Satoh T, Yokozeki H. Close association between metal allergy and nail lichen planus: detection of causative metals in nail lesions. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2013; 27(2): e231-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hellgren L. The prevalence of lichen ruber planus in different geographical areas in Sweden. Acta Derm Venereol 1970; 50(5): 374-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd AS, Neldner KH. Lichen planus. J Am Acad Dermatol 1991; 25(4): 593-619.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li C, Tang X, Zheng X et al. global prevalence and incidence estimates of oral lichen planus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Dermatol 2020; 156(2): 172-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCartan BE, Healy CM. The reported prevalence of oral lichen planus: a review and critique. J Oral Pathol Med 2008; 37(8): 447-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermejo-Fenoll A, Sanchez-Siles M, Lopez-Jornet P et al. A retrospective clinicopathological study of 550 patients with oral lichen planus in south-eastern Spain. J Oral Pathol Med 2010; 39(6): 491-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carbone M, Arduino PG, Carrozzo M et al. Course of oral lichen planus: a retrospective study of 808 northern Italian patients. Oral Dis 2009; 15(3): 235-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meinhard J, Stroux A, Lunnemann L et al. Lichen planopilaris: Epidemiology and prevalence of subtypes - a retrospective analysis in 104 patients. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2014; 12(3): 229-35, -36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pai VV, Kikkeri NN, Sori T, Dinesh U. Graham-Little Piccardi Lasseur syndrome: an unusual variant of follicular lichen planus. Int J Trichology 2011; 3(1): 28-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yazdi AS, Rocken M, Ghoreschi K. Cutaneous immunology: basics and new concepts. Semin Immunopathol 2016; 38(1): 3-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pietschke K, Holstein J, Meier K et al. The inflammation in cutaneous lichen planus is dominated by IFN-Upsilon and IL-21-A basis for therapeutic JAK1 inhibition. Exp Dermatol 2021; 30(2): 262-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shao S, Tsoi LC, Sarkar MK et al. IFN-gamma enhances cell-mediated cytotoxicity against keratinocytes via JAK2/STAT1 in lichen planus. Sci Transl Med 2019; 11(511).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves de Medeiros AK, Speeckaert R, Desmet E et al. JAK3 as an Emerging Target for Topical Treatment of Inflammatory Skin Diseases. PLoS One 2016; 11(10): e0164080.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solimani F, Meier K, Ghoreschi K. Emerging Topical and Systemic JAK Inhibitors in Dermatology. Front Immunol 2019; 10: 2847.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javvadi LR, Parachuru VP, Milne TJ et al. Regulatory T-cells and IL17A(+) cells infiltrate oral lichen planus lesions. Pathology 2016; 48(6): 564-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou L, Cao T, Wang Y et al. Frequently increased but functionally impaired CD4+CD25+ regulatory T cells in patients with oral lichen planus. Inflammation 2016; 39(3): 1205-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang K, Miao T, Lu W et al. Analysis of oral microbial community and Th17-associated cytokines in saliva of patients with oral lichen planus. Microbiol Immunol 2015; 59(3): 105-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu R, Zeng X, Han Q et al. Overexpression and selectively regulatory roles of IL-23/IL-17 axis in the lesions of oral lichen planus. Mediators Inflamm 2014; 2014: 701094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pouralibaba F, Babaloo Z, Pakdel F, Aghazadeh M. Serum level of interleukin 17 in patients with erosive and non erosive oral lichen planus. J Dent Res Dent Clin Dent Prospects 2013; 7(2): 91-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge X, Xie H, Nguyen T et al. Renin promotes STAT4 phosphorylation to induce IL-17 production in keratinocytes of oral lichen planus. iScience 2020; 23(4): 100983.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gueiros LA, Arao T, Souza T et al. IL17A polymorphism and elevated IL17A serum levels are associated with oral lichen planus. Oral Dis 2018; 24(3): 377-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamauchi M, Moriyama M, Hayashida JN et al. Myeloid dendritic cells stimulated by thymic stromal lymphopoietin promote Th2 immune responses and the pathogenesis of oral lichen planus. PLoS One 2017; 12(3): e0173017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt T, Solimani F, Pollmann R et al. TH1/TH17 cell recognition of desmoglein 3 and bullous pemphigoid antigen 180 in patients with lichen planus. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2018; 142(2): 669-672.e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen Z, Gao X, Ma L et al. Expression of Foxp3 and interleukin-17 in lichen planus lesions with emphasis on difference in oral and cutaneous variants. Arch Dermatol Res 2014; 306(5): 441-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hobo A, Harada K, Maeda T et al. IL-17-positive mast cell infiltration in the lesional skin of lichen planopilaris: Possible role of mast cells in inducing inflammation and dermal fibrosis in cicatricial alopecia. Exp Dermatol 2020; 29(3): 273-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ross TH. Caspary-Joseph spaces: a comment on priority. Int J Dermatol 1977; 16(10): 842-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crowson AN, Magro CM, Mihm MC, Jr. Interface dermatitis. Arch Pathol Lab Med 2008; 132(4): 652-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tandon YK, Somani N, Cevasco NC, Bergfeld WF. A histologic review of 27 patients with lichen planopilaris. J Am Acad Dermatol 2008; 59(1): 91-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muramatsu K, Nishie W, Natsuga K et al. Two cases of erosive oral lichen planus with autoantibodies to desmoglein 3. J Dermatol 2016; 43(11): 1350-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gholizadeh N, Khoini Poorfar H et al. Comparison of serum autoantibodies to desmogleins I, III in patients with oral lichen planus and healthy controls. Iran J Pathol 2015; 10(2): 136-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamanaka Y, Yamashita M, Innocentini LMA et al. Direct immunofluorescence as a helpful tool for the differential diagnosis of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions. Am J Dermatopathol 2018; 40(7): 491-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kulthanan K, Jiamton S, Varothai S et al. Direct immunofluorescence study in patients with lichen planus. Int J Dermatol 2007; 46(12): 1237-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewer JD, Ekdawi NS, Torgerson RR et al. Lichen planus and cicatricial conjunctivitis: disease course and response to therapy of 11 patients. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2011; 25(1): 100-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JH, Kim SC. Paraneoplastic pemphigus: paraneoplastic autoimmune disease of the skin and mucosa. Front Immunol 2019; 10: 1259.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solimani F, Maglie R, Pollmann R et al. Thymoma-associated paraneoplastic autoimmune multiorgan syndrome-from pemphigus to lichenoid dermatitis. Front Immunol 2019; 10: 1413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escudier M, Ahmed N, Shirlaw P et al. A scoring system for mucosal disease severity with special reference to oral lichen planus. Br J Dermatol 2007; 157(4): 765-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang C, Sah D, Cho BK et al. Hydroxychloroquine and lichen planopilaris: efficacy and introduction of Lichen Planopilaris Activity Index scoring system. J Am Acad Dermatol 2010; 62(3): 387-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iraji F, Faghihi G, Asilian A et al. Comparison of the narrow band UVB versus systemic corticosteroids in the treatment of lichen planus: A randomized clinical trial. J Res Med Sci 2011; 16(12): 1578-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alsenaid A, Alamri A, Prinz JC et al. Lichen planus of the lower limbs: successful treatment with psoralen cream plus ultraviolet A photochemotherapy. Dermatol Ther 2016; 29(2): 109-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laurberg G, Geiger JM, Hjorth N et al. Treatment of lichen planus with acitretin. A double-blind, placebo-controlled study in 65 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol 1991; 24(3): 434-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woo TY. Systemic isotretinoin treatment of oral and cutaneous lichen planus. Cutis 1985; 35(4): 385-6, 90-1, 93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ioannides D, Vakirlis E, Kemeny L et al. European S1 guidelines on the management of lichen planus: a cooperation of the European Dermatology Forum with the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2020; 34(7): 1403-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radwan-Oczko M, Zwyrtek E, Owczarek JE, Szczesniak D. Psychopathological profile and quality of life of patients with oral lichen planus. J Appl Oral Sci 2018; 26: e20170146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabolli S, Bergamo F, Alessandroni L et al. Quality of life and psychological problems of patients with oral mucosal disease in dermatological practice. Dermatology 2009; 218(4): 314-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carbone M, Goss E, Carrozzo M et al. Systemic and topical corticosteroid treatment of oral lichen planus: a comparative study with long-term follow-up. J Oral Pathol Med 2003; 32(6): 323-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman S, Jr, Gorsky M, Lozada-Nur F, Giannotti K. A prospective study of findings and management in 214 patients with oral lichen planus. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol 1991; 72(6): 665-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xia J, Li C, Hong Y et al. Short-term clinical evaluation of intralesional triamcinolone acetonide injection for ulcerative oral lichen planus. J Oral Pathol Med 2006; 35(6): 327-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun SL, Liu JJ, Zhong B et al. Topical calcineurin inhibitors in the treatment of oral lichen planus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Dermatol 2019; 181(6): 1166-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gungor S, Gokdemir G, Buyukbabani N, Bahcetepe N. Squamous cell carcinoma on the lower lip after using topical calcineurin inhibitor. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2013; 11(9): 868-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niwa Y, Terashima T, Sumi H. Topical application of the immunosuppressant tacrolimus accelerates carcinogenesis in mouse skin. Br J Dermatol 2003; 149(5): 960-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castellsague J, Kuiper JG, Pottegard A et al. A cohort study on the risk of lymphoma and skin cancer in users of topical tacrolimus, pimecrolimus, and corticosteroids (Joint European Longitudinal Lymphoma and Skin Cancer Evaluation - JOELLE study). Clin Epidemiol 2018; 10: 299-310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choonhakarn C, Busaracome P, Sripanidkulchai B, Sarakarn P. The efficacy of aloe vera gel in the treatment of oral lichen planus: a randomized controlled trial. Br J Dermatol 2008; 158(3): 573-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mansourian A, Momen-Heravi F, Saheb-Jamee M et al. Comparison of aloe vera mouthwash with triamcinolone acetonide 0.1 % on oral lichen planus: a randomized double-blinded clinical trial. Am J Med Sci 2011; 342(6): 447-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salazar-Sanchez N, Lopez-Jornet P, Camacho-Alonso F, Sanchez-Siles M. Efficacy of topical Aloe vera in patients with oral lichen planus: a randomized double-blind study. J Oral Pathol Med 2010; 39(10): 735-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Divakar NM. Topical tocopherol for the treatment of reticular oral lichen planus: Randomized, double-blind crossover study - A query. Oral Dis 2018; 24(6): 1140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cosgarea R, Pollmann R, Sharif J et al. Photodynamic therapy in oral lichen planus: A prospective case-controlled pilot study. Sci Rep 2020; 10(1): 1667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lajevardi V, Ghodsi SZ, Hallaji Z et al. Treatment of erosive oral lichen planus with methotrexate. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2016; 14(3): 286-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attwa EM, Elkot RA, Abdelshafey AS, Hafez AR. Subcutaneous methotrexate versus oral form for the treatment and prophylaxis of chronic plaque psoriasis. Dermatol Ther 2019; 32(5): e13051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoke PC, Tin GB, Kim MJ et al. A randomized controlled trial to compare steroid with cyclosporine for the topical treatment of oral lichen planus. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod 2006; 102(1): 47-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bender A, Fix C, Eubel V et al. Adjuvant high-dose intravenous immunoglobulins for recalcitrant erosive oral lichen planus: mixed clinical responses. Eur J Dermatol 2018; 28(4): 496-501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paslin DA. Sustained remission of generalized lichen planus induced by cyclophosphamide. Arch Dermatol 1985; 121(2): 236-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beck HI, Brandrup F. Treatment of erosive lichen planus with dapsone. Acta Derm Venereol 1986; 66(4): 366-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falk DK, Latour DL, King LE, Jr. Dapsone in the treatment of erosive lichen planus. J Am Acad Dermatol 1985; 12(3): 567-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y, Zhou G, Zeng H et al. A randomized double-blind, positive-control trial of topical thalidomide in erosive oral lichen planus. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod 2010; 110(2): 188-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mauskar MM, Marathe K, Venkatesan A et al. Vulvar diseases: Conditions in adults and children. J Am Acad Dermatol 2020; 82(6): 1287-98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Meijden WI, Boffa MJ, Ter Harmsel WA et al. 2016 European guideline for the management of vulval conditions. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2017; 31(6): 925-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mannweiler S, Sygulla S, Beham-Schmid C et al. Penile carcinogenesis in a low-incidence area: a clinicopathologic and molecular analysis of 115 invasive carcinomas with special emphasis on chronic inflammatory skin diseases. Am J Surg Pathol 2011; 35(7): 998-1006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regauer S, Reich O, Eberz B. Vulvar cancers in women with vulvar lichen planus: a clinicopathological study. J Am Acad Dermatol 2014; 71(4): 698-707.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blazek C, Megahed M. [Lichen planopilaris. Successful treatment with tacrolimus]. Hautarzt 2008; 59(11): 874-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang CC, Khanna T, Sallee B et al. Tofacitinib for the treatment of lichen planopilaris: A case series. Dermatol Ther 2018; 31(6): e12656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gkini MA, Riaz R, Jolliffe V. A retrospective analysis of efficacy and safety of intralesional triamcinolone injections in the treatment of frontal fibrosing alopecia either as monotherapy or as a concomitant therapy. Int J Trichology 2018; 10(4): 162-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jorge AM, Melles RB, Zhang Y et al. Hydroxychloroquine prescription trends and predictors for excess dosing per recent ophthalmology guidelines. Arthritis Res Ther 2018; 20(1): 133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naeini FF, Saber M, Asilian A, Hosseini SM. Clinical efficacy and safety of methotrexate versus hydroxychloroquine in preventing lichen planopilaris progress: a randomized clinical trial. Int J Prev Med 2017; 8: 37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho BK, Sah D, Chwalek J et al. Efficacy and safety of mycophenolate mofetil for lichen planopilaris. J Am Acad Dermatol 2010; 62(3): 393-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manousaridis I, Manousaridis K, Peitsch WK, Schneider SW. Individualizing treatment and choice of medication in lichen planus: a step by step approach. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2013; 11(10): 981-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang YZ, Bundy C, Griffiths CE et al. The role of beliefs: lessons from a pilot study on illness perception, psychological distress and quality of life in patients with primary cicatricial alopecia. Br J Dermatol 2015; 172(1): 130-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saxena K, Saxena DK, Savant SS. Successful hair transplant outcome in cicatricial lichen planus of the scalp by combining scalp and beard hair along with platelet rich plasma. J Cutan Aesthet Surg 2016; 9(1): 51-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JA, Levy DA, Patel KG et al. Hair transplantation in frontal fibrosing alopecia and lichen planopilaris: a systematic review. Laryngoscope 2021; 131(1): 59-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donovan J. Lichen planopilaris after hair transplantation: report of 17 cases. Dermatol Surg 2012; 38(12): 1998-2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ekelem C, Pham C, Atanaskova Mesinkovska N. A systematic review of the outcome of hair transplantation in primary scarring alopecia. Skin Appendage Disord 2019; 5(2): 65-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McClanahan DR, English JC, 3rd. Therapeutics for adult nail psoriasis and nail lichen planus: a guide for clinicians. Am J Clin Dermatol 2018; 19(4): 559-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ujiie H, Shibaki A, Akiyama M, Shimizu H. Successful treatment of nail lichen planus with topical tacrolimus. Acta Derm Venereol 2010; 90(2): 218-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pita da Veiga G, Perez-Feal P, Moreiras-Arias N et al. Treatment of nail lichen planus with localized bath-PUVA. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed 2020; 36(3): 241-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iorizzo M, Tosti A, Starace M et al. Isolated nail lichen planus: An expert consensus on treatment of the classical form. J Am Acad Dermatol 2020; 83(6): 1717-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goettmann S, Zaraa I, Moulonguet I. Nail lichen planus: epidemiological, clinical, pathological, therapeutic and prognosis study of 67 cases. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2012; 26(10): 1304-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zychowska M, Batycka-Baran A, Baran W. Oral lichen planus with severe nail involvement in a 10-year-old boy. Acta Derm Venereol 2015; 95(3): 372-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iorizzo M, Haneke E. Tofacitinib as treatment for nail lichen planus associated with alopecia universalis. JAMA Dermatol 2021; 157(3): 352-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ismail FF, Sinclair R. Clinical healing of erosive oral lichen planus with tildrakizumab implicates the interleukin-23/interleukin-17 pathway in the pathogenesis of lichen planus. Australas J Dermatol 2020; 61(2): e244-e5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solimani F, Pollmann R, Schmidt T et al. Therapeutic targeting of Th17/Tc17 cells leads to clinical improvement of lichen planus. Front Immunol 2019; 10: 1808.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solimani F, Hilke FJ, Ghoreschi K. [Pharmacology of Janus kinase inhibitors]. Hautarzt 2019; 70(12): 934-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Damsky W, Wang A, Olamiju B et al. Treatment of severe lichen planus with the JAK inhibitor tofacitinib. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2020; 145(6): 1708-10 e2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seiringer P, Lauffer F, Pilz AC et al. Tofacitinib in hypertrophic lichen planus. Acta Derm Venereol 2020; 100(14): adv00220.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gladman D, Rigby W, Azevedo VF et al. Tofacitinib for psoriatic arthritis in patients with an inadequate response to TNF inhibitors. N Engl J Med 2017; 377(16): 1525-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee EB, Fleischmann R, Hall S et al. Tofacitinib versus methotrexate in rheumatoid arthritis. N Engl J Med 2014; 370(25): 2377-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bettencourt M. Oral lichen planus treated with apremilast. J Drugs Dermatol 2016; 15(8): 1026-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul J, Foss CE, Hirano SA et al. An open-label pilot study of apremilast for the treatment of moderate to severe lichen planus: a case series. J Am Acad Dermatol 2013; 68(2): 255-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang AL, Badger J, Rehmus W, Kimball AB. Alefacept for erosive lichen planus: a case series. J Drugs Dermatol 2008; 7(4): 379-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fivenson DP, Mathes B. Treatment of generalized lichen planus with alefacept. Arch Dermatol 2006; 142(2): 151-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheth N, Bull R, Cerio R et al. Fatal erosive lichen planus. Br J Dermatol 2006; 155(5): 1075-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irla N, Schneiter T, Haneke E, Yawalkar N. Nail lichen planus: successful treatment with etanercept. Case Rep Dermatol 2010; 2(3): 173-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yarom N. Etanercept for the management of oral lichen planus. Am J Clin Dermatol 2007; 8(2): 121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
