<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34100449</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Ki20227 aggravates apoptosis, inflammatory response, and oxidative stress after focal cerebral ischemia injury.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>137</StartPage>
          <EndPage>143</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>137-143</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.314318</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The survival of microglia depends on the colony-stimulating factor-1 receptor (CSF1R) signaling pathway under physiological conditions. Ki20227 is a highly selective CSF1R inhibitor that has been shown to change the morphology of microglia. However, the effects of Ki20227 on the progression of ischemic stroke are unclear. In this study, male C57BL/6 mouse models of focal cerebral ischemic injury were established through the occlusion of the middle cerebral artery and then administered 3 mg/g Ki20227 for 3 successive days. The results revealed that the number of ionized calcium-binding adaptor molecule 1/bromodeoxyuridine double positive cells in the infarct tissue was reduced, the degree of edema was increased, neurological deficits were aggravated, infarct volume was increased, and the number of peri-infarct Nissl bodies was reduced. The number of terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling-positive cells in the peri-infarct tissue was increased. The expression levels of Bax and Cleaved caspase-3 were up-regulated. Bcl-2 expression was downregulated. The expression levels of inflammatory factors and oxidative stress-associated factors were increased. These findings suggested that Ki20227 blocked microglial proliferation and aggravated the pathological progression of ischemia/reperfusion injury in a transient middle cerebral artery occlusion model. This study was approved by the Animal Ethics Committee of Lanzhou University Second Hospital (approval No. D2020-68) on March 6, 2020.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital; Institute of Neurology, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ze-Ning</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital; Institute of Neurology, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu-Chen</ForeName>
            <Initials>YC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital; Second Clinical Medical College, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital; Institute of Neurology, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei-Xin</ForeName>
            <Initials>WX</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ren</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hai-Jun</ForeName>
            <Initials>HJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bo-Ru</ForeName>
            <Initials>BR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Lanzhou University Second Hospital, Lanzhou, Gansu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016441">Retracted Publication</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="RetractionIn">
          <RefSource>Neural Regen Res. 2022 Oct;17(10):2165</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">35259857</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ki20227</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colony-stimulating factor-1 receptor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory response</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemia/reperfusion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transient middle cerebral artery occlusion</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34100449</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8451550</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.314318</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_1_137_314318</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Kuraishy HM, Al-Gareeb AI, Naji MT, Al-Mamorry F. Role of vinpocetine in ischemic stroke and poststroke outcomes: A critical review. Brain Circ. 2020;6:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7045535</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bieber M, Gronewold J, Scharf AC, Schuhmann MK, Langhauser F, Hopp S, Mencl S, Geuss E, Leinweber J, Guthmann J, Doeppner TR, Kleinschnitz C, Stoll G, Kraft P, Hermann DM. Validity and reliability of neurological scores in mice exposed to middle cerebral artery occlusion. Stroke. 2019;50:2875–2882.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang T, Messing RO, Chou WH. Mouse model of middle cerebral artery occlusion. J Vis Exp. 2011:2761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3197421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21372780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui J, Placzek WJ. Post-transcriptional regulation of anti-apoptotic BCL2 family members. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19:308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29361709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui SS, Feng XB, Zhang BH, Xia ZY, Zhan LY. Exendin-4 attenuates pain-induced cognitive impairment by alleviating hippocampal neuroinflammation in a rat model of spinal nerve ligation. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:1333–1339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7047783</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31960821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Datta A, Sarmah D, Mounica L, Kaur H, Kesharwani R, Verma G, Veeresh P, Kotian V, Kalia K, Borah A, Wang X, Dave KR, Yavagal DR, Bhattacharya P. Cell death pathways in ischemic stroke and targeted pharmacotherapy. Transl Stroke Res. 2020;11:1185–1202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32219729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del Rio D, Stewart AJ, Pellegrini N. A review of recent studies on malondialdehyde as toxic molecule and biological marker of oxidative stress. Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. 2005;15:316–328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16054557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dinapoli VA, Benkovic SA, Li X, Kelly KA, Miller DB, Rosen CL, Huber JD, O’Callaghan JP. Age exaggerates pro-inflammatory cytokine signaling and truncates signal transducers and activators of transcription 3 signaling following ischemic stroke in the rat. Neuroscience. 2010;170:633–644.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du X, Xu Y, Chen S, Fang M. Inhibited CSF1R alleviates ischemia injury via inhibition of microglia M1 polarization and NLRP3 pathway. Neural Plast. 2020;2020:8825954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32908485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu H, Zhao Y, Hu D, Wang S, Yu T, Zhang L. Depletion of microglia exacerbates injury and impairs function recovery after spinal cord injury in mice. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11:528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7359318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32661227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gheorghe RO, Deftu A, Filippi A, Grosu A, Bica-Popi M, Chiritoiu M, Chiritoiu G, Munteanu C, Silvestro L, Ristoiu V. Silencing the cytoskeleton protein Iba1 (ionized calcium binding adapter protein 1) interferes with BV2 microglia functioning. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2020;40:1011–1027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31950314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayakawa K, Esposito E, Wang X, Terasaki Y, Liu Y, Xing C, Ji X, Lo EH. Transfer of mitochondria from astrocytes to neurons after stroke. Nature. 2016;535:551–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4968589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27466127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillis AE, Wityk RJ, Barker PB, Beauchamp NJ, Gailloud P, Murphy K, Cooper O, Metter EJ. Subcortical aphasia and neglect in acute stroke: the role of cortical hypoperfusion. Brain. 2002;125:1094–1104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11960898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hou BR, Ju FR, Guo XM, Wang D, Cheng XF, Khan A, Zhang SX, Ren HJ. Ki20227 influences the morphology of microglia and neurons through inhibition of CSF1R during global ischemia. Int J Clin Exp Pathol. 2016;9:12459–12469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu X, Li S, Doycheva DM, Huang L, Lenahan C, Liu R, Huang J, Gao L, Tang J, Zuo G, Zhang JH. Rh-CSF1 attenuates oxidative stress and neuronal apoptosis via the CSF1R/PLCG2/PKA/UCP2 signaling pathway in a rat model of neonatal HIE. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2020;2020:6801587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7568161</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33101590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang MM, Hu Y, Wang BC, Zhang C, Xie YJ, Wang JX, Wang L, Xu FY. Bibliometric and visual analysis of international literature addressing ischemic stroke rehabilitation in recent 10 years. Zhongguo Zuzhi Gongcheng Yanjiu. 2020;25:3725–3733.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang Y, Xu Z, Xiong S, Sun F, Qin G, Hu G, Wang J, Zhao L, Liang YX, Wu T, Lu Z, Humayun MS, So KF, Pan Y, Li N, Yuan TF, Rao Y, Peng B. Repopulated microglia are solely derived from the proliferation of residual microglia after acute depletion. Nat Neurosci. 2018;21:530–540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29472620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hume DA, Gutowska-Ding MW, Garcia-Morales C, Kebede A, Bamidele O, Trujillo AV, Gheyas AA, Smith J. Functional evolution of the colony-stimulating factor 1 receptor (CSF1R) and its ligands in birds. J Leukoc Biol. 2020;107:237–250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31487076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inamasu J, Suga S, Sato S, Horiguchi T, Akaji K, Mayanagi K, Kawase T. Post-ischemic hypothermia delayed neutrophil accumulation and microglial activation following transient focal ischemia in rats. J Neuroimmunol. 2000;109:66–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10996208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang X, Andjelkovic AV, Zhu L, Yang T, Bennett MVL, Chen J, Keep RF, Shi Y. Blood-brain barrier dysfunction and recovery after ischemic stroke. Prog Neurobiol. 2018;163-164:144–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5886838</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalogeris T, Baines CP, Krenz M, Korthuis RJ. Ischemia/reperfusion. Compr Physiol. 2016;7:113–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5648017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanazawa M, Ninomiya I, Hatakeyama M, Takahashi T, Shimohata T. Microglia and monocytes/macrophages polarization reveal novel therapeutic mechanism against stroke. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:2135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5666817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29027964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerkhofs D, van Hagen BT, Milanova IV, Schell KJ, van Essen H, Wijnands E, Goossens P, Blankesteijn WM, Unger T, Prickaerts J, Biessen EA, van Oostenbrugge RJ, Foulquier S. Pharmacological depletion of microglia and perivascular macrophages prevents vascular cognitive impairment in Ang II-induced hypertension. Theranostics. 2020;10:9512–9527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449902</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32863942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koellhoffer EC, McCullough LD. The effects of estrogen in ischemic stroke. Transl Stroke Res. 2013;4:390–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24323337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li P, Stetler RA, Leak RK, Shi Y, Li Y, Yu W, Bennett MVL, Chen J. Oxidative stress and DNA damage after cerebral ischemia: Potential therapeutic targets to repair the genome and improve stroke recovery. Neuropharmacology. 2018;134:208–217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5940593</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29128308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Y, Wang J, Wang Y, Yang GY. The biphasic function of microglia in ischemic stroke. Prog Neurobiol. 2017;157:247–272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manwani B, Bentivegna K, Benashski SE, Venna VR, Xu Y, Arnold AP, McCullough LD. Sex differences in ischemic stroke sensitivity are influenced by gonadal hormones, not by sex chromosome complement. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2015;35:221–229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4426738</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25388681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mo Y, Sun YY, Liu KY. Autophagy and inflammation in ischemic stroke. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:1388–1396.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31997797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neal ML, Fleming SM, Budge KM, Boyle AM, Kim C, Alam G, Beier EE, Wu LJ, Richardson JR. Pharmacological inhibition of CSF1R by GW2580 reduces microglial proliferation and is protective against neuroinflammation and dopaminergic neurodegeneration. FASEB J. 2020;34:1679–1694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31914683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nematipour S, Vahidinia Z, Nejati M, Naderian H, Beyer C, Azami Tameh A. Estrogen and progesterone attenuate glutamate neurotoxicity via regulation of EAAT3 and GLT-1 in a rat model of ischemic stroke. Iran J Basic Med Sci. 2020;23:1346–1352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33149869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu J, Li C, Wu H, Feng X, Su Q, Li S, Zhang L, Yew DT, Cho EY, Sha O. Propidium iodide (PI) stains Nissl bodies and may serve as a quick marker for total neuronal cell count. Acta Histochem. 2015;117:182–187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25596876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohno H, Kubo K, Murooka H, Kobayashi Y, Nishitoba T, Shibuya M, Yoneda T, Isoe T. A c-fms tyrosine kinase inhibitor, Ki20227, suppresses osteoclast differentiation and osteolytic bone destruction in a bone metastasis model. Mol Cancer Ther. 2006;5:2634–2643.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17121910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin C, Zhou LQ, Ma XT, Hu ZW, Yang S, Chen M, Bosco DB, Wu LJ, Tian DS. Dual functions of microglia in ischemic stroke. Neurosci Bull. 2019;35:921–933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6754485</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31062335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radenovic L, Nenadic M, Ułamek-Kozioł M, Januszewski S, Czuczwar SJ, Andjus PR, Pluta R. Heterogeneity in brain distribution of activated microglia and astrocytes in a rat ischemic model of Alzheimer’s disease after 2 years of survival. Aging (Albany NY) 2020;12:12251–12267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7343500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32501292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritzel RM, Capozzi LA, McCullough LD. Sex, stroke, and inflammation: the potential for estrogen-mediated immunoprotection in stroke. Horm Behav. 2013;63:238–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3426619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22561337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekeljic V, Bataveljic D, Stamenkovic S, Ułamek M, Jabłoński M, Radenovic L, Pluta R, Andjus PR. Cellular markers of neuroinflammation and neurogenesis after ischemic brain injury in the long-term survival rat model. Brain Struct Funct. 2012;217:411–420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21706330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shadman J, Sadeghian N, Moradi A, Bohlooli S, Panahpour H. Magnesium sulfate protects blood-brain barrier integrity and reduces brain edema after acute ischemic stroke in rats. Metab Brain Dis. 2019;34:1221–1229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31037556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siddiqui WA, Ahad A, Ahsan H. The mystery of BCL2 family: Bcl-2 proteins and apoptosis: an update. Arch Toxicol. 2015;89:289–317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25618543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taupin P. BrdU immunohistochemistry for studying adult neurogenesis: paradigms, pitfalls, limitations, and validation. Brain Res Rev. 2007;53:198–214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17020783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Upadhya R, Zingg W, Shetty S, Shetty AK. Astrocyte-derived extracellular vesicles: Neuroreparative properties and role in the pathogenesis of neurodegenerative disorders. J Control Release. 2020;323:225–239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299747</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uzdensky AB. Apoptosis regulation in the penumbra after ischemic stroke: expression of pro- and anti-apoptotic proteins. Apoptosis. 2019;24:687–702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31256300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Xing H, Wan L, Jiang X, Wang C, Wu Y. Treatment targets for M2 microglia polarization in ischemic stroke. Biomed Pharmacother. 2018;105:518–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Shen Y, Liu Z, Gu J, Xu C, Qian S, Zhang X, Zhou B, Jin Y, Sun Y. Dl-NBP (Dl-3-N-butylphthalide) treatment promotes neurological functional recovery accompanied by the upregulation of white matter integrity and HIF-1α/VEGF/Notch/Dll4 expression. Front Pharmacol. 2019;10:1595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6993069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32038259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie ST, Chen AX, Song B, Fan J, Li W, Xing Z, Peng SY, Zhang QP, Dong L, Yan C, Zhang XY, Wang JJ, Zhu JN. Suppression of microglial activation and monocyte infiltration ameliorates cerebellar hemorrhage induced-brain injury and ataxia. Brain Behav Immun. 2020;89:400–413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiong XY, Liu L, Yang QW. Functions and mechanisms of microglia/macrophages in neuroinflammation and neurogenesis after stroke. Prog Neurobiol. 2016;142:23–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27166859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao SC, Wang C, Xu H, Wu WQ, Chu ZH, Ma LS, Zhang YD, Liu F. Age-related differences in interferon regulatory factor-4 and -5 signaling in ischemic brains of mice. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2017;38:1425–1434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5672072</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28905935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
