<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34113106</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1176-6328</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuropsychiatric disease and treatment</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Effect of Viloxazine Extended-Release Capsules on Functional Impairments Associated with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) in Children and Adolescents in Four Phase 3 Placebo-Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1751</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1762</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1751-1762</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/NDT.S312011</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The ADHD Rating Scale (ADHD-RS) assesses 18 symptoms of inattention and hyperactivity/impulsivity and has been used in many clinical trials to evaluate the treatment effect of drugs on ADHD. The fifth edition of this scale (ADHD-RS-5) also assesses the impact of inattention and hyperactivity/impulsivity symptoms on six domains of functional impairment (FI): family relationships, peer relationships, completing/returning homework, academic performance at school, controlling behavior at school, and self-esteem. Here, we report the effect of viloxazine extended-release capsules (viloxazine ER), a novel nonstimulant treatment for ADHD in children and adolescents (ages 6-17 years), on FI from a post hoc analysis of four randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Phase 3 clinical trials (N=1354).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">ADHD-RS-5 investigator ratings of ADHD symptoms and FIs were conducted at baseline and weekly post-baseline for 6-8 weeks in the four trials. Change from baseline (CFB) in ADHD-RS-5 FI scores (Total score [sum of 12 FI items] and Inattention and Hyperactivity/Impulsivity subscale scores [sum of 6 corresponding FI items]) and the 30% and 50% Responder Rates (ADHD-RS-5 FI Total score) were compared between viloxazine ER and placebo.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The reduction (improvement) in ADHD-RS-5 FI scores (Total and subscale scores) and the percentage of responders (30% and 50%) at Week 6 were significantly greater in each viloxazine ER dose group vs placebo. In the 100-400 mg/day viloxazine ER groups, improvements were found as early as Week 1 (100-mg/day) or Week 2 (200-, 400-mg/day) of treatment. Analysis of individual items of ADHD-related FIs demonstrated that the effect of viloxazine ER was observed across all domains of impairment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Significant improvements observed in ADHD-related FIs are consistent with the reduction in inattention and hyperactivity/impulsivity symptoms demonstrated in the viloxazine ER Phase 3 pediatric trials. Therefore, viloxazine ER provides clinically meaningful improvement of ADHD symptoms and functioning in children and adolescents with ADHD, starting as early as Week 1-2 of treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Nasser et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nasser</LastName>
            <ForeName>Azmi</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hull</LastName>
            <ForeName>Joseph T</ForeName>
            <Initials>JT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liranso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tesfaye</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Busse</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gregory D</ForeName>
            <Initials>GD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Affairs, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Melyan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zare</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Affairs, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Childress</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ann C</ForeName>
            <Initials>AC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Psychiatry and Behavioral Medicine, Inc., Las Vegas, NV, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>A Lopez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Frank</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Children's Developmental Center, Winter Park, FL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rubin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101240304</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1176-6328</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic performance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavior</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impairment domains</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-esteem</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>AN, JTH, TL, GDB, ZM, and JR are employees of Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc. FAL has served as a consultant to and received speaker fees and/or research support from Eli Lilly, GSK, Ironshore, Neos, Novartis, Noven, Pfizer, Shire, Sunovion, Supernus, and Tris. ACC has served as a consultant, participated in advisory board meetings and received speaker fees and/or research support from Allergan, Takeda (Shire), Emalex, Akili, Arbor, Cingulate, Ironshore, Aevi Genomic Medicine, Neos, Otsuka, Pfizer, Purdue, Adlon, Rhodes, Sunovion, Tris, KemPharm, Supernus, US FDA, Corium, Jazz, Tulex Pharma, and Receptor. The authors report no other conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34113106</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184252</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S312011</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">312011</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattingly GW, Anderson RH. Optimizing outcomes in ADHD treatment: from clinical targets to novel delivery systems. CNS Spectr. 2016;21(S1):45–59. doi:10.1017/S1092852916000808</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1092852916000808</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Childress A, Tran C. Current investigational drugs for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2016;25(4):463–474. doi:10.1517/13543784.2016.1147558</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/13543784.2016.1147558</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26814173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cutler AJ, Mattingly GW, Jain R, O’Neal W. Current and future nonstimulants in the treatment of pediatric ADHD: monoamine reuptake inhibitors, receptor modulators, and multimodal agents. CNS Spectr. 2020;1–27. doi:10.1017/S1092852920001984</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1092852920001984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein JN, Weiss MD. Assessing treatment outcomes in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: a narrative review. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2012;14(6). doi:10.4088/PCC.11r01336</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/PCC.11r01336</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3622525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23585986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Asherson P, Banaschewski T, et al. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2015;1:15020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th Ed.). Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Publishing; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss M, Childress A, Mattingly G, Nordbrock E, Kupper RJ, Adjei AL. Relationship between symptomatic and functional improvement and remission in a treatment response to stimulant trial. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2018;28(8):521–529. doi:10.1089/cap.2017.0166</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2017.0166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6201781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens J, Johannes LM, Karpenko V. The relation between change in symptoms and functioning in children with ADHD receiving school-based mental health services. School Ment Health. 2009;1:183–195. doi:10.1007/s12310-009-9020-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12310-009-9020-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodgkins P, Setyawan J, Mitra D, et al. Management of ADHD in children across Europe: patient demographics, physician characteristics and treatment patterns. Eur J Pediatr. 2013;172(7):895–906. doi:10.1007/s00431-013-1969-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-013-1969-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701791</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sikirica V, Flood E, Dietrich CN, et al. Unmet needs associated with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in eight European countries as reported by caregivers and adolescents: results from qualitative research. Patient. 2015;8(3):269–281. doi:10.1007/s40271-014-0083-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40271-014-0083-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biederman J, Petty CR, Evans M, Small J, Faraone SV. How persistent is ADHD? A controlled 10-year follow-up study of boys with ADHD. Psychiatry Res. 2010;177(3):299–304. doi:10.1016/j.psychres.2009.12.010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2009.12.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchida M, Spencer TJ, Faraone SV, Biederman J. Adult outcome of ADHD: an overview of results from the MGH longitudinal family studies of pediatrically and psychiatrically referred youth with and without ADHD of both sexes. J Atten Disord. 2018;22(6):523–534. doi:10.1177/1087054715604360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1087054715604360</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26396145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DuPaul GJ, Power TJ, Anastopoulos AD, et al. ADHD Rating Scale-5 for Children and Adolescents: Checklists, Norms, and Clinical Interpretation. New York, NY: The Guilford Press; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Power TJ, Watkins MW, Anastopoulos AD, Reid R, Lambert MC, DuPaul GJ. Multi-informant assessment of ADHD symptom-related impairments among children and adolescents. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2017;46(5):661–674. doi:10.1080/15374416.2015.1079781</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15374416.2015.1079781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajria K, Kosinski M, Sikirica V, et al. Psychometric validation of the Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Report Form in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2015;13:184. doi:10.1186/s12955-015-0379-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-015-0379-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4650258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26577642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabiano GA, Pelham WE, Waschbusch DA, et al. A practical measure of impairment: psychometric properties of the impairment rating scale in samples of children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder and two school-based samples. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2006;35(3):369–385. doi:10.1207/s15374424jccp3503_3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15374424jccp3503_3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16836475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vazquez AL, Sibley MH, Campez M. Measuring impairment when diagnosing adolescent ADHD: differentiating problems due to ADHD versus other sources. Psychiatry Res. 2018;264:407–411. doi:10.1016/j.psychres.2018.03.083</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2018.03.083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29679844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. A phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled trial to assess the efficacy and safety of once-daily SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in school-age children. Clin Ther. 2020;42(8):1452–1466. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2020.05.021</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2020.05.021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. A phase 3, placebo-controlled trial of once-daily viloxazine extended-release in adolescents with ADHD. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2021;In press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. Once-Daily SPN-812 200 and 400 mg in the treatment of ADHD in school-aged children: a phase III randomized, controlled trial. Clin Ther. 2021. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2021.01.027</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2021.01.027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33750646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. A phase 3 placebo-controlled trial of once-daily 400-mg and 600-mg SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in adolescents with ADHD. Psychopharmacol Bull. 2021;51(2):43–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guy W. Clinical Global Impression (CGI). Early Clinical Drug Evaluation Unit (ECDEU) Assessment Manual for Psychopharmacology. Rockville, MD: U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare; Public Health Service, Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Administration; National Institute of Mental Health; Psychopharmacology Research Branch; Division of Extramural Research Programs; 1976:218–222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michelson D, Allen AJ, Busner J, et al. Once-daily atomoxetine treatment for children and adolescents with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a randomized, placebo-controlled study. Am J Psychiatry. 2002;159(11):1896–1901. doi:10.1176/appi.ajp.159.11.1896</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.159.11.1896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12411225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemner JE, Starr HL, Ciccone PE, Hooper-Wood CG, Crockett RS. Outcomes of OROS methylphenidate compared with atomoxetine in children with ADHD: a multicenter, randomized prospective study. Adv Ther. 2005;22(5):498–512. doi:10.1007/BF02849870</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02849870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16418159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spencer T, Biederman J, Wilens T, et al. Efficacy of a mixed amphetamine salts compound in adults with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2001;58(8):775–782. doi:10.1001/archpsyc.58.8.775</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.58.8.775</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11483144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodman D, Faraone SV, Adler LA, et al. Interpreting ADHD rating scale scores: linking ADHD rating scale scores and CGI levels in two randomized controlled trials of lisdexamfetamine dimesylate in ADHD. Prim Psychiatry. 2010;17(3):44–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Kosheleff AR, Hull JT, et al. Translating ADHD-RS-5 and WFIRS-P effectiveness scores into CGI clinical significance levels in four randomized clinical trials of SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in children and adolescents with ADHD. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2021;31:214–226. doi:10.1089/cap.2020.0148</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2020.0148</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busner J, Targum SD. The clinical global impressions scale: applying a research tool in clinical practice. Psychiatry (Edgmont). 2007;4(7):28–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20526405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kay SR. Positive-negative symptom assessment in schizophrenia: psychometric issues and scale comparison. Psychiatr Q. 1990;61(3):163–178. doi:10.1007/BF01064966</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01064966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2075220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Kosheleff AR, Hull JT, et al. Evaluating the likelihood to be helped or harmed after treatment with viloxazine extended-release in children and adolescents with attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;In press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33971070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson T, Lloyd A, Joseph A, Weiss M. The Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Form for assessing ADHD: evaluating diagnostic accuracy and determining optimal thresholds using ROC analysis. Qual Life Res. 2017;26(7):1879–1885. doi:10.1007/s11136-017-1514-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-017-1514-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5486894</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28220338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Gomeni R, Hull JT, et al. Early response to SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) can predict efficacy outcome in pediatric subjects with ADHD: a machine learning post-hoc analysis of four randomized clinical trials. Psychiatry Res. 2021;296:113664. doi:10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113664</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33418457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34113106</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1176-6328</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuropsychiatric disease and treatment</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Effect of Viloxazine Extended-Release Capsules on Functional Impairments Associated with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) in Children and Adolescents in Four Phase 3 Placebo-Controlled Trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1751</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1762</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1751-1762</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/NDT.S312011</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The ADHD Rating Scale (ADHD-RS) assesses 18 symptoms of inattention and hyperactivity/impulsivity and has been used in many clinical trials to evaluate the treatment effect of drugs on ADHD. The fifth edition of this scale (ADHD-RS-5) also assesses the impact of inattention and hyperactivity/impulsivity symptoms on six domains of functional impairment (FI): family relationships, peer relationships, completing/returning homework, academic performance at school, controlling behavior at school, and self-esteem. Here, we report the effect of viloxazine extended-release capsules (viloxazine ER), a novel nonstimulant treatment for ADHD in children and adolescents (ages 6-17 years), on FI from a post hoc analysis of four randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled Phase 3 clinical trials (N=1354).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">ADHD-RS-5 investigator ratings of ADHD symptoms and FIs were conducted at baseline and weekly post-baseline for 6-8 weeks in the four trials. Change from baseline (CFB) in ADHD-RS-5 FI scores (Total score [sum of 12 FI items] and Inattention and Hyperactivity/Impulsivity subscale scores [sum of 6 corresponding FI items]) and the 30% and 50% Responder Rates (ADHD-RS-5 FI Total score) were compared between viloxazine ER and placebo.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The reduction (improvement) in ADHD-RS-5 FI scores (Total and subscale scores) and the percentage of responders (30% and 50%) at Week 6 were significantly greater in each viloxazine ER dose group vs placebo. In the 100-400 mg/day viloxazine ER groups, improvements were found as early as Week 1 (100-mg/day) or Week 2 (200-, 400-mg/day) of treatment. Analysis of individual items of ADHD-related FIs demonstrated that the effect of viloxazine ER was observed across all domains of impairment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Significant improvements observed in ADHD-related FIs are consistent with the reduction in inattention and hyperactivity/impulsivity symptoms demonstrated in the viloxazine ER Phase 3 pediatric trials. Therefore, viloxazine ER provides clinically meaningful improvement of ADHD symptoms and functioning in children and adolescents with ADHD, starting as early as Week 1-2 of treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Nasser et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nasser</LastName>
            <ForeName>Azmi</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hull</LastName>
            <ForeName>Joseph T</ForeName>
            <Initials>JT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liranso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tesfaye</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Busse</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gregory D</ForeName>
            <Initials>GD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Affairs, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Melyan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zare</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Affairs, Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Childress</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ann C</ForeName>
            <Initials>AC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Psychiatry and Behavioral Medicine, Inc., Las Vegas, NV, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>A Lopez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Frank</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Children's Developmental Center, Winter Park, FL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rubin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Rockville, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101240304</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1176-6328</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic performance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behavior</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impairment domains</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-esteem</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>AN, JTH, TL, GDB, ZM, and JR are employees of Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc. FAL has served as a consultant to and received speaker fees and/or research support from Eli Lilly, GSK, Ironshore, Neos, Novartis, Noven, Pfizer, Shire, Sunovion, Supernus, and Tris. ACC has served as a consultant, participated in advisory board meetings and received speaker fees and/or research support from Allergan, Takeda (Shire), Emalex, Akili, Arbor, Cingulate, Ironshore, Aevi Genomic Medicine, Neos, Otsuka, Pfizer, Purdue, Adlon, Rhodes, Sunovion, Tris, KemPharm, Supernus, US FDA, Corium, Jazz, Tulex Pharma, and Receptor. The authors report no other conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34113106</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184252</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S312011</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">312011</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattingly GW, Anderson RH. Optimizing outcomes in ADHD treatment: from clinical targets to novel delivery systems. CNS Spectr. 2016;21(S1):45–59. doi:10.1017/S1092852916000808</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1092852916000808</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28044946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Childress A, Tran C. Current investigational drugs for the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2016;25(4):463–474. doi:10.1517/13543784.2016.1147558</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/13543784.2016.1147558</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26814173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cutler AJ, Mattingly GW, Jain R, O’Neal W. Current and future nonstimulants in the treatment of pediatric ADHD: monoamine reuptake inhibitors, receptor modulators, and multimodal agents. CNS Spectr. 2020;1–27. doi:10.1017/S1092852920001984</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1092852920001984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33121553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein JN, Weiss MD. Assessing treatment outcomes in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: a narrative review. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2012;14(6). doi:10.4088/PCC.11r01336</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/PCC.11r01336</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3622525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23585986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Asherson P, Banaschewski T, et al. Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2015;1:15020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th Ed.). Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Publishing; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss M, Childress A, Mattingly G, Nordbrock E, Kupper RJ, Adjei AL. Relationship between symptomatic and functional improvement and remission in a treatment response to stimulant trial. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2018;28(8):521–529. doi:10.1089/cap.2017.0166</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2017.0166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6201781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30036076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens J, Johannes LM, Karpenko V. The relation between change in symptoms and functioning in children with ADHD receiving school-based mental health services. School Ment Health. 2009;1:183–195. doi:10.1007/s12310-009-9020-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12310-009-9020-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodgkins P, Setyawan J, Mitra D, et al. Management of ADHD in children across Europe: patient demographics, physician characteristics and treatment patterns. Eur J Pediatr. 2013;172(7):895–906. doi:10.1007/s00431-013-1969-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-013-1969-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701791</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sikirica V, Flood E, Dietrich CN, et al. Unmet needs associated with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in eight European countries as reported by caregivers and adolescents: results from qualitative research. Patient. 2015;8(3):269–281. doi:10.1007/s40271-014-0083-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40271-014-0083-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4445478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25344102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biederman J, Petty CR, Evans M, Small J, Faraone SV. How persistent is ADHD? A controlled 10-year follow-up study of boys with ADHD. Psychiatry Res. 2010;177(3):299–304. doi:10.1016/j.psychres.2009.12.010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2009.12.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2881837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20452063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchida M, Spencer TJ, Faraone SV, Biederman J. Adult outcome of ADHD: an overview of results from the MGH longitudinal family studies of pediatrically and psychiatrically referred youth with and without ADHD of both sexes. J Atten Disord. 2018;22(6):523–534. doi:10.1177/1087054715604360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1087054715604360</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26396145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DuPaul GJ, Power TJ, Anastopoulos AD, et al. ADHD Rating Scale-5 for Children and Adolescents: Checklists, Norms, and Clinical Interpretation. New York, NY: The Guilford Press; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Power TJ, Watkins MW, Anastopoulos AD, Reid R, Lambert MC, DuPaul GJ. Multi-informant assessment of ADHD symptom-related impairments among children and adolescents. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2017;46(5):661–674. doi:10.1080/15374416.2015.1079781</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15374416.2015.1079781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajria K, Kosinski M, Sikirica V, et al. Psychometric validation of the Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Report Form in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2015;13:184. doi:10.1186/s12955-015-0379-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-015-0379-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4650258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26577642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabiano GA, Pelham WE, Waschbusch DA, et al. A practical measure of impairment: psychometric properties of the impairment rating scale in samples of children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder and two school-based samples. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2006;35(3):369–385. doi:10.1207/s15374424jccp3503_3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15374424jccp3503_3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16836475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vazquez AL, Sibley MH, Campez M. Measuring impairment when diagnosing adolescent ADHD: differentiating problems due to ADHD versus other sources. Psychiatry Res. 2018;264:407–411. doi:10.1016/j.psychres.2018.03.083</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2018.03.083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29679844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. A phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled trial to assess the efficacy and safety of once-daily SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in school-age children. Clin Ther. 2020;42(8):1452–1466. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2020.05.021</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2020.05.021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. A phase 3, placebo-controlled trial of once-daily viloxazine extended-release in adolescents with ADHD. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2021;In press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. Once-Daily SPN-812 200 and 400 mg in the treatment of ADHD in school-aged children: a phase III randomized, controlled trial. Clin Ther. 2021. doi:10.1016/j.clinthera.2021.01.027</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2021.01.027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33750646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, et al. A phase 3 placebo-controlled trial of once-daily 400-mg and 600-mg SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in adolescents with ADHD. Psychopharmacol Bull. 2021;51(2):43–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guy W. Clinical Global Impression (CGI). Early Clinical Drug Evaluation Unit (ECDEU) Assessment Manual for Psychopharmacology. Rockville, MD: U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare; Public Health Service, Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Administration; National Institute of Mental Health; Psychopharmacology Research Branch; Division of Extramural Research Programs; 1976:218–222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michelson D, Allen AJ, Busner J, et al. Once-daily atomoxetine treatment for children and adolescents with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder: a randomized, placebo-controlled study. Am J Psychiatry. 2002;159(11):1896–1901. doi:10.1176/appi.ajp.159.11.1896</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.159.11.1896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12411225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemner JE, Starr HL, Ciccone PE, Hooper-Wood CG, Crockett RS. Outcomes of OROS methylphenidate compared with atomoxetine in children with ADHD: a multicenter, randomized prospective study. Adv Ther. 2005;22(5):498–512. doi:10.1007/BF02849870</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02849870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16418159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spencer T, Biederman J, Wilens T, et al. Efficacy of a mixed amphetamine salts compound in adults with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2001;58(8):775–782. doi:10.1001/archpsyc.58.8.775</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.58.8.775</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11483144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodman D, Faraone SV, Adler LA, et al. Interpreting ADHD rating scale scores: linking ADHD rating scale scores and CGI levels in two randomized controlled trials of lisdexamfetamine dimesylate in ADHD. Prim Psychiatry. 2010;17(3):44–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Kosheleff AR, Hull JT, et al. Translating ADHD-RS-5 and WFIRS-P effectiveness scores into CGI clinical significance levels in four randomized clinical trials of SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in children and adolescents with ADHD. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2021;31:214–226. doi:10.1089/cap.2020.0148</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2020.0148</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busner J, Targum SD. The clinical global impressions scale: applying a research tool in clinical practice. Psychiatry (Edgmont). 2007;4(7):28–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2880930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20526405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kay SR. Positive-negative symptom assessment in schizophrenia: psychometric issues and scale comparison. Psychiatr Q. 1990;61(3):163–178. doi:10.1007/BF01064966</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01064966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2075220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Kosheleff AR, Hull JT, et al. Evaluating the likelihood to be helped or harmed after treatment with viloxazine extended-release in children and adolescents with attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Int J Clin Pract. 2021;In press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33971070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson T, Lloyd A, Joseph A, Weiss M. The Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Form for assessing ADHD: evaluating diagnostic accuracy and determining optimal thresholds using ROC analysis. Qual Life Res. 2017;26(7):1879–1885. doi:10.1007/s11136-017-1514-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-017-1514-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5486894</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28220338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Gomeni R, Hull JT, et al. Early response to SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) can predict efficacy outcome in pediatric subjects with ADHD: a machine learning post-hoc analysis of four randomized clinical trials. Psychiatry Res. 2021;296:113664. doi:10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113664</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33418457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
