<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34133837</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-1331</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European journal of neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Immunity and Gilles de la Tourette syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis of evidence for immune implications in Tourette syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>3187</StartPage>
          <EndPage>3200</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>3187-3200</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ene.14983</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE">The neurobiology of Gilles de la Tourette syndrome (GTS) is known to involve corticostriatal loops possibly under genetic control. Less is known about possible environmental triggers of GTS. Specifically, immune-related events following possible environmental inducers have been evoked, but important controversies still exist. In this systematic review and meta-analysis, we looked for evidence in favor of such possibilities.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">We performed a systematic review and meta-analysis of all immunological data in PubMed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We found large discrepancies concerning immune dysfunctions in GTS, and meta-analyzing cytokines data did not allow us to conclude there is an involvement of specific cytokines in GTS neurobiology. When looking specifically at pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with streptococcus/pediatric acute onset neuropsychiatric syndrome, we found some important evidence of a possible infectious involvement but in a limited number of studies. Our meta-analysis found an increased level of anti-streptolysin O antibodies in GTS patients, but the level of anti-DNase B antibodies was not increased.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Too many questions still exist to allow us to definitively reach the conclusion that there is an infectious and immunological etiology in GTS. Much work is still needed to elucidate the possible role of immunology in GTS neurobiology and to favor immunological treatment rather than classical treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 European Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lamothe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hugues</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3100-6301</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Assistance Publique-Hôpitaux de Paris, Pôle de Psychiatrie, Hôpitaux Universitaires Henri Mondor-Albert Chenevier, Paris-East Créteil University, Créteil, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut du Cerveau et de la Moelle Épinière, INSERM U1127, CNRS UMR 7225, Sorbonne University, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tamouza</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ryad</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Assistance Publique-Hôpitaux de Paris, Pôle de Psychiatrie, Hôpitaux Universitaires Henri Mondor-Albert Chenevier, Paris-East Créteil University, Créteil, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut Mondor de Recherche Biomédical, Paris-East Créteil University, Team "Psychiatrie Translationnelle, INSERM U955, Créteil, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hartmann</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andreas</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut du Cerveau et de la Moelle Épinière, INSERM U1127, CNRS UMR 7225, Sorbonne University, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre Hospitalo-Universitaire de la Pitié Salpétrière, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mallet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luc</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Assistance Publique-Hôpitaux de Paris, Pôle de Psychiatrie, Hôpitaux Universitaires Henri Mondor-Albert Chenevier, Paris-East Créteil University, Créteil, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut du Cerveau et de la Moelle Épinière, INSERM U1127, CNRS UMR 7225, Sorbonne University, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mental Health and Psychiatry, Global Health Institute, University of Geneva, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9506311</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1351-5101</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009771" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005879" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tourette Syndrome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">PANS/PANDAS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">autoimmunity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cytokines</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">tic disorders</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133837</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14983</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 5th edn. Arlington, VA: American Psychiatric Association; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robertson MM, Eapen V, Singer HS, et al. Gilles de la Tourette syndrome. Nat Rev Dis Primer. 2017;3:16097. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrdp.2016.97</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jalenques I, Auclair C, Morand D, et al. Health-related quality of life, anxiety and depression in parents of adolescents with Gilles de la Tourette syndrome: a controlled study. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2017;26(5):603-617. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00787-016-0923-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eapen V, Snedden C, Črnčec R, Pick A, Sachdev P. Tourette syndrome, co-morbidities and quality of life. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2016;50(1):82-93. https://doi.org/10.1177/0004867415594429</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kataoka Y, Kalanithi PSA, Grantz H, et al. Decreased number of parvalbumin and cholinergic interneurons in the striatum of individuals with Tourette syndrome. J Comp Neurol. 2010;518(3):277-291. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22206</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maia TV, Conceição VA. Dopaminergic disturbances in Tourette syndrome: an integrative account. Biol Psychiatry. 2018;84(5):332-344. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2018.02.1172</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dwyer JB. A developmental perspective of dopaminergic dysfunction in Tourette syndrome. Biol Psychiatry. 2018;84(5):e33-e35. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2018.07.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartmann A, Martino D, Murphy T. Gilles de la Tourette syndrome - A treatable condition? Rev Neurol (Paris). 2016;172(8-9):446-454. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurol.2016.07.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng W, Li X-B, Xiang Y-Q, et al. Aripiprazole for Tourette's syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Psychopharmacol. 2016;31(1):11-18. https://doi.org/10.1002/hup.2498</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baldermann JC, Schüller T, Huys D, et al. Deep brain stimulation for tourette-syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Brain Stimulat. 2016;9(2):296-304. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brs.2015.11.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller-Vahl KR, Cath DC, Cavanna AE, et al. European clinical guidelines for Tourette syndrome and other tic disorders. Part IV: deep brain stimulation. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2011;20(4):209-217. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00787-011-0166-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budman C, Coffey BJ, Shechter R, et al. Aripiprazole in children and adolescents with Tourette disorder with and without explosive outbursts. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2008;18(5):509-515. https://doi.org/10.1089/cap.2007.061</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen K, Budman CL, Diego Herrera L, et al. Prevalence and clinical correlates of explosive outbursts in Tourette syndrome. Psychiatry Res. 2013;205(3):269-275. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2012.09.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patterson AL, Choudhri AF, Igarashi M, McVicar K, Shah N, Morgan R. Severe neurological complications associated with Tourette syndrome. Pediatr Neurol. 2016;61:99-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2016.05.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pauls DL, Abramovitch A, Rauch SL, Geller DA. Obsessive-compulsive disorder: an integrative genetic and neurobiological perspective. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2014;15(6):410-424. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3746</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamothe H, Baleyte J-M, Smith P, Pelissolo A, Mallet L. Individualized immunological data for precise classification of OCD patients. Brain Sci. 2018;8(8):149. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci8080149</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couto JP, Moreira R. Oral N-acetylcysteine in the treatment of obsessive-compulsive disorder: a systematic review of the clinical evidence. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2018;86:245-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2018.06.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sethi R, Gómez-Coronado N, Walker AJ, et al. Neurobiology and therapeutic potential of cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) inhibitors for inflammation in neuropsychiatric disorders. Front Psychiatry. 2019;10:605. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00605</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Garvey M, et al. Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry. 1998;155(2):264-271. https://doi.org/10.1176/ajp.155.2.264</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiarello F, Spitoni S, Hollander E, Matucci Cerinic M, Pallanti S. An expert opinion on PANDAS/PANS: highlights and controversies. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract. 2017;21(2):91-98. https://doi.org/10.1080/13651501.2017.1285941</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matz J, Krause DL, Dehning S, et al. Altered monocyte activation markers in Tourette's syndrome: a case-control study. BMC Psychiatry. 2012;12:29. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-244X-12-29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabbay V, Coffey BJ, Guttman LE, et al. A cytokine study in children and adolescents with Tourette's disorder. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2009;33(6):967-971. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnpbp.2009.05.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng Y, Zheng Y, He F, et al. Detection of autoantibodies and increased concentrations of interleukins in plasma from patients with Tourette's syndrome. J Mol Neurosci MN. 2012;48(1):219-224. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12031-012-9811-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loiselle CR, Wendlandt JT, Rohde CA, Singer HS. Antistreptococcal, neuronal, and nuclear antibodies in Tourette syndrome. Pediatr Neurol. 2003;28(2):119-125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris-Berry CM, Pollard M, Gao S, Thompson C, Tourette Syndrome Study Group, Singer HS. Anti-streptococcal, tubulin, and dopamine receptor 2 antibodies in children with PANDAS and Tourette syndrome: single-point and longitudinal assessments. J Neuroimmunol. 2013;264(1-2):106-113. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2013.09.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller N, Riedel M, Straube A, Günther W, Wilske B. Increased anti-streptococcal antibodies in patients with Tourette's syndrome. Psychiatry Res. 2000;94(1):43-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller N, Kroll B, Schwarz MJ, et al. Increased titers of antibodies against streptococcal M12 and M19 proteins in patients with Tourette's syndrome. Psychiatry Res. 2001;101(2):187-193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Chiarotti F, Buttiglione M, et al. The relationship between group A streptococcal infections and Tourette syndrome: a study on a large service-based cohort. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2011;53(10):951-957. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1469-8749.2011.04018.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Church AJ, Dale RC, Lees AJ, Giovannoni G, Robertson MM. Tourette's syndrome: a cross sectional study to examine the PANDAS hypothesis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2003;74(5):602-607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li E, Ruan Y, Chen Q, et al. Streptococcal infection and immune response in children with Tourette's syndrome. Childs Nerv Syst ChNS Off J Int Soc Pediatr Neurosurg. 2015;31(7):1157-1163. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00381-015-2692-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzo R, Gulisano M, Pavone P, Fogliani F, Robertson MM. Increased antistreptococcal antibody titers and anti-basal ganglia antibodies in patients with Tourette syndrome: controlled cross-sectional study. J Child Neurol. 2006;21(9):747-753. https://doi.org/10.1177/08830738060210091001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebrahimi Taj F, Noorbakhsh S, Ghavidel Darestani S, Shirazi E, Javadinia S. Group A β-hemolytic streptococcal infection in children and the resultant neuro-psychiatric disorder; a cross sectional study; Tehran. Iran. Basic Clin Neurosci. 2015;6(1):38-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelley GA, Kelley KS. Statistical models for meta-analysis: a brief tutorial. World J Methodol. 2012;2(4):27-32. https://doi.org/10.5662/wjm.v2.i4.27</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeon S-M, Lee JH, Kang D, et al. A cytokine study of pediatric Tourette's disorder without obsessive compulsive disorder. Psychiatry Res. 2017;247:90-96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2016.11.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Gause C, Morris C, Lopez P, Tourette Syndrome Study Group. Serial immune markers do not correlate with clinical exacerbations in pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections. Pediatrics. 2008;121(6):1198-1205. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2007-2658</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parker-Athill EC, Ehrhart J, Tan J, Murphy TK. Cytokine correlations in youth with tic disorders. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2015;25(1):86-92. https://doi.org/10.1089/cap.2014.0103</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morer A, Chae W, Henegariu O, Bothwell ALM, Leckman JF, Kawikova I. Elevated expression of MCP-1, IL-2 and PTPR-N in basal ganglia of Tourette syndrome cases. Brain Behav Immun. 2010;24(7):1069-1073. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2010.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fond G, Hamdani N, Kapczinski F, et al. Effectiveness and tolerance of anti-inflammatory drugs' add-on therapy in major mental disorders: a systematic qualitative review. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2014;129(3):163-179. https://doi.org/10.1111/acps.12211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zunszain PA, Hepgul N, Pariante CM. Inflammation and depression. Curr Top Behav Neurosci. 2013;14:135-151. https://doi.org/10.1007/7854_2012_211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pranzatelli MR, Tate ED, Allison TJ. Case-control, exploratory study of cerebrospinal fluid chemokines/cytokines and lymphocyte subsets in childhood Tourette syndrome with positive streptococcal markers. Cytokine. 2017;96:49-53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cyto.2017.03.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yildirim Z, Karabekiroglu K, Yildiran A, et al. An examination of the relationship between regulatory T cells and symptom flare-ups in children and adolescents diagnosed with chronic tic disorder and Tourette syndrome. Nord J Psychiatry. 2021;75:1-7. https://doi.org/10.1080/08039488.2020.1779808</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarchioto M, Howe F, Dumitriu IE, et al. Analyses of peripheral blood dendritic cells and magnetic resonance spectroscopy support dysfunctional neuro-immune crosstalk in Tourette syndrome. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28(6):1910-1921. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.14837</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemmer B, Kerschensteiner M, Korn T. Role of the innate and adaptive immune responses in the course of multiple sclerosis. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(4):406-419. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70305-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feinstein A, Magalhaes S, Richard J-F, Audet B, Moore C. The link between multiple sclerosis and depression. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10(9):507-517. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrneurol.2014.139</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Möller JC, Tackenberg B, Heinzel-Gutenbrunner M, et al. Immunophenotyping in Tourette syndrome-a pilot study. Eur J Neurol. 2008;15(7):749-753. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-1331.2008.02159.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsieh M-Y, Lee W-I, Lin K-L, et al. Immunologic analysis and serum heavy metal levels in exacerbated Tourette syndrome. Pediatr Allergy Immunol Off Publ Eur Soc Pediatr Allergy Immunol. 2010;21(4 Pt 2):e764-e771. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3038.2010.01009.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapping RI, Tobias PS. Soluble CD14-mediated cellular responses to lipopolysaccharide. Chem Immunol. 2000;74:108-121. https://doi.org/10.1159/000058751</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weidinger E, Krause D, Wildenauer A, et al. Impaired activation of the innate immune response to bacterial challenge in Tourette syndrome. World J Biol Psychiatry Off J World Fed Soc Biol Psychiatry. 2014;15(6):453-458. https://doi.org/10.3109/15622975.2014.907503</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaure C, Liu Y. A comparative review of toll-like receptor 4 expression and functionality in different animal species. Front Immunol. 2014;5:316. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2014.00316</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stubljar D, Kopitar AN, Groselj-Grenc M, Suhadolc K, Fabjan T, Skvarc M. Diagnostic accuracy of presepsin (sCD14-ST) for prediction of bacterial infection in cerebrospinal fluid samples from children with suspected bacterial meningitis or ventriculitis. J Clin Microbiol. 2015;53(4):1239-1244. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.03052-14</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qi Y, Zheng Y, Li Z, Xiong L. Progress in genetic studies of Tourette's syndrome. Brain Sci. 2017;7(10):134. https://doi.org/10.3390/brainsci7100134</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caine ED, Weitkamp LR, Chiverton P, et al. Tourette syndrome and HLA. J Neurol Sci. 1985;69(3):201-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Comings DE, Gursey BT, Hecht T, Blume K. HLA typing in Tourette syndrome. Adv Neurol. 1982;35:251-253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoenian S, Konig I, Oertel W, et al. HLA-DRB genotyping in Gilles de la Tourette patients and their parents. Am J Med Genet Part B Neuropsychiatr Genet Off Publ Int Soc Psychiatr Genet. 2003;119B(1):60-64. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.b.20003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Min SK, Lee H, Park KI, Park MS, Namkoong K. Tourette disorder and HLA typing. Yonsei Med J. 1991;32(4):315-318. https://doi.org/10.3349/ymj.1991.32.4.315</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorakshakar A, Gogri H, Ghosh K. Evolution of technology for molecular genotyping in blood group systems. Indian J Med Res. 2017;146(3):305-315. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijmr.IJMR_914_16</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kindler J, Schosser A, Stamenkovic M, et al. Tourette's syndrome is not associated with interleukin-10 receptor 1 variants on chromosome 11q23.3. Psychiatry Res. 2008;157(1-3):235-239. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2007.07.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S, Yi M, Qi F, Che F, Ma X. Lack of association between polymorphism -592A/C in the promoter region of the IL10 gene and Tourette's syndrome in a family-based association study in the Chinese Han population. Genet Test Mol Biomark. 2011;15(10):733-735. https://doi.org/10.1089/gtmb.2010.0272</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S, Yi M, Wang M, Sun Y, Che F, Ma X. Association of IL8 -251A/T, IL12B -1188A/C and TNF-α -238A/G polymorphisms with Tourette syndrome in a family-based association study in a Chinese Han population. Neurosci Lett. 2011;495(2):155-158. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2011.03.060</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He F, Shao X, Yi M, Wang Y, Wang C-Y, Liu S. Association of IL-1α rs17561 and IL-1 RN rs315952 polymorphisms with Tourette syndrome: a family-based study. Int J Clin Exp Pathol. 2015;8(4):4182-4185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chou I-C, Lin H-C, Wang C-H, et al. Polymorphisms of interleukin 1 gene IL1RN are associated with Tourette syndrome. Pediatr Neurol. 2010;42(5):320-324. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2010.01.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keszler G, Kruk E, Kenezloi E, Tarnok Z, Sasvari-Szekely M, Nemoda Z. Association of the tumor necrosis factor -308 A/G promoter polymorphism with Tourette syndrome. Int J Immunogenet. 2014;41(6):493-498. https://doi.org/10.1111/iji.12147</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi M, Shao X, Ma J, Tian B, Zhang Y, Liu S. rs2043211 polymorphism in CARD8 is not associated with Tourette syndrome in a family-based association study in the Chinese Han population. Int J Psychiatry Med. 2015;49(3):208-214. https://doi.org/10.1177/0091217415582190</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang Y, Gilbert DL, Glauser TA, Hershey AD, Sharp FR. Blood gene expression profiling of neurologic diseases: a pilot microarray study. Arch Neurol. 2005;62(2):210-215. https://doi.org/10.1001/archneur.62.2.210</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsetsos F, Yu D, Sul JH, et al. Synaptic processes and immune-related pathways implicated in Tourette syndrome. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11(1):56. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41398-020-01082-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He F, Zheng Y, Huang H-H, Cheng Y-H, Wang C-Y. Association between Tourette syndrome and the dopamine D3 receptor gene rs6280. Chin Med J (Engl). 2015;128(5):654-658. https://doi.org/10.4103/0366-6999.151665</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang AY, Yu D, Davis LK, et al. Rare copy number variants in NRXN1 and CNTN6 increase risk for Tourette syndrome. Neuron. 2017;94(6):1101-1111.e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.06.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bassett AS, Scherer SW. Copy number variation in Tourette syndrome. Neuron. 2017;94(6):1041-1043. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.06.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scharf JM, Yu D, Mathews CA, et al. Genome-wide association study of Tourette's syndrome. Mol Psychiatry. 2013;18(6):721-728. https://doi.org/10.1038/mp.2012.69</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennington JB, Coppola G, Kataoka-Sasaki Y, et al. Transcriptome analysis of the human striatum in Tourette syndrome. Biol Psychiatry. 2016;79(5):372-382. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2014.07.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Mittleman BB, et al. Identification of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections by a marker associated with rheumatic fever. Am J Psychiatry. 1997;154(1):110-112. https://doi.org/10.1176/ajp.154.1.110</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mejia NI, Jankovic J. Secondary tics and tourettism. Rev Bras Psiquiatr Sao Paulo Braz 1999. 2005;27(1):11-17. https://doi.org/10.1590/s1516-44462005000100006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo E, From S. Research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome). Pediatr Ther. 2012;2(2):1-8. https://doi.org/10.4172/2161-0665.1000113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA, Swedo SE. PANDAS: current status and directions for research. Mol Psychiatry. 2004;9(10):900-907. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.mp.4001542</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang K, Frankovich J, Cooperstock M, et al. Clinical evaluation of youth with pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS): recommendations from the 2013 PANS Consensus Conference. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. 2015;25(1):3-13. https://doi.org/10.1089/cap.2014.0084</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC. Immune-mediated extrapyramidal movement disorders, including Sydenham chorea. Handb Clin Neurol. 2013;112:1235-1241. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-444-52910-7.00046-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morer A, Viñas O, Lázaro L, Bosch J, Toro J, Castro J. D8/17 monoclonal antibody: an unclear neuropsychiatric marker. Behav Neurol. 2005;16(1):1-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Goodman WK, Fudge MW, et al. B lymphocyte antigen D8/17: a peripheral marker for childhood-onset obsessive-compulsive disorder and Tourette's syndrome? Am J Psychiatry. 1997;154(3):402-407. https://doi.org/10.1176/ajp.154.3.402</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman F, Visvanathan K, Carreño-Manjarrez R, Zabriskie JB. A flow cytometric assay for D8/17 B cell marker in patients with Tourette's syndrome and obsessive compulsive disorder. J Immunol Methods. 1998;219(1-2):181-186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weisz JL, McMahon WM, Moore JC, et al. D8/17 and CD19 expression on lymphocytes of patients with acute rheumatic fever and Tourette's disorder. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 2004;11(2):330-336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brimberg L, Benhar I, Mascaro-Blanco A, et al. Behavioral, pharmacological, and immunological abnormalities after streptococcal exposure: a novel rat model of Sydenham chorea and related neuropsychiatric disorders. Neuropsychopharmacol Off Publ Am Coll Neuropsychopharmacol. 2012;37(9):2076-2087. https://doi.org/10.1038/npp.2012.56</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laurino JP, Hallett J, Kiessling LS, Benson M, Pelletier T, Kuhn C. An immunoassay for anti-neuronal antibodies associated with involuntary repetitive movement disorders. Ann Clin Lab Sci. 1997;27(3):230-235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morshed SA, Parveen S, Leckman JF, et al. Antibodies against neural, nuclear, cytoskeletal, and streptococcal epitopes in children and adults with Tourette's syndrome, Sydenham's chorea, and autoimmune disorders. Biol Psychiatry. 2001;50(8):566-577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh C-B, Shui H-A, Chu T-H, Chen Y-A, Tsung H-C, Shyu J-F. Hyperpolarisation-activated cyclic nucleotide channel 4 (HCN4) involvement in Tourette's syndrome autoimmunity. J Neuroimmunol. 2012;250(1-2):18-26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneuroim.2012.05.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Giuliano JD, Hansen BH, et al. Antibodies against human putamen in children with Tourette syndrome. Neurology. 1998;50(6):1618-1624.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Giuliano JD, Hansen BH, et al. Antibodies against a neuron-like (HTB-10 neuroblastoma) cell in children with Tourette syndrome. Biol Psychiatry. 1999;46(6):775-780.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wendlandt JT, Grus FH, Hansen BH, Singer HS. Striatal antibodies in children with Tourette's syndrome: multivariate discriminant analysis of IgG repertoires. J Neuroimmunol. 2001;119(1):106-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Hong JJ, Yoon DY, Williams PN. Serum autoantibodies do not differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. Neurology. 2005;65(11):1701-1707. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000183223.69946.f1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morer A, Lázaro L, Sabater L, Massana J, Castro J, Graus F. Antineuronal antibodies in a group of children with obsessive-compulsive disorder and Tourette syndrome. J Psychiatr Res. 2008;42(1):64-68. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychires.2006.09.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris CM, Pardo-Villamizar C, Gause CD, Singer HS. Serum autoantibodies measured by immunofluorescence confirm a failure to differentiate PANDAS and Tourette syndrome from controls. J Neurol Sci. 2009;276(1-2):45-48. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2008.08.032</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brilot F, Merheb V, Ding A, Murphy T, Dale RC. Antibody binding to neuronal surface in Sydenham chorea, but not in PANDAS or Tourette syndrome. Neurology. 2011;76(17):1508-1513. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182181090</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox CJ, Sharma M, Leckman JF, et al. Brain human monoclonal autoantibody from sydenham chorea targets dopaminergic neurons in transgenic mice and signals dopamine D2 receptor: implications in human disease. J Immunol Baltim Md 1950. 2013;191(11):5524-5541. https://doi.org/10.4049/jimmunol.1102592</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Addabbo F, Baglioni V, Schrag A, et al. Anti-dopamine D2 receptor antibodies in chronic tic disorders. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2020;62(10):1205-1212. https://doi.org/10.1111/dmcn.14613</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A, Williams MT, Chugani HT. Evaluation of basal ganglia and thalamic inflammation in children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection and tourette syndrome: a positron emission tomographic (PET) study using 11C-[R]-PK11195. J Child Neurol. 2015;30(6):749-756. https://doi.org/10.1177/0883073814543303</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag A, Gilbert R, Giovannoni G, Robertson MM, Metcalfe C, Ben-Shlomo Y. Streptococcal infection, Tourette syndrome, and OCD: is there a connection? Neurology. 2009;73(16):1256-1263. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181bd10fd</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leslie DL, Kozma L, Martin A, et al. Neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection: a case-control study among privately insured children. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2008;47(10):1166-1172. https://doi.org/10.1097/CHI.0b013e3181825a3d</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mell LK, Davis RL, Owens D. Association between streptococcal infection and obsessive-compulsive disorder, Tourette's syndrome, and tic disorder. Pediatrics. 2005;116(1):56-60. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2004-2058</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkman NJ, Libbey JE, Sweeten TL, et al. How relevant are GFAP autoantibodies in autism and Tourette syndrome? J Autism Dev Disord. 2008;38(2):333-341. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-007-0398-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Church AJ, Defazio G, et al. Soluble adhesion molecules in Gilles de la Tourette's syndrome. J Neurol Sci. 2005;234(1-2):79-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2005.03.032</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dale RC, Merheb V, Pillai S, et al. Antibodies to surface dopamine-2 receptor in autoimmune movement and psychiatric disorders. Brain J Neurol. 2012;135(Pt 11):3453-3468. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aws256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sühs K-W, Skripuletz T, Pul R, et al. Gilles de la Tourette syndrome is not linked to contactin-associated protein receptor 2 antibodies. Mol Brain. 2015;8(1):62. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13041-015-0154-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Krumholz A, Giuliano J, Kiessling LS. Antiphospholipid antibodies: an epiphenomenon in Tourette syndrome. Mov Disord Off J Mov Disord Soc. 1997;12(5):738-742. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.870120518</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toren P, Toren A, Weizman A, et al. Tourette's disorder: is there an association with the antiphospholipid syndrome? Biol Psychiatry. 1994;35(7):495-498. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-3223(94)90051-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh C-B, Wu C-H, Tsung H-C, Chen C-W, Shyu J-F, Leckman JF. Antineural antibody in patients with Tourette's syndrome and their family members. J Biomed Sci. 2006;13(1):101-112. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11373-005-9033-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baglioni V, Coutinho E, Menassa DA, et al. Antibodies to neuronal surface proteins in Tourette Syndrome: lack of evidence in a European paediatric cohort. Brain Behav Immun. 2019;81:665-669. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2019.08.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mataix-Cols D, Frans E, Pérez-Vigil A, et al. A total-population multigenerational family clustering study of autoimmune diseases in obsessive-compulsive disorder and Tourette's/chronic tic disorders. Mol Psychiatry. 2018;23(7):1652-1658. https://doi.org/10.1038/mp.2017.215</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zykov VP, Shcherbina AY, Novikova EB, Shvabrina TV. Neuroimmune aspects of the pathogenesis of Tourette's syndrome and experience in the use of immunoglobulins in children. Neurosci Behav Physiol. 2009;39(7):635-638. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11055-009-9184-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Defazio G, Church AJ, et al. Antineuronal antibody status and phenotype analysis in Tourette's syndrome. Mov Disord Off J Mov Disord Soc. 2007;22(10):1424-1429. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.21454</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Draganski B, Cavanna A, et al. Anti-basal ganglia antibodies and Tourette's syndrome: a voxel-based morphometry and diffusion tensor imaging study in an adult population. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79(7):820-822. https://doi.org/10.1136/jnnp.2007.136689</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgaertel C, Skripuletz T, Kronenberg J, et al. Immunity in Gilles de la Tourette-Syndrome: results from a cerebrospinal fluid study. Front Neurol. 2019;10:732. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2019.00732</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wenzel C, Wurster U, Müller-Vahl KR. Oligoclonal bands in cerebrospinal fluid in patients with Tourette's syndrome. Mov Disord Off J Mov Disord Soc. 2011;26(2):343-346. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.23403</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bos-Veneman NGP, Olieman R, Tobiasova Z, et al. Altered immunoglobulin profiles in children with Tourette syndrome. Brain Behav Immun. 2011;25(3):532-538. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2010.12.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tylee DS, Sun J, Hess JL, et al. Genetic correlations among psychiatric and immune-related phenotypes based on genome-wide association data. Am J Med Genet Part B Neuropsychiatr Genet Off Publ Int Soc Psychiatr Genet. 2018;177(7):641-657. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.b.32652</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuce M, Guner SN, Karabekiroglu K, et al. Association of Tourette syndrome and obsessive-compulsive disorder with allergic diseases in children and adolescents: a preliminary study. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2014;18(3):303-310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang Y-T, Li Y-F, Muo C-H, et al. Correlation of Tourette syndrome and allergic disease: nationwide population-based case-control study. J Dev Behav Pediatr JDBP. 2011;32(2):98-102. https://doi.org/10.1097/DBP.0b013e318208f561</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landau YE, Steinberg T, Richmand B, Leckman JF, Apter A. Involvement of immunologic and biochemical mechanisms in the pathogenesis of Tourette's syndrome. J Neural Transm Vienna Austria 1996. 2012;119(5):621-626. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00702-011-0739-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartůnková J, Kayserová J, Shoenfeld Y. Allergy and autoimmunity: parallels and dissimilarity: the yin and yang of immunopathology. Autoimmun Rev. 2009;8(4):302-308. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autrev.2008.09.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai C-S, Yang Y-H, Huang K-Y, Lee Y, McIntyre RS, Chen VC-H. Association of tic disorders and enterovirus infection: a nationwide population-based study. Medicine (Baltimore). 2016;95(15):e3347. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000003347</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krause D, Matz J, Weidinger E, et al. Association between intracellular infectious agents and Tourette's syndrome. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2010;260(4):359-363. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00406-009-0084-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krause DL, Weidinger E, Matz J, et al. Infectious agents are associated with psychiatric diseases. Ment Illn. 2012;4(1):e10. https://doi.org/10.4081/mi.2012.e10</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller N, Riedel M, Blendinger C, Oberle K, Jacobs E, Abele-Horn M. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection and Tourette's syndrome. Psychiatry Res. 2004;129(2):119-125. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2004.04.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller BJ, Goldsmith DR. Towards an immunophenotype of schizophrenia: progress, potential mechanisms, and future directions. Neuropsychopharmacol Off Publ Am Coll Neuropsychopharmacol. 2017;42(1):299-317. https://doi.org/10.1038/npp.2016.211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cubo E, Hortigüela M, Jorge-Roldan S, et al. Prenatal and perinatal morbidity in children with tic disorders: a mainstream school-based population study in Central Spain. Tremor Hyperkinetic Mov N Y N. 2014;4:272. https://doi.org/10.7916/D8FN14W9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirano T. Interleukin 6 in autoimmune and inflammatory diseases: a personal memoir. Proc Jpn Acad Ser B Phys Biol Sci. 2010;86(7):717-730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Church AJ, Dale RC, Cardoso F, et al. CSF and serum immune parameters in Sydenham's chorea: evidence of an autoimmune syndrome? J Neuroimmunol. 2003;136(1-2):149-153.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF, King RA, Gilbert DL, et al. Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and exacerbations of tic and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective longitudinal study. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2011;50(2):108-118.e3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaac.2010.10.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R, Johnson D, Kaplan EL, Tourette Syndrome Study Group. Streptococcal infection and exacerbations of childhood tics and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective blinded cohort study. Pediatrics. 2008;121(6):1188-1197. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2007-2657</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hollander E, DelGiudice-Asch G, Simon L, et al. B lymphocyte antigen D8/17 and repetitive behaviors in autism. Am J Psychiatry. 1999;156(2):317-320. https://doi.org/10.1176/ajp.156.2.317</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhabhar FS. Effects of stress on immune function: the good, the bad, and the beautiful. Immunol Res. 2014;58(2-3):193-210. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12026-014-8517-0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen S, Tyrrell DA, Smith AP. Psychological stress and susceptibility to the common cold. N Engl J Med. 1991;325(9):606-612. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM199108293250903</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biondi M, Zannino LG. Psychological stress, neuroimmunomodulation, and susceptibility to infectious diseases in animals and man: a review. Psychother Psychosom. 1997;66(1):3-26. https://doi.org/10.1159/000289101</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen A, Zachariae R, Bovbjerg DH. Influence of psychological stress on upper respiratory infection-a meta-analysis of prospective studies. Psychosom Med. 2010;72(8):823-832. https://doi.org/10.1097/PSY.0b013e3181f1d003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song H, Fall K, Fang F, et al. Stress related disorders and subsequent risk of life threatening infections: population based sibling controlled cohort study. BMJ. 2019;367:l5784. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.l5784</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Modafferi S, Stornelli M, Chiarotti F, Cardona F, Bruni O. Sleep, anxiety and psychiatric symptoms in children with Tourette syndrome and tic disorders. Eur J Paediatr Neurol EJPN Off J Eur Paediatr Neurol Soc. 2016;20(5):696-703. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpn.2016.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loiselle CR, Lee O, Moran TH, Singer HS. Striatal microinfusion of Tourette syndrome and PANDAS sera: failure to induce behavioral changes. Mov Disord Off J Mov Disord Soc. 2004;19(4):390-396. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.10522</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor JR, Morshed SA, Parveen S, et al. An animal model of Tourette's syndrome. Am J Psychiatry. 2002;159(4):657-660. https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.159.4.657</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baganz NL, Blakely RD. A dialogue between the immune system and brain, spoken in the language of serotonin. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2013;4(1):48-63. https://doi.org/10.1021/cn300186b</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Worbe Y, Mallet L, Golmard J-L, et al. Repetitive behaviours in patients with Gilles de la Tourette syndrome: tics, compulsions, or both? PLoS ONE. 2010;5(9):e12959. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0012959</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Zis P, Buttiglione M. The role of immune mechanisms in Tourette syndrome. Brain Res. 2015;1617:126-143. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2014.04.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elamin I, Edwards MJ, Martino D. Immune dysfunction in Tourette syndrome. Behav Neurol. 2013;27(1):23-32. https://doi.org/10.3233/BEN-120295</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoekstra PJ, Dietrich A, Edwards MJ, Elamin I, Martino D. Environmental factors in Tourette syndrome. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2013;37(6):1040-1049. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2012.10.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Dale RC, Gilbert DL, Giovannoni G, Leckman JF. Immunopathogenic mechanisms in Tourette syndrome: a critical review. Mov Disord Off J Mov Disord Soc. 2009;24(9):1267-1279. https://doi.org/10.1002/mds.22504</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag A, Martino D, Apter A, et al. European Multicentre Tics in Children Studies (EMTICS): protocol for two cohort studies to assess risk factors for tic onset and exacerbation in children and adolescents. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2019;28(1):91-109. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00787-018-1190-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino D, Schrag A, Anastasiou Z, et al. Association of Group A Streptococcus exposure and exacerbations of chronic tic disorders: a multinational prospective cohort study. Neurology. 2021;96:e1680-e1693. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000011610</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pringsheim T, Okun MS, Müller-Vahl K, et al. Practice guideline recommendations summary: Treatment of tics in people with Tourette syndrome and chronic tic disorders. Neurology. 2019;92(19):896-906. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000007466</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
