<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34141810</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>06</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <Issue>17</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Anti-Yo antibody-positive paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in a patient with possible cholangiocarcinoma: A case report and review of the literature.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>4423</StartPage>
          <EndPage>4432</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>4423-4432</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v9.i17.4423</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration (PCD), which is rare in clinical practice, is closely related to autoimmunity. Cases positive for anti-Yo antibodies (anti-Purkinje cytoplasmic antibody 1) are the main subtype of PCD. PCD is subacute cerebellar degeneration, and while it progresses over weeks to months, its resultant deficits last much longer. Cancer patients with anti-Yo antibody-positive PCD are very rare. Most of them are breast cancer or ovarian cancer patients but also occasionally lung cancer patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CASE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 61-year-old woman presented with sudden vertigo, nausea, and vomiting for approximately 10 d. The patient's neurological examination showed torsion with downbeat nystagmus and ataxia of the right limb and trunk. Laboratory examination found that the patient's cerebrospinal fluid and serum were anti-Yo antibody-positive, positron emission tomography computed tomography showed an increased metabolic rate in the retroperitoneal lymph nodes, and the pathology of lymph node punctures in the retroperitoneum and neck suggested adenocarcinoma of the pancreaticobiliary duct, which strengthens the hypothesis of paraneoplastic origin. Intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIg) 0.4 g/kg/d for 5 d and methylprednisolone 160 mg for 3 d were initiated, which was reduced to 80 mg for 3 d and then to 40 mg for 7 d. After treatment with IVIg and a steroid, the patient's vertigo and ataxia alleviated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The patient's vertigo and ataxia alleviated after treatment, suggesting that early immunotherapeutic intervention may have certain value in stopping neurological loss.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©The Author(s) 2021. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yue</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Affiliated Zhejiang Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shan-Hu</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Affiliated Zhejiang Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Si-Ran</ForeName>
            <Initials>SR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Affiliated Zhejiang Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qin-Fen</ForeName>
            <Initials>QF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Affiliated Zhejiang Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiao-Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>XL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Affiliated Zhejiang Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou 310000, Zhejiang Province, China. liuxiaoli0907@126.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Yo antibody</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case report</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cholangiocarcinoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare that they have no competing interests to report.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>48</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34141810</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173421</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v9.i17.4423</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahman SU, Sana MK, Tahir Z, Ali A, Shah PA. Paraneoplastic syndromes in cholangiocarcinoma. World J Hepatol. 2020;12:897–907.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7701960</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogrig A, Gigli GL, Segatti S, Corazza E, Marini A, Bernardini A, Valent F, Fabris M, Curcio F, Brigo F, Iacono D, Passadore P, Rana M, Honnorat J, Valente M. Epidemiology of paraneoplastic neurological syndromes: a population-based study. J Neurol. 2020;267:26–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31552550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Höftberger R, Lassmann H. Immune-mediated disorders. Handb Clin Neurol. 2017;145:285–299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vatankulu B, Yilmaz Aksoy S, Asa S, Sager S, Sayman HB, Halac M, Sonmezoglu K. Accuracy of FDG-PET/CT and paraneoplastic antibodies in diagnosing cancer in paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. Rev Esp Med Nucl Imagen Mol. 2016;35:17–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26260889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graus F, Delattre JY, Antoine JC, Dalmau J, Giometto B, Grisold W, Honnorat J, Smitt PS, Vedeler Ch, Verschuuren JJ, Vincent A, Voltz R. Recommended diagnostic criteria for paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2004;75:1135–1140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15258215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venkatraman A, Opal P. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration with anti-Yo antibodies - a review. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2016;3:655–663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999597</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27606347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogrig A, Bernardini A, Gigli GL, Corazza E, Marini A, Segatti S, Fabris M, Honnorat J, Valente M. Stroke-Like Presentation of Paraneoplastic Cerebellar Degeneration: a Single-Center Experience and Review of the Literature. Cerebellum. 2019;18:976–982.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31463826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitoma H, Adhikari K, Aeschlimann D, Chattopadhyay P, Hadjivassiliou M, Hampe CS, Honnorat J, Joubert B, Kakei S, Lee J, Manto M, Matsunaga A, Mizusawa H, Nanri K, Shanmugarajah P, Yoneda M, Yuki N. Consensus Paper: Neuroimmune Mechanisms of Cerebellar Ataxias. Cerebellum. 2016;15:213–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4591117</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25823827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yshii LM, Gebauer CM, Pignolet B, Mauré E, Quériault C, Pierau M, Saito H, Suzuki N, Brunner-Weinzierl M, Bauer J, Liblau R. CTLA4 blockade elicits paraneoplastic neurological disease in a mouse model. Brain. 2016;139:2923–2934.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27604307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panja D, Vedeler CA, Schubert M. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: Yo antibody alters mitochondrial calcium buffering capacity. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2019;45:141–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7379599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29679372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monstad SE, Storstein A, Dørum A, Knudsen A, Lønning PE, Salvesen HB, Aarseth JH, Vedeler CA. Yo antibodies in ovarian and breast cancer patients detected by a sensitive immunoprecipitation technique. Clin Exp Immunol. 2006;144:53–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1809634</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16542365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruhnding A, Notch D, Beard A. Anti-Yo positive paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in the setting of cholangiocarcinoma. J Clin Neurosci. 2017;36:71–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27816258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Funston G, Hamilton W, Abel G, Crosbie EJ, Rous B, Walter FM. The diagnostic performance of CA125 for the detection of ovarian and non-ovarian cancer in primary care: A population-based cohort study. PLoS Med. 2020;17:e1003295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592785</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33112854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiu Y, He J, Chen X, Huang P, Hu K, Yan H. The diagnostic value of five serum tumor markers for patients with cholangiocarcinoma. Clin Chim Acta. 2018;480:186–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29438681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laurens J, Angelaki DE. Simple spike dynamics of Purkinje cells in the macaque vestibulo-cerebellum during passive whole-body self-motion. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2020;117:3232–3238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7022220</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31988119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaikh AG, Ghasia FF, Dickman JD, Angelaki DE. Properties of cerebellar fastigial neurons during translation, rotation, and eye movements. J Neurophysiol. 2005;93:853–863.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15371498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Small M, Treilleux I, Couillault C, Pissaloux D, Picard G, Paindavoine S, Attignon V, Wang Q, Rogemond V, Lay S, Ray-Coquard I, Pfisterer J, Joly F, Du Bois A, Psimaras D, Bendriss-Vermare N, Caux C, Dubois B, Honnorat J, Desestret V. Genetic alterations and tumor immune attack in Yo paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135:569–579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29299667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carpenter EL, Vance BA, Klein RS, Voloschin A, Dalmau J, Vonderheide RH. Functional analysis of CD8+ T cell responses to the onconeural self protein cdr2 in patients with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. J Neuroimmunol. 2008;193:173–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18053582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Coevorden-Hameete MH, de Graaff E, Titulaer MJ, Hulsenboom E, Sabater L, Hoogenraad CC, Sillevis Smitt PA. Plasticity-related gene 5: A novel surface autoantigen in paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2015;2:e156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4582903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26445730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein JP, Stover DG, Oxnard GR, Levy BD, Loscalzo J. Restoring Balance: Paraneoplastic Cerebellar Degeneration. Am J Med. 2017;130:e85–e87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27816447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storstein A, Krossnes BK, Vedeler CA. Morphological and immunohistochemical characterization of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with Yo antibodies. Acta Neurol Scand. 2009;120:64–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19486326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vernino S. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration. Handb Clin Neurol. 2012;103:215–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21827891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsuboguchi S, Yajima R, Higuchi Y, Ishikawa M, Kawachi I, Koyama Y, Nishizawa M. A case of slowly progressive anti-Yo-associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration successfully treated with antitumor and immunotherapy. Rinsho Shinkeigaku. 2016;56:477–480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27356731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojas I, Graus F, Keime-Guibert F, Reñé R, Delattre JY, Ramón JM, Dalmau J, Posner JB. Long-term clinical outcome of paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and anti-Yo antibodies. Neurology. 2000;55:713–715.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10980743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shams'ili S, Grefkens J, de Leeuw B, van den Bent M, Hooijkaas H, van der Holt B, Vecht C, Sillevis Smitt P. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration associated with antineuronal antibodies: analysis of 50 patients. Brain. 2003;126:1409–1418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12764061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradley WH, Dottino PR, Rahaman J. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration in ovarian carcinoma: case report with review of immune modulation. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2008;18:1364–1367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18217973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raibagkar P, Ho D, Gunturu KS, Srinivasan J. Worsening of anti-Hu paraneoplastic neurological syndrome related to anti-PD-1 treatment: Case report and review of literature. J Neuroimmunol. 2020;341:577184.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manson G, Maria ATJ, Poizeau F, Danlos FX, Kostine M, Brosseau S, Aspeslagh S, Du Rusquec P, Roger M, Pallix-Guyot M, Ruivard M, Dousset L, Grignou L, Psimaras D, Pluvy J, Quéré G, Grados F, Duval F, Bourdain F, Maigne G, Perrin J, Godbert B, Taifas BI, Forestier A, Voisin AL, Martin-Romano P, Baldini C, Marabelle A, Massard C, Honnorat J, Lambotte O, Michot JM. Worsening and newly diagnosed paraneoplastic syndromes following anti-PD-1 or anti-PD-L1 immunotherapies, a descriptive study. J Immunother Cancer. 2019;7:337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6892018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31796119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vedeler CA, Antoine JC, Giometto B, Graus F, Grisold W, Hart IK, Honnorat J, Sillevis Smitt PA, Verschuuren JJ, Voltz R  Paraneoplastic Neurological Syndrome Euronetwork. Management of paraneoplastic neurological syndromes: report of an EFNS Task Force. Eur J Neurol. 2006;13:682–690.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16834698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widdess-Walsh P, Tavee JO, Schuele S, Stevens GH. Response to intravenous immunoglobulin in anti-Yo associated paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration: case report and review of the literature. J Neurooncol. 2003;63:187–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12825823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez GG, Read SB, Gerschenson LE, Santoli D, Zweifach A, Kruse CA. Interactions of the allogeneic effector leukemic T cell line, TALL-104, with human malignant brain tumors. Neuro Oncol. 2004;6:83–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1871983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15134622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
