<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34156512</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-0350</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>37</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Childs Nerv Syst</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Iatrogenic syringomyelia postcranial surgery in pediatric patients: systematic review and illustrative case.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2879</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2890</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2879-2890</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00381-021-05268-8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Iatrogenic syringomyelia has previously been described preoperatively due to space occupying lesions and postoperatively predominantly postspinal CSF drainage. Iatrogenic syringomyelia after cranial surgery is a rare entity. The purpose of this study is to review the current literature for iatrogenic syringomyelia following cranial surgery in children.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS">We performed a systematic review in accordance with the PRISMA (Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and meta-analyses) guidelines. Using keywords "de novo," "acquired," "iatrogenic," "postoperative development," and "syringomyelia," we searched PubMed and Scopus databases. We paid particular attention to type of surgery, clinical presentation, management, and outcome. We also present a relevant case report, operated on at John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The systematic literature review provided 19 cases of iatrogenic syringomyelia postcranial surgery in pediatric patients, in addition to our case report, resulting in a total of 20 cases reported. The patients' mean age at surgery preceding syringomyelia was 8.1 years (range 0.1-17) with a female sex predilection (2.7:1). The mean time of manifestation of the iatrogenic syringomyelia after surgery was 5.7 years (range 0.1-51), and the median time to presentation was 1.7 years. Nine children had surgery for Chiari I malformation before formation of the syrinx, 8 patients underwent shunt surgery, 2 children had intracranial tumor surgery, and 1 patient had lambdoid and sagittal suturectomy for scaphocephaly before developing a syrinx. Surgery after the manifestation of the iatrogenic syrinx resolved the symptoms in 9 patients; in 8 patients, the symptoms partially resolved; and in 1 patient, the symptoms persisted. After surgery addressing the syrinx, it resolved in 5, decreased in size in 10, and remained unchanged in 2 of the patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Iatrogenic syringomyelia after cranial surgery in pediatric patients occurs mainly after decompressive surgery for Chiari I malformation, shunt surgery, and less frequently following intracranial tumor surgery. Risk factors are postoperative intracranial scarring, shunt malfunction, and mass effect on the foramen magnum. Surgery addressing the iatrogenic syrinx seems to be effective in the majority of the patients in terms of clinical and radiological outcome.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kurzbuch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Arthur R</ForeName>
            <Initials>AR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9999-1147</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Neurosurgery, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, UK. kurzbuch@web.de.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Service de Neurochirurgie, Hôpital du Valais, Centre Hospitalier du Valais Romand (CHVR), Hôpital de Sion, Sion, Switzerland. kurzbuch@web.de.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Magdum</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shailendra</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Neurosurgery, Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Childs Nerv Syst</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8503227</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0256-7040</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001139" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arnold-Chiari Malformation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005539" MajorTopicYN="N">Foramen Magnum</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007049" MajorTopicYN="N">Iatrogenic Disease</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013595" MajorTopicYN="Y">Syringomyelia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Acquired</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">De novo</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Iatrogenic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Pediatric</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Postoperative</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Syringomyelia</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34156512</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-021-05268-8</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00381-021-05268-8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middlebrooks EH, Okromelidze L, Vilanilam GK, Gopal N, Luetmer PH, Gupta V (2020) Syrinx secondary to Chiari-like tonsillar herniation in spontaneous intracranial hypotension. World Neurosurg 143:e268–e274</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2020.07.108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del Maestro M, De Paulis D, Ricci A, Di Cola F, Galzio R (2014) Syringobulbia associated with posterior fossa meningioma: a review of the literature. Childs Nerv Syst 30(10):1749–1752</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-014-2457-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morioka T, Shono T, Nishio S, Yoshida K, Hasuo K, Fukui M (1995) Acquired Chiari I malformation and syringomyelia associated with bilateralchronic subdural hematoma. Case report J Neurosurg 83(3):556–558</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7666236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fischer EG, Welch K, Shillito J Jr (1977) Syringomyelia following lumboureteral shunting for communicating hydrocephalus. Report of three cases J Neurosurg 47:96–100</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">864509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnston I, Jacobson E, Besser M (1998) The acquired Chiari malformation and syringomyelia following spinal CSF drainage: a study of incidence and management. Acta Neurochir(Wien) 140:417–428</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padmanabhan R, Crompton D, Burn D, Birchall D (2005) AcquiredChiari 1 malformation and syringomyelia following lumboperitoneal shunting for pseudotumour cerebri. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 76:298</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2004.051276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riffaud L, Moughty C, Henaux PL, Haegelen C, Morandi X (2008) Acquired Chiari I malformation and syringomyelia after valveless lumboperitoneal shunt in infancy. Pediatr Neurosurg 44:229–233</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000121381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scholsem M, Scholtes F, Belachew S, Martin D (2008) Acquired tonsillar herniation and syringomyelia after pleural effusion aspiration: case report. Neurosurgery 62:E1172–E1173</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/01.neu.0000325884.05871.aa</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben Nsir A, Boubaker A, Jemel H (2016) Syringomyelia following surgery for a spontaneous spinal subdural hematoma in a 13-year-old girl with congenital von Willebrand disease: case report and literature review. Childs Nerv Syst 32:727–731</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-015-2875-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG; PRISMA Group (2009) Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PloS Med 6(7)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naftel RP, Tubbs RS, Menendez JY, Wellons JC 3rd, Pollack IF, Oakes WJ (2013) Worsening or development of syringomyelia following Chiari I decompression: case report. J Neurosurg Pediatr 12(4):351–356</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2013.7.PEDS12522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giordano M, Di Rocco C (2016) Iatrogenic intradiploic cerebrospinal fluid collection. Childs Nerv Syst 32(5):787–790</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-016-3037-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurzbuch AR, Magdum S (2020) CSF goes astray no matter what is in the way: occipital intradiploic pseudomeningocele and de novo syringomyelia following foramen magnum decompression for Chiari I malformation in a pediatric patient. J Neurosurg Pediatr 7:1–6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng CH, Lin HL, Chuang HY (2018) Tonsillar herniation as a complication of lumboperitoneal shunt: case report and literature review. Br J Neurosurg 6:1–4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02688697.2018.1538481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park SW, Park MS, Hwang JS, Shin YS, Yoon SH (2006) A case of Sotos syndrome with subduroperitoneal shunt. Pediatr Neurosurg 42(3):174–179</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000091863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peraud A, Grau S (2009) Decompensated hydrocephalus causing syringomyelia and tetraparesis: a case report. Childs Nerv Syst 25(2):263–266</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-008-0739-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramakrishna R, Mai JC, Filardi T, Browd SR, Ellenbogen RG (2011) Brainstem hypertrophy, acquired Chiari malformation, syringomyelia, and hydrocephalus: diagnostic dilemma. J Neurosurg Pediatr 8(2):184–188</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2011.5.PEDS10380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter EO, Pincus DW (2006) Development of syringohydromyelia associated with Dandy-Walker malformation: treatment with cystoperitoneal shunt placement. Case report J Neurosurg 104(3 Suppl):206–209</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16572641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang R, Qiu Y, Jiang J, Liu Z (2007) Atypical syringomyelia without cavity in a patient with Chiari malformation and hydrocephalus. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 32(16):E467–E470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang C, Deng X, Yang J, Xu Y (2019) Shunt dependency syndrome and acquired Chiari malformation secondary to cerebrospinal fluid diversion procedures: a 9-year longitudinal observation. Childs Nerv Sys 35(4):707–711</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-018-4014-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokota H, Tamaki R, Sugimoto T, Horiuchi K, Mori K, Miyamae S, Yaegaki T, Tanaka H, Iida JI (2020) Communicating syringomyelia World Neurosurg 140:96–100</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.wneu.2020.05.073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feller CN, Jensen JN, Lew SM (2021) Chiari malformation type 1 and syringomyelia in a patient with prior surgically-treated sagittal synostosis effectively treated with posterior cranial vault distraction osteogenesis. J Craniofac Surg. https://doi.org/10.1097/SCS.0000000000007401</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SCS.0000000000007401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muzumdar D, Balasubramanian S, Goel A (2009) Tonsillar herniation and cervical syringomyelia due to postoperative meningitis in case of pineal region epidermoid. Pediatr Neurosurg 45(1):56–60</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000204905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Rocco C (2019) Should we stop using the term “malformation”for Chiari type I? Childs Nerv Syst 35(10):1649–1650</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-019-04311-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
