<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34175860</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6971</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in pulmonary medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Genetics in sarcoidosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>423</StartPage>
          <EndPage>429</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>423-429</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000798</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Epidemiological and clinical observations as well as familial clustering support the existence of a genetic predisposition to sarcoidosis. In this article, we review the most recent findings in genetics of sarcoidosis and discuss how the identification of risk alleles may help advancing our understanding of disease etiology and development.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Genetic studies of sarcoidosis phenotypes have identified novel and ancestry-specific associations. Gene-environment interaction studies highlighted the importance of integrating genetic information when assessing the relationship between sarcoidosis and environmental exposures. A case-control-family study revealed that the heritability of sarcoidosis is only 49%, suggesting the existence of additional important contributors to disease risk. The application of whole-exome sequencing has identified associations with disease activity and prognosis. Finally, gene expression studies of circulating immune cells have identified shared and unique pathways between sarcoidosis and other granulomatous diseases.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Sarcoidosis genetic research has led to the identification of a number of associations with both sarcoidoses per se and disease phenotypes. Newer sequencing technologies are likely to increase the number of genetic variants associated with sarcoidosis. However, studying phenotypically and ethnically homogeneous patient subsets remains critically important regardless of the genetic approach used.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spagnolo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paolo</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Respiratory Disease Unit, Department of Cardiac Thoracic, Vascular Sciences and Public Health, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maier</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lisa A</ForeName>
            <Initials>LA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, National Jewish Health.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Colorado School of Public Health, University of Colorado Denver - Anschutz Medical Campus, Aurora, Colorado, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 HL140357</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 HL142049</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R21 HL081766</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pulm Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9503765</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1070-5287</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012507" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcoidosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000073359" MajorTopicYN="N">Whole Exome Sequencing</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest. There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175860</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1716561</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8373710</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000798</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00063198-202109000-00020</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spagnolo P Sarcoidosis: A critical review of history and milestones. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol 2015;49:1–5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25737246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spagnolo P, Rossi G, Trisolini R, Sverzellati N, Baughman RP, Wells AU. Pulmonary sarcoidosis. Lancet Respir Med 2018;6:389–402</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moller DR, Rybicki BA, Hamzeh NY, Montgomery CG, Chen ES, Drake W, et al.Genetic, Immunologic, and Environmental Basis of Sarcoidosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2017;14:S429–S436</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822412</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato H, Woodhead FA, Ahmad T, Grutters JC, Spagnolo P, van den Bosch JM, et al.Sarcoidosis HLA class II genotyping distinguishes differences of clinical phenotype across ethnic groups. Hum Mol Genet 2010;19:4100–11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4351376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20685690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garman L, Pezant N, Pastori A, Savoy KA, Li C, Levin AM, et al.Genome-Wide Association Study of Ocular Sarcoidosis Confirms HLA Associations and Implicates Barrier Function and Autoimmunity in African Americans. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2020March6;1–6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32141793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozyilmaz E, Akilli R, Berk İ, Deniz A, Ozturk OG, Baydar O, et al.The frequency of diastolic dysfunction in patients with sarcoidosis and it’s relationship with HLA DRB1* alleles. Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis 2019;36:285–293</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32476964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sikorova K, Kishore A, Rapti A, Adam K, Kocourkova L, Zizkova V, et al.Association of TGF-β3 and ANXA11 with pulmonary sarcoidosis in Greek population. Expert Rev Respir Med 2020;14:1065–1069</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32552203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaperon M, Pacheco Y, Maucort-Boulch D, Iwaz J, Perard L, Broussolle C, et al.BTNL2 gene polymorphism and sarcoid uveitis. Br J Ophthalmol 2019;103:1690–1694</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meguro A, Ishihara M, Petrek M, Yamamoto K, Takeuchi M, Mrazek F, et al.Genetic control of CCL24, POR, and IL23R contributes to the pathogenesis of sarcoidosis. Commun Biol 2020;3:465.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7442816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stjepanovic MI, Mihailovic-Vucinic V, Spasovski V, Milin-Lazovic J, Skodric-Trifunovic V, Stankovic S, et al.Genes and metabolic pathway of sarcoidosis: identification of key players and risk modifiers. Arch Med Sci 2019;15:1138–1146</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6764301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31572458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaessinger S, Zhou Y, Bray SJ, Tapon N, Djiane A. Drosophila MAGI interacts with RASSF8 to regulate E-Cadherin-based adherens junctions in the developing eye. Development 2015;142:1102–1112</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4360174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25725070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen T, Liu XK, Zhang Y, Dong C. BTNL2, a Butyrophilin-Like Molecule That Functions to Inhibit T Cell Activation. J Immunol 2006;176:7354–7360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1626526</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16751379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valentonyte R, Hampe J, Huse K, Rosenstiel P, Albrecht M, Stenzel A, et al.Sarcoidosis is associated with a truncating splice site mutation in BTNL2. Nat Genet 2005;37:357–364</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spagnolo P, Sato H, Grutters JC, Renzoni EA, Marshall SE, Ruven HJ, et al.Analysis of BTNL2 genetic polymorphisms in British and Dutch patients with sarcoidosis. Tissue Antigens 2007;70:219–227</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17661910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin Y, Wei J, Fan L, Cheng D. BTNL2 gene polymorphism and sarcoidosis susceptibility: a meta-analysis. PLoS One 2017;10:e0122639</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4388687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25849037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman LS, Rose CS, Bresnitz EA, Rossman MD, Barnard J, Frederick M, et al.A case control etiologic study of sarcoidosis: Environmental and occupational risk factors. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2004;170:1324–1330</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15347561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ungprasert P, Crowson CS, Matteson EL. Smoking, obesity and risk of sarcoidosis: A population-based nested case- control study. Resp Med 2016;120:87–90</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5185320</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Julian MW, Shao G, Schlesinger LS, et al.Nicotine treat- ment improves Toll-like receptor 2 and Toll-like receptor 9 responsiveness in active pulmonary sarcoidosis. Chest 2013;143:461–470</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22878868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta D, Singh AD, Agarwal R, Aggarwal AN, Joshi K, Jindal SK. Is tobacco smoking protective for sarcoidosis? A case-control study from North India. Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis. 2010;27:19–26</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21086901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webber MP, Yip J, Zeig-Owens R, Moir W, Ungprasert P, Crowson CS, et al.Post-9/11 sarcoidosis in WTC-exposed firefighters and emergency medical service workers. Respir Med 2017;132:232–237</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5720928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28622920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grunewald J, Spagnolo P, Wahlström J, Eklund A. Immunogenetics of Disease-Causing Inflammation in Sarcoidosis. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol 2015;49:19–35</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25791751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolin A, Lahtela EL, Anttila V, Petrek M, Grunewald J, van Moorsel CHM, et al.SNP Variants in Major Histocompatibility Complex Are Associated with Sarcoidosis Susceptibility-A Joint Analysis in Four European Populations. Front Immunol 2017;8:422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5395694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elenkov IJ, Wilder RL, Bakalov VK, Link AA, Dimitrov MA, Fisher S, et al.IL-12, TNF-α, and hormonal changes during late pregnancy and early postpartum: implications for autoimmune disease activity during these times. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2001;86:4933–4938</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen AL, Sun X, Wang W, Liu JF, Zeng X, Qiu JF, et al.Activation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis contributes to the immunosuppression of mice infected with Angiostrongylus cantonensis. J Neuroinflammation 2016;13:266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neville E, Walker AN, James DG. Prognostic factors predicting the outcome of sarcoidosis: an analysis of 818 patients. Q J Med 1983;52:525–533</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6657915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillerdal G, Nou E, Osterman K, Schmekel B. Sarcoidosis: epidemiology and prognosis. A 15-year European study. Am Rev Respir Dis 1984;130:29–32</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6742607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selroos O. Sarcoidosis and pregnancy: a review with results of a retrospective survey. J Intern Med 1990;227:221–224</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2324675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clamp M, Fry B, Kamal M, Xie X, Cuff J, Lin MF, et al.Distinguishing proteincoding and noncoding genes in the human genome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U.S.A. 2007;104:19428–33</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2148306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18040051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishore A, Petersen BS, Nutsua M, Müller-Quernheim J, Franke A, Fischer A, et al.Whole-exome sequencing identifies rare genetic variations in German families with pulmonary sarcoidosis. Hum Genet 2018;137:705–16</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calender A, Lim CX, Weichhart T, Buisson A, Besnard V, Rollat-Farnier PA, et al.Exome sequencing and pathogenicity-network analysis of 5 French families implicate TOR signalling and autophagy in familial sarcoidosis. Eur Respir J. 2019August1;54(2):1900430.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LeMaoult J, Zafaranloo K, Le Danff C, Carosella ED. HLA-G up-regulates ILT2, ILT3, ILT4, and KIR2DL4 in antigen presenting cells, NK cells, and T cells. FASEB J 2005;19:662–4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15670976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sverrild A, Backer V, Kyvik KO, Kaprio J, Milman N, Svendsen CB, et al.Heredity in sarcoidosis: a registry-based twin study. Thorax 2008;63:894–896</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18535119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linke M, Pham HT, Katholnig K, Schnöller T, Miller A, Demel F, et al.Chronic signaling via the metabolic checkpoint kinase mTORC1 induces macrophage granuloma formation and marks sarcoidosis progression. Nat Immunol 2017;18:293–302</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28092373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossides M, Grunewald J, Eklund A, Kullberg S, Di Giuseppe D, Askling J, et al.Familial aggregation and heritability of sarcoidosis: a Swedish nested case-control study. Eur Respir J 2018;52:1800385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Visscher PM, Wray NR, Zhang Q, Sklar P, McCarthy MI, Brown MA, et al.10 years of GWAS discovery: biology, function, and translation. Am J Hum Genet 2017;101:5–22</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casanova NG, Gonzalez-Garay ML, Sun B, Bime C, Sun X, Knox KS, et al.Differential transcriptomics in sarcoidosis lung and lymph node granulomas with comparisons to pathogen-specific granulomas. Respir Res 2020;21:321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716494</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33276795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koth LL, Solberg OD, Peng JC, Bhakta NR, Nguyen CP, Woodruff PG. Sarcoidosis blood transcriptome reflects lung inflammation and overlaps with tuberculosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2011;184:1153–1163</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3262024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21852540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talreja J, Farshi P, Alazizi A, Luca F, Pique-Regi R, Samavati L. RNA-sequencing identifies novel pathways in sarcoidosis monocytes. Sci Rep 2017;7:2720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28577019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garman L, Pelikan RC, Rasmussen A, Lareau CA, Savoy KA, Deshmukh US, et al.Single Cell Transcriptomics Implicate Novel Monocyte and T Cell Immune Dysregulation in Sarcoidosis. Front Immunol 2020;11:567342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaulian E, Karin M. AP-1 in cell proliferation and survival. Oncogene 2001;20:2390–2400</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11402335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34175860</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-6971</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in pulmonary medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Pulm Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Genetics in sarcoidosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>423</StartPage>
          <EndPage>429</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>423-429</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000798</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">Epidemiological and clinical observations as well as familial clustering support the existence of a genetic predisposition to sarcoidosis. In this article, we review the most recent findings in genetics of sarcoidosis and discuss how the identification of risk alleles may help advancing our understanding of disease etiology and development.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">Genetic studies of sarcoidosis phenotypes have identified novel and ancestry-specific associations. Gene-environment interaction studies highlighted the importance of integrating genetic information when assessing the relationship between sarcoidosis and environmental exposures. A case-control-family study revealed that the heritability of sarcoidosis is only 49%, suggesting the existence of additional important contributors to disease risk. The application of whole-exome sequencing has identified associations with disease activity and prognosis. Finally, gene expression studies of circulating immune cells have identified shared and unique pathways between sarcoidosis and other granulomatous diseases.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Sarcoidosis genetic research has led to the identification of a number of associations with both sarcoidoses per se and disease phenotypes. Newer sequencing technologies are likely to increase the number of genetic variants associated with sarcoidosis. However, studying phenotypically and ethnically homogeneous patient subsets remains critically important regardless of the genetic approach used.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spagnolo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paolo</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Respiratory Disease Unit, Department of Cardiac Thoracic, Vascular Sciences and Public Health, University of Padova, Padova, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maier</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lisa A</ForeName>
            <Initials>LA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, National Jewish Health.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Colorado School of Public Health, University of Colorado Denver - Anschutz Medical Campus, Aurora, Colorado, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 HL140357</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 HL142049</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R21 HL081766</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Pulm Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9503765</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1070-5287</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020022" MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic Predisposition to Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012507" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sarcoidosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000073359" MajorTopicYN="N">Whole Exome Sequencing</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest. There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34175860</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1716561</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8373710</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCP.0000000000000798</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00063198-202109000-00020</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spagnolo P Sarcoidosis: A critical review of history and milestones. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol 2015;49:1–5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25737246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spagnolo P, Rossi G, Trisolini R, Sverzellati N, Baughman RP, Wells AU. Pulmonary sarcoidosis. Lancet Respir Med 2018;6:389–402</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moller DR, Rybicki BA, Hamzeh NY, Montgomery CG, Chen ES, Drake W, et al.Genetic, Immunologic, and Environmental Basis of Sarcoidosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc 2017;14:S429–S436</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5822412</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato H, Woodhead FA, Ahmad T, Grutters JC, Spagnolo P, van den Bosch JM, et al.Sarcoidosis HLA class II genotyping distinguishes differences of clinical phenotype across ethnic groups. Hum Mol Genet 2010;19:4100–11</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4351376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20685690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garman L, Pezant N, Pastori A, Savoy KA, Li C, Levin AM, et al.Genome-Wide Association Study of Ocular Sarcoidosis Confirms HLA Associations and Implicates Barrier Function and Autoimmunity in African Americans. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2020March6;1–6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32141793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozyilmaz E, Akilli R, Berk İ, Deniz A, Ozturk OG, Baydar O, et al.The frequency of diastolic dysfunction in patients with sarcoidosis and it’s relationship with HLA DRB1* alleles. Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis 2019;36:285–293</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32476964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sikorova K, Kishore A, Rapti A, Adam K, Kocourkova L, Zizkova V, et al.Association of TGF-β3 and ANXA11 with pulmonary sarcoidosis in Greek population. Expert Rev Respir Med 2020;14:1065–1069</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32552203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaperon M, Pacheco Y, Maucort-Boulch D, Iwaz J, Perard L, Broussolle C, et al.BTNL2 gene polymorphism and sarcoid uveitis. Br J Ophthalmol 2019;103:1690–1694</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meguro A, Ishihara M, Petrek M, Yamamoto K, Takeuchi M, Mrazek F, et al.Genetic control of CCL24, POR, and IL23R contributes to the pathogenesis of sarcoidosis. Commun Biol 2020;3:465.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7442816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32826979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stjepanovic MI, Mihailovic-Vucinic V, Spasovski V, Milin-Lazovic J, Skodric-Trifunovic V, Stankovic S, et al.Genes and metabolic pathway of sarcoidosis: identification of key players and risk modifiers. Arch Med Sci 2019;15:1138–1146</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6764301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31572458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaessinger S, Zhou Y, Bray SJ, Tapon N, Djiane A. Drosophila MAGI interacts with RASSF8 to regulate E-Cadherin-based adherens junctions in the developing eye. Development 2015;142:1102–1112</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4360174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25725070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen T, Liu XK, Zhang Y, Dong C. BTNL2, a Butyrophilin-Like Molecule That Functions to Inhibit T Cell Activation. J Immunol 2006;176:7354–7360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1626526</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16751379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valentonyte R, Hampe J, Huse K, Rosenstiel P, Albrecht M, Stenzel A, et al.Sarcoidosis is associated with a truncating splice site mutation in BTNL2. Nat Genet 2005;37:357–364</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15735647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spagnolo P, Sato H, Grutters JC, Renzoni EA, Marshall SE, Ruven HJ, et al.Analysis of BTNL2 genetic polymorphisms in British and Dutch patients with sarcoidosis. Tissue Antigens 2007;70:219–227</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17661910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin Y, Wei J, Fan L, Cheng D. BTNL2 gene polymorphism and sarcoidosis susceptibility: a meta-analysis. PLoS One 2017;10:e0122639</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4388687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25849037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman LS, Rose CS, Bresnitz EA, Rossman MD, Barnard J, Frederick M, et al.A case control etiologic study of sarcoidosis: Environmental and occupational risk factors. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2004;170:1324–1330</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15347561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ungprasert P, Crowson CS, Matteson EL. Smoking, obesity and risk of sarcoidosis: A population-based nested case- control study. Resp Med 2016;120:87–90</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5185320</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Julian MW, Shao G, Schlesinger LS, et al.Nicotine treat- ment improves Toll-like receptor 2 and Toll-like receptor 9 responsiveness in active pulmonary sarcoidosis. Chest 2013;143:461–470</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22878868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta D, Singh AD, Agarwal R, Aggarwal AN, Joshi K, Jindal SK. Is tobacco smoking protective for sarcoidosis? A case-control study from North India. Sarcoidosis Vasc Diffuse Lung Dis. 2010;27:19–26</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21086901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webber MP, Yip J, Zeig-Owens R, Moir W, Ungprasert P, Crowson CS, et al.Post-9/11 sarcoidosis in WTC-exposed firefighters and emergency medical service workers. Respir Med 2017;132:232–237</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5720928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28622920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grunewald J, Spagnolo P, Wahlström J, Eklund A. Immunogenetics of Disease-Causing Inflammation in Sarcoidosis. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol 2015;49:19–35</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25791751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolin A, Lahtela EL, Anttila V, Petrek M, Grunewald J, van Moorsel CHM, et al.SNP Variants in Major Histocompatibility Complex Are Associated with Sarcoidosis Susceptibility-A Joint Analysis in Four European Populations. Front Immunol 2017;8:422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5395694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28469621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elenkov IJ, Wilder RL, Bakalov VK, Link AA, Dimitrov MA, Fisher S, et al.IL-12, TNF-α, and hormonal changes during late pregnancy and early postpartum: implications for autoimmune disease activity during these times. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 2001;86:4933–4938</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11600565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen AL, Sun X, Wang W, Liu JF, Zeng X, Qiu JF, et al.Activation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis contributes to the immunosuppression of mice infected with Angiostrongylus cantonensis. J Neuroinflammation 2016;13:266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neville E, Walker AN, James DG. Prognostic factors predicting the outcome of sarcoidosis: an analysis of 818 patients. Q J Med 1983;52:525–533</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6657915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillerdal G, Nou E, Osterman K, Schmekel B. Sarcoidosis: epidemiology and prognosis. A 15-year European study. Am Rev Respir Dis 1984;130:29–32</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6742607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selroos O. Sarcoidosis and pregnancy: a review with results of a retrospective survey. J Intern Med 1990;227:221–224</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2324675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clamp M, Fry B, Kamal M, Xie X, Cuff J, Lin MF, et al.Distinguishing proteincoding and noncoding genes in the human genome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U.S.A. 2007;104:19428–33</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2148306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18040051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishore A, Petersen BS, Nutsua M, Müller-Quernheim J, Franke A, Fischer A, et al.Whole-exome sequencing identifies rare genetic variations in German families with pulmonary sarcoidosis. Hum Genet 2018;137:705–16</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30054724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calender A, Lim CX, Weichhart T, Buisson A, Besnard V, Rollat-Farnier PA, et al.Exome sequencing and pathogenicity-network analysis of 5 French families implicate TOR signalling and autophagy in familial sarcoidosis. Eur Respir J. 2019August1;54(2):1900430.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LeMaoult J, Zafaranloo K, Le Danff C, Carosella ED. HLA-G up-regulates ILT2, ILT3, ILT4, and KIR2DL4 in antigen presenting cells, NK cells, and T cells. FASEB J 2005;19:662–4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15670976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sverrild A, Backer V, Kyvik KO, Kaprio J, Milman N, Svendsen CB, et al.Heredity in sarcoidosis: a registry-based twin study. Thorax 2008;63:894–896</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18535119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linke M, Pham HT, Katholnig K, Schnöller T, Miller A, Demel F, et al.Chronic signaling via the metabolic checkpoint kinase mTORC1 induces macrophage granuloma formation and marks sarcoidosis progression. Nat Immunol 2017;18:293–302</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5321578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28092373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossides M, Grunewald J, Eklund A, Kullberg S, Di Giuseppe D, Askling J, et al.Familial aggregation and heritability of sarcoidosis: a Swedish nested case-control study. Eur Respir J 2018;52:1800385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29946010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Visscher PM, Wray NR, Zhang Q, Sklar P, McCarthy MI, Brown MA, et al.10 years of GWAS discovery: biology, function, and translation. Am J Hum Genet 2017;101:5–22</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casanova NG, Gonzalez-Garay ML, Sun B, Bime C, Sun X, Knox KS, et al.Differential transcriptomics in sarcoidosis lung and lymph node granulomas with comparisons to pathogen-specific granulomas. Respir Res 2020;21:321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716494</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33276795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koth LL, Solberg OD, Peng JC, Bhakta NR, Nguyen CP, Woodruff PG. Sarcoidosis blood transcriptome reflects lung inflammation and overlaps with tuberculosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2011;184:1153–1163</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3262024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21852540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talreja J, Farshi P, Alazizi A, Luca F, Pique-Regi R, Samavati L. RNA-sequencing identifies novel pathways in sarcoidosis monocytes. Sci Rep 2017;7:2720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28577019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garman L, Pelikan RC, Rasmussen A, Lareau CA, Savoy KA, Deshmukh US, et al.Single Cell Transcriptomics Implicate Novel Monocyte and T Cell Immune Dysregulation in Sarcoidosis. Front Immunol 2020;11:567342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaulian E, Karin M. AP-1 in cell proliferation and survival. Oncogene 2001;20:2390–2400</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11402335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
