<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34176127</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-4632</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>61</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The in vitro effect of nanoliposomal amphotericin B against two clinically important dermatophytes.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>383</StartPage>
          <EndPage>389</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>383-389</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ijd.15609</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The present study aimed to investigate the antifungal activity of amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes against Trichophyton interdigitale and Trichophyton rubrum. Moreover, it was attempted to assess the obtained resistance in vitro.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In total, 29 archived clinical strains, namely, T. interdigitale (n = 16) and T. rubrum (n = 13), were included in this study. These strains were determined using a previous ITS1-ITS2 region sequence. Moreover, a liposomal formulation of amphotericin B was formulated by a thin-film hydration method. Particle size, polydispersity index (PdI), and zeta potential (ZP) were measured by a Zetasizer. Furthermore, physicochemical properties, such as appearance, aggregation of particles, particle size, PdI, and ZP, were determined at 0-, 1-, and 3-month intervals. A scanning electron microscope (SEM) was also used to examine nanoparticles structure. The minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) of amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes, itraconazole, efinaconazole, terbinafine, and ciclopirox was determined according to the protocol of the broth microdilution method of CLSI M38-A2. The morphological changes of T. interdigitale and T. rubrum strains exposed to the amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes were observed using SEM.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes displayed a lower MIC compared to those of the amphotericin B and liposomes when used separately. Based on the results, amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes induced no drug resistance in any of the tested strains.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Accordingly, amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes can be a potent antifungal for the topical treatment of onychomycosis. There was no in vitro evidence regarding the resistance of the tested strains to amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes. This reflects that amphotericin B-loaded nanoliposomes have a low probability to induce drug resistance in dermatophyte species.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 the International Society of Dermatology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ahmad Nasrollahi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Saman</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research and Training in Skin Diseases and Leprosy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fattahi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Azam</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3613-4644</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research and Training in Skin Diseases and Leprosy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Naeimifar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atefeh</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Department, School of Pharmacy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lotfali</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ensieh</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Parasitology and Mycology, School of Medicine, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Firooz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alireza</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research and Training in Skin Diseases and Leprosy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Khamesipoor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ali</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research and Training in Skin Diseases and Leprosy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Skandari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Seyed Ebrahim</ForeName>
            <Initials>SE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research and Training in Skin Diseases and Leprosy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miramin Mohammadi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akram</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Research and Training in Skin Diseases and Leprosy, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0243704</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0011-9059</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>304NUG5GF4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017964">Itraconazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>7XU7A7DROE</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000666">Amphotericin B</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>G7RIW8S0XP</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077291">Terbinafine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000666" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amphotericin B</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003883" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthrodermataceae</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017964" MajorTopicYN="N">Itraconazole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008826" MajorTopicYN="N">Microbial Sensitivity Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077291" MajorTopicYN="N">Terbinafine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34176127</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.15609</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwata A, Watanabe Y, Kumagai N, et al. In vitro and in vivo assessment of dermatophyte acquired resistance to efinaconazole, a novel triazole antifungal. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2014; 58: 4920-4922.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG, Shear NH. Onychomycosis in the 21st century: an update on diagnosis, epidemiology, and treatment. J Cutan Med Surg 2017; 21: 525-539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A, Ryder J, Johnson A. Cumulative meta-analysis of systemic antifungal agents for the treatment of onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2004; 150: 537-544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taghipour S, Shamsizadeh F, Pchelin IM, et al. Emergence of terbinafine resistant Trichophyton mentagrophytes in Iran, harboring mutations in the squalene epoxidase (SQLE) gene. Infect Drug Resist 2020; 13: 845-850.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh A, Masih A, Khurana A, et al. High terbinafine resistance in Trichophyton interdigitale isolates in Delhi, India harbouring mutations in the squalene epoxidase gene. Mycoses 2018; 61: 477-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Süß A, Uhrlass S, Ludes A, et al. Extensive tinea corporis due to a terbinafine-resistant Trichophyton mentagrophytes isolate of the Indian genotype in a young infant from Bahrain in Germany. Hautarzt 2019; 70: 888-896.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pchelin IM, Azarov DV, Churina MA, et al. Species boundaries in the Trichophyton mentagrophytes/T. interdigitale species complex. Med Mycol 2019; 57: 781-789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiruma J, Kitagawa H, Noguchi H, et al. Terbinafine-resistant strain of Trichophyton interdigitale strain isolated from a tinea pedis patient. J Dermatol 2019; 46: 351-353.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khurana A, Masih A, Chowdhary A, et al. Correlation of in vitro susceptibility based on MICs and squalene epoxidase mutations with clinical response to terbinafine in patients with tinea corporis/cruris. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2018; 62: e01038-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alipour M, Mozafari N. Terbinafine susceptibility and genotypic heterogeneity in clinical isolates of Trichophyton mentagrophytes by random amplified polymorphic DNA (RAPD). J Mycol Med 2015; 25: e1-e9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saunte DM, Hare RK, Jørgensen KM, et al. Emerging terbinafine resistance in Trichophyton: clinical characteristics, squalene epoxidase gene mutations, and a reliable EUCAST method for detection. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2019; 63: e01126-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsieh A, Quenan S, Riat A, et al. A new mutation in the SQLE gene of Trichophyton mentagrophytes associated to terbinafine resistance in a couple with disseminated tinea corporis. J Mycol Med 2019; 29: 352-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burmester A, Hipler U-C, Hensche R, et al. Point mutations in the squalene epoxidase gene of Indian ITS genotype VIII T. mentagrophytes identified after DNA isolation from infected scales. Med Mycol Case Rep 2019; 26: 23-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shankarnarayan SA, Shaw D, Sharma A, et al. Rapid detection of terbinafine resistance in Trichophyton species by amplified refractory mutation system-polymerase chain reaction. Sci Rep 2020; 10: 1-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ola H, Yahiya SA, El-Gazayerly ON. Effect of formulation design and freeze-drying on properties of fluconazole multilamellar liposomes. Saudi Pharm J 2010; 18: 217-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farboud ES, Nasrollahi SA, Tabbakhi Z. Novel formulation and evaluation of a Q10-loaded solid lipid nanoparticle cream: in vitro and in vivo studies. Int J Nanomed 2011; 6: 611.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wayne P. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute: reference method for broth dilution antifungal susceptibility testing of yeasts; approved standard. CLSI document M27-A3 and Supplement S 2008; 3: 6-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vijayan V, Aafreen S, Sakthivel S, et al. Formulation and characterization of solid lipid nanoparticles loaded Neem oil for topical treatment of acne. J Acute Dis 2013; 2: 282-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehnert W, Mäder K. Solid lipid nanoparticles: production, characterization and applications. Adv Drug Deliv Rev 2012; 64: 83-101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zylberberg C, Matosevic S. Pharmaceutical liposomal drug delivery: a review of new delivery systems and a look at the regulatory landscape. Drug Deliv 2016; 23: 3319-3329.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barratt G, Bretagne S. Optimizing efficacy of amphotericin B through nanomodification. Int J Nanomed 2007; 2: 301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dua J, Rana A, Bhandari A. Liposome: methods of preparation and applications. Int J Pharm Stud Res. 2012; 3: 14-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solano Umaña V, Vega Baudrit J, González Paz RJ. The new field of the nanomedicine. Int J Appl Sci Technol 2015; 1: 79-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honary S, Zahir F. Effect of zeta potential on the properties of nano-drug delivery systems-a review (Part 1). Trop J Pharm Res 2013; 12: 255-264.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asadi M, Hamishehkar H, Hashemi S. Evaluation of antifungal effects of nanoliposomal fluconazole against fluconazole susceptible and resistant Candida species isolated from patients in vitro and comparison with common fluconazole. Paper presented at: 11th International Symposium on Antimicrobial Agents and Resistance (ISAAR)/3rd International Interscience Conference on Infection and Chemotherapy (ICIC); 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang YU, Yang MO, Portney NG, et al. Zeta potential: a surface electrical characteristic to probe the interaction of nanoparticles with normal and cancer human breast epithelial cells. Biomed Microdevices 2008; 10: 321-328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vikaas B, Manjusha B, Manjusha C. Nanotechnology: applications in pharmaceutical drug delivery systems. J Chem Pharm Res 2016; 8: 259-265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subbenaik SC. Physical and chemical nature of nanoparticles. In: Kole C, Kumar D, Khodakovskaya M, eds. Plant Nanotechnology. Cham:Springer, 2016: 15-27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum M, Isham N, Verma A, et al. In vitro antifungal activity of naftifine hydrochloride against dermatophytes. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2013; 57: 4369-4372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aktas AE, Yigit N, Aktas A, et al. Investigation of in vitro activity of five antifungal drugs against dermatophytes species isolated from clinical samples using the E-test method. Eurasian J Med 2014; 46: 26-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernández-Torres B, Carrillo AJ, Martín E, et al. In vitro activities of 10 antifungal drugs against 508 dermatophyte strains. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 2001; 45: 2524-2528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badali H, Mohammadi R, Mashedi O, et al. In vitro susceptibility patterns of clinically important Trichophyton and Epidermophyton species against nine antifungal drugs. Mycoses 2015; 58: 303-307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coelho LM, Aquino-Ferreira R, Maffei CML, et al. In vitro antifungal drug susceptibilities of dermatophytes microconidia and arthroconidia. J Antimicrob Chemother 2008; 62: 758-761.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinha S, Sardana K. Antifungal efficacy of amphotericin b against dermatophytes and its relevance in recalcitrant dermatophytoses: a commentary. Indian Dermatol Online J 2018; 9: 120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
