<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34182207</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-8421</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>358</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neuroimmunology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroimmunol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A case of longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis following vaccination against Covid-19.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>577606</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>577606</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2021.577606</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0165-5728(21)00133-8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis (LETM) is a rare subtype of transverse myelitis (TM) that potentially results in relevant disability. Apart from association to neuromyelitis optica and other chronic demyelinating diseases of the central nervous system, many other aetiologies are known. Particularly systemic infections and vaccination are considered potential triggers for immune mediated inflammation of the spinal cord. In the course of the current Covid-19 pandemic several cases of TM following Covid-19 infection have been described. Here we present a case of LETM following vaccination against Covid-19 with AZD1222, AstraZeneca. An extensive diagnostic work up was performed to rule out alternative causes, including prior and current Covid-19 infection.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">To our knowledge this is first case of LETM possibly related to Covid-19 vaccination that is published after marketing authorisation of various vaccine candidates.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pagenkopf</LastName>
            <ForeName>Claudia</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Klinikum Ernst von Bergmann, Department of Neurology, Charlottenstrasse 72, 14467 Potsdam, Germany. Electronic address: claudia.pagenkopf@klinikumevb.de.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Südmeyer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Martin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Klinikum Ernst von Bergmann, Department of Neurology, Charlottenstrasse 72, 14467 Potsdam, Germany; Department of Neurology, Medical Faculty, University Düsseldorf, Düsseldorf, Germany. Electronic address: martin.suedmeyer@klinikumevb.de.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>06</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Neuroimmunol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8109498</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0165-5728</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000305">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>B5S3K2V0G8</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000090985">ChAdOx1 nCoV-19</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000305" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenal Cortex Hormones</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000090985" MajorTopicYN="N">ChAdOx1 nCoV-19</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009188" MajorTopicYN="N">Myelitis, Transverse</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="Y">chemically induced</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014611" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccination</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="Y">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Covid-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Covid-19 vaccination</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Transverse myelitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Vaccine related disorder</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34182207</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8223023</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2021.577606</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0165-5728(21)00133-8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agmon-Levin N., Kivity S., Szyper-Kravitz M., Shoenfeld Y. Transverse myelitis and vaccines: a multi-analysis. Lupus. 2009;18:1198–1204. doi: 10.1177/0961203309345730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203309345730</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19880568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akkad W., Salem B., Freeman J.W., Huntington M.K. Longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis following vaccination with nasal attenuated novel influenza A(H1N1) vaccine. Arch. Neurol. 2010;67 doi: 10.1001/archneurol.2010.167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneurol.2010.167</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20697056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Artemiadis A., Liampas A., Hadjigeorgiou L., Zis P. Myelopathy associated with SARS-COV-2 infection. A systematic review. Neurol. Res. 2021:1–9. doi: 10.1080/01616412.2021.1915078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01616412.2021.1915078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33870878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chow C.C.N., Magnussen J., Ip J., Su Y. Acute transverse myelitis in COVID-19 infection. BMJ Case Rep. 2020;13 doi: 10.1136/bcr-2020-236720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bcr-2020-236720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7418849</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellul M.A., Benjamin L., Singh B., Lant S., Michael B.D., Easton A., Kneen R., Defres S., Sejvar J., Solomon T. Neurological associations of COVID-19. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:767–783. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30221-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30221-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332267</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32622375</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Folegatti P.M., Ewer K.J., Aley P.K., Angus B., Becker S., Belij-Rammerstorfer S., Bellamy D., Bibi S., Bittaye M., Clutterbuck E.A., Dold C., Faust S.N., Finn A., Flaxman A.L., Hallis B., Heath P., Jenkin D., Lazarus R., Makinson R., Minassian A.M., Pollock K.M., Ramasamy M., Robinson H., Snape M., Tarrant R., Voysey M., Green C., Douglas A.D., Hill A.V.S., Lambe T., Gilbert S.C., Pollard A.J., Aboagye J., Adams K., Ali A., Allen E., Allison J.L., Anslow R., Arbe-Barnes E.H., Babbage G., Baillie K., Baker M., Baker N., Baker P., Baleanu I., Ballaminut J., Barnes E., Barrett J., Bates L., Batten A., Beadon K., Beckley R., Berrie E., Berry L., Beveridge A., Bewley K.R., Bijker E.M., Bingham T., Blackwell L., Blundell C.L., Bolam E., Boland E., Borthwick N., Bower T., Boyd A., Brenner T., Bright P.D., Brown-O’Sullivan C., Brunt E., Burbage J., Burge S., Buttigieg K.R., Byard N., Cabera Puig I., Calvert A., Camara S., Cao M., Cappuccini F., Carr M., Carroll M.W., Carter V., Cathie K., Challis R.J., Charlton S., Chelysheva I., Cho J.-S., Cicconi P., Cifuentes L., Clark H., Clark E., Cole T., Colin-Jones R., Conlon C.P., Cook A., Coombes N.S., Cooper R., Cosgrove C.A., Coy K., Crocker W.E.M., Cunningham C.J., Damratoski B.E., Dando L., Datoo M.S., Davies H., De Graaf H., Demissie T., Di Maso C., Dietrich I., Dong T., Donnellan F.R., Douglas N., Downing C., Drake J., Drake-Brockman R., Drury R.E., Dunachie S.J., Edwards N.J., Edwards F.D.L., Edwards C.J., Elias S.C., Elmore M.J., Emary K.R.W., English M.R., Fagerbrink S., Felle S., Feng S., Field S., Fixmer C., Fletcher C., Ford K.J., Fowler J., Fox P., Francis E., Frater J., Furze J., Fuskova M., Galiza E., Gbesemete D., Gilbride C., Godwin K., Gorini G., Goulston L., Grabau C., Gracie L., Gray Z., Guthrie L.B., Hackett M., Halwe S., Hamilton E., Hamlyn J., Hanumunthadu B., Harding I., Harris S.A., Harris A., Harrison D., Harrison C., Hart T.C., Haskell L., Hawkins S., Head I., Henry J.A., Hill J., Hodgson S.H.C., Hou M.M., Howe E., Howell N., Hutlin C., Ikram S., Isitt C., Iveson P., Jackson S., Jackson F., James S.W., Jenkins M., Jones E., Jones K., Jones C.E., Jones B., Kailath R., Karampatsas K., Keen J., Kelly S., Kelly D., Kerr D., Kerridge S., Khan L., Khan U., Killen A., Kinch J., King T.B., King L., King J., Kingham-Page L., Klenerman P., Knapper F., Knight J.C., Knott D., Koleva S., Kupke A., Larkworthy C.W., Larwood J.P.J., Laskey A., Lawrie A.M., Lee A., Ngan Lee K.Y., Lees E.A., Legge H., Lelliott A., Lemm N.-M., Lias A.M., Linder A., Lipworth S., Liu X., Liu S., Lopez Ramon R., Lwin M., Mabesa F., Madhavan M., Mallett G., Mansatta K., Marcal I., Marinou S., Marlow E., Marshall J.L., Martin J., McEwan J., McInroy L., Meddaugh G., Mentzer A.J., Mirtorabi N., Moore M., Moran E., Morey E., Morgan V., Morris S.J., Morrison H., Morshead G., Morter R., Mujadidi Y.F., Muller J., Munera-Huertas T., Munro C., Munro A., Murphy S., Munster V.J., Mweu P., Noé A., Nugent F.L., Nuthall E., O’Brien K., O’Connor D., Oguti B., Oliver J.L., Oliveira C., O’Reilly P.J., Osborn M., Osborne P., Owen C., Owens D., Owino N., Pacurar M., Parker K., Parracho H., Patrick-Smith M., Payne V., Pearce J., Peng Y., Peralta Alvarez M.P., Perring J., Pfafferott K., Pipini D., Plested E., Pluess-Hall H., Pollock K., Poulton I., Presland L., Provstgaard-Morys S., Pulido D., Radia K., Ramos Lopez F., Rand J., Ratcliffe H., Rawlinson T., Rhead S., Riddell A., Ritchie A.J., Roberts H., Robson J., Roche S., Rohde C., Rollier C.S., Romani R., Rudiansyah I., Saich S., Sajjad S., Salvador S., Sanchez Riera L., Sanders H., Sanders K., Sapaun S., Sayce C., Schofield E., Screaton G., Selby B., Semple C., Sharpe H.R., Shaik I., Shea A., Shelton H., Silk S., Silva-Reyes L., Skelly D.T., Smee H., Smith C.C., Smith D.J., Song R., Spencer A.J., Stafford E., Steele A., Stefanova E., Stockdale L., Szigeti A., Tahiri-Alaoui A., Tait M., Talbot H., Tanner R., Taylor I.J., Taylor V., Te Water Naude R., Thakur N., Themistocleous Y., Themistocleous A., Thomas M., Thomas T.M., Thompson A., Thomson-Hill S., Tomlins J., Tonks S., Towner J., Tran N., Tree J.A., Truby A., Turkentine K., Turner C., Turner N., Turner S., Tuthill T., Ulaszewska M., Varughese R., Van Doremalen N., Veighey K., Verheul M.K., Vichos I., Vitale E., Walker L., Watson M.E.E., Welham B., Wheat J., White C., White R., Worth A.T., Wright D., Wright S., Yao X.L., Yau Y. Safety and immunogenicity of the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine against SARS-CoV-2: a preliminary report of a phase 1/2, single-blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2020;396:467–478. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31604-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31604-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32702298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garg R.K., Paliwal V.K., Gupta A. Spinal cord involvement in COVID-19: A review. J. Spinal Cord Med. 2021:1–15. doi: 10.1080/10790268.2021.1888022.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10790268.2021.1888022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33705268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goss A.L., Samudralwar R.D., Das R.R., Nath A. ANA investigates: neurological complications of COVID-19 vaccines. Ann. Neurol. 2021;89:856–857. doi: 10.1002/ana.26065.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26065</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33710649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S., Paul F., Franciotta D., Ruprecht K., Ringelstein M., Bergamaschi R., Rommer P., Kleiter I., Stich O., Reuss R., Rauer S., Zettl U.K., Wandinger K.P., Melms A., Aktas O., Kristoferitsch W., Wildemann B. Cerebrospinal fluid findings in aquaporin-4 antibody positive neuromyelitis optica: results from 211 lumbar punctures. J. Neurol. Sci. 2011;306:82–90. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2011.03.038.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2011.03.038</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21550068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jumah M., Rahman F., Figgie M., Prasad A., Zampino A., Fadhil A., Palmer K., Buerki R.A., Gunzler S., Gundelly P., Abboud H. COVID-19, HHV6 and MOG antibody: a perfect storm. J. Neuroimmunol. 2021;353:577521. doi: 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2021.577521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2021.577521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7879032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33607505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karussis D., Petrou P. The spectrum of post-vaccination inflammatory CNS demyelinating syndromes. Autoimmun. Rev. 2014;13:215–224. doi: 10.1016/j.autrev.2013.10.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.autrev.2013.10.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24514081</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilbertus S. Acute transverse myelitis attributed to SARS-CoV-2 infection presenting as impaired mobility: a case report. Can. J. Emerg. Med. 2021 doi: 10.1007/s43678-021-00104-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s43678-021-00104-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7917167</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33646523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitley J., Leite M., George J., Palace J. The differential diagnosis of longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis. Mult. Scler. 2012;18:271–285. doi: 10.1177/1352458511406165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458511406165</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21669935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) COVID-19 Vaccine AstraZeneca, Solution for Injection in Multidose Container COVID-19 Vaccine (ChAdOx1-S [Recombinant]) [WWW Document] 2021. https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/regulatory-approval-of-covid-19-vaccine-astrazeneca#history URL.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) COVID-19 Vaccine AstraZeneca Analysis Print [WWW Document] 2021. https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=2ahUKEwihn8Td4ofwAhUswQIHHdIsA04QFjABegQIBBAD&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.publishing.service.gov.uk%2Fgovernment%2Fuploads%2Fsystem%2Fuploads%2Fattachment_data%2Ffile%2F977006%2FCOVID-19_vaccine_AstraZeneca_analysis_print.pdf&amp;usg=AOvVaw3vAgGHPWUudjuoQIib5A3L URL. (accessed 8.5.21)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medicines and Healthcare products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) COVID-19 mRNA Pfizer-BionNTech Vaccine Analysis Print [WWW Document] 2021. https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiekdi244fwAhUPMuwKHd_QDgEQFjAAegQIBRAD&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fassets.publishing.service.gov.uk%2Fgovernment%2Fuploads%2Fsystem%2Fuploads%2Fattachment_data%2Ffile%2F978316%2F050421_PF_DAP.pdf&amp;usg=AOvVaw2IiHFsKW5ZdTyb5OEz2okB URL. (accessed 8.5.21)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno-Escobar M.C., Kataria S., Khan E., Subedi R., Tandon M., Peshwe K., Kramer J., Niaze F., Sriwastava S. Acute transverse myelitis with Dysautonomia following SARS-CoV-2 infection: a case report and review of literature. J. Neuroimmunol. 2021;353:577523. doi: 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2021.577523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2021.577523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7895682</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33640717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munz M., Wessendorf S., Koretsis G., Tewald F., Baegi R., Krämer S., Geissler M., Reinhard M. Acute transverse myelitis after COVID-19 pneumonia. J. Neurol. 2020;267:2196–2197. doi: 10.1007/s00415-020-09934-w.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-09934-w</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul-Ehrlich-Institut (PEI) Sicherheitsbericht Verdachtsfälle von Nebenwirkungen und Impfkomplikationen nach Impfung zum Schutz vor COVID-19 [WWW Document] 2021. https://www.pei.de/DE/newsroom/dossier/coronavirus/coronavirus-inhalt.html?cms_pos=5 URL. (accessed 8.5.21)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfeuffer S., Strippel C., Wiendl H. NMO-Spektrum-Erkrankungen. Akt Neurol. 2017;44:180–193. doi: 10.1055/s-0042-124178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-124178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy D., Ghosh R., Dubey S., Dubey M.J., Benito-León J., Kanti Ray B. Neurological and neuropsychiatric impacts of COVID-19 pandemic. Can. J. Neurol. Sci. 2021;48:9–24. doi: 10.1017/cjn.2020.173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/cjn.2020.173</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7533477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahali H., Ghasemi A., Farahani R.H., Nezami Asl A., Hazrati E. Acute transverse myelitis after SARS-CoV-2 infection: a rare complicated case of rapid onset paraplegia. J. Neuro-Oncol. 2021 doi: 10.1007/s13365-021-00957-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13365-021-00957-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7920546</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33650074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh Malhotra H., Gupta P., Prabhu V., Garg R.K., Dandu H., Agarwal V. COVID-19 vaccination-associated myelitis. QJM. 2021 doi: 10.1093/qjmed/hcab069. hcab069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/qjmed/hcab069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8083508</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Transverse Myelitis Consortium Working Group Proposed diagnostic criteria and nosology of acute transverse myelitis. Neurology. 2002;59:499–505. doi: 10.1212/WNL.59.4.499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.59.4.499</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12236201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voysey M., Clemens S.A.C., Madhi S.A., Weckx L.Y., Folegatti P.M., Aley P.K., Angus B., Baillie V.L., Barnabas S.L., Bhorat Q.E., Bibi S., Briner C., Cicconi P., Collins A.M., Colin-Jones R., Cutland C.L., Darton T.C., Dheda K., Duncan C.J.A., Emary K.R.W., Ewer K.J., Fairlie L., Faust S.N., Feng S., Ferreira D.M., Finn A., Goodman A.L., Green C.M., Green C.A., Heath P.T., Hill C., Hill H., Hirsch I., Hodgson S.H.C., Izu A., Jackson S., Jenkin D., Joe C.C.D., Kerridge S., Koen A., Kwatra G., Lazarus R., Lawrie A.M., Lelliott A., Libri V., Lillie P.J., Mallory R., Mendes A.V.A., Milan E.P., Minassian A.M., McGregor A., Morrison H., Mujadidi Y.F., Nana A., O’Reilly P.J., Padayachee S.D., Pittella A., Plested E., Pollock K.M., Ramasamy M.N., Rhead S., Schwarzbold A.V., Singh N., Smith A., Song R., Snape M.D., Sprinz E., Sutherland R.K., Tarrant R., Thomson E.C., Török M.E., Toshner M., Turner D.P.J., Vekemans J., Villafana T.L., Watson M.E.E., Williams C.J., Douglas A.D., Hill A.V.S., Lambe T., Gilbert S.C., Pollard A.J., Aban M., Abayomi F., Abeyskera K., Aboagye J., Adam M., Adams K., Adamson J., Adelaja Y.A., Adewetan G., Adlou S., Ahmed K., Akhalwaya Y., Akhalwaya S., Alcock A., Ali A., Allen E.R., Allen L., Almeida T.C.D.S.C., Alves M.P.S., Amorim F., Andritsou F., Anslow R., Appleby M., Arbe-Barnes E.H., Ariaans M.P., Arns B., Arruda L., Azi P., Azi L., Babbage G., Bailey C., Baker K.F., Baker M., Baker N., Baker P., Baldwin L., Baleanu I., Bandeira D., Bara A., Barbosa M.A.S., Barker D., Barlow G.D., Barnes E., Barr A.S., Barrett J.R., Barrett J., Bates L., Batten A., Beadon K., Beales E., Beckley R., Belij-Rammerstorfer S., Bell J., Bellamy D., Bellei N., Belton S., Berg A., Bermejo L., Berrie E., Berry L., Berzenyi D., Beveridge A., Bewley K.R., Bexhell H., Bhikha S., Bhorat A.E., Bhorat Z.E., Bijker E., Birch G., Birch S., Bird A., Bird O., Bisnauthsing K., Bittaye M., Blackstone K., Blackwell L., Bletchly H., Blundell C.L., Blundell S.R., Bodalia P., Boettger B.C., Bolam E., Boland E., Bormans D., Borthwick N., Bowring F., Boyd A., Bradley P., Brenner T., Brown P., Brown C., Brown-O’Sullivan C., Bruce S., Brunt E., Buchan R., Budd W., Bulbulia Y.A., Bull M., Burbage J., Burhan H., Burn A., Buttigieg K.R., Byard N., Cabera Puig I., Calderon G., Calvert A., Camara S., Cao M., Cappuccini F., Cardoso J.R., Carr M., Carroll M.W., Carson-Stevens A., de Carvalho Y.M., Carvalho J.A.M., Casey H.R., Cashen P., Castro T., Castro L.C., Cathie K., Cavey A., Cerbino-Neto J., Chadwick J., Chapman D., Charlton S., Chelysheva I., Chester O., Chita S., Cho J.-S., Cifuentes L., Clark E., Clark M., Clarke A., Clutterbuck E.A., Collins S.L.K., Conlon C.P., Connarty S., Coombes N., Cooper C., Cooper R., Cornelissen L., Corrah T., Cosgrove C., Cox T., Crocker W.E.M., Crosbie S., Cullen L., Cullen D., Cunha D.R.M.F., Cunningham C., Cuthbertson F.C., Da Guarda S.N.F., da Silva L.P., Damratoski B.E., Danos Z., Dantas M.T.D.C., Darroch P., Datoo M.S., Datta C., Davids M., Davies S.L., Davies H., Davis E., Davis Judith, Davis John, De Nobrega M.M.D., De Oliveira Kalid L.M., Dearlove D., Demissie T., Desai A., Di Marco S., Di Maso C., Dinelli M.I.S., Dinesh T., Docksey C., Dold C., Dong T., Donnellan F.R., Dos Santos T., dos Santos T.G., Dos Santos E.P., Douglas N., Downing C., Drake J., Drake-Brockman R., Driver K., Drury R., Dunachie S.J., Durham B.S., Dutra L., Easom N.J.W., van Eck S., Edwards M., Edwards N.J., El Muhanna O.M., Elias S.C., Elmore M., English M., Esmail A., Essack Y.M., Farmer E., Farooq M., Farrar M., Farrugia L., Faulkner B., Fedosyuk S., Felle S., Feng S., Ferreira Da Silva C., Field S., Fisher R., Flaxman A., Fletcher J., Fofie H., Fok H., Ford K.J., Fowler J., Fraiman P.H.A., Francis E., Franco M.M., Frater J., Freire M.S.M., Fry S.H., Fudge S., Furze J., Fuskova M., Galian-Rubio P., Galiza E., Garlant H., Gavrila M., Geddes A., Gibbons K.A., Gilbride C., Gill H., Glynn S., Godwin K., Gokani K., Goldoni U.C., Goncalves M., Gonzalez I.G.S., Goodwin J., Goondiwala A., Gordon-Quayle K., Gorini G., Grab J., Gracie L., Greenland M., Greenwood N., Greffrath J., Groenewald M.M., Grossi L., Gupta G., Hackett M., Hallis B., Hamaluba M., Hamilton E., Hamlyn J., Hammersley D., Hanrath A.T., Hanumunthadu B., Harris S.A., Harris C., Harris T., Harrison T.D., Harrison D., Hart T.C., Hartnell B., Hassan S., Haughney J., Hawkins S., Hay J., Head I., Henry J., Hermosin Herrera M., Hettle D.B., Hill J., Hodges G., Horne E., Hou M.M., Houlihan C., Howe E., Howell N., Humphreys J., Humphries H.E., Hurley K., Huson C., Hyder-Wright A., Hyams C., Ikram S., Ishwarbhai A., Ivan M., Iveson P., Iyer V., Jackson F., De Jager J., Jaumdally S., Jeffers H., Jesudason N., Jones B., Jones K., Jones E., Jones C., Jorge M.R., Jose A., Joshi A., Júnior E.A.M.S., Kadziola J., Kailath R., Kana F., Karampatsas K., Kasanyinga M., Keen J., Kelly E.J., Kelly D.M., Kelly D., Kelly S., Kerr D., de Kfouri R.Á., Khan L., Khozoee B., Kidd S., Killen A., Kinch J., Kinch P., King L.D.W., King T.B., Kingham L., Klenerman P., Knapper F., Knight J.C., Knott D., Koleva S., Lang M., Lang G., Larkworthy C.W., Larwood J.P.J., Law R., Lazarus E.M., Leach A., Lees E.A., Lemm N.-M., Lessa A., Leung S., Li Y., Lias A.M., Liatsikos K., Linder A., Lipworth S., Liu S., Liu X., Lloyd A., Lloyd S., Loew L., Lopez Ramon R., Lora L., Lowthorpe V., Luz K., MacDonald J.C., MacGregor G., Madhavan M., Mainwaring D.O., Makambwa E., Makinson R., Malahleha M., Malamatsho R., Mallett G., Mansatta K., Maoko T., Mapetla K., Marchevsky N.G., Marinou S., Marlow E., Marques G.N., Marriott P., Marshall R.P., Marshall J.L., Martins F.J., Masenya M., Masilela M., Masters S.K., Mathew M., Matlebjane H., Matshidiso K., Mazur O., Mazzella A., McCaughan H., McEwan J., McGlashan J., McInroy L., McIntyre Z., McLenaghan D., McRobert N., McSwiggan S., Megson C., Mehdipour S., Meijs W., Mendonça R.N.Á., Mentzer A.J., Mirtorabi N., Mitton C., Mnyakeni S., Moghaddas F., Molapo K., Moloi M., Moore M., Moraes-Pinto M.I., Moran M., Morey E., Morgans R., Morris Susan, Morris Sheila, Morris H.C., Morselli F., Morshead G., Morter R., Mottal L., Moultrie A., Moya N., Mpelembue M., Msomi S., Mugodi Y., Mukhopadhyay E., Muller J., Munro A., Munro C., Murphy S., Mweu P., Myasaki C.H., Naik G., Naker K., Nastouli E., Nazir A., Ndlovu B., Neffa F., Njenga C., Noal H., Noé A., Novaes G., Nugent F.L., Nunes G., O’Brien K., O’Connor D., Odam M., Oelofse S., Oguti B., Olchawski V., Oldfield N.J., Oliveira M.G., Oliveira C., Oosthuizen A., O’Reilly P., Osborne P., Owen D.R.J., Owen L., Owens D., Owino N., Pacurar M., Paiva B.V.B., Palhares E.M.F., Palmer S., Parkinson S., Parracho H.M.R.T., Parsons K., Patel D., Patel B., Patel F., Patel K., Patrick-Smith M., Payne R.O., Peng Y., Penn E.J., Pennington A., Peralta Alvarez M.P., Perring J., Perry N., Perumal R., Petkar S., Philip T., Phillips D.J., Phillips J., Phohu M.K., Pickup L., Pieterse S., Piper J., Pipini D., Plank M., Du Plessis J., Pollard S., Pooley J., Pooran A., Poulton I., Powers C., Presa F.B., Price D.A., Price V., Primeira M., Proud P.C., Provstgaard-Morys S., Pueschel S., Pulido D., Quaid S., Rabara R., Radford A., Radia K., Rajapaska D., Rajeswaran T., Ramos A.S.F., Ramos Lopez F., Rampling T., Rand J., Ratcliffe H., Rawlinson T., Rea D., Rees B., Reiné J., Resuello-Dauti M., Reyes Pabon E., Ribiero C.M., Ricamara M., Richter A., Ritchie N., Ritchie A.J., Robbins A.J., Roberts H., Robinson R.E., Robinson H., Rocchetti T.T., Rocha B.P., Roche S., Rollier C., Rose L., Ross Russell A.L., Rossouw L., Royal S., Rudiansyah I., Ruiz S., Saich S., Sala C., Sale J., Salman A.M., Salvador N., Salvador S., Sampaio M., Samson A.D., Sanchez-Gonzalez A., Sanders H., Sanders K., Santos E., Santos Guerra M.F.S., Satti I., Saunders J.E., Saunders C., Sayed A., Schim Van Der Loeff I., Schmid A.B., Schofield E., Screaton G., Seddiqi S., Segireddy R.R., Senger R., Serrano S., Shah R., Shaik I., Sharpe H.E., Sharrocks K., Shaw R., Shea A., Shepherd A., Shepherd J.G., Shiham F., Sidhom E., Silk S.E., da Silva Moraes A.C., Silva-Junior G., Silva-Reyes L., Silveira A.D., Silveira M.B.V., Sinha J., Skelly D.T., Smith D.C., Smith N., Smith H.E., Smith D.J., Smith C.C., Soares A., Soares T., Solórzano C., Sorio G.L., Sorley K., Sosa-Rodriguez T., Souza C.M.C.D.L., Souza B.S.D.F., Souza A.R., Spencer A.J., Spina F., Spoors L., Stafford L., Stamford I., Starinskij I., Stein R., Steven J., Stockdale L., Stockwell L.V., Strickland L.H., Stuart A.C., Sturdy A., Sutton N., Szigeti A., Tahiri-Alaoui A., Tanner R., Taoushanis C., Tarr A.W., Taylor K., Taylor U., Taylor I.J., Taylor J., te Water Naude R., Themistocleous Y., Themistocleous A., Thomas M., Thomas K., Thomas T.M., Thombrayil A., Thompson F., Thompson Amber, Thompson K., Thompson Ameeka, Thomson J., Thornton-Jones V., Tighe P.J., Tinoco L.A., Tiongson G., Tladinyane B., Tomasicchio M., Tomic A., Tonks S., Towner J., Tran N., Tree J., Trillana G., Trinham C., Trivett R., Truby A., Tsheko B.L., Turabi A., Turner R., Turner C., Ulaszewska M., Underwood B.R., Varughese R., Verbart D., Verheul M., Vichos I., Vieira T., Waddington C.S., Walker L., Wallis E., Wand M., Warbick D., Wardell T., Warimwe G., Warren S.C., Watkins B., Watson E., Webb S., Webb-Bridges A., Webster A., Welch J., Wells J., West A., White C., White R., Williams P., Williams R.L., Winslow R., Woodyer M., Worth A.T., Wright D., Wroblewska M., Yao A., Zimmer R., Zizi D., Zuidewind P. Safety and efficacy of the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine (AZD1222) against SARS-CoV-2: an interim analysis of four randomised controlled trials in Brazil, South Africa, and the UK. Lancet. 2021;397:99–111. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32661-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32661-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723445</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33306989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West T., Hess C., Cree B. Acute transverse myelitis: demyelinating, inflammatory, and infectious myelopathies. Semin. Neurol. 2012;32:097–113. doi: 10.1055/s-0032-1322586.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0032-1322586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22961185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk D.M., Weinshenker B.G.  Vol. 19. 2013. Acute Disseminated Encephalomyelitis, Transverse Myelitis, and Neuromyelitis Optica: CONTINUUM: Lifelong Learning in Neurology; pp. 944–967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.CON.0000433289.38339.a2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
