<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34196456</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-849X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>31</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of prosthodontics : official journal of the American College of Prosthodontists</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Prosthodont</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Accuracy of Transferring Casts in Maximal Intercuspal Position to a Virtual Articulator.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>326</StartPage>
          <EndPage>332</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>326-332</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jopr.13405</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To analyze the accuracy of transferring casts in maximal intercuspal position to a virtual articulator by using transfer plates in the laboratory scanner before and after occlusal optimization.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Five sets of standard dental casts were mounted on a mechanical articulator in maximal intercuspal position. The number and position of occlusal contacts were determined with 12-μm articulating foil. After a calibration process according to the manufacturer's instructions, the mountings were transferred to a virtual articulator using the transfer plates in a laboratory scanner. The occlusion of the digital casts was determined before and after the occlusal optimization process. Then, the sensitivity and positive predictive value were determined by comparing the occlusal contact points in the virtual articulator with those in the mechanical articulator. To evaluate trueness, the occlusal surface of the maxillary teeth in the mechanical articulator was recorded by polyvinyl siloxane occlusal record in maximal intercuspal position and retained on the mandibular arch. The trueness was calculated as the deviation between the occlusal surface of the maxillary teeth in the mechanical articulator and the virtual articulator. To evaluate precision, one set of the casts was scanned 10 times. And the deviation of the interarch position of the maxillary arches when superimposing the mandibular arches of every 2 different scans was calculated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The sensitivity before occlusal optimization (0.14 ± 0.15) was significantly lower than that after occlusal optimization (0.82 ± 0.10) (p = 0.003). However, there was no significant difference between the positive predictive value before (0.80 ± 0.45) and after (0.81 ± 0.09) occlusal optimization (p = 0.952). The trueness before (91.0 ± 10.7 µm) and after (75.4 ± 25.2 µm) occlusal optimization had no significant difference (p = 0.249). The precision before occlusal optimization (11.6 ± 3.8 µm) was significantly superior to that after occlusal optimization (75.6 ± 39.2 µm ) (p &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The accuracy of transferring casts in maximal intercuspal position to a virtual articulator using transfer plates in the laboratory scanner could be improved after occlusal optimization and can meet the clinical needs for occlusal design and analysis of prostheses.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 by the American College of Prosthodontists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mingzhu</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4440-4467</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ding</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Linlin</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Digital Dentistry, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Engineering Laboratory for Digital and Material Technology of Stomatology, Research Center of Engineering and Technology for Digital Dentistry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guangju</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yijiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Digital Dentistry, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Engineering Laboratory for Digital and Material Technology of Stomatology, Research Center of Engineering and Technology for Digital Dentistry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuchun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3424-5028</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Digital Dentistry, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Engineering Laboratory for Digital and Material Technology of Stomatology, Research Center of Engineering and Technology for Digital Dentistry, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lei</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Peking University School and Hospital of Stomatology, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Prosthodont</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9301275</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1059-941X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003725" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dental Articulators</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003766" MajorTopicYN="N">Dental Occlusion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007574" MajorTopicYN="N">Jaw Relation Record</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008437" MajorTopicYN="N">Maxilla</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tooth</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Accuracy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maximal intercuspal position</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occlusion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transfer plate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virtual articulator</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>50</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196456</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jopr.13405</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lepidi L, Galli M, Mastrangelo F, et al. Virtual articulators and virtual mounting procedures: where do we stand? J Prosthodont 2021;30: 24-35</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bisler A, Bockholt U, Kordass B, et al. The virtual articulator. Int J Comput Dent 2002;5: 101-106</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gärtner C, Kordass B. The virtual articulator: development and evaluation. Int J Comput Dent 2003;6: 11-24</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koralakunte PR, Aljanakh M: The role of virtual articulator in prosthetic and restorative dentistry. J Clin Diagn Res 2014;8: 25-28</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solaberrieta E, Otegi JR, Goicoechea N, et al. Comparison of a conventional and virtual occlusal record. J Prosthet Dent 2015;114: 92-97</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yee SHX, Esguerra RJ, Chew AAQ, et al. Three-dimensional static articulation accuracy of virtual models - part I: system trueness and precision. J Prosthodont 2018;27: 129-136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delong R, Ko CC, Anderson GC, et al. Comparing maximum intercuspal contacts of virtual dental patients and mounted dental casts. J Prosthet Dent 2002;88: 622-630</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ury E, Fornai C, Weber GW: Accuracy of transferring analog dental casts to a virtual articulator. J Prosthet Dent 2019;123: 305-313</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee W, Kwon H: Vertical repositioning accuracy of magnetic mounting systems on 4 articulator models. J Prosthet Dent 2018;119: 446-449</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delong R, Knorr S, Anderson GC, et al. Accuracy of contacts calculated from 3D images of occlusal surfaces. J Dent 2007;35: 528-534</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbosa JM, Urtula AB, Hirata R, et al. Thickness evaluation of articulating papers and foils. J Esthet Restor Dent 2018;30:70-72</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogawa T, Ogimoto T, Koyano K: Validity of the examination method of occlusal contact pattern relating to mandibular position. J Dent 2000;28: 23-29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yee SHX, Esguerra RJ, Chew AAQ, et al. Three-dimensional static articulation accuracy of virtual models part II: effect of model scanner-CAD systems and articulation method. J Prosthodont 2018;27:137-144</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwaki Y, Wakabayashi N, Igarashi Y: Dimensional accuracy of optical bite registration in single and multiple unit restorations. Oper Dent 2013;38: 309-315</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu MR, Driscoll CF, Romberg E, et al. Accuracy of dynamic virtual articulation: trueness and precision. J Prosthodont 2019;28: 436-443</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breeding LC, Dixon DL, Kinderknecht KE: Accuracy of three interocclusal recording materials used to mount a working cast. J Prosthet Dent 1994;71: 265-270</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piehslinger E, Bauer W, Schmiedmayer HB: Computer simulation of occlusal discrepancies resulting from different mounting techniques. J Prosthet Dent 1995;74: 279-283</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roraff AR, Stansbury BE: Errors caused by dimensional change in mounting material. J Prosthet Dent 1972;28: 247-252</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung CCJ, Chai J, Jameson LM: Interchangeability of a semiadjustable articulator. Int J Prosthodont 2001;14: 427-431</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pietrokovski Y, Shakartsi-Amar O, Ben-Gal G, et al. Determining the interchangeability of KaVo PROTAR semi-adjustable articulators. Quintessence Int 2018;49: 549-555</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwauchi Y, Tanaka S, Kamimura-Sugimura E, et al. Clinical evaluation of the precision of interocclusal registration by using digital and conventional techniques. J Prosthet Dent 2021;25:S0022-S3913(21)00066-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies S, Al-Ani Z, Jeremiah H, et al. Reliability of recording static and dynamic occlusal contact marks using transparent acetate sheet. J Prosthet Dent 2005;94: 458-461</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velasco AB, Arenal ÁÁ, Echevarria JE, et al. Influence of articulating paper thickness on occlusal contacts registration: a preliminary report. Int J Prosthodont 2015;28: 360-362</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeon JH, Kim HY, Kim JH, et al. Accuracy of 3D white light scanning of abutment teeth impressions: evaluation of trueness and precision. J Adv Prosthodont 2014;6:468-473</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatzi P, Millstein P, Maya A: Determining the accuracy of articulator interchangeability. J Prosthet Dent 2001;85: 236-245</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
