<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34215021</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility : the official journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Activation of CRF<sub>1</sub> receptors expressed in brainstem autonomic nuclei stimulates colonic enteric neurons and secreto-motor function in male rats.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14189</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14189</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.14189</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Hypothalamic corticotropin-releasing factor (CRF) receptor 1 (CRF<sub>1</sub> ) plays a role in acute stress-related stimulation of colonic motor function. Less is known on CRF<sub>1</sub> signaling in the brainstem.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">We investigate CRF<sub>1</sub> expression in the brainstem and the colonic response to 4<sup>th</sup> ventricle (4V) injection of CRF and urocortin (Ucn) 2 (3 µg/rat) in chronically cannulated male rats.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS">Transcripts of CRF<sub>1</sub> wild-type 1a and splice variants 1c, 1e, 1f, 1o along with three novel variants 1a-2 (desK-110 in exon 5), 1p (-exon 7), and 1q (exon 5 extension) were identified in the pons and medulla. The area postrema, nucleus tractus solitarius, dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus, locus coeruleus, and Barrington's nucleus isolated by laser capture microdissection expressed 1a, 1a-2, and 1p but not 1q. Compared to 4V vehicle, 4V CRF induced fecal pellet output (FPO) and diarrhea that were blocked by the CRF antagonist, astressin-B. CRF<sub>2</sub> agonist, Ucn2 had no effect on basal or CRF-induced FPO. CRF actions were correlated with the induction of c-Fos immunoreactivity in myenteric neurons of the proximal and distal colon (pC, dC) and submucosal neurons of dC. c-Fos immunoreactivity occurred in 39% and 37% of myenteric cholinergic and 7% and 58% of nitrergic neurons in the pC and dC, respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS &amp; INFERENCES">CRF<sub>1a</sub> and its splice variants are expressed in brainstem nuclei, and activation of CRF<sub>1</sub> signaling at the level of the brainstem stimulates colonic secretory-motor function through activation of colonic enteric neurons.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yuan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pu-Qing</ForeName>
            <Initials>PQ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0067-510X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>David Geffen School of Medicine, Vatche and Tamar Manoukian Division of Digestive Diseases, University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>S Vincent</ForeName>
            <Initials>SV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stengel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andreas</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>David Geffen School of Medicine, Vatche and Tamar Manoukian Division of Digestive Diseases, University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychosomatic Medicine and Psychotherapy, Medical University Hospital, Tübingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department for Psychosomatic Medicine, Charité Center for Internal Medicine and Dermatology, Charité-Universitätsmedizin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ken</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>David Geffen School of Medicine, Vatche and Tamar Manoukian Division of Digestive Diseases, University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sato Clinic 13-14 Choei Moriyamaku, Nagoya City, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Taché</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yvette</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>David Geffen School of Medicine, Vatche and Tamar Manoukian Division of Digestive Diseases, University of California at Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VA Greater Los Angeles Healthcare System, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018019">Receptors, Corticotropin-Releasing Hormone</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>5CLY6W2H1M</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C101530">CRF receptor type 1</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001341" MajorTopicYN="N">Autonomic Nervous System</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001933" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Stem</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003106" MajorTopicYN="N">Colon</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017615" MajorTopicYN="N">Enteric Nervous System</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018019" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Corticotropin-Releasing Hormone</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">CRF1 receptor isoforms</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">brainstem</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">c-Fos</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">colon</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pChAT</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">rat</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">urocortin 2</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215021</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14189</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang L. The role of stress on physiologic responses and clinical symptoms in irritable bowel syndrome. Gastroenterology. 2011;140:761-765.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellissier S, Bonaz B. The place of stress and emotions in the irritable bowel syndrome. Vitam Horm. 2017;103:327-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Mahony SM, Clarke G, Dinan TG, Cryan JF. Irritable bowel syndrome and stress-related psychiatric co-morbidities: focus on early life stress. Handb Exp Pharmacol. 2017;239:219-246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taché Y, Larauche M, Yuan PQ, Million M. Brain and gut CRF signaling: biological actions and role in the gastrointestinal tract. Curr Mol Pharmacol. 2018;11:51-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dedic N, Chen A, Deussing JM. The CRF family of neuropeptides and their receptors-mediators of the central stress response. Curr Mol Pharmacol. 2018;11:4-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauger RL, Grigoriadis DE, Dallman MF, Plotsky PM, Vale WW, Dautzenberg FM. International union of pharmacology. XXXVI. Current status of the nomenclature for receptors for corticotropin-releasing factor and their ligands. Pharmacol Rev. 2003;55(1):21-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu S, Yuan PQ, Wang L, Peng YL, Chen CY, Taché Y. Identification and characterization of multiple corticotropin-releasing factor type 2 receptor isoforms in the rat esophagus. Endocrinology. 2007;148:1675-1687.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu SV, Yuan PQ, Lai J, et al. Activation of Type 1 CRH receptor isoforms induces serotonin release from human carcinoid BON-1N cells: an enterochromaffin cell model. Endocrinology. 2011;152:126-137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pisarchik A, Slominski A. Corticotropin releasing factor receptor type 1: molecular cloning and investigation of alternative splicing in the hamster skin. J Invest Dermatol. 2002;118:1065-1072.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grammatopoulos DK, Dai Y, Randeva HS, et al. A novel spliced variant of the type 1 corticotropin-releasing hormone receptor with a deletion in the seventh transmembrane domain present in the human pregnant term myometrium and fetal membranes. Mol Endocrinol. 1999;13:2189-2202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markovic D, Vatish M, Gu M, et al. The onset of labor alters corticotropin-releasing hormone type 1 receptor variant expression in human myometrium: putative role of interleukin-1beta. Endocrinology. 2007;148:3205-3213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zmijewski MA, Slominski AT. Emerging role of alternative splicing of CRF1 receptor in CRF signaling. Acta Biochim Pol. 2010;57:1-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawchenko PE, Swanson LW. Immunohistochemical identification of neurons in the paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus that project to the medulla or the spinal cord in the rat. J Comp Neurol. 1982;205:260-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mönnikes H, Tebbe J, Bauer C, Grote C, Arnold R. Neuropeptide Y in the paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus stimulates colonic transit by peripheral cholinergic and central CRF pathways. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2000;12:343-352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mönnikes H, Schmidt BG, Raybould HE, Taché Y. CRF in the paraventricular nucleus mediates gastric and colonic motor response to restraint stress. Am J Physiol. 1992;262:G137-G143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tebbe JJ, Mronga S, Tebbe CG, Ortmann E, Arnold R, Schafer MK. Ghrelin-induced stimulation of colonic propulsion is dependent on hypothalamic neuropeptide Y1- and corticotrophin-releasing factor 1 receptor activation. J Neuroendocrinol. 2005;17:570-576.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valentino RJ, Kosboth M, Colflesh M, Miselis RR. Transneuronal labeling from the rat distal colon: anatomic evidence for regulation of distal colon function by a pontine corticotropin-releasing factor system. J Comp Neurol. 2000;417:399-414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berthoud HR, Carlson NR, Powley TL. Topography of efferent vagal innervation of the rat gastrointestinal tract. Am J Physiol. 1991;260:R200-R207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rouzade-Dominguez ML, Miselis R, Valentino RJ. Central representation of bladder and colon revealed by dual transsynaptic tracing in the rat: substrates for pelvic visceral coordination. Eur J Neurosci. 2003;18:3311-3324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ter Horst GJ, Toes GJ, Van Willigen JD. Locus coeruleus projections to the dorsal motor vagus nucleus in the rat. Neuroscience. 1991;45:153-160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valentino RJ, Pavcovich LA, Hirata H. Evidence for corticotropin-releasing hormone projections from Barrington's nucleus to the periaqueductal gray and dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus in the rat. J Comp Neurol. 1995;363:402-422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holst MC, Kelly JB, Powley TL. Vagal preganglionic projections to the enteric nervous system characterized with Phaseolus vulgaris-leucoagglutinin. J Comp Neurol. 1997;381:81-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mönnikes H, Schmidt BG, Tebbe J, Bauer C, Taché Y. Microinfusion of corticotropin releasing factor into the locus coeruleus/subcoeruleus stimulates colonic motor function in rats. Brain Res. 1994;644:101-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan JI, Curran T. Stimulus-transcription coupling in the nervous system: involvement of the inducible proto-oncogenes fos and jun. Annu Rev Neurosci. 1991;14:421-451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Pett K, Viau V, Bittencourt JC, et al. Distribution of mRNAs encoding CRF receptors in brain and pituitary of rat and mouse. J Comp Neurol. 2000;428:191-212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paxinos G, Watson C. The Rat Brain In Stereotaxic Coordinates, 4th edn. Orlando: Academic Press; 1998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan PQ, Wu SV, Pothoulakis C, Taché Y. Urocortins and CRF receptor type 2 variants in the male rat colon: gene expression and regulation by endotoxin and anti-inflammatory effect. Am J Physiol. 2016;310:G387-G398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleige S, Pfaffl MW. RNA integrity and the effect on the real-time qRT-PCR performance. Mol Aspects Med. 2006;27:126-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stengel A, Goebel M, Wang L, et al. Central nesfatin-1 reduces dark-phase food intake and gastric emptying in rats: differential role of corticotropin-releasing factor2 receptor. Endocrinology. 2009;150:4911-4919.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Million M, Zhao JF, Luckey A, et al. The newly developed CRF1-receptor antagonists, NGD 98-2 and NGD 9002, suppress acute stress-induced stimulation of colonic motor function and visceral hypersensitivity in rats. PLoS One. 2013;8:e73749.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czimmer J, Million M, Taché Y. Urocortin 2 acts centrally to delay gastric emptying through sympathetic pathways while CRF and urocortin 1 inhibitory actions are vagal dependent in rats. Am J Physiol. 2006;290:G511-G518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larauche M, Moussaoui N, Biraud M, et al. Brain corticotropin-releasing factor signaling: Involvement in acute stress-induced visceral analgesia in male rats. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2018;e13489.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan PQ, Million M, Wu SV, Rivier J, Taché Y. Peripheral corticotropin releasing factor (CRF) and a novel CRF1 receptor agonist, stressin1-A activate CRF1 receptor expressing cholinergic and nitrergic myenteric neurons selectively in the colon of conscious rats. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2007;19:923-936.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura S, Bellier JP, Matsuo A, Tooyama I, Kimura H. The production of antibodies that distinguish rat choline acetyltransferase from its splice variant product of a peripheral type. Neurochem Int. 2007;50:251-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan PQ, Kimura H, Million M, et al. Central vagal stimulation activates enteric cholinergic neurons in the stomach and VIP neurons in the duodenum in conscious rats. Peptides. 2005;26:653-664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson TM, Bredt DS, Fotuhi M, Hwang PM, Snyder SH. Nitric oxide synthase and neuronal NADPH diaphorase are identical in brain and peripheral tissues. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1991;88:7797-7801.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrin MH, Donaldson CJ, Chen R, Lewis KA, Vale WW. Cloning and functional expression of rat brain corticotropin releasing factor (CRF) receptor. Endocrinology. 1993;133:3058-3061.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang C-P, Pearse RV II, O'Connell S, Resenfeld MG. Identification of a seven transmembrane Helix receptor for corticotropin-releasing factor and sauvagine in mammalian brain. Neuron. 1993;11:1187-1195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai-Morris CH, Buczko E, Geng Y, Gamboa-Pinto A, Dufau ML. The genomic structure of the rat corticotropin releasing factor receptor. a member of the class II G protein-coupled receptors. J Biol Chem. 1996;271:14519-14525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillhouse EW, Grammatopoulos DK. The molecular mechanisms underlying the regulation of the biological activity of corticotropin-releasing hormone receptors: implications for physiology and pathophysiology. Endocr Rev. 2006;27:260-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen R, Lewis KA, Perrin MH, Vale WW. Expression cloning of a human corticotropin-releasing-factor receptor. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1993;90:8967-8971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pisarchik A, Slominski AT. Alternative splicing of CRH-R1 receptors in human and mouse skin: identification of new variants and their differential expression. FASEB J. 2001;15:2754-2756.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markovic D, Lehnert H, Levine MA, Grammatopoulos DK. Structural determinants critical for localization and signaling within the seventh transmembrane domain of the type 1 corticotropin releasing hormone receptor: lessons from the receptor variant R1d. Mol Endocrinol. 2008;22:2505-2519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ET, Sandberg R, Luo S, et al. Alternative isoform regulation in human tissue transcriptomes. Nature. 2008;456:470-476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu SV, Jiang M, Million M, Yuan PQ, Taché Y. Identification and characterization of novel rat CRF receptor type 1 Isoforms in the GI tract. Gastroenterology. 2008;134:A-245.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tebbe JJ, Pasat IR, Mönnikes H, Ritter M, Kobelt P, Schafer MK. Excitatory stimulation of neurons in the arcuate nucleus intitiates central CRF-dependent stimulation of colonic propulsion in rats. Brain Res. 2005;1036:130-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mönnikes H, Schmidt BG, Taché Y. Psychological stress-induced accelerated colonic transit in rats involves hypothalamic corticotropin-releasing factor. Gastroenterology. 1993;104:716-723.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maillot C, Million M, Wei JY, Gauthier A, Taché Y. Peripheral corticotropin-releasing factor and stress-stimulated colonic motor activity involve type 1 receptor in rats. Gastroenterology. 2000;119:1569-1579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gourcerol G, Wu SV, Yuan PQ, et al. Activation of corticotropin-releasing factor receptor 2 mediates the colonic motor coping response to acute stress in rodents. Gastroenterology. 2011;140:1586-1596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reyes TM, Lewis K, Perrin MH, et al. Urocortin II: A member of the corticotropin-releasing factor (CRF) neuropeptide family that is selectively bound by type 2 CRF receptors. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2001;98:2843-2848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nozu T, Takakusaki K, Okumura T. A balance theory of peripheral corticotropin-releasing factor receptor type 1 and type 2 signaling to induce colonic contractions and visceral hyperalgesia in rats. Endocrinology. 2014;155:4655-4664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sved AF, Cano G, Passerin AM, Rabin BS. The locus coeruleus, Barrington's nucleus, and neural circuits of stress. Physiol Behav. 2002;77:737-742.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonaz B, Taché Y. Water-avoidance stress-induced c-fos expression in the rat brain and stimulation of fecal output: role of corticotropin-releasing factor. Brain Res. 1994;641:21-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
