<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34213484</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">0975-5764</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Season>Apr-Jun</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of African medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Afr Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Panhypopituitarism in acute myocardial infarction.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>145</StartPage>
          <EndPage>149</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>145-149</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/aam.aam_66_19</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>While hypopituitarism is known to be associated with increased cardiovascular morbidity and mortality, panhypopituitarism as a complication of myocardial infarction (MI) is very rare. Here, we report a case of rapidly developing empty sella syndrome with florid manifestations of panhypopituitarism after MI (due to critical stenosis in the left anterior descending artery) complicated by cardiogenic shock in a 65-year-old man. The patient was initially stabilized with conservative management of non-ST-elevated MI and cardiogenic shock, but after initial improvement, he again deteriorated with refractory shock (not adequately responding to vasopressors), seizures, hypoglycemia, hyponatremia, hyperkalemia, and metabolic acidosis. After ruling out recurrent cardiogenic shock or other causes of refractory hypotension, panhypopituitarism was diagnosed with the help of hormonal assays and imaging. With no prior evidence of hypopituitarism, we suspect that panhypopituitarism developed due to acute pituitary apoplexy secondary to initial cardiogenic shock. The patient was successfully survived by the emergency endocrine management followed by secondary coronary angioplasty.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghosh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ritwik</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, Burdwan Medical College and Hospital, Burdwan, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chatterjee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Subhankar</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, Rajendra Institute of Medical Sciences, Ranchi, Jharkhand, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Devlina</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Medicine, Burdwan Medical College and Hospital, Burdwan, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dubey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Souvik</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuromedicine, Bangur Institute of Neurosciences, Kolkata, West Bengal, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lavie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carl J</ForeName>
            <Initials>CJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, John Ochsner Heart and Vascular Institute, New Orleans, LA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Afr Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101231417</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0975-5764</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C580003">Combined Pituitary Hormone Deficiency</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006333" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Failure</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007018" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypopituitarism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009203" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardial Infarction</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="Y">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">
        <AbstractText><b>Résumé</b> Bien que l'hypopituitarisme soit associé à une augmentation de la morbidité et de la mortalité cardiovasculaires, le panhypopituitarisme en tant que complication de l'infarctus du myocarde (IM) est très rare. Ici, nous rapportons un cas de développement rapide du syndrome de la selle vide avec des manifestations florales de panhypopituitarisme après IM (en raison d'une sténose critique dans l'artère descendante antérieure gauche) compliquée par un choc cardiogénique chez un homme de 65 ans. Le patient a été initialement stabilisé avec une gestion conservatrice de l'IM non élevé ST et du choc cardiogénique, mais après une amélioration initiale, il s'est à nouveau détérioré avec un choc réfractaire (ne répondant pas adéquatement aux vasopresseurs), des convulsions, une hypoglycémie, une hyponatrémie, une hyperkaliémie et une acidose métabolique. Après avoir écarté le choc cardiogénique récurrent ou d'autres causes d'hypotension réfractaire, le panhypopituitarisme a été diagnostiqué à l'aide de tests hormonaux et d'imagerie. En l'absence de preuve antérieure d'hypopituitarisme, nous soupçonnons que le panhypopituitarisme s'est développé en raison d'une apoplexie hypophysaire aiguë secondaire au choc cardiogénique initial. Le patient a été survécu avec succès par la prise en charge endocrinienne d'urgence suivie d'une angioplastie coronaire secondaire.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute myocardial infarction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">empty sella</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">heart failure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">panhypopituitarism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pituitary</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pituitary apoplexy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34213484</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8378457</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/aam.aam_66_19</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">AnnAfrMed_2021_20_2_145_320047</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laway BA, Ramzan M, Allai MS, Wani AI, Misgar RA. Cardiac structural and functional abnormalities in females with untreated hypopituitarism due to sheehan syndrome: Response to hormone replacement therapy. Endocr Pract. 2016;22:1096–103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27359291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giri S, Bansal P, Malik S, Bansal R. Hypopituitarism presenting as congestive heart failure. J Postgrad Med. 2017;63:268–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5664874</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28272076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin-Grace J, Ahmed M, Mulvihill N, Feeney ER, Crowley RK. Getting to the heart of hypopituitarism. Clin Med (Lond) 2017;17:140–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6297610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mittal A, Ray A, Talupula RM, Sood R. Sheehan's syndrome presenting as cardiac tamponade. BMJ Case Rep 2018. 2018 pii: Bcr-2017-223129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5812377</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29431100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lane JD, Keenan NG, Bouloux P, Rogers D. A heart without hormones. Lancet. 2012;379:1922.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22608340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bao SS, Fisher SJ. Repairing a “broken heart” with hormone replacement therapy: Case report of cardiogenic shock due to undiagnosed pituitary insufficiency. Endocr Pract. 2012;18:e26–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22138080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahi M, Beshyah SA, Hackett D, Sharp PS, Johnston DG, Foale RA. Myocardial dysfunction in treated adult hypopituitarism: A possible explanation for increased cardiovascular mortality. Br Heart J. 1992;67:92–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1024710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1739534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filges I, Bischof-Renner A, Röthlisberger B, Potthoff C, Glanzmann R, Günthard J, et al.  Panhypopituitarism presenting as life-threatening heart failure caused by an inherited microdeletion in 1q25 including LHX4. Pediatrics. 2012;129:e529–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22232309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plácido R, Martins AF, Robalo Martins S, do Vale S, Almeida AG, Pinto F, et al.  Takotsubo syndrome: A pathway through the pituitary disease. Case Rep Cardiol 2016. 2016 9219018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4785244</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27019756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta V, Patil S, Raval D, Gopani P. Pituitary apoplexy presenting as myocardial infarction. Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2014;18:232–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3987278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24741524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C, Chan V, Tse TF, Yeung RT. Effect of acute myocardial infarction on pituitary-testicular function. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 1978;9:249–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">709895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanhaelst L, Degaute JP, Golstein J, Bastenie PA. Pituitary-thyroid axis reaction after myocardial infarction. Horm Metab Res. 1976;8:42–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1248789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donald RA, Crozier IG, Foy SG, Richards AM, Livesey JH, Ellis MJ, et al.  Plasma corticotrophin releasing hormone, vasopressin, ACTH and cortisol responses to acute myocardial infarction. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 1994;40:499–504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8187316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arcopinto M, Bobbio E, Bossone E, Perrone-Filardi P, Napoli R, Sacca L, et al.  The GH/IGF-1 axis in chronic heart failure. Endocr Metab Immune Disord Drug Targets. 2013;13:76–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23369140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bevan JS, Oza AM, Burke CW, Adams CB. Pituitary apoplexy following isosorbide administration. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1987;50:636–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1031981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3585391</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oo MM, Krishna AY, Bonavita GJ, Rutecki GW. Heparin therapy for myocardial infarction: An unusual trigger for pituitary apoplexy. Am J Med Sci. 1997;314:351–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9365341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang L, Liu JB, Chen FQ, Zhao J, Zhang XL. Refractory hypotension induced by Sheehan syndrome with pituitary crisis: A case report. Exp Ther Med. 2017;13:2097–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5443209</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28565814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edeiken J, Bass H. prolonged shock after myocardial infarction relieved by ACTH and cortisone. Am Heart J. 1964;68:686–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14222408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang DG, Kim SE, Park MS, Kim EJ, Lee JH, Park DG, et al.  Acquired long QT syndrome manifesting with torsades de pointes in a patient with panhypopituitarism due to radiotherapy. Korean Circ J. 2013;43:340–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3675309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23755081</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kissell N, Mudd JO, Gelow JM, Chong LE, Yuen KC. Cardiogenic shock due to nonischemic cardiomyopathy induced by severe anterior hypopituitarism. AACE Clinical Case Rep. 2015;1:e147–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang D, Kreitler K, Tilton S, Cavarocchi NC, Hirose H. Cardiogenic shock requiring extracorporeal membrane oxygenation support in a patient with panhypopituitarism: A Case Report. Cureus. 2019;11:e4995.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6726413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31497426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranabir S, Baruah MP. Pituitary apoplexy. Indian J Endocrinol Metab. 2011;15(Suppl 3):S188–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3183518</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22029023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marume K, Arima Y, Igata M, Nishikawa T, Yamamoto E, Yamamuro M, et al.  Prolonged hyponatremia due to hypopituitarism in a patient with non-ST-elevation myocardial infarction. J Cardiol Cases. 2014;10:226–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6279656</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30534249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosari SA, Amiruddin A, Shorakae S, Kane R. A rare cause of hypoactive delirium. BMJ Case Rep 2014. 2014 pii: Bcr2014205382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4208129</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25331146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yücesoy K, Yüceer N, Göktay Y. Empty sella syndrome following pituitary apoplexy. Acta Neurochir (Wien) 2000;142:355–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10819270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
