<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34224444</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>08</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1542-233X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>47</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Eye &amp; contact lens</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eye Contact Lens</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Infectious Scleritis: Pathophysiology, Diagnosis, and Management.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>434</StartPage>
          <EndPage>441</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>434-441</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ICL.0000000000000813</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Infectious scleritis (IS) is a rare and severe ocular disorder responsible for approximately 5%-15% of all scleritis cases. It is often associated with a poor prognosis due to its similar clinical presentation to autoimmune scleritis, resulting in a delayed diagnosis and treatment. Therefore, differentiating between infectious and noninfectious entities is critical. Several details extracted from the patient's history and clinical examination can raise suspicion for infection. The most common predisposing factor is previous ocular surgery, especially pterygium, cataract, and vitreoretinal surgeries. Ocular trauma, poor contact lens hygiene, "eye-whitening" procedures, and subtenon triamcinolone injections have also been implicated. Clinical features of infection include the presence of scleral necrosis, hypopyon, unifocal or multifocal scleral abscesses, and mucopurulent discharge. Thorough diagnostic testing is essential before excluding infection as a possibility. Empiric broad-spectrum topical and systemic antibiotic therapy should be initiated while awaiting laboratory results and adjusted accordingly. Most IS cases require both aggressive medical and surgical treatment, and various studies have reported favorable outcomes with this combination. At this time, there is no consensus on the management of this severe ocular condition, and future studies are needed to establish clear treatment guidelines.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Contact Lens Association of Ophthalmologists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julia</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cornea Service, Wills Eye Hospital, Sidney Kimmel Medical College, Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Syed</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zeba A</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZA</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rapuano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christopher J</ForeName>
            <Initials>CJ</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eye Contact Lens</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101160941</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1542-2321</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015818" MajorTopicYN="Y">Eye Infections, Bacterial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013508" MajorTopicYN="N">Ophthalmologic Surgical Procedures</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011625" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pterygium</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012590" MajorTopicYN="N">Sclera</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015423" MajorTopicYN="Y">Scleritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34224444</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICL.0000000000000813</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00140068-202108000-00002</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jabs DA, Mudun A, Dunn JP, et al. Episcleritis and scleritis: Clinical features and treatment results. Am J Ophthalmol 2000;130:469–476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn SJ, Oh JY, Kim MK, et al. Clinical features, predisposing factors, and treatment outcomes of scleritis in the Korean population. Korean J Ophthalmol 2010;24:331–335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds MG, Alfonso E. Treatment of infectious scleritis and keratoscleritis. Am J Ophthalmol 1991;112:543–547.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain V, Garg P, Sharma S. Microbial scleritis-experience from a developing country. Eye\ 2009;23:255–261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodson KL, Galor A, Karp CL, et al. Epidemiology and visual outcomes in patients with infectious scleritis. Cornea 2013;32:466–472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tittler EH, Nguyen P, Rue KS, et al. Early surgical debridement in the management of infectious scleritis after pterygium excision. J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect 2012;2:81–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su CY, Tsai JJ, Chang YC, et al. Immunologic and clinical manifestations of infectious scleritis after pterygium excision. Cornea 2006;25:663–666.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbey AM, Shah NV, Forster RK, et al. Infectious Pseudomonas and Bipolaris scleritis following history of pterygium surgery. Indian J Ophthalmol 2016;64:674–676.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murthy SI, Sabhapandit S, Balamurugan S, et al. Scleritis: Differentiating infectious from non-infectious entities. Indian J Ophthalmol 2020;68:1818–1828.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Hemady RK, Foster CS. Infectious scleritis: Report of four cases. Doc Ophthalmol 1993;83:33–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lane J, Nyugen E, Morrison J, et al. Clinical features of scleritis across the Asia-Pacific region. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2019;27:920–926.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Amin S, Lung KI, et al. Incidence, prevalence, and risk factors of infectious uveitis and scleritis in the United States: A claims-based analysis. PLoS One 2020;15:e0237995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YW, Poon YC, Yu HJ, et al. Experience of scleritis and episcleritis at a tertiary center in Southern Taiwan. Taiwan J Ophthalmol 2015;5:19–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ho YF, Yeh LK, Tan HY, et al. Infectious scleritis in Taiwan-a 10-year review in a tertiary-care hospital. Cornea 2014;33:838–843.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy JC, Murthy SI, Reddy AK, et al. Risk factors and clinical outcomes of bacterial and fungal scleritis at a tertiary eye care hospital. Middle East Afr J Ophthalmol 2015;22:203–211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Barqi M, Behrens A, Alfawaz AM. Clinical features and visual outcomes of scleritis patients presented to tertiary care eye centers in Saudi Arabia. Int J Ophthalmol 2015;8:1215–1219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahu SK, Das S, Sahani D, et al. Fungal scleritis masquerading as surgically induced necrotizing scleritis: A case report. J Med Case Rep 2013;7:288.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsiao CH, Chen JJ, Huang SC, et al. Intrascleral dissemination of infectious scleritis following pterygium excision. Br J Ophthalmol 1998;82:29–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin HC, Ma DHK, Chen YF, et al. Late-onset intrascleral dissemination of Stenotrophomonas maltophilia scleritis after pterygium excision. Cornea 2011;30:712–715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JE, Oum BS, Choi HY, et al. Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus sclerokeratitis after pterygium excision. Cornea 2007;26:744–746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taravella MJ, Johnson DW, Petty JG, et al. Infectious posterior scleritis caused by Pseudallescheria boydii. Clinicopathologic findings. Ophthalmology 1997;104:1312–1316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pradhan ZS, Jacob P. Infectious scleritis: Clinical spectrum and management outcomes in India. Indian J Ophthalmol 2013;61:590–593.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar Sahu S, Das S, Sharma S, et al. Clinico-microbiological profile and treatment outcome of infectious scleritis: Experience from a tertiary eye care center of India. Int J Inflam 2012;2012:753560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rich RM, Smiddy WE, Davis JL. Infectious scleritis after retinal surgery. Am J Ophthalmol 2008;145:695–699.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chao DL, Albini TA, McKeown CA, et al. Infectious Pseudomonas scleritis after strabismus surgery. J AAPOS 2013;17:423–425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham MA, Alexander JK, Matoba AY, et al. Management and outcome of microbial anterior scleritis. Cornea 2011;30:1020–1023.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riono WP, Hidayat AA, Rao NA. Scleritis: A clinicopathologic study of 55 cases. Ophthalmology 1999;106:1328–1333.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad S, Lopez M, Attala M, et al. Interventions and outcomes in patients with infectious Pseudomonas scleritis: A 10-year Perspective. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2019;27:499–506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moshirfar M, McCaughey MV, Fenzl CR, et al. Delayed manifestation of bilateral scleral thinning after I-BRITE(®) procedure and review of literature for cosmetic eye-whitening procedures. Clin Ophthalmol 2015;9:445–451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunha LPda, Juncal V, Carvalhaes CG, et al. Nocardial scleritis: A case report and a suggested algorithm for disease management based on a literature review. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2018;10:1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maskin SL. Infectious scleritis after a diabetic foot ulcer. Am J Ophthalmol 1993;115:254–255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora R, Shroff D, Narula R, et al. Inverse hypopyon as the presenting feature of infectious scleritis in a case of tropical pyomyositis. Can J Ophthalmol 2006;41:769–771.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Todokoro D, Hoshino J, Yo A, et al. Scedosporium apiospermum infectious scleritis following posterior subtenon triamcinolone acetonide injection: A case report and literature review. BMC Ophthalmol 2018;18:40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gharaee H, Khalife M, Poor SSH, et al. Infectious scleritis after subtenon triamcinolone acetonide injection. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2011;19:284–285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seth RK, Gaudio PA. Nocardia asteroides necrotizing scleritis associated with subtenon triamcinolone acetonide injection. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2008;16:139–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coussa RG, Wakil SM, Saheb H, et al. Anterior infectious necrotizing scleritis secondary to Pseudomonas aeruginosa infection following intravitreal ranibizumab injection. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2017;5:16–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syed ZA, Rapuano CJ. Umbilical amnion and amniotic membrane transplantation for infectious scleritis and scleral melt: A case series. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2021;21:101013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howell A, Midturi J, Sierra-Hoffman M, et al. Aspergillus flavus scleritis: Successful treatment with voriconazole and caspofungin. Med Mycol 2005;43:651–655.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fincher T, Fulcher SFA. Diagnostic and therapeutic challenge of Aspergillus flavus scleritis. Cornea 2007;26:618–620.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rush RB. Contact lens-associated nocardial necrotizing scleritis. Korean J Ophthalmol 2013;27:291–293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chau SF, Lee CY, Huang JY, et al. The existence of periodontal disease and subsequent ocular diseases: A population-based cohort study. Medicina 2020;56. doi: 10.3390/medicina56110621.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/medicina56110621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moshirfar M, Ronquillo Y. Infectious scleritis. In: StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing; 2020. Available at: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK560818/. Accessed February 12, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramenaden ER, Raiji VR. Clinical characteristics and visual outcomes in infectious scleritis: A review. Clin Ophthalmol 2013;7:2113–2122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal AM, Dutta Majumder P. Tubercular posterior scleritis: A case report and review of literature. Indian J Ophthalmol 2019;67:1362–1365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno Honrado M, del Campo Z, Buil JA. A case of necrotizing scleritis resulting from Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Cornea 2009;28:1065–1066.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul L, Agarwal M, Singh S, et al. Tuberculous scleritis in a young Asian Indian girl-a case presentation and literature review. J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect 2019;9:22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tananuvat N, Supalaset S, Niparugs M, et al. Ocular basidiobolomycosis: A case report. Case Rep Ophthalmol 2018;9:315–321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng X, Kodama T, Goto T, et al. Autologous fascia lata grafts for scleral repair in eyes with infectious necrotizing scleritis. Arch Ophthalmol 2011;129:1225–1227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paula JS, Simão MLH, Rocha EM, et al. Atypical pneumococcal scleritis after pterygium excision: Case report and literature review. Cornea 2006;25:115–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaikh SI, Biswas J, Rishi P. Nodular syphilitic scleritis masquerading as an ocular tumor. J Ophthalmic Inflamm Infect 2015;5:8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal R, Tripathi M, Kashyap S, et al. Recalcitrant infective scleritis masquerading an autoimmune necrotising scleritis: A primary presentation of biopsy-proven granulomatosis with polyangiitis. BMJ Case Rep 2021;14. doi: 10.1136/bcr-2020-239517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bcr-2020-239517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doshi RR, Harocopos GJ, Schwab IR, et al. The spectrum of postoperative scleral necrosis. Surv Ophthalmol 2013;58:620–633.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmood S, Suresh PS, Carley F, et al. Surgically induced necrotising scleritis: Report of a case presenting 51 years following strabismus surgery. Eye 2002;16:503–504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyer JJ, Espandar L, Marx DP, et al. Pseudomonas scleritis resistant to fourth-generation fluoroquinolones in a patient without prior trauma or surgery. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2008;16:127–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos-Esteban JC, Jeng BH. Posttraumatic Stenotrophomonas maltophilia infectious scleritis. Cornea 2008;27:232–235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sainz de la Maza M, Foster CS. Necrotizing scleritis after ocular surgery. A clinicopathologic study. Ophthalmology 1991;98:1720–1726.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuman JS, Weinberg RS, Ferry AP, et al. Toxoplasmic scleritis. Ophthalmology 1988;95:1399–1403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Passarin O, Zografos L, Schalenbourg A, et al. Scleritis after proton therapy in uveal melanoma. Klin Monbl Augenheilkd 2012;229:395–398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ram R Tectonic corneal lamellar grafting for surgically-induced necrotizing scleritis after strabismus surgery: Case report &amp; literature review. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep 2018;11:28–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altman AJ, Cohen EJ, Berger ST, et al. Scleritis and Streptococcus pneumoniae. Cornea 1991;10:341–345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerrero-Wooley RL, Peacock JE. Infectious scleritis: What the ID clinician should know. Open Forum Infect Dis 2018;5:ofy140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krist D, Wenkel H. Posterior scleritis associated with Borrelia burgdorferi (Lyme disease) infection. Ophthalmology 2002;109:143–145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patnaik G, Sudharshan S, George AE, et al. Clinical profile of patients with anterior nodular scleritis in India. Indian J Ophthalmol 2020;68:1925–1928.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moorthy RS, Valluri S, Rao NA. Nontuberculous mycobacterial ocular and adnexal infections. Surv Ophthalmol 2012;57:202–235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kheir WJ, Sheheitli H, Abdul Fattah M, et al. Nontuberculous mycobacterial ocular infections: A systematic review of the literature. Biomed Res Int 2015;2015:164989.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilhelmus KR, Yokoyama CM. Syphilitic episcleritis and scleritis. Am J Ophthalmol 1987;104:595–597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim H, Ahn JY, Chung IY, et al. A case report of infectious scleritis with corneal ulcer caused by Scedosporium aurantiacum. Medicine 2019;98:e16063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narita A, Seguchi J, Shiraga F. Paecilomyces lilacinus-induced scleritis following bleb-associated endophthalmitis after trabeculectomy. Acta Med Okayama 2015;69:313–318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ti SE, Tan DTH. Tectonic corneal lamellar grafting for severe scleral melting after pterygium surgery. Ophthalmology 2003;110:1126–1136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iovieno A, Gore DM, Carnt N, et al. Acanthamoeba sclerokeratitis: Epidemiology, clinical features, and treatment outcomes. Ophthalmology 2014;121:2340–2347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pak KY, Park SW, Byon IS, et al. Ocular toxocariasis presenting as bilateral scleritis with suspect retinal granuloma in the nerve fiber layer: A case report. BMC Infect Dis 2016;16:426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Gonzalez LA, Molina-Prat N, Doctor P, et al. Clinical features and presentation of infectious scleritis from herpes viruses: A report of 35 cases. Ophthalmology 2012;119:1460–1464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hankins M, Margo CE. Histopathological evaluation of scleritis. J Clin Pathol 2019;72:386–390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Accorinti M, Abbouda A, Gilardi M, et al. Cytomegalovirus-related scleritis. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2013;21:413–415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bustos-Mejia DA, Parra-Medina R, de-la-Torre A. Nodular necrotizing-scleritis associated with epstein-barr virus infection: A case report. Ocul Immunol Inflamm 2020;28:556–558.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoo WS, Kim CR, Kim BJ, et al. Successful treatment of infectious scleritis by Pseudomonas aeruginosa with autologous perichondrium graft of conchal cartilage. Yonsei Med J 2015;56:1738–1741.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murugan N, Malathi J, Umashankar V, et al. Virulence genome analysis of Pseudomonas aeruginosa VRFPA10 recovered from patient with scleritis. Genom Data 2017;12:1–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meallet MA. Subpalpebral lavage antibiotic treatment for severe infectious scleritis and keratitis. Cornea 2006;25:159–163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siatiri H, Mirzaee-Rad N, Aggarwal S, et al. Combined tenonplasty and scleral graft for refractory Pseudomonas scleritis following pterygium removal with mitomycin C application. J Ophthalmic Vis Res 2018;13:200–202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
