<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34269712</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1752-2978</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in endocrinology, diabetes, and obesity</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>International patient group harnesses social media to help inform rare disease research: use of a low carbohydrate ketogenic diet in McArdle disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>441</StartPage>
          <EndPage>445</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>441-445</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MED.0000000000000663</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW">To highlight the benefits of a partnership between patient advocacy organizations (PAO) and clinical researchers in order to clinically study the prior anecdotal patient experience of utilizing a low-carbohydrate ketogenic diet (LCKD) to manage McArdle disease.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS">The bedside-to-bench and back again method of translational research is well suited to explore anecdotal patient experiences, particularly for rare diseases. In McArdle disease, patients have explored the use of a LCKD to address the ubiquitous occurrence of physical activity intolerance and minimize associated adverse events. The International Association for Muscle Glycogen Storage Disease harnessed the power of social media to better understand this patient-centric finding and has subsequently partnered with clinical researchers to convey patient-centered priorities for research. From this partnership, a series of clinical and survey studies have been initiated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Collaboration between PAOs and clinical researchers has the potential to foster patient empowerment, advance anecdotal experiences into scientific hypotheses, and ultimately guide the development of management guidelines that reflect the patient perspective.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Reason</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stacey L</ForeName>
            <Initials>SL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Association for Muscle Glycogen Storage Disease, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Løkken</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicoline</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Copenhagen University Hospital, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Voermans</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicol</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behavior, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT04694547</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101308636</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1752-296X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D002241">Carbohydrates</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002241" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbohydrates</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055423" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet, Ketogenic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006012" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glycogen Storage Disease Type V</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D035583" MajorTopicYN="N">Rare Diseases</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061108" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Media</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34269712</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MED.0000000000000663</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">01266029-202110000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charles EJ, Kron IL. Bedside-to-bench and back again: surgeon-initiated translational research. Ann Thorac Surg 2017; 105:10–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pietrusz A, Scalco RS, Quinlivan R. Resistance exercise training in McArdle disease: myth or reality? Case Rep Neurol Med 2018; 2018: 9658251, 1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braakhekke JP, DeBruin MI, Stegeman DF, et al. The second wind phenomenon in mcardle's disease. Brain J Neurol 1986; 109:1087–1101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haller RG. Treatment of McArdle disease. Arch Neurol 2000; 57:923–924.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vissing J, Haller R G. The effect of oral sucrose on exercise tolerance in patients with Mcardle's Disease. N Engl J Med. 2003; 349: 2503–2509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vissing J, Haller R G. A diagnostic cycle test for Mcardle's Disease. Ann Neurol. 2003; 54: 539–542.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reason SL, Godfrey RJ. The potential of a ketogenic diet to minimize effects of the metabolic fault in glycogen storage disease V and VII. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes 2020; 5:283–290.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nogales-Gadea G, Santalla A, Ballester-Lopez A, et al. Exercise and preexercise nutrition as treatment for McArdle disease. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2016; 48:673–679.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersen ST, Haller RG, Vissing J. Effect of oral sucrose shortly before exercise on work capacity in McArdle disease. Arch Neurol 2008; 65:786–789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reason SL, Westman EC, Godfrey R, et al. Can a low-carbohydrate diet improve exercise tolerance mcardle disease? J Rare Disord Diagn Ther 2017; 3:1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koay PP, Sharp RR. The role of patient advocacy organizations in shaping genomic science. Annu Rev Genomics Hum Genet 2013; 14:579–595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IamGSD. Nutrition Ketosis in McArdle disease: a situation report. 28 March 2021. Retrieved from: https://www.iamgsd.org/iamgsd-research-papers.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark. Oral Ketone Body Supplementation in Patients With McArdle Disease (GSDV). (Clinicaltrials.gov Identifier NCT03945370). 28 March 2021. Retrieved from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03945370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark. Modified Ketogenic Diet in Patients With McArdle Disease Part B. (Clinicaltrials.gov Identifier NCT04044508). 28 March 2021. Retrieved from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04044508?cond=NCT04044508&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark. Modified Ketogenic Diet in Patients With McArdle Disease Part A. (Clinicaltrials.gov Identifier NCT03843606). 28 March 2019. Retrieved from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03843606?cond=NCT03843606&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lokken N, Hansen K, Storgaard J, et al. Titrating a modified ketogenic diet for patients with McArdle disease: A pilot study. Journal of inherited metabolic disease, [10.1002/jimd.12223.] Advance online publication. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1002/jimd.12223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lokken N. Ketogenic Diet Survey in Patients With McArdle Disease (GSDV). (Clinicaltrials.gov Identifier NCT04694547). 28 March 2021. Retrieved from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04694547?cond=NCT04694547&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>RYR-1 Foundation. Clinical Care Guidelines. 12 April 2021. Retrieved from: https://www.ryr1.org/ccg?gclid=EAIaIQobChMI8fDC6OHQ7wIVkud3Ch1eFA1uEAAYASAAEgIeLPD_BwE.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FSHD Society. Hot off the press: FSHD care guidelines. 12 April 2021. Retrieved from: https://www.fshdsociety.org/2015/07/27/hot-off-the-press-fshd-care-guideline/.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
