<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34262005</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-7355</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical rheumatology : practical reports on rheumatic &amp; musculoskeletal diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Characterization of Patients With Dermatomyositis According to Anti-Melanoma Differentiation-Associated Gene-5 Autoantibodies in Centers from 3 Latin American Countries: A Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e444</StartPage>
          <EndPage>e448</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e444-e448</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/RHU.0000000000001756</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/OBJECTIVE">The anti-melanoma differentiation-associated protein 5 (MDA5) autoantibodies have been associated with a high frequency of interstitial lung disease (ILD) and rapidly progressive ILD (RP-ILD) in dermatomyositis (DM) patients, mainly in Asian subjects. However, there is scarce information about these parameters in Latin American patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD">This was a medical records review cohort study that included classic DM (CDM) and clinically amyopathic DM (CADM) patients from 3 Latin American countries (Argentina, Brazil, and Mexico).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 270 DM patients were evaluated: 25.9% with CADM and 74.1% with CDM. The overall prevalence of ILD and RP-ILD, respectively, was 70 (25.9%) and 4 (1.5%) of the 270 patients, and the distributions were comparable between patients with CDM and CADM. The anti-MDA5 was present in 31 (25.4%) of 122 CDM patients and in 17 (48.6%) of 35 CADM patients; it was not associated with presence of ILD and RP-ILD. However, anti-MDA5-positive CDM patients had significantly high frequency of "mechanic's hands," arthralgia, arthritis, and lower serum levels of creatine phosphokinase, whereas anti-MDA5-positive CADM patients had significantly high frequency of arthritis. Pulmonary infection and ILD are main causes of death in DM patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In the present study, the prevalence of ILD in DM patients is comparable to that described in the literature, in contrast to the very low frequency of RP-ILD. In addition, the anti-MDA5 is not associated with ILD and RP-ILD, but anti-MDA5-positive DM patients present conditions that mimic antisynthetase syndrome. Pulmonary infection and ILD were the main causes of death in our sample.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Olivo Pallo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pablo Arturo</ForeName>
            <Initials>PA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of Rheumatology, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hoff</LastName>
            <ForeName>Leonardo Santos</ForeName>
            <Initials>LS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology and Rheumatology Department, Salvador Zubirán National Institute of Health Sciences and Nutrition, Mexico City, Mexico.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Borges</LastName>
            <ForeName>Isabela Bruna Pires</ForeName>
            <Initials>IBP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of Rheumatology, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Torres-Ruiz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jiram</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology and Rheumatology Department, Salvador Zubirán National Institute of Health Sciences and Nutrition, Mexico City, Mexico.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cassiano-Quezada</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fabiola</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology and Rheumatology Department, Salvador Zubirán National Institute of Health Sciences and Nutrition, Mexico City, Mexico.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Granel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amelia</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, San Roque de Gonnet Hospital, La Plata, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gomez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Graciela</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Alfred Lanari Medical Research Institute.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pisoni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cecilia</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology and Rheumatology Department, CEMIC University Institute.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gomez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ramiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, National Hospital Dr. Alejandro Posadas, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shinjo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samuel Katsuyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>SK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of Rheumatology, Faculdade de Medicina FMUSP, Universidade de São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9518034</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1076-1608</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 3.6.4.13</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000072640">Interferon-Induced Helicase, IFIH1</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatomyositis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000072640" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferon-Induced Helicase, IFIH1</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007843" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Latin America</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34262005</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RHU.0000000000001756</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00124743-202203000-00031</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Inflammatory muscle diseases. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:1734–1747.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundberg IE, Tjärnlund A, Bottai M, et al. European League Against Rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for adult and juvenile idiopathic inflammatory myopathies and their major subgroups. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76:1955–1964.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohan A, Peter JB. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis (first of two parts). N Engl J Med. 1975;292:344–347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohan A, Peter JB. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis (second of two parts). N Engl J Med. 1975;292:403–407.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Euwer RL, Sontheimer RD. Amyopathic dermatomyositis (dermatomyositis sine myositis): presentation of six new cases and review of the literature. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1991;24:959–966.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerami P, Schope JM, McDonald L, et al. A systematic review of adult-onset clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis (dermatomyositis sine myositis): a missing link within the spectrum of the idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2006;54:597–613.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirakata M, Nagai S. Interstitial lung disease in polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2000;12:501–508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fathi M, Dastmalchi M, Rasmussen E, et al. Interstitial lung disease, a common manifestation of newly diagnosed polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2004;63:297–301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tani K, Tomioka R, Sato K, et al. Comparison of clinical course of polymyositis and dermatomyositis: a follow-up study in Tokushima University Hospital. J Med Invest. 2007;54:295–302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato S, Hoshino K, Satoh T, et al. RNA helicase encoded by melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 is a major autoantigen in patients with clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis: association with rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;60:2193–2200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao H, Pan M, Kang Y, et al. Clinical manifestations of dermatomyositis and clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis patients with positive expression of anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 antibody. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2012;64:1602–1610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang EH, Lee EB, Shin KC, et al. Interstitial lung disease in patients with polymyositis, dermatomyositis and amyopathic dermatomyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2005;44:1282–1286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connors GR, Christopher-Stine L, Oddis CV, et al. Interstitial lung disease associated with the idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: what progress has been made in the past 35 years?Chest. 2010;138:1464–1474.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Wang Q, Yang F, et al. Anti-MDA-5 antibody as a potential diagnostic and prognostic biomarker in patients with dermatomyositis. Oncotarget. 2017;8:26552–26564.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Liu Y, Li Y, et al. Associations between anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 antibody and demographics, clinical characteristics and laboratory results of patients with dermatomyositis: a systematic meta-analysis. J Dermatol. 2018;45:46–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Wu G, Gao D, et al. Factors associated with interstitial lung disease in patients with polymyositis and dermatomyositis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2016;11:1–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Gao X, Li Y, et al. Predictors and mortality of rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease in patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathy: a series of 474 patients. Front Med. 2020;7:1–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall JC, Casciola-Rosen L, Samedy LA, et al. Anti-melanoma differentiation-associated protein 5-associated dermatomyositis: expanding the clinical spectrum. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2013;65:1307–1315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y, Yang CS, Li YJ, et al. Predictive factors of rapidly progressive-interstitial lung disease in patients with clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis. Clin Rheumatol. 2016;35:113–116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Z, Cao M, Plana MN, et al. Utility of anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 antibody measurement in identifying patients with dermatomyositis and a high risk for developing rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease: a review of the literature and a meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res. 2013;65:1316–1324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borges IBP, Silva MG, Shinjo SK. Prevalence and reactivity of anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 (anti-MDA-5) autoantibody in Brazilian patients with dermatomyositis. An Bras Dermatol. 2018;93:517–523.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labrador-Horrillo M, Martinez MA, Selva-O'Callaghan A, et al. Anti-MDA5 antibodies in a large Mediterranean population of adults with dermatomyositis. J Immunol Res. 2014;2014:1–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bodoki L, Nagy-Vincze M, Griger Z, et al. Four dermatomyositis-specific autoantibodies-anti-TIF1gamma, anti-NXP2, anti-SAE and anti-MDA-5 in adult and juvenile patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathies in a Hungarian cohort. Autoimmun Rev. 2014;13:1211–1219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moghadam-Kia S, Oddis CV, Sato S, et al. Anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5. Is associated with rapidly progressive lung disease and poor survival in US patients with amyopathic and myopathic dermatomyositis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2016;68:689–694.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fiorentino D, Chung L, Zwerner J, et al. The mucocutaneous and systemic phenotype of dermatomyositis patients with antibodies to MDA-5 (CADM-140): a retrospective study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2011;65:25–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maraví Z, Burgos P, Prieto-González S. Clinical manifestations and antibody profile in 15 patients with dermatomyositis [in Spanish]. Rev Med Chile. 2020;148:160–167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortigosa LCM, Silva dos Reis VM. Dermatomyositis: analysis of 109 patients surveyed at the Hospital das Clínicas (HCFMUSP), São Paulo, Brazil. An Bras Dermatol. 2014;89:719–727.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Compston A. Aids to the investigation of peripheral nerve injuries. Medical Research Council: Nerve Injuries Research Committee. His Majesty's Stationery Office: 1942; pp. 48 (iii) and 74 figures and 7 diagrams; with aids to the examination of the peripheral nervous system. By Michael O'Brien for the Guarantors of Brain. Saunders Elsevier: 2010; pp. [8] 64 and 94 Figures. Brain. 2010;133:2838–2844.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rider LG, Werth VP, Huber AM, et al. Measures of adult and juvenile dermatomyositis, polymyositis, and inclusion body myositis: Physician and Patient/Parent Global Activity, Manual Muscle Testing (MMT), Health Assessment Questionnaire (HAQ)/Childhood Health Assessment Questionnaire (C-HAQ), Childhood Myositis Assessment Scale (CMAS), Myositis Disease Activity Assessment Tool (MDAAT), Disease Activity Score (DAS), Short Form 36 (SF-36), Child Health Questionnaire (CHQ), physician global damage, Myositis Damage Index (MDI), Quantitative Muscle Testing (QMT), Myositis Functional Index-2 (FI-2), Myositis Activities Profile (MAP), Inclusion Body Myositis Functional Rating Scale (IBMFRS), Cutaneous Dermatomyositis Disease Area and Severity Index (CDASI), Cutaneous Assessment Tool (CAT), Dermatomyositis Skin Severity Index (DSSI), Skindex, and Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI). Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2011;63:S118–S157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruellas M, Viana V, Levy-Neto M, et al. Myositis-specific and myositis-associated autoantibody profiles and their clinical associations in a large series of patients with polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Clinics. 2013;68:909–914.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato S, Murakami A, Kuwajima A, et al. Clinical utility of an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay for detecting anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 autoantibodies. PLoS One. 2016;11:1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jablonski R, Bhorade S, Strek ME, et al. Recognition and management of myositis-associated rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease. Chest. 2020;158:252–263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hervier B, Uzunhan Y. Inflammatory myopathy related interstitial lung disease: from pathophysiology to treatment. Front Med. 2020;6:1–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morisset J, Johnson C, Rich E, et al. Management of myositis related interstitial lung disease. Chest. 2016;150:1118–1128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vuillard C, Pineton de Chambrun M, de Prost N, et al. Clinical features and outcome of patients with acute respiratory failure revealing anti-synthetase or anti-MDA-5 dermato pulmonary syndrome: a French multicenter retrospective study. Ann Int Care. 2018;8:1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
