<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34260107</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-2299</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>83</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Drug development research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Drug Dev Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Targeting TRAF3IP2 alleviates high glucose-induced cardiomyocyte inflammation and apoptosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>167</StartPage>
          <EndPage>175</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>167-175</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ddr.21856</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>To clarify the role of TRAF3IP2 in high glucose (HG)-stimulated cardiomyocyte inflammation and apoptosis and its action mechanism. SiRNA plasmid of TRAF3IP2 was constructed and transfected into HG-stimulated cardiomyocytes to silence TRAF3IP2. The expression of TRAF3IP2 was determined by quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR) and western blot. Cell viability and cytotoxicity were first observed using cell counting kit-8 and lactate dehydrogenase assays. The inflammatory injury of the cardiomyocytes was then examined by real time-qPCR (RT-qPCR) and western blot. The oxidative stress of the cardiomyocytes was evaluated using reactive oxygen species assay kit, RT-qPCR, western blot and enzyme activity assay kit. Next, cell apoptosis was detected employing TUNEL and western blot. Finally, RT-qPCR and western blot were performed to investigate the effects of inhibitors of dipeptidyl peptidase-4, including saxagliptin, empagliflozin and linagliptin, on TRAF3IP2. TRAF3IP2 expression was found to be increased in HG-stimulated cardiomyocytes. TRAF3IP2 interference inhibited HG-induced cell viability loss, cytotoxicity, inflammatory response, oxidative stress and apoptosis of the cardiomyocytes. Moreover, saxagliptin, empagliflozin and linagliptin inhibited the expression of TRAF3IP2. TRAF3IP2 interference alleviates HG-induced inflammation and apoptosis of cardiomyocytes. The result suggests that TRAF3IP2 may be a promising therapeutic target in treating diabetic cardiomyopathy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wei</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, People's Hospital Affiliated to Chongqing Three Gorges Medical College, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tao</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, People's Hospital Affiliated to Chongqing Three Gorges Medical College, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuanhong</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1945-534X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Guangdong Cardiovascular Institute, Guangdong Provincial People's Hospital, Guangdong, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Linzhi people's Hospital, Linzhi, Tibet, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Drug Dev Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8204468</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0272-4391</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D048868">Adaptor Proteins, Signal Transducing</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C414202">TRAF3IP2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>IY9XDZ35W2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005947">Glucose</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D048868" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptor Proteins, Signal Transducing</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017209" MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058065" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetic Cardiomyopathies</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005947" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D032383" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myocytes, Cardiac</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018384" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">TRAF3IP2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">apoptosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cardiomyocyte</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">high glucose</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">inflammation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34260107</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ddr.21856</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alavi, A., Sibbald, R. G., Mayer, D., Goodman, L., Botros, M., Armstrong, D. G., Woo, K, Boeni, T, Ayello, E. A., &amp; Kirsner, R. S. (2014). Diabetic foot ulcers: Part I. Pathophysiology and prevention. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology, 70(1), 1.e1-1.e18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2013.06.055</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alt, E. U., Barabadi, Z., Pfnur, A., Ochoa, J. E., Daneshimehr, F., Lang, L. M., … Izadpanah, R. (2018). TRAF3IP2, a novel therapeutic target in glioblastoma multiforme. Oncotarget, 9(51), 29772-29788. https://doi.org/10.18632/oncotarget.25710</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aroor, A. R., Habibi, J., Kandikattu, H. K., Garro-Kacher, M., Barron, B., Chen, D., … DeMarco, V. G. (2017). Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 (DPP-4) inhibition with linagliptin reduces western diet-induced myocardial TRAF3IP2 expression, inflammation and fibrosis in female mice. Cardiovascular Diabetology, 16(1), 61. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-017-0544-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohm, B., Burkhardt, H., Uebe, S., Apel, M., Behrens, F., Reis, A., &amp; Huffmeier, U. (2012). Identification of low-frequency TRAF3IP2 coding variants in psoriatic arthritis patients and functional characterization. Arthritis Research &amp; Therapy, 14(2), R84. https://doi.org/10.1186/ar3807</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown, S. M., Smith, C. E., Meuth, A. I., Khan, M., Aroor, A. R., Cleeton, H. M., … Bender, S. B. (2017). Dipeptidyl Peptidase-4 inhibition with Saxagliptin ameliorates angiotensin II-induced cardiac diastolic dysfunction in male mice. Endocrinology, 158(10), 3592-3604. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2017-00416</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ciccacci, C., Biancone, L., Di Fusco, D., Ranieri, M., Condino, G., Giardina, E., … Borgiani, P. (2013). TRAF3IP2 gene is associated with cutaneous extraintestinal manifestations in inflammatory bowel disease. Journal of Crohn's &amp; Colitis, 7(1), 44-52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.crohns.2012.02.020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cole, J. B., &amp; Florez, J. C. (2020). Genetics of diabetes mellitus and diabetes complications. Nature Reviews. Nephrology, 16(7), 377-390. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41581-020-0278-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das, N. A., Carpenter, A. J., Belenchia, A., Aroor, A. R., Noda, M., Siebenlist, U., … DeMarco, V. G. (2020). Empagliflozin reduces high glucose-induced oxidative stress and miR-21-dependent TRAF3IP2 induction and RECK suppression, and inhibits human renal proximal tubular epithelial cell migration and epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition. Cellular Signalling, 68, 109506. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2019.109506</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das, N. A., Carpenter, A. J., Yoshida, T., Kumar, S. A., Gautam, S., Mostany, R., … Chandrasekar, B. (2018). TRAF3IP2 mediates TWEAK/TWEAKR-induced pro-fibrotic responses in cultured cardiac fibroblasts and the heart. Journal of Molecular and Cellular Cardiology, 121, 107-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yjmcc.2018.07.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhalla, N. S., Shah, A. K., &amp; Tappia, P. S. (2020). Role of oxidative stress in metabolic and subcellular abnormalities in diabetic cardiomyopathy. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21(7), 2413. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21072413</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dillmann, W. H. (2019). Diabetic cardiomyopathy. Circulation Research, 124(8), 1160-1162. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.118.314665</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giacco, F., &amp; Brownlee, M. (2010). Oxidative stress and diabetic complications. Circulation Research, 107(9), 1058-1070. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.110.223545</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jia, G., Hill, M. A., &amp; Sowers, J. R. (2018). Diabetic cardiomyopathy: An update of mechanisms contributing to this clinical entity. Circulation Research, 122(4), 624-638. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCRESAHA.117.311586</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jia, G., Whaley-Connell, A., &amp; Sowers, J. R. (2018). Diabetic cardiomyopathy: A hyperglycaemia- and insulin-resistance-induced heart disease. Diabetologia, 61(1), 21-28. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00125-017-4390-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, W. S., &amp; Kim, J. (2017). Diabetic cardiomyopathy: Where we are and where we are going. The Korean Journal of Internal Medicine, 32(3), 404-421. https://doi.org/10.3904/kjim.2016.208</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogura, Y., Kitada, M., Monno, I., Kanasaki, K., Watanabe, A., &amp; Koya, D. (2018). Renal mitochondrial oxidative stress is enhanced by the reduction of Sirt3 activity, in Zucker diabetic fatty rats. Redox Report, 23(1), 153-159. https://doi.org/10.1080/13510002.2018.1487174</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orime, K., &amp; Terauchi, Y. (2020). Efficacy and safety of saxagliptin for the treatment of type 2 diabetes mellitus. Expert Opinion on Pharmacotherapy, 21(17), 2101-2114. https://doi.org/10.1080/14656566.2020.1803280</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouyang, C., You, J., &amp; Xie, Z. (2014). The interplay between autophagy and apoptosis in the diabetic heart. Journal of Molecular and Cellular Cardiology, 71, 71-80. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yjmcc.2013.10.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padilla, J., Carpenter, A. J., Das, N. A., Kandikattu, H. K., Lopez-Ongil, S., Martinez-Lemus, L. A., … Chandrasekar, B. (2018). TRAF3IP2 mediates high glucose-induced endothelin-1 production as well as endothelin-1-induced inflammation in endothelial cells. American Journal of Physiology. Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 314(1), H52-H64. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00478.2017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paolillo, S., Marsico, F., Prastaro, M., Renga, F., Esposito, L., De Martino, F., … Gargiulo, P. (2019). Diabetic cardiomyopathy: Definition, diagnosis, and therapeutic implications. Heart Failure Clinics, 15(3), 341-347. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hfc.2019.02.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papadopoulou-Marketou, N., Chrousos, G. P., &amp; Kanaka-Gantenbein, C. (2017). Diabetic nephropathy in type 1 diabetes: A review of early natural history, pathogenesis, and diagnosis. Diabetes/Metabolism Research and Reviews, 33(2). https://doi.org/10.1002/dmrr.2841</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pappachan, J. M., Varughese, G. I., Sriraman, R., &amp; Arunagirinathan, G. (2013). Diabetic cardiomyopathy: Pathophysiology, diagnostic evaluation and management. World Journal of Diabetes, 4(5), 177-189. https://doi.org/10.4239/wjd.v4.i5.177</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raev, D. C. (1994). Which left ventricular function is impaired earlier in the evolution of diabetic cardiomyopathy? An echocardiographic study of young type I diabetic patients. Diabetes Care, 17(7), 633-639. https://doi.org/10.2337/diacare.17.7.633</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regan, T. J., Lyons, M. M., Ahmed, S. S., Levinson, G. E., Oldewurtel, H. A., Ahmad, M. R., &amp; Haider, B. (1977). Evidence for cardiomyopathy in familial diabetes mellitus. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 60(4), 884-899. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI108843</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo, I., &amp; Frangogiannis, N. G. (2016). Diabetes-associated cardiac fibrosis: Cellular effectors, molecular mechanisms and therapeutic opportunities. Journal of Molecular and Cellular Cardiology, 90, 84-93. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yjmcc.2015.12.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamuri, S., Higashi, Y., Sukhanov, S., Siddesha, J. M., Delafontaine, P., Siebenlist, U., &amp; Chandrasekar, B. (2016). TRAF3IP2 mediates atherosclerotic plaque development and vulnerability in ApoE(−/−) mice. Atherosclerosis, 252, 153-160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2016.05.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamuri, S. S., Valente, A. J., Siddesha, J. M., Delafontaine, P., Siebenlist, U., Gardner, J. D., &amp; Bysani, C. (2016). TRAF3IP2 mediates aldosterone/salt-induced cardiac hypertrophy and fibrosis. Molecular and Cellular Endocrinology, 429, 84-92. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mce.2016.03.038</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salin Raj, P., Swapna, S. U. S., &amp; Raghu, K. G. (2019). High glucose induced calcium overload via impairment of SERCA/PLN pathway and mitochondrial dysfunction leads to oxidative stress in H9c2 cells and amelioration with ferulic acid. Fundamental &amp; Clinical Pharmacology, 33(4), 412-425. https://doi.org/10.1111/fcp.12452</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sivasankar, D., George, M., &amp; Sriram, D. K. (2018). Novel approaches in the treatment of diabetic cardiomyopathy. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy, 106, 1039-1045. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2018.07.051</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, Y., Chen, L., Li, Y., Lin, Q., Liu, W., &amp; Zhang, L. (2019). Knockdown of TRAF3IP2 suppresses the expression of VEGFA and the proliferation of keratinocytes and vascular endothelial cells. Heliyon, 5(5), e01642. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e01642</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valente, A. J., Irimpen, A. M., Siebenlist, U., &amp; Chandrasekar, B. (2014). OxLDL induces endothelial dysfunction and death via TRAF3IP2: Inhibition by HDL3 and AMPK activators. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 70, 117-128. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2014.02.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valente, A. J., Sakamuri, S. S., Siddesha, J. M., Yoshida, T., Gardner, J. D., Prabhu, R., … Chandrasekar, B. (2013). TRAF3IP2 mediates interleukin-18-induced cardiac fibroblast migration and differentiation. Cellular Signalling, 25(11), 2176-2184. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2013.07.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venkatesan, B., Valente, A. J., Das, N. A., Carpenter, A. J., Yoshida, T., Delafontaine, J. L., … Chandrasekar, B. (2013). CIKS (Act1 or TRAF3IP2) mediates high glucose-induced endothelial dysfunction. Cellular Signalling, 25(1), 359-371. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2012.10.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang, Q., Chen, L., Hou, S., Fang, J., Zhou, Y., Bai, L., … Yang, P. (2014). TRAF5 and TRAF3IP2 gene polymorphisms are associated with Behcet's disease and Vogt-Koyanagi-Harada syndrome: A case-control study. PLoS One, 9(1), e84214. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0084214</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
