<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34272903</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-1136</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>69</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Glia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Glia</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Enhanced enteric neurogenesis by Schwann cell precursors in mouse models of Hirschsprung disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2575</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2590</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2575-2590</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/glia.24059</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Hirschsprung disease (HSCR) is characterized by congenital absence of enteric neurons in distal portions of the gut. Although recent studies identified Schwann cell precursors (SCPs) as a novel cellular source of enteric neurons, it is unknown how SCPs contribute to the disease phenotype of HSCR. Using Schwann cell-specific genetic labeling, we investigated SCP-derived neurogenesis in two mouse models of HSCR; Sox10 haploinsufficient mice exhibiting distal colonic aganglionosis and Ednrb knockout mice showing small intestinal aganglionosis. We also examined Ret dependency in SCP-derived neurogenesis using mice displaying intestinal aganglionosis in which Ret expression was conditionally removed in the Schwann cell lineage. SCP-derived neurons were abundant in the transition zone lying between the ganglionated and aganglionic segments, although SCP-derived neurogenesis was scarce in the aganglionic region. In the transition zone, SCPs mainly gave rise to nitrergic neurons that are rarely observed in the SCP-derived neurons under the normal condition. Enhanced SCP-derived neurogenesis was also detected in the transition zone of mice lacking RET expression in the Schwann cell lineage. Increased SCP-derived neurogenesis in the transition zone suggests that reduction in the vagal neural crest-derived enteric neurons promotes SCP-derived neurogenesis. SCPs may adopt a neuronal subtype by responding to changes in the gut environment. Robust SCP-derived neurogenesis can occur in a Ret-independent manner, which suggests that SCPs are a cellular source to compensate for missing enteric neurons in HSCR.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Uesaka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Toshihiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3420-1746</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division for Neural Differentiation and Regeneration, Department of Physiology and Cell Biology, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Okamoto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mitsumasa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division for Neural Differentiation and Regeneration, Department of Physiology and Cell Biology, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Surgery, Japanese Red Cross Society, Himeji Hospital, Himeji, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nagashimada</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mayumi</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division for Neural Differentiation and Regeneration, Department of Physiology and Cell Biology, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Health Science, Graduate School of Medical Science, Kanazawa University, Kanazawa, Ishikawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsuda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoshihiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division for Neural Differentiation and Regeneration, Department of Physiology and Cell Biology, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kihara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Miho</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory for Animal Resources and Genetic Engineering, RIKEN Center for Biosystems Dynamics Research, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kiyonari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1509-8747</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory for Animal Resources and Genetic Engineering, RIKEN Center for Biosystems Dynamics Research, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Enomoto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hideki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8004-8885</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division for Neural Differentiation and Regeneration, Department of Physiology and Cell Biology, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Glia</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8806785</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0894-1491</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017615" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enteric Nervous System</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006627" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hirschsprung Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018345" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice, Knockout</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009432" MajorTopicYN="N">Neural Crest</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055495" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurogenesis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012583" MajorTopicYN="N">Schwann Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Ret</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">SCPs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">extrinsic innervation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">intestinal aganglionosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">regeneration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>37</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34272903</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.24059</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adameyko, I., Lallemend, F., Aquino, J. B., Pereira, J. A., Topilko, P., Muller, T., … Ernfors, P. (2009). Schwann cell precursors from nerve innervation are a cellular origin of melanocytes in skin. Cell, 139(2), 366-379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrenschee, M., Lange, C., Cossais, F., Egberts, J. H., Becker, T., Wedel, T., &amp; Bottner, M. (2015). Expression and function of Neuregulin 1 and its signaling system ERBB2/3 in the enteric nervous system. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 9, 360. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2015.00360</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bondurand, N., Natarajan, D., Barlow, A., Thapar, N., &amp; Pachnis, V. (2006). Maintenance of mammalian enteric nervous system progenitors by SOX10 and endothelin 3 signalling. Development, 133(10), 2075-2086. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.02375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brennan, A., Dean, C. H., Zhang, A. L., Cass, D. T., Mirsky, R., &amp; Jessen, K. R. (2000). Endothelins control the timing of Schwann cell generation in vitro and in vivo. Developmental Biology, 227(2), 545-557. https://doi.org/10.1006/dbio.2000.9887</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Britsch, S., Goerich, D. E., Riethmacher, D., Peirano, R. I., Rossner, M., Nave, K. A., Birchmeier, C., &amp; Wegner, M. (2001). The transcription factor Sox10 is a key regulator of peripheral glial development. Genes &amp; Development, 15(1), 66-78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cacalano, G., Farinas, I., Wang, L. C., Hagler, K., Forgie, A., Moore, M., … Rosenthal, A. (1998). GFRα1 is an essential receptor component for GDNF in the developing nervous system and kidney. Neuron, 21(1), 53-62. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0896-6273(00)80514-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatterjee, S., Kapoor, A., Akiyama, J. A., Auer, D. R., Lee, D., Gabriel, S., Berrios, C., Pennacchio, L. A., &amp; Chakravarti, A. (2016). Enhancer variants synergistically drive dysfunction of a gene regulatory network in Hirschsprung disease. Cell, 167(2), 355-368 e310. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2016.09.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper, J. E., McCann, C. J., Natarajan, D., Choudhury, S., Boesmans, W., Delalande, J. M., vanden Berghe, P., Burns, A. J., &amp; Thapar, N. (2016). In vivo transplantation of enteric neural crest cells into mouse gut; engraftment, functional integration and long-term safety. PLoS One, 11(1), e0147989. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0147989</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Druckenbrod, N. R., Powers, P. A., Bartley, C. R., Walker, J. W., &amp; Epstein, M. L. (2008). Targeting of endothelin receptor-B to the neural crest. Genesis, 46(8), 396-400. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvg.20415</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyachuk, V., Furlan, A., Shahidi, M. K., Giovenco, M., Kaukua, N., Konstantinidou, C., Pachnis, V., Memic, F., Marklund, U., Müller, T., Birchmeier, C., Fried, K., Ernfors, P., &amp; Adameyko, I. (2014). Parasympathetic neurons originate from nerve-associated peripheral glial progenitors. Science, 345(6192), 82-87. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1253281</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enomoto, H., Araki, T., Jackman, A., Heuckeroth, R. O., Snider, W. D., Johnson, E. M., Jr., &amp; Milbrandt, J. (1998). GFRα1-deficient mice have deficits in the enteric nervous system and kidneys. Neuron, 21(2), 317-324. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(00)80541-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinosa-Medina, I., Outin, E., Picard, C. A., Chettouh, Z., Dymecki, S., Consalez, G. G., Coppola, E., &amp; Brunet, J. F. (2014). Parasympathetic ganglia derive from Schwann cell precursors. Science, 345(6192), 87-90. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1253286</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furlan, A., Dyachuk, V., Kastriti, M. E., Calvo-Enrique, L., Abdo, H., Hadjab, S., Chontorotzea, T., Akkuratova, N., Usoskin, D., Kamenev, D., Petersen, J., Sunadome, K., Memic, F., Marklund, U., Fried, K., Topilko, P., Lallemend, F., Kharchenko, P. V., Ernfors, P., &amp; Adameyko, I. (2017). Multipotent peripheral glial cells generate neuroendocrine cells of the adrenal medulla. Science, 357(6346), eaal3753. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aal3753</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gianino, S., Grider, J. R., Cresswell, J., Enomoto, H., &amp; Heuckeroth, R. O. (2003). GDNF availability determines enteric neuron number by controlling precursor proliferation. Development, 130(10), 2187-2198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hao, M. M., &amp; Young, H. M. (2009). Development of enteric neuron diversity. Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, 13(7), 1193-1210. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1582-4934.2009.00813.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heuckeroth, R. O. (2018). Hirschsprung disease - Integrating basic science and clinical medicine to improve outcomes. Nature Reviews. Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, 15(3), 152-167. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrgastro.2017.149</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosoda, K., Hammer, R. E., Richardson, J. A., Baynash, A. G., Cheung, J. C., Giaid, A., &amp; Yanagisawa, M. (1994). Targeted and natural (piebald-lethal) mutations of endothelin-B receptor gene produce megacolon associated with spotted coat color in mice. Cell, 79(7), 1267-1276. https://doi.org/10.1016/0092-8674(94)90017-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isern, J., Garcia-Garcia, A., Martin, A. M., Arranz, L., Martin-Perez, D., Torroja, C., … Mendez-Ferrer, S. (2014). The neural crest is a source of mesenchymal stem cells with specialized hematopoietic stem cell niche function. eLife, 3, e03696. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.03696</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaegle, M., Ghazvini, M., Mandemakers, W., Piirsoo, M., Driegen, S., Levavasseur, F., Raghoenath, S., Grosveld, F., &amp; Meijer, D. (2003). The POU proteins Brn-2 and Oct-6 share important functions in Schwann cell development. Genes &amp; Development, 17(11), 1380-1391.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain, S., Golden, J. P., Wozniak, D., Pehek, E., Johnson, E. M., Jr., &amp; Milbrandt, J. (2006). RET is dispensable for maintenance of midbrain dopaminergic neurons in adult mice. The Journal of Neuroscience, 26(43), 11230-11238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jing, S., Wen, D., Yu, Y., Holst, P. L., Luo, Y., Fang, M., Tamir, R., Antonio, L., Hu, Z., Cupples, R., Louis, J. C., Hu, S., Altrock, B. W., &amp; Fox, G. M. (1996). GDNF-induced activation of the ret protein tyrosine kinase is mediated by GDNFR-α, a novel receptor for GDNF. Cell, 85(7), 1113-1124. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0092-8674(00)81311-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joseph, N. M., Mukouyama, Y. S., Mosher, J. T., Jaegle, M., Crone, S. A., Dormand, E. L., Lee, K. F., Meijer, D., Anderson, D. J., &amp; Morrison, S. J. (2004). Neural crest stem cells undergo multilineage differentiation in developing peripheral nerves to generate endoneurial fibroblasts in addition to Schwann cells. Development, 131(22), 5599-5612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaukua, N., Shahidi, M. K., Konstantinidou, C., Dyachuk, V., Kaucka, M., Furlan, A., An, Z., Wang, L., Hultman, I., Ährlund-Richter, L., Blom, H., Brismar, H., Lopes, N. A., Pachnis, V., Suter, U., Clevers, H., Thesleff, I., Sharpe, P., Ernfors, P., … Adameyko, I. (2014). Glial origin of mesenchymal stem cells in a tooth model system. Nature, 513(7519), 551-554. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature13536</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, J., Lo, L., Dormand, E., &amp; Anderson, D. J. (2003). SOX10 maintains multipotency and inhibits neuronal differentiation of neural crest stem cells. Neuron, 38(1), 17-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewandoski, M., Meyers, E. N., &amp; Martin, G. R. (1997). Analysis of Fgf8 gene function in vertebrate development. Cold Spring Harbor Symposia on Quantitative Biology, 62, 159-168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindeboom, F., Gillemans, N., Karis, A., Jaegle, M., Meijer, D., Grosveld, F., &amp; Philipsen, S. (2003). A tissue-specific knockout reveals that Gata1 is not essential for Sertoli cell function in the mouse. Nucleic Acids Research, 31(18), 5405-5412. https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkg723</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madisen, L., Zwingman, T. A., Sunkin, S. M., Oh, S. W., Zariwala, H. A., Gu, H., Ng, L. L., Palmiter, R. D., Hawrylycz, M. J., Jones, A. R., Lein, E. S., &amp; Zeng, H. (2010). A robust and high-throughput Cre reporting and characterization system for the whole mouse brain. Nature Neuroscience, 13(1), 133-140. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2467</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meintanis, S., Thomaidou, D., Jessen, K. R., Mirsky, R., &amp; Matsas, R. (2001). The neuron-glia signal beta-neuregulin promotes Schwann cell motility via the MAPK pathway. Glia, 34(1), 39-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore, M. W., Klein, R. D., Farinas, I., Sauer, H., Armanini, M., Phillips, H., … Rosenthal, A. (1996). Renal and neuronal abnormalities in mice lacking GDNF. Nature, 382(6586), 76-79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris, J. K., Lin, W., Hauser, C., Marchuk, Y., Getman, D., &amp; Lee, K. F. (1999). Rescue of the cardiac defect in ErbB2 mutant mice reveals essential roles of ErbB2 in peripheral nervous system development. Neuron, 23(2), 273-283. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0896-6273(00)80779-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musser, M. A., Correa, H., &amp; Southard-Smith, E. M. (2015). Enteric neuron imbalance and proximal dysmotility in ganglionated intestine of the Sox10(Dom/+) Hirschsprung mouse model. Cellular and Molecular Gastroenterology and Hepatology, 1(1), 87-101. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcmgh.2014.08.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Natarajan, D., Marcos-Gutierrez, C., Pachnis, V., &amp; de Graaff, E. (2002). Requirement of signalling by receptor tyrosine kinase RET for the directed migration of enteric nervous system progenitor cells during mammalian embryogenesis. Development, 129(22), 5151-5160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishiyama, C., Uesaka, T., Manabe, T., Yonekura, Y., Nagasawa, T., Newgreen, D. F., Young, H. M., &amp; Enomoto, H. (2012). Trans-mesenteric neural crest cells are the principal source of the colonic enteric nervous system. Nature Neuroscience, 15(9), 1211-1218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okamoto, M., Yoshioka, Y., Maeda, K., Bito, Y., Fukumoto, T., Uesaka, T., &amp; Enomoto, H. (2019). Mice conditionally expressing RET(C618F) mutation display C cell hyperplasia and hyperganglionosis of the enteric nervous system. Genesis, 57(5), e23292. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvg.23292</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okamura, Y., &amp; Saga, Y. (2008). Notch signaling is required for the maintenance of enteric neural crest progenitors. Development, 135(21), 3555-3565. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.022319</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pichel, J. G., Shen, L., Sheng, H. Z., Granholm, A. C., Drago, J., Grinberg, A., Lee, E. J., Huang, S. P., Saarma, M., Hoffer, B. J., Sariola, H., &amp; Westphal, H. (1996). Defects in enteric innervation and kidney development in mice lacking GDNF. Nature, 382(6586), 73-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian, H., Kang, X., Hu, J., Zhang, D., Liang, Z., Meng, F., Zhang, X., Xue, Y., Maimon, R., Dowdy, S. F., Devaraj, N. K., Zhou, Z., Mobley, W. C., Cleveland, D. W., &amp; Fu, X. D. (2020). Reversing a model of Parkinson's disease with in situ converted nigral neurons. Nature, 582, 550-556. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2388-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qu, Z. D., Thacker, M., Castelucci, P., Bagyanszki, M., Epstein, M. L., &amp; Furness, J. B. (2008). Immunohistochemical analysis of neuron types in the mouse small intestine. Cell and Tissue Research, 334(2), 147-161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quintes, S., Brinkmann, B. G., Ebert, M., Frob, F., Kungl, T., Arlt, F. A., … Nave, K. A. (2016). Zeb2 is essential for Schwann cell differentiation, myelination and nerve repair. Nature Neuroscience, 19(8), 1050-1059. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4321</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez, C. I., Buchholz, F., Galloway, J., Sequerra, R., Kasper, J., Ayala, R., … Dymecki, S. M. (2000). High-efficiency deleter mice show that FLPe is an alternative to Cre-loxP. Nature Genetics, 25(2), 139-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanchez, M. P., Silos-Santiago, I., Frisen, J., He, B., Lira, S. A., &amp; Barbacid, M. (1996). Renal agenesis and the absence of enteric neurons in mice lacking GDNF. Nature, 382, 70-73. https://doi.org/10.1038/382070a0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sang, Q., &amp; Young, H. M. (1996). Chemical coding of neurons in the myenteric plexus and external muscle of the small and large intestine of the mouse. Cell and Tissue Research, 284(1), 39-53. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004410050565</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuchardt, A., D'Agati, V., Larsson-Blomberg, L., Costantini, F., &amp; Pachnis, V. (1994). Defects in the kidney and enteric nervous system of mice lacking the tyrosine kinase receptor Ret. Nature, 367(6461), 380-383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonnenberg-Riethmacher, E., Miehe, M., Stolt, C. C., Goerich, D. E., Wegner, M., &amp; Riethmacher, D. (2001). Development and degeneration of dorsal root ganglia in the absence of the HMG-domain transcription factor Sox10. Mechanisms of Development, 109(2), 253-265. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0925-4773(01)00547-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soret, R., Schneider, S., Bernas, G., Christophers, B., Souchkova, O., Charrier, B., Righini-Grunder, F., Aspirot, A., Landry, M., Kembel, S. W., Faure, C., Heuckeroth, R. O., &amp; Pilon, N. (2020). Glial cell derived neurotrophic factor induces enteric neurogenesis and improves Colon structure and function in mouse models of Hirschsprung disease. Gastroenterology, 159(5), 1824-1838.e17. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2020.07.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taraviras, S., Marcos-Gutierrez, C. V., Durbec, P., Jani, H., Grigoriou, M., Sukumaran, M., Wang, L. C., Hynes, M., Raisman, G., &amp; Pachnis, V. (1999). Signalling by the RET receptor tyrosine kinase and its role in the development of the mammalian enteric nervous system. Development, 126(12), 2785-2797.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Treanor, J. J., Goodman, L., de Sauvage, F., Stone, D. M., Poulsen, K. T., Beck, C. D., … Rosenthal, A. (1996). Characterization of a multicomponent receptor for GDNF. Nature, 382(6586), 80-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueki, Y., Wilken, M. S., Cox, K. E., Chipman, L., Jorstad, N., Sternhagen, K., Simic, M., Ullom, K., Nakafuku, M., &amp; Reh, T. A. (2015). Transgenic expression of the proneural transcription factor Ascl1 in Müller glia stimulates retinal regeneration in young mice. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 112(44), 13717-13722. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1510595112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uesaka, T., &amp; Enomoto, H. (2010). Neural precursor death is central to the pathogenesis of intestinal aganglionosis in Ret hypomorphic mice. The Journal of Neuroscience, 30(15), 5211-5218. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.6244-09.2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uesaka, T., Nagashimada, M., &amp; Enomoto, H. (2013). GDNF signaling levels control migration and neuronal differentiation of enteric ganglion precursors. The Journal of Neuroscience, 33(41), 16372-16382. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2079-13.2013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uesaka, T., Nagashimada, M., &amp; Enomoto, H. (2015). Neuronal differentiation in Schwann cell lineage underlies postnatal neurogenesis in the enteric nervous system. The Journal of Neuroscience, 35(27), 9879-9888. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1239-15.2015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uesaka, T., Nagashimada, M., Yonemura, S., &amp; Enomoto, H. (2008). Diminished Ret expression compromises neuronal survival in the colon and causes intestinal aganglionosis in mice. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 118(5), 1890-1898. https://doi.org/10.1172/jci34425</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, J., Williams, J. P., Rizvi, T. A., Kordich, J. J., Witte, D., Meijer, D., Stemmer-Rachamimov, A. O., Cancelas, J. A., &amp; Ratner, N. (2008). Plexiform and dermal neurofibromas and pigmentation are caused by Nf1 loss in desert hedgehog-expressing cells. Cancer Cell, 13(2), 105-116. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2007.12.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, Z., Parry, M., Hou, X. Y., Liu, M. H., Wang, H., Cain, R., Pei, Z. F., Chen, Y. C., Guo, Z. Y., Abhijeet, S., &amp; Chen, G. (2020). Gene therapy conversion of striatal astrocytes into GABAergic neurons in mouse models of Huntington's disease. Nature Communications, 11, 1105. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-14855-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie, M., Kamenev, D., Kaucka, M., Kastriti, M. E., Zhou, B., Artemov, A. V., Storer, M., Fried, K., Adameyko, I., Dyachuk, V., &amp; Chagin, A. S. (2019). Schwann cell precursors contribute to skeletal formation during embryonic development in mice and zebrafish. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 116(30), 15068-15073. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1900038116</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young, H. M., Bergner, A. J., &amp; Muller, T. (2003). Acquisition of neuronal and glial markers by neural crest-derived cells in the mouse intestine. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 456(1), 1-11. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10448</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young, H. M., Hearn, C. J., Farlie, P. G., Canty, A. J., Thomas, P. Q., &amp; Newgreen, D. F. (2001). GDNF is a chemoattractant for enteric neural cells. Developmental Biology, 229(2), 503-516. https://doi.org/10.1006/dbio.2000.0100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young, H. M., Jones, B. R., &amp; McKeown, S. J. (2002). The projections of early enteric neurons are influenced by the direction of neural crest cell migration. The Journal of Neuroscience, 22(14), 6005-6018. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.22-14-06005.2002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu, Q., Du, M., Zhang, W., Liu, L., Gao, Z., Chen, W., … Wang, L. (2020). Mesenteric neural crest cells are the embryological basis of skip segment Hirschsprung's disease. Cellular and Molecular Gastroenterology and Hepatology, 12(1), 1-24. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcmgh.2020.12.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, H., Su, J., Hu, X., Zhou, C., Li, H., Chen, Z., Xiao, Q., Wang, B., Wu, W., Sun, Y., Zhou, Y., Tang, C., Liu, F., Wang, L., Feng, C., Liu, M., Li, S., Zhang, Y., Xu, H., … Yang, H. (2020). Glia-to-neuron conversion by CRISPR-CasRx alleviates symptoms of neurological disease in mice. Cell, 181(3), 590-603 e516. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2020.03.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
