<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34321847</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2219-2840</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>25</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>World journal of gastroenterology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>World J Gastroenterol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer: Epidemiological aspects and immunological considerations.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>3825</StartPage>
          <EndPage>3836</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>3825-3836</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3748/wjg.v27.i25.3825</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Ordinary chronic pancreatitis is a well-known risk factor for pancreatic cancer, whereas such an association with autoimmune pancreatitis (AIP) is widely debated. Due to the rarity of the latter disorder, there are few specific clinical and epidemiological studies investigating the relation between AIP and pancreatic cancer, which do not seem to support it. However, these studies are affected by several limitations and, therefore, a link between AIP (and, specifically, type 1 AIP) and pancreatic cancer cannot be ruled out definitively on this basis. Moreover, several immunopathological aspects of type 1 AIP and, in general, immunoglobulin G4-related disease can create an immunological context that may impair the tumoral immunosurveillance and promote the pancreatic carcinogenesis and its progression. In detail, Th2 immunological dominance, type 2 macrophage polarization and basophil infiltration observed in type 1 AIP, may play a permissive role in creating a favorable immunological environment for pancreatic carcinogenesis, in addition to the immunosuppressive therapies that can be used in these patients.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©The Author(s) 2021. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Poddighe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dimitri</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine, Nazarbayev University, Nur-Sultan 010000, Kazakhstan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>World J Gastroenterol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100883448</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1007-9327</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000081012" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Pancreatitis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010190" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pancreatic Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D050500" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pancreatitis, Chronic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune pancreatitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Basophils</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic pancreatitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunoglobulin G4-related disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Macrophages</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pancreatic cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Th2 cells</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The author declares no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34321847</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8291014</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v27.i25.3825</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beyer G, Habtezion A, Werner J, Lerch MM, Mayerle J. Chronic pancreatitis. Lancet. 2020;396:499–512.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32798493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchida K, Masamune A, Shimosegawa T, Okazaki K. Prevalence of IgG4-Related Disease in Japan Based on Nationwide Survey in 2009. Int J Rheumatol. 2012;2012:358371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3415093</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22899936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madhani K, Farrell JJ. Autoimmune Pancreatitis: An Update on Diagnosis and Management. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2016;45:29–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26895679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Toki F, Takeuchi T, Watanabe S, Shiratori K, Hayashi N. Chronic pancreatitis caused by an autoimmune abnormality. Proposal of the concept of autoimmune pancreatitis. Dig Dis Sci. 1995;40:1561–1568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7628283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chari ST, Kloeppel G, Zhang L, Notohara K, Lerch MM, Shimosegawa T  Autoimmune Pancreatitis International Cooperative Study Group (APICS) Histopathologic and clinical subtypes of autoimmune pancreatitis: the Honolulu consensus document. Pancreas. 2010;39:549–554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20562576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaho M, Dítě P, Kunovský L, Kianička B. Autoimmune pancreatitis - An ongoing challenge. Adv Med Sci. 2020;65:403–408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32805624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Pretis N, Frulloni L. Autoimmune pancreatitis type 2. Curr Opin Gastroenterol. 2020;36:417–420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32618613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vashi B, Khosroshahi A. IgG4-Related Disease with Emphasis on Its Gastrointestinal Manifestation. Gastroenterol Clin North Am. 2019;48:291–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31046976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe T, Minaga K, Kamata K, Kudo M, Strober W. Mechanistic Insights into Autoimmune Pancreatitis and IgG4-Related Disease. Trends Immunol. 2018;39:874–889.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30401468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsuboi H, Honda F, Takahashi H, Ono Y, Abe S, Kondo Y, Matsumoto I, Sumida T. Pathogenesis of IgG4-related disease. Comparison with Sjögren's syndrome. Mod Rheumatol. 2020;30:7–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31425659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rebours V, Lévy P. Pancreatic and biliary tract involvement in IgG4-related disease. Presse Med. 2020;49:104015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32234378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee HM, Deheragoda M, Harrison P, Devlin J, Sellars M, Hadzic N, Dhawan A, Grammatikopoulos T. Autoimmune pancreatitis in children: A single centre experience in diagnosis, management and long term follow up. Pancreatology. 2019;19:169–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30455055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khalaf N, El-Serag HB, Abrams HR, Thrift AP. Burden of Pancreatic Cancer: From Epidemiology to Practice. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19:876–884.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32147593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lowenfels AB, Maisonneuve P, Cavallini G, Ammann RW, Lankisch PG, Andersen JR, Dimagno EP, Andrén-Sandberg A, Domellöf L. Pancreatitis and the risk of pancreatic cancer. International Pancreatitis Study Group. N Engl J Med. 1993;328:1433–1437.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8479461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Kamisawa T, Brugge WR, Chung JB, Culver EL, Czakó L, Frulloni L, Go VL, Gress TM, Kim MH, Kawa S, Lee KT, Lerch MM, Liao WC, Löhr M, Okazaki K, Ryu JK, Schleinitz N, Shimizu K, Shimosegawa T, Soetikno R, Webster G, Yadav D, Zen Y, Chari ST. Long-term outcomes of autoimmune pancreatitis: a multicentre, international analysis. Gut. 2013;62:1771–1776.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3862979</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23232048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huggett MT, Culver EL, Kumar M, Hurst JM, Rodriguez-Justo M, Chapman MH, Johnson GJ, Pereira SP, Chapman RW, Webster GJM, Barnes E. Type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis and IgG4-related sclerosing cholangitis is associated with extrapancreatic organ failure, malignancy, and mortality in a prospective UK cohort. Am J Gastroenterol. 2014;109:1675–1683.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4552254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25155229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto M, Takahashi H, Tabeya T, Suzuki C, Naishiro Y, Ishigami K, Yajima H, Shimizu Y, Obara M, Yamamoto H, Himi T, Imai K, Shinomura Y. Risk of malignancies in IgG4-related disease. Mod Rheumatol. 2012;22:414–418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21894525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shiokawa M, Kodama Y, Yoshimura K, Kawanami C, Mimura J, Yamashita Y, Asada M, Kikuyama M, Okabe Y, Inokuma T, Ohana M, Kokuryu H, Takeda K, Tsuji Y, Minami R, Sakuma Y, Kuriyama K, Ota Y, Tanabe W, Maruno T, Kurita A, Sawai Y, Uza N, Watanabe T, Haga H, Chiba T. Risk of cancer in patients with autoimmune pancreatitis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2013;108:610–617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23318486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Law RJ, Dierkhising RA, Smyrk TC, Takahashi N, Chari ST. Risk of cancer in autoimmune pancreatitis: a case-control study and review of the literature. Pancreas. 2014;43:417–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24622072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirano K, Tada M, Sasahira N, Isayama H, Mizuno S, Takagi K, Watanabe T, Saito T, Kawahata S, Uchino R, Hamada T, Miyabayashi K, Mohri D, Sasaki T, Kogure H, Yamamoto N, Nakai Y, Yoshida H, Ito Y, Akiyama D, Toda N, Arizumi T, Yagioka H, Takahara N, Matsubara S, Yashima Y, Koike K. Incidence of malignancies in patients with IgG4-related disease. Intern Med. 2014;53:171–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24492683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimizu S, Naitoh I, Nakazawa T, Hayashi K, Miyabe K, Kondo H, Nishi Y, Yoshida M, Umemura S, Hori Y, Kato A, Okumura F, Sano H, Hirata Y, Takada H, Ohara H, Joh T. Correlation between long-term outcome and steroid therapy in type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis: relapse, malignancy and side effect of steroid. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2015;50:1411–1418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26061806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buijs J, Cahen DL, van Heerde MJ, Rauws EA, de Buy Wenniger LJ, Hansen BE, Biermann K, Verheij J, Vleggaar FP, Brink MA, Beuers UH, van Buuren HR, Bruno MJ. The Long-Term Impact of Autoimmune Pancreatitis on Pancreatic Function, Quality of Life, and Life Expectancy. Pancreas. 2015;44:1065–1071.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26355549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeura T, Miyoshi H, Shimatani M, Uchida K, Takaoka M, Okazaki K. Long-term outcomes of autoimmune pancreatitis. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22:7760–7766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5016376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27678359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bojková M, Dítě P, Dvořáčková J, Novotný I, Floreánová K, Kianička B, Uvírová M, Martínek A. Immunoglobulin G4, autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer. Dig Dis. 2015;33:86–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25531501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta R, Khosroshahi A, Shinagare S, Fernandez C, Ferrone C, Lauwers GY, Stone JH, Deshpande V. Does autoimmune pancreatitis increase the risk of pancreatic carcinoma? Pancreas. 2013;42:506–510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23271394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeura T, Miyoshi H, Uchida K, Fukui T, Shimatani M, Fukui Y, Sumimoto K, Matsushita M, Takaoka M, Okazaki K. Relationship between autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer: a single-center experience. Pancreatology. 2014;14:373–379.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25278307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ngwa T, Law R, Hart P, Smyrk TC, Chari ST. Serum IgG4 elevation in pancreatic cancer: diagnostic and prognostic significance and association with autoimmune pancreatitis. Pancreas. 2015;44:557–560.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25785724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang P, Zhang X, Wang C, Lang Y, Xu L, Huang L, Shen J, Feng ST. Pancreatic tumor in type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis: a diagnostic challenge. BMC Cancer. 2019;19:814.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6698045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31419961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedayat AA, Lisovsky M, Suriawinata AA, Longnecker DS. Association of IgG4 response and autoimmune pancreatitis with intraductal papillary-mucinous neoplasms. Pancreatology. 2017;17:263–266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28215485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morales-Oyarvide V, Fong ZV, Fernández-Del Castillo C, Warshaw AL. Intraductal Papillary Mucinous Neoplasms of the Pancreas: Strategic Considerations. Visc Med. 2017;33:466–476.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5757605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29344522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang H, Yang H, Zhang P, Wu D, Zhang S, Zhao J, Peng L, Chen H, Fei Y, Zhang X, Zhao Y, Zeng X, Zhang F, Zhang W. Malignancy and IgG4-related disease: the incidence, related factors and prognosis from a prospective cohort study in China. Sci Rep. 2020;10:4910.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7080711</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32188869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishikawa T, Kawashima H, Ohno E, Iida T, Suzuki H, Uetsuki K, Yamada K, Yashika J, Yoshikawa M, Gibo N, Aoki T, Kataoka K, Mori H, Fujishiro M. Risks and characteristics of pancreatic cancer and pancreatic relapse in autoimmune pancreatitis patients. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;35:2281–2288.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32583452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Islam AD, Selmi C, Datta-Mitra A, Sonu R, Chen M, Gershwin ME, Raychaudhuri SP. The changing faces of IgG4-related disease: Clinical manifestations and pathogenesis. Autoimmun Rev. 2015;14:914–922.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akiyama M, Suzuki K, Yamaoka K, Yasuoka H, Takeshita M, Kaneko Y, Kondo H, Kassai Y, Miyazaki T, Morita R, Yoshimura A, Takeuchi T. Number of Circulating Follicular Helper 2 T Cells Correlates With IgG4 and Interleukin-4 Levels and Plasmablast Numbers in IgG4-Related Disease. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67:2476–2481.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25989153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akiyama M, Yasuoka H, Yamaoka K, Suzuki K, Kaneko Y, Kondo H, Kassai Y, Koga K, Miyazaki T, Morita R, Yoshimura A, Takeuchi T. Enhanced IgG4 production by follicular helper 2 T cells and the involvement of follicular helper 1 T cells in the pathogenesis of IgG4-related disease. Arthritis Res Ther. 2016;18:167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4944254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27411315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arai Y, Yamashita K, Kuriyama K, Shiokawa M, Kodama Y, Sakurai T, Mizugishi K, Uchida K, Kadowaki N, Takaori-Kondo A, Kudo M, Okazaki K, Strober W, Chiba T, Watanabe T. Plasmacytoid Dendritic Cell Activation and IFN-α Production Are Prominent Features of Murine Autoimmune Pancreatitis and Human IgG4-Related Autoimmune Pancreatitis. J Immunol. 2015;195:3033–3044.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26297761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe T, Yamashita K, Sakurai T, Kudo M, Shiokawa M, Uza N, Kodama Y, Uchida K, Okazaki K, Chiba T. Toll-like receptor activation in basophils contributes to the development of IgG4-related disease. J Gastroenterol. 2013;48:247–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22744834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanagawa M, Uchida K, Ando Y, Tomiyama T, Yamaguchi T, Ikeura T, Fukui T, Nishio A, Uemura Y, Miyara T, Okamoto H, Satoi S, Okazaki K. Basophils activated via TLR signaling may contribute to pathophysiology of type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis. J Gastroenterol. 2018;53:449–460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5847205</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28921377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sokol CL, Medzhitov R. Emerging functions of basophils in protective and allergic immune responses. Mucosal Immunol. 2010;3:129–137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20072123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poddighe D, Mathias CB, Freyschmidt EJ, Kombe D, Caplan B, Marseglia GL, Oettgen HC. Basophils are rapidly mobilized following initial aeroallergen encounter in naïve mice and provide a priming source of IL-4 in adaptive immune responses. J Biol Regul Homeost Agents. 2014;28:91–103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24750795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poddighe D, Mathias CB, Brambilla I, Marseglia GL, Oettgen HC. Importance of basophils in eosinophilic asthma: the murine counterpart. J Biol Regul Homeost Agents. 2018;32:335–339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29685015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dossybayeva K, Abdukhakimova D, Poddighe D. Basophils and Systemic Lupus Erythematosus in Murine Models and Human Patients. Biology (Basel) 2020;9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32977704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe T, Yamashita K, Arai Y, Minaga K, Kamata K, Nagai T, Komeda Y, Takenaka M, Hagiwara S, Ida H, Sakurai T, Nishida N, Strober W, Kudo M. Chronic Fibro-Inflammatory Responses in Autoimmune Pancreatitis Depend on IFN-α and IL-33 Produced by Plasmacytoid Dendritic Cells. J Immunol. 2017;198:3886–3896.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28373582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cayrol C, Girard JP. IL-33: an alarmin cytokine with crucial roles in innate immunity, inflammation and allergy. Curr Opin Immunol. 2014;31:31–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25278425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vivier E, Artis D, Colonna M, Diefenbach A, Di Santo JP, Eberl G, Koyasu S, Locksley RM, McKenzie ANJ, Mebius RE, Powrie F, Spits H. Innate Lymphoid Cells: 10 Years On. Cell. 2018;174:1054–1066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30142344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma X, Wu D, Zhou S, Wan F, Liu H, Xu X, Zhao Y, Tang M. The pancreatic cancer secreted REG4 promotes macrophage polarization to M2 through EGFR/AKT/CREB pathway. Oncol Rep. 2016;35:189–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26531138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapouri-Moghaddam A, Mohammadian S, Vazini H, Taghadosi M, Esmaeili SA, Mardani F, Seifi B, Mohammadi A, Afshari JT, Sahebkar A. Macrophage plasticity, polarization, and function in health and disease. J Cell Physiol. 2018;233:6425–6440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29319160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furukawa S, Moriyama M, Tanaka A, Maehara T, Tsuboi H, Iizuka M, Hayashida JN, Ohta M, Saeki T, Notohara K, Sumida T, Nakamura S. Preferential M2 macrophages contribute to fibrosis in IgG4-related dacryoadenitis and sialoadenitis, so-called Mikulicz's disease. Clin Immunol. 2015;156:9–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25450336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mingomataj EÇ, Bakiri AH. Regulator Versus Effector Paradigm: Interleukin-10 as Indicator of the Switching Response. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2016;50:97–113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26450621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosser DM, Zhang X. Interleukin-10: new perspectives on an old cytokine. Immunol Rev. 2008;226:205–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2724982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19161426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raimondi S, Lowenfels AB, Morselli-Labate AM, Maisonneuve P, Pezzilli R. Pancreatic cancer in chronic pancreatitis; aetiology, incidence, and early detection. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2010;24:349–358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20510834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maitra A, Fukushima N, Takaori K, Hruban RH. Precursors to invasive pancreatic cancer. Adv Anat Pathol. 2005;12:81–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15731576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Tsuruta K, Okamoto A, Horiguchi S, Hayashi Y, Yun X, Yamaguchi T, Sasaki T. Frequent and significant K-ras mutation in the pancreas, the bile duct, and the gallbladder in autoimmune pancreatitis. Pancreas. 2009;38:890–895.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19752775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kinugawa Y, Uehara T, Sano K, Matsuda K, Maruyama Y, Kobayashi Y, Nakajima T, Hamano H, Kawa S, Higuchi K, Hosaka N, Shiozawa S, Ishigame H, Ota H. Methylation of Tumor Suppressor Genes in Autoimmune Pancreatitis. Pancreas. 2017;46:614–618.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato N, Parker AR, Fukushima N, Miyagi Y, Iacobuzio-Donahue CA, Eshleman JR, Goggins M. Epigenetic inactivation of TFPI-2 as a common mechanism associated with growth and invasion of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Oncogene. 2005;24:850–858.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15592528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sideras K, Braat H, Kwekkeboom J, van Eijck CH, Peppelenbosch MP, Sleijfer S, Bruno M. Role of the immune system in pancreatic cancer progression and immune modulating treatment strategies. Cancer Treat Rev. 2014;40:513–522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24315741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantovani A, Allavena P, Sica A, Balkwill F. Cancer-related inflammation. Nature. 2008;454:436–444.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18650914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tassi E, Gavazzi F, Albarello L, Senyukov V, Longhi R, Dellabona P, Doglioni C, Braga M, Di Carlo V, Protti MP. Carcinoembryonic antigen-specific but not antiviral CD4+ T cell immunity is impaired in pancreatic carcinoma patients. J Immunol. 2008;181:6595–6603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18941250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siveen KS, Kuttan G. Role of macrophages in tumour progression. Immunol Lett. 2009;123:97–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19428556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keir ME, Liang SC, Guleria I, Latchman YE, Qipo A, Albacker LA, Koulmanda M, Freeman GJ, Sayegh MH, Sharpe AH. Tissue expression of PD-L1 mediates peripheral T cell tolerance. J Exp Med. 2006;203:883–895.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2118286</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16606670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian L, Ma J, Ma L, Zheng B, Liu L, Song D, Wang Y, Zhang Z, Gao Q, Song K, Wang X. PD-1/PD-L1 expression profiles within intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma predict clinical outcome. World J Surg Oncol. 2020;18:303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686719</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33228682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu SW, Pan HC, Hsu YH, Chang KC, Wu LW, Chen WY, Chang MS. IL-20 antagonist suppresses PD-L1 expression and prolongs survival in pancreatic cancer models. Nat Commun. 2020;11:4611.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7490368</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32929072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu H, Hang JJ, Han T, Zhuo M, Jiao F, Wang LW. The M2 phenotype of tumor-associated macrophages in the stroma confers a poor prognosis in pancreatic cancer. Tumour Biol. 2016;37:8657–8664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26738860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poddighe D, Brambilla I, Marseglia GL. Basophils activated via TLR signaling may contribute to pathophysiology of type I autoimmune pancreatitis". J Gastroenterol. 2018;53:791–792.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29663078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Monte L, Wörmann S, Brunetto E, Heltai S, Magliacane G, Reni M, Paganoni AM, Recalde H, Mondino A, Falconi M, Aleotti F, Balzano G, Algül H, Doglioni C, Protti MP. Basophil Recruitment into Tumor-Draining Lymph Nodes Correlates with Th2 Inflammation and Reduced Survival in Pancreatic Cancer Patients. Cancer Res. 2016;76:1792–1803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26873846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marone G, Schroeder JT, Mattei F, Loffredo S, Gambardella AR, Poto R, de Paulis A, Schiavoni G, Varricchi G. Is There a Role for Basophils in Cancer? Front Immunol. 2020;11:2103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7505934</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33013885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seo MS, Yeo J, Hwang IC, Shim JY. Risk of pancreatic cancer in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: a meta-analysis. Clin Rheumatol. 2019;38:3109–3116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31270697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan Q, Gong L, Xiao H, Feng Y, Li L, Deng Z, Ye L, Zheng J, Dickerson CA, An N, Yang C, Liu HF. Basophil Activation-Dependent Autoantibody and Interleukin-17 Production Exacerbate Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Front Immunol. 2017;8:348.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5366357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28396669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poddighe D, Marseglia GL. Commentary: Basophil Activation-Dependent Autoantibody and Interleukin-17 Production Exacerbate Systemic Lupus Erythematosus. Front Immunol. 2017;8:787.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5500626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28736553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
