<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34338622</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-7732</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>116</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pathogens and global health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pathog Glob Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Presence of <i>Leptospira</i> spp. and absence of <i>Bartonella</i> spp. in urban rodents of Buenos Aires province, Argentina.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>185</StartPage>
          <EndPage>192</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>185-192</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/20477724.2021.1959793</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Big cities of Argentina are characterized by a strong social and economic fragmentation. This context enables the presence of urban rodents in close contact to the human population, mostly in the peripheral areas of the cities. Urban rodents can harbor a large variety of zoonotic pathogens. The aim of this study was to molecularly characterize <i>Leptospira</i> spp. and <i>Bartonella</i> spp. in urban rodents from the area of Gran La Plata, Buenos Aires province, Argentina. The species of urban rodents captured and tested were <i>Rattus norvegicus, Rattus rattus</i>, and <i>Mus musculus. Leptospira interrogans</i> and <i>L. borgpetersenii</i> were detected in <i>R. norvegicus</i> and <i>M. musculus</i> respectively. <i>Bartonella</i> spp. DNA was not detected in any of the kidney samples tested. No significant differences were observed between the prevalence of bacteria and rodent and environmental variables such as host sex, presence of stream and season by Generalized Linear Model analysis. These results confirm the role of urban rodents as infection sources of <i>Leptospira</i> spp., suggesting the need to implement public health measures to prevent the transmission of <i>Leptospira</i> spp. and other zoonotic pathogens from rodents to humans. <i>Bartonella</i> was not detected in this set of samples.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fitte</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bruno</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1060-7685</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centro de Estudios Parasitológicos y de Vectores, CEPAVE (CCT La Plata CONICET UNLP), La Plata, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kosoy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>KB One Health LLC, Fort Collins.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Pathog Glob Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101583421</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2047-7724</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001118" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Argentina</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001473" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bartonella</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007919" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leptospira</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012376" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rodent Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012377" MajorTopicYN="N">Rodentia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Argentina</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bartonella</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leptospira</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rodents</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urban ecology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">zoonotic diseases</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34338622</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090354</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20477724.2021.1959793</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grimmond SU.
Urbanization and global environmental change: local effects of urban warming. Geog J. 2007;173(1):83–88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosoy M, Bai Y.. 
Bartonella bacteria in urban rats: a movement from the jungles of Southeast Asia to metropoles around the globe. Front Ecol Evol. 2019;7:88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarlane R, Sleigh A, McMichael T. Synanthropy of wild mammals as a determinant of emerging infectious diseases in the Asian–Australasian region. EcoHealth. 2012;9(1):24–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7088064</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22526750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Battersby S, Hirschhorn RB, Amman BR. Commensal rodents. In: Bonnefoy X, Kampen H, Sweeney K, editors. Public health significance of urban pests. Copenhagen: World Health Organization; 2008. p. 387–419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abuauad A, Cecilia M, Osorio G, et al. Leptospirosis: presentación de una infección fulminante y revisión de la literatura. Rev Chil Infectol. 2005;22(1):93–97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meerburg BG, Singleton GR, Kijlstra A. Rodent-borne diseases and their risks for public health. Crit Rev Microbiol. 2009;35(3):221–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19548807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hancke D, Navone GT, Suárez OV. Endoparasite community of Rattus norvegicus captured in a shantytown of Buenos Aires City, Argentina. Helminthologia. 2011;48(3):167–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zonta M, Navone G, Y Oyhenart E. Intestinal parasites in preschool and school age children: current situation in urban, periurban and rural populations in Brandsen, Buenos Aires, Argentina. Parasitol Latinoam. 2007;62(1–2):54–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fitte B, Robles M, Dellarupe A, et al. Taenia taeniformis larvae (Strobilocercus fasciolaris) (Cestoda: cyclophyllidea) from commensal rodents in Argentina: potential sanitary risk. Mastozool Neotrop. 2017;24(1):227–233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hancke D, Suárez OV. Environmental health education in schools as strategy for rodent control: an experience in a shantytown of Buenos Aires, Argentina. EcoHealth. 2014;11(1):133–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24136385</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hancke D, Suárez OV. Helminth diversity in synanthropic rodents from an urban ecosystem. EcoHealth. 2017;14(3):603–613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28417211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Himsworth CG, Bidulka J, Parsons KL, et al. Ecology of Leptospira interrogans in Norway rats (Rattus norvegicus) in an inner-city neighborhood of Vancouver, Canada. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2013a;7(6):e2270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3688548</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23818996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jittapalapong S, Herbreteau V, Hugot JP, et al. Relationship of parasites and pathogens diversity to rodents in Thailand. Kasetsart J Nat Sci. 2009;43:106–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kataranovski M, Mirkov I, Belij S, et al. Intestinal helminths infection of rats (Ratus norvegicus) in the Belgrade area (Serbia): the effect of sex, age and habitat. Parasite. 2011;18(2):189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3671415</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21678796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otteson EW, Riolo J, Rowe JE, et al. Occurrence of hantavirus within the rodent population of northeasternCalifornia and Nevada. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 1996;54(2):127–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8619434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofmann J, Weiss S, Kuhns M, et al. Importation of human Seoul virus infection to Germany from Indonesia. Emerg Infect Dis. 2018;24(6):1099.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6004851</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29774860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bierque E, Thibeaux R, Girault D, et al. A systematic review of Leptospira in water and soil environments. PLoS One. 2020;15(1):e0227055.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6984726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boey K, Shiokawa K, Rajeev S. Leptospira infection in rats: a literature review of global prevalence and distribution. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2019;13(8):e0007499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6688788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31398190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulouis HJ, Chang CC, Henn JB, et al. Factors associated with the rapid emergence of zoonotic Bartonella infections. Vet Res. 2005;36(3):383–410.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15845231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown PD, Gravekamp C, Carrington DG, et al. Evaluation of the polymerase chain reaction for early diagnosis of leptospirosis. J Med Microbiol. 1995;43(2):110–114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7629850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caraballo-Blanco L, Arrieta-Bolaño P, Castellar-Martínez A, et al. Leptospira spp. patógenas en roedores del municipio de Sincelejo. Sucre; 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel BB, Boulouis HJ, Breitschwerdt EB. Cat scratch disease and other zoonotic Bartonella infections. J Am Vet Med Assoc. 2004;224(8):1270–1279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15112775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Himsworth CG, Parsons KL, Jardine C, et al. Rats, cities, people, and pathogens: a systematic review and narrative synthesis of literature regarding the ecology of rat-associated zoonoses in urban centers. Vector-borne Zoonotic Dis. 2013b;13(6):349–359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23590323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agudelo-Florez P, Londoño AF, Quiroz VH, et al. Prevalence of Leptospira spp. in urban rodents from a groceries trade center of Medellín. Colomb Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2009;81(5):906–910.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sacsaquispe R, Glenny M, Céspedes M. Estudio preliminar de leptospirosis en roedores y canes en salitral, Piura-1999. Rev Peru Med Exp Salud Pública. 2003;20(1):39–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent AT, Schiettekatte O, Goarant C, et al. Revisiting the taxonomy and evolution of pathogenicity of the genus Leptospira through the prism of genomics. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2019;13(5):e0007270. pntd.0007270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6532842</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31120895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daher EDF, Abreu KLSD, Silva Junior GBD. Leptospirosis-associated acute kidney injury. J Bras Nefrol. 2010;32(4):408–415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21541456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko AI, Goarant C, Picardeau M. Leptospira: the dawn of the molecular genetics era for an emerging zoonotic pathogen. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2009;7(10):736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3384523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19756012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musacchio HM, Dorigo C, Volpato V, et al. Características clínicas y epidemiológicas de leptospirosis: 10 años de experiencia en Santa Fe, Argentina. Rev Panam Infect. 2010;12(1):43–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres-Castro M, Cruz-Camargo B, Medina-Pinto R, et al. Detección molecular de leptospiras patógenas en roedores sinantrópicos y silvestres capturados en Yucatán, México. Biomédica. 2018;38(3):51–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yalin W, Lingbing Z, Hongliang Y, et al. High prevalence of pathogenic Leptospira in wild and domesticated animals in an endemic area of China. Asian Pac J Trop Med. 2011;4(11):841–845.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Billeter SA, Gundi VA, Rood MP, et al. Molecular detection and identification of Bartonella species in Xenopsylla cheopis fleas (Siphonaptera: pulicidae) collected from Rattus norvegicus rats in Los Angeles, California. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2001;77(21):7850–7852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt EB, Kordick DL. Bartonella infection in animals: carriership, reservoir potential, pathogenicity, and zoonotic potential for human infection. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2000;13(3):428–438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88941</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10885985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner DJ, O’Connor SP, Winkler HH, et al. Proposals to unify the genera Bartonella and Rochalimaea, with descriptions of Bartonella quintana comb. nov., Bartonella vinsonii comb. nov., Bartonella henselae comb. nov., and Bartonella elizabethae comb. nov., and to remove the family Bartonellaceae from the order Rickettsiales. Int J Syst Evol Microbiol. 1993;43(4):777–786.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz MH, Bai Y, Malania L, et al. Development of a Novel Genus-Specific Real-Time PCR assay for detection and differentiation of Bartonella species and genotypes. J Clin Microbiol. 2012;50(5):1645–1649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diniz PP, Maggi RG, Schwartz DS, et al. Canine bartonellosis: serological and molecular prevalence in Brazil and evidence of co-infection with Bartonella henselae and Bartonella vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii. Vet Res. 2007;38(5):697–710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17583666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasereddin A, Risheq A, Harrus S, et al. Bartonella species in fleas from Palestinian territories: prevalence and genetic diversity. J Vector Ecol. 2014;39(2):261–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25424254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanco JR, Raoult D. Enfermedades producidas por Bartonella spp. Enferm Infecc Microbiol Clín. 2005;23(5):313–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15899181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Mendonça Favacho AR, Andrade MN, de Oliveira RC, et al. Zoonotic Bartonella species in wild rodents in the state of Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil. Microbes Infect. 2015;17(11–12):889–892.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malania L, Bai Y, Osikowicz LM, et al. Prevalence and diversity of Bartonella species in rodents from Georgia (Caucasus). Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2016;95(2):466–471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4973202</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27162268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arango J, Cittadino E, Agostini A, et al. Prevalencia de leptospiras en Rattus rattus y Rattus norvegicus en el Gran Buenos Aires, Argentina. Ecología austral. 2001;11(1):25–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernández MS, Cueto G, Cavia R, et al. Prevalencia de Leptospira interrogans en Rattus norvegicus y Mus domesticus en un ambiente urbano marginal de la Ciudad de Buenos Aires, Argentina. Acta Bioquím Clín Latinoam. 2006;3:252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scialfa E, Bolpe J, Bardón JC, et al. Aislamiento de Leptospira interrogans de ratas suburbanas de Tandil, Buenos Aires, Argentina. Rev Arg Microbiol. 2010;42(2):126–128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanasco NB, Kemerer R, Oliva ME. Brote de leptospirosis rural en un tambo de la provincia de Entre Ríos, Argentina, febrero-marzo 2003. Salud (i) Cienc. 2004;12(4):26–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cacchione RA, Bulgini MJD, Cascelli ES, et al. Leptospirosis en animales silvestres. Estado actual de sus investigaciones, aislamientos y clasificación de cepas argentinas. Rev Fac Cienc Vet. 1967;20:37–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cacchione RA. Enfoques de los estudios de las leptospirosis humana y animal en América Latina. Rev Arg Microbiol. 1973;1:36–53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loffler SG, Pavan ME, Vanasco B, et al. Genotypes of pathogenic Leptospira spp isolated from rodents in Argentina. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz. 2014;109(2):163–167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4015264</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24676656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cicuttin GL, Brambati DF, De Gennaro MF, et al. Bartonella spp. in cats from Buenos Aires, Argentina. Vet Microbiol. 2014;168(1):225–228.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24247021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cicuttin GL, De Salvo MN, La Rosa I, et al. Neorickettsia risticii, Rickettsia sp. and Bartonella sp. in Tadarida brasiliensis bats from Buenos Aires, Argentina. Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis. 2017;52:1–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28673455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lareschi M, Venzal JM, Nava S, et al. The human flea Pulex irritans (Siphonaptera: pulicidae) in northwestern Argentina, with an investigation of Bartonella and Rickettsia spp. Rev Mex Biodivers. 2018;89(2).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Instituto Nacional de Estadísticas y Censos de la República Argentina, web . Resultados CENSO 2010. Argentina; 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stoddard RA. Detection of pathogenic Leptospira spp. through real-time PCR (qPCR) targeting the LipL32 gene. Methods Mol Biol. 2013;943(17):257–266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galloway RL, Hoffmaster AR. Optimization of LipL32 PCR assay for increased sensitivity in diagnosing leptospirosis. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2015;82(3):199–200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rózsa L, Reiczigel J, Majoros G. Quantifying parasites in samples of hosts. J Parasitol. 2000;86(2):228–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10780537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R Core Team . R: a language and environment for statistical computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna; 2013. ISBN 3-900051-07-0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evangelista KV, Coburn J. Leptospira as an emerging pathogen: a review of its biology, pathogenesis and host immune responses. Future Microbiol. 2010;5(9):1413–1425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3037011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20860485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez J, Brescia F, Becam J, et al. Rodent abundance dynamics and leptospirosis carriage in an area of hyper-endemicity in new caledonia. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2010;5(10):e1361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Faria MT, Calderwood MS, Athanazio DA, et al. Carriage of Leptospira interrogans among domestic rats from an urban setting highly endemic for leptospirosis in Brazil. Acta Trop. 2009;108(1):1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adler B, de la Peña Moctezuma A. Leptospira and leptospirosis. Vet Microbiol. 2010;140(3–4):287–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19345023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinoza-Martínez D, Sáancez-Montes DS, León-Paniagua L, et al. New wildlife hosts of Leptospira interrogans in Campeche, Mexico. Rev Inst Med Trop Sap Paulo. 2015;57(2):181–183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levett PN. Systematics of leptospiraceae. In: Leptospira and Leptospirosis. Current Topics in Microbiology and Immunology. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2015;387: 11–20. 10.1007/978-3-662-45059-8_2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-662-45059-8_2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blasdell KR, Morand S, Perera D, et al. Association of rodent-borne Leptospira spp. with urban environments in Malaysian Borneo. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2019;13(2):e0007141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6411199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romero-Vivas CM, Falconar AK. Leptospira spp. y leptospirosis humana. Salud. 2016;32(1):123–143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coto H. Biología y control de ratas sinantrópicas. Buenos Aires: Editorial Abierta; 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rim BM, Rim CW, Chang WH, et al. Leptospirosis serology in Korean wild animals. J Wildl Dis. 1993;29(4):602–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8258863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Da Silva ÉF, Félix SR, Cerqueira GM, et al. Preliminary characterization of mus musculus–derived pathogenic strains of leptospira borgpetersenii serogroup ballum in a Hamster model. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2010;83(2):336–337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2911180</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thornley CN, Baker MG, Weinstein P, et al. Changing epidemiology of human leptospirosis in New Zealand. Epidemiol Infect. 2002;128(1):29–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2869792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11895088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vieira ML, Gama-Simoes MJ, Collares-Pereira M. Human leptospirosis in Portugal: a retrospective study of eighteen years. Int J Infect Dis. 2006;10(5):378–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16600656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez A, Rodriguez Y, Batista N, et al. Immunogenicity and protective capacity of leptospiral whole-cell monovalent serogroup Ballum vaccines in hamsters. Rev Arg Microbiol. 2005;37(4):169–175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slack AT, Symonds ML, Dohnt MF, et al. The epidemiology of leptospirosis and the emergence of Leptospira borgpetersenii serovar Arborea in Queensland, Australia, 1998–2004. Epidemiol Infect. 2006;134(6):1217–1225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2870520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16690001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosoy M, Mckee C, Albayrak L, et al. Genotyping of Bartonella bacteria and their animal hosts: current status and perspectives. Parasitol. 2017;145(5):543–562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gundi VA, Kosoy MY, Myint KS, et al. Prevalence and genetic diversity of Bartonella species detected in different tissies of small mammals in Nepal. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2010;76(24):8247–8254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3008224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21037303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis BA, Regnery RL, Beati L, et al. Rats of the genus Rattus are reservoir hosts for pathogenic Bartonella species: an Old World origin for a New World disease?
J Infect Dis. 1999;180(1):220–224.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10353885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue K, Kabeya H, Shiratori H, et al. Bartonella japonica sp. nov. and Bartonella silvatica sp. nov., isolated from Apodemus mice. Int J Syst Evol Microbiol. 2010;60(4):759–763.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19656930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin-Alonso A, Houemenou G, Abreu-Yanes E, et al. Bartonella spp. in small mammals, Benin. Vector-Borne Zoonotic Dis. 2016;16(4):229–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26910412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa F, Porter FH, Rodrigues G, et al. Infections by Leptospira interrogans, Seoul virus, and Bartonella spp. among Norway rats (Rattus norvegicus) from the urban slum environment in Brazil. Vector-Borne Zoonotic. 2014;14(1):33–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
