<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34347860</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-6084</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>157</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>JAMA dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of Upadacitinib vs Dupilumab in Adults With Moderate-to-Severe Atopic Dermatitis: A Randomized Clinical Trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1047</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1055</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1047-1055</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.3023</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Atopic dermatitis (AD) is a chronic, recurrent, inflammatory skin disease with an unmet need for treatments that provide rapid and high levels of skin clearance and itch improvement.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the safety and efficacy of upadacitinib vs dupilumab in adults with moderate-to-severe AD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Heads Up was a 24-week, head-to-head, phase 3b, multicenter, randomized, double-blinded, double-dummy, active-controlled clinical trial comparing the safety and efficacy of upadacitinib with dupilumab among 692 adults with moderate-to-severe AD who were candidates for systemic therapy. The study was conducted from February 21, 2019, to December 9, 2020, at 129 centers located in 22 countries across Europe, North and South America, Oceania, and the Asia-Pacific region. Efficacy analyses were conducted in the intent-to-treat population.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients were randomized 1:1 and treated with oral upadacitinib, 30 mg once daily, or subcutaneous dupilumab, 300 mg every other week.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">The primary end point was achievement of 75% improvement in the Eczema Area and Severity Index (EASI75) at week 16. Secondary end points were percentage change from baseline in the Worst Pruritus Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) (weekly average), proportion of patients achieving EASI100 and EASI90 at week 16, percentage change from baseline in Worst Pruritus NRS at week 4, proportion of patients achieving EASI75 at week 2, percentage change from baseline in Worst Pruritus NRS (weekly average) at week 1, and Worst Pruritus NRS (weekly average) improvement of 4 points or more at week 16. End points at week 24 included EASI75, EASI90, EASI100, and improvement of 4 points or more in Worst Pruritus NRS from baseline (weekly average). Safety was assessed as treatment-emergent adverse events in all patients receiving 1 or more dose of either drug.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 924 patients screened, 348 (183 men [52.6%]; mean [SD] age, 36.6 [14.6] years) were randomized to receive upadacitinib and 344 were randomized to receive dupilumab (194 men [56.4%]; mean [SD] age, 36.9 [14.1] years); demographic and disease characteristics were balanced among treatment groups. At week 16, 247 patients receiving upadacitinib (71.0%) and 210 patients receiving dupilumab (61.1%) achieved EASI75 (P = .006). All ranked secondary end points also demonstrated the superiority of upadacitinib vs dupilumab, including improvement in Worst Pruritus NRS as early as week 1 (mean [SE], 31.4% [1.7%] vs 8.8% [1.8%]; P &lt; .001), achievement of EASI75 as early as week 2 (152 [43.7%] vs 60 [17.4%]; P &lt; .001), and achievement of EASI100 at week 16 (97 [27.9%] vs 26 [7.6%]; P &lt; .001). Rates of serious infection, eczema herpeticum, herpes zoster, and laboratory-related adverse events were higher for patients who received upadacitinib, whereas rates of conjunctivitis and injection-site reactions were higher for patients who received dupilumab.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">During 16 weeks of treatment, upadacitinib demonstrated superior efficacy vs dupilumab in patients with moderate-to-severe AD, with no new safety signals.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT03738397.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Blauvelt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrew</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oregon Medical Research Center, Portland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Teixeira</LastName>
            <ForeName>Henrique D</ForeName>
            <Initials>HD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Simpson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eric L</ForeName>
            <Initials>EL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Oregon Health &amp; Science University, Portland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Costanzo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Antonio</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Unit, Department of Biomedical Sciences, Humanitas University, Pieve Emanuele, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Humanitas Clinical and Research Center, Scientific Institute for Research, Hospitalization and Healthcare, Rozzano, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>De Bruin-Weller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marjolein</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergology, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barbarot</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sebastien</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Nantes Université, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nantes, Nantes, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prajapati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vimal H</ForeName>
            <Initials>VH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Community Pediatrics, Department of Pediatrics, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Rheumatology, Department of Pediatrics, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Skin Health &amp; Wellness Centre, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Research Institute, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Probity Medical Research, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Peter</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Dermatology Associates of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaofei</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tianshuang</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ladizinski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Barry</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alvina D</ForeName>
            <Initials>AD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eyerich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kilian</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Karolinska Institutet and Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergy, Technical University of Munich, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT03738397</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>JAMA Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101589530</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2168-6068</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D006575">Heterocyclic Compounds, 3-Ring</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>420K487FSG</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C582203">dupilumab</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>4RA0KN46E0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C000613732">upadacitinib</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn">
          <RefSource>JAMA Dermatol. 2022 Feb 1;158(2):219</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">34910077</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn">
          <RefSource>JAMA Dermatol. 2022 Feb 1;158(2):219</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">35171223</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatitis, Atopic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004485" MajorTopicYN="Y">Eczema</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006575" MajorTopicYN="N">Heterocyclic Compounds, 3-Ring</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Blauvelt reported receiving personal fees and reimbursement for performing clinical studies from AbbVie and Regeneron; and personal fees from Sanofi during the conduct of the study; and served as a scientific adviser and/or clinical study investigator for Abcentra, Aligos, Almirall, Amgen, Arcutis, Arena, ASLAN, Athenex, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Dermavant, Eli Lilly and Company, Evommune, Forte, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen, Landos, Leo, Novartis, Pfizer, Rapt, Sun Pharma, and UCB Pharma. Drs Teixeira, Hu, Wu, Liu, Ladizinski, and Chu are full-time employees of AbbVie Inc, and may hold AbbVie stock and/or stock options. Dr Simpson reported receiving grants from AbbVie, Amgen, Eli Lilly, Incyte, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Leo Pharmaceuticals, Merck, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron, Sanofi, Tioga, and Vanda; personal fees from AbbVie, Amgen, Arena, BenevolentAI Bio Limited, BiomX Ltd, Bluefin Biomedicine Inc, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Consulting Group, Collective Acumen LLC (CA), Coronado, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Evidera, ExcerptaMedica, Forte Bio RX, Incyte, Janssen, Kyowa Kirin Pharmaceutical Development, Leo Pharm, Medscape LLC, Novartis, Ortho Dermatologics, Pfizer, Pierre Fabre Dermo Cosmetique, Regeneron, Roivant, Sanofi Genzyme, SPARC India, and Valeant outside the submitted work. Dr Costanzo reported receiving grants from AbbVie during the conduct of the study; grants from Novartis and Galderma; and personal fees from Janssen, UCB, Lilly, and Sanofi outside the submitted work. Dr de Bruin-Weller reported receiving grants from and serving as a speaker, advisory board member, and consultant for AbbVie; serving as a speaker and consultant for Almirall; serving as an advisory board member for Arena; serving as an advisory board member for ASLAN; serving as a speaker and advisory board member for Galderma; serving as an advisory board member for Janssen; serving as a speaker, advisory board member, and consultant for Pfizer; grants from Eli Lilly, Leo Pharma, Regeneron, and Sanofi Genzyme outside the submitted work. Dr Barbarot reported receiving grants from Novartis; and personal fees from Sanofi, Leo Pharma, AbbVie, Janssen, Lilly, Pfizer, UCB, and Almirall during the conduct of the study. Dr Prajapati reported receiving personal fees from AbbVie, Actelion, Amgen, AnaptysBio, Aralez, Arcutis, Aspen, Bausch Health, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Cipher, Concert, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Galderma, GlaxoSmithKline, Homeocan, Incyte, Janssen, Leo Pharma, Medexus, Novartis, Pediapharm, Pfizer, Regeneron, Sanofi Genzyme, Sun Pharma, Tribute, UCB, and Valeant outside the submitted work. Dr Lio reported receiving grants from AOBiome, Regeneron/Sanofi Genzyme, and AbbVie; personal fees from Regeneron/Sanofi Genzyme, Leo, Eli Lilly, Pfizer, Galderma, L’Oreal, Almirall, ASLAN Pharma Advisory board, Dermavant, Pierre Fabre, Menlo Therapeutics, IntraDerm, Exeltis, AOBiome, Arbonne, and Amyris; stock options from Micreos and; other royalties from patented product from Theraplex; in addition, Dr Lio had a patent for Theraplex AIM moisturizer pending Theraplex company. Dr Chu reported receiving personal fees from AbbVie during the conduct of the study; and personal fees from AbbVie outside the submitted work. Dr Eyerich reported receiving grants and personal fees from AbbVie during the conduct of the study; personal fees from Almirall, BMS, Lilly, Leo, Janssen, Novartis, UCB, and Sanofi; and grants from Lilly, Leo, Janssen, Novartis, and UCB outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347860</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8340015</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.3023</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">2782803</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weidinger S, Beck LA, Bieber T, Kabashima K, Irvine AD. Atopic dermatitis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2018;4(1):1. doi:10.1038/s41572-018-0001-z
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-018-0001-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29930242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langan SM, Irvine AD, Weidinger S. Atopic dermatitis. Lancet. 2020;396(10247):345-360. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31286-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31286-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howell MD, Kuo FI, Smith PA. Targeting the Janus kinase family in autoimmune skin diseases. Front Immunol. 2019;10:2342. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2019.02342
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2019.02342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6794457</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31649667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He H, Guttman-Yassky E. JAK inhibitors for atopic dermatitis: an update. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2019;20(2):181-192. doi:10.1007/s40257-018-0413-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-018-0413-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30536048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Bieber T, Guttman-Yassky E, et al. ; SOLO 1 and SOLO 2 Investigators . Two phase 3 trials of dupilumab versus placebo in atopic dermatitis. N Engl J Med. 2016;375(24):2335-2348. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1610020
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1610020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27690741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parmentier JM, Voss J, Graff C, et al. . In vitro and in vivo characterization of the JAK1 selectivity of upadacitinib (ABT-494). BMC Rheumatol. 2018;2:23. doi:10.1186/s41927-018-0031-x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41927-018-0031-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390583</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30886973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guttman-Yassky E, Thaçi D, Pangan AL, et al. . Upadacitinib in adults with moderate to severe atopic dermatitis: 16-week results from a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2020;145(3):877-884. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2019.11.025
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2019.11.025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guttman-Yassky E, Teixeira HD, Simpson EL, et al. . Once-daily upadacitinib versus placebo in adolescents and adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (Measure Up 1 and Measure Up 2): results from two replicate double-blind, randomised controlled phase 3 trials. Lancet. 2021;397(10290):2151-2168. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00588-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00588-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reich K, Teixeira HD, de Bruin-Weller M, et al. . Safety and efficacy of upadacitinib in combination with topical corticosteroids in adolescents and adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (AD Up): results from a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;397(10290):2169-2181. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00589-4
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00589-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Medical Association . World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191-2194. doi:10.1001/jama.2013.281053</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.281053</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanifin JM, Rajka G. Diagnostic features of atopic dermatitis. Acta Dermatovener (Stockholm). 1980;60(92):44-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Lei D, Yousaf M, et al. . What are the best endpoints for Eczema Area and Severity Index and Scoring Atopic Dermatitis in clinical practice? a prospective observational study. Br J Dermatol. 2021;184(5):888-895. doi:10.1111/bjd.19457</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.19457</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32959390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt J, Csötönyi F, Bauer A, Meurer M. Determinants of treatment goals and satisfaction of patients with atopic eczema. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 2008;6(6):458-465. doi:10.1111/j.1610-0387.2007.06609.x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1610-0387.2007.06609.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18190558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Kantor RW, Dalal P, et al. . A comprehensive conceptual model of the experience of chronic itch in adults. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2018;19(5):759-769. doi:10.1007/s40257-018-0381-6
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-018-0381-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6161822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30155595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Augustin M, Langenbruch A, Blome C, et al. . Characterizing treatment-related patient needs in atopic eczema: insights for personalized goal orientation. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34(1):142-152. doi:10.1111/jdv.15919
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15919</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31465587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leung DY, Guttman-Yassky E. Deciphering the complexities of atopic dermatitis: shifting paradigms in treatment approaches. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2014;134(4):769-779. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2014.08.008
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2014.08.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4186710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25282559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Simpson EL, Thyssen JP, et al. . Efficacy and safety of abrocitinib in patients with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156(8):863-873. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.1406
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.1406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Sinclair R, Forman S, et al. . Efficacy and safety of abrocitinib in adults and adolescents with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (JADE MONO-1): a multicentre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2020;396(10246):255-266. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30732-7
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30732-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Lacour JP, Spelman L, et al. . Baricitinib in patients with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis and inadequate response to topical corticosteroids: results from two randomized monotherapy phase III trials. Br J Dermatol. 2020;183(2):242-255. doi:10.1111/bjd.18898
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.18898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31995838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eichenfield LF, Tom WL, Berger TG, et al. . Guidelines of care for the management of atopic dermatitis, section 2: management and treatment of atopic dermatitis with topical therapies. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2014;71(1):116-132. doi:10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.023
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4326095</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24813302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
