<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34344259</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-8069</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Season>Jan-Dec</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Molecular pain</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Mol Pain</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Spinally projecting noradrenergic neurons of the locus coeruleus display resistance to AAV2retro-mediated transduction.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>17448069211037887</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>17448069211037887</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17448069211037887</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17448069211037887</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The locus coeruleus (LC) is the principal source of noradrenaline (NA) in the central nervous system. Projection neurons in the ventral portion of the LC project to the spinal cord and are considered the main source of spinal NA. To understand the precise physiology of this pathway, it is important to have tools that allow specific genetic access to these descending projections. AAV2retro serotype vectors are a potential tool to transduce these neurons via their axon terminals in the spinal cord, and thereby limit the expression of genetic material to the spinal projections from the LC. Here, we assess the suitability of AAV2retro to target these neurons and investigate strategies to increase their labelling efficiency.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We show that the neurons in the LC that project to the spinal dorsal horn are largely resistant to transduction with AAV2retro serotype vectors. Compared to Cholera toxin B (CTb) tracing, AAV2retro.eGFP labelled far fewer neurons within the LC and surrounding regions, particularly within neurons that express tyrosine hydroxylase (TH), the rate-limiting enzyme for NA synthesis. We also show that the sensitivity for transduction of this projection can be increased using AAV2retro.eGFP.cre in ROSA26<sup>tdTom</sup> reporter mice (23% increase), with a higher proportion of the newly revealed neurons expressing TH compared to those directly labelled with AAV2retro containing an eGFP expression sequence.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">These tracing studies identify limitations in AAV2retro-mediated retrograde transduction of a subset of projection neurons, specifically those that express NA and project to the spinal cord. This is likely to have implications for the study of NA-containing projections as well as other types of projection neuron in the central nervous system.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ganley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert P</ForeName>
            <Initials>RP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8502-9870</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Pharmacology and Toxicology, University of Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Werder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kira</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Pharmacology and Toxicology, University of Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wildner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hendrik</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Pharmacology and Toxicology, University of Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zeilhofer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hanns Ulrich</ForeName>
            <Initials>HU</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6954-4629</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Pharmacology and Toxicology, University of Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Pharmaceutical Sciences, ETH Zürich, Zürich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neuroscience Center Zurich, Zürich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Mol Pain</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101242662</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1744-8069</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>X4W3ENH1CV</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D009638">Norepinephrine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059331" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adrenergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008125" MajorTopicYN="Y">Locus Coeruleus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009638" MajorTopicYN="N">Norepinephrine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017729" MajorTopicYN="N">Presynaptic Terminals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013116" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D066148" MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal Cord Dorsal Horn</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Spinal cord</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">locus coeruleus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">noradrenaline</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">projection neuron</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Declaration of conflicting interests:</b> The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>35</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34344259</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8351027</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17448069211037887</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khroud NK, Reddy V, Saadabadi A.
Neuroanatomy, locus ceruleus. 
Treasure Island, FL: 
StatPearls Publishing, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris LS, McCall JG, Charney DS, Murrough JW.
The role of the locus coeruleus in the generation of pathological anxiety. Brain Neurosci Adv
2020; 
4: 2398212820930321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7479871</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32954002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Floriou-Servou A, von Ziegler L, Waag R, Schläppi C, Germain PL, Bohacek J.
The acute stress response in the multiomic era. Biol Psychiatry Epub ahead of print 17 March 2021. DOI: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2020.12.031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33722387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zerbi V, Floriou-Servou A, Markicevic M, Vermeiren Y, Sturman O, Privitera M, von Ziegler L, Ferrari KD, Weber B, De Deyn PP, Wenderoth N, Bohacek J.
Rapid reconfiguration of the functional connectome after chemogenetic locus coeruleus activation. Neuron
2019; 
103: 702–718.e5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31227310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwarz LA, Miyamichi K, Gao XJ, Beier KT, Weissbourd B, DeLoach KE, Ren J, Ibanes S, Malenka RC, Kremer EJ, Luo L.
Viral-genetic tracing of the input-output organization of a central noradrenaline circuit. Nature
2015; 
524: 88–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4587569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borodovitsyna O, Duffy BC, Pickering AE, Chandler DJ.
Anatomically and functionally distinct locus coeruleus efferents mediate opposing effects on anxiety-like behavior. Neurobiol Stress
2020; 
13: 100284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7739179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howorth PW, Thornton SR, O'Brien V, Smith WD, Nikiforova N, Teschemacher AG, Pickering AE.
Retrograde viral vector-mediated inhibition of pontospinal noradrenergic neurons causes hyperalgesia in rats. J Neurosci
2009; 
29: 12855–12864.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bannister K, Patel R, Goncalves L, Townson L, Dickenson AH.
Diffuse noxious inhibitory controls and nerve injury: restoring an imbalance between descending monoamine inhibitions and facilitations. Pain
2015; 
156: 1803–1811.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirschberg S, Li Y, Randall A, Kremer EJ, Pickering AE.
Functional dichotomy in spinal- vs prefrontal-projecting locus coeruleus modules splits descending noradrenergic analgesia from ascending aversion and anxiety in rats. Elife
2017; 
6: 10–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5653237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29027903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor BK, Westlund KN.
The noradrenergic locus coeruleus as a chronic pain generator. J Neurosci Res
2017; 
95: 1336–1346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5374049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27685982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohro Y, Matsuda T, Yoshihara K, Kohno K, Koga K, Katsuragi R, Oka T, Tashima R, Muneta S, Yamane T, Okada S, Momokino K, Furusho A, Hamase K, Oti T, Sakamoto H, Hayashida K, Kobayashi R, Horii T, Hatada I, Tozaki-Saitoh H, Mikoshiba K, Taylor V, Inoue K, Tsuda M.
Spinal astrocytes in superficial laminae gate brainstem descending control of mechanosensory hypersensitivity. Nat Neurosci
2020; 
23: 1376–1387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33020652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tervo DGR, Hwang B-Y, Viswanathan S, Gaj T, Lavzin M, Ritola KD, Lindo S, Michael S, Kuleshova E, Ojala D, Huang C-C, Gerfen CR, Schiller J, Dudman JT, Hantman AW, Looger LL, Schaffer DV, Karpova AY.
A designer AAV variant permits efficient retrograde access to projection neurons. Neuron
2016; 
92: 372–382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5872824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27720486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haenraets K, Albisetti GW, Foster E, Wildner H.
Adeno-associated virus-mediated transgene expression in genetically defined neurons of the spinal cord. J Vis Exp
2018; 
135: 57382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6101182</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29806830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frezel N, Platonova E, Voigt FF, Mateos JM, Kastli R, Ziegler U, Karayannis T, Helmchen F, Wildner H, Zeilhofer HU.
In-depth characterization of layer 5 output neurons of the primary somatosensory cortex innervating the mouse dorsal spinal cord. Cerebral Cortex Commun
2020; 
1; tgaa052.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8152836</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34296117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Z, Maunze B, Wang Y, Tsoulfas P, Blackmore MG.
Global connectivity and function of descending spinal input revealed by 3D microscopy and retrograde transduction. J Neurosci
2018; 
38: 10566–10581.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6284107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30341180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito H, Sales AC, Fry CH, Kanai AJ, Drake MJ, Pickering AE.
Probabilistic, spinally-gated control of bladder pressure and autonomous micturition by barrington's nucleus CRH neurons. Elife
2020; 
9: 4–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7217699</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32347794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao J, Zhang Q, Liao X, Li Q, Liang S, Li X, Zhang Y, Li X, Wang H, Qin H, Wang M, Li J, Zhang J, He W, Zhang W, Li T, Xu F, Gong H, Jia H, Xu X, Yan J, Chen X.
A corticopontine circuit for initiation of urination. Nat Neurosci
2018; 
21: 1541–1550.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30361547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahman M, Siddik AB.
Neuroanatomy, pontine micturition center. 
Treasure Island, FL: 
StatPearls Publishing, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwiat GC, Basbaum AI.
The origin of brainstem noradrenergic and serotonergic projections to the spinal cord dorsal horn in the rat. Somatosens Mot Res
1992; 
9: 157–173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1354402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sluka KA, Westlund KN.
Spinal projections of the locus coeruleus and the nucleus subcoeruleus in the Harlan and the Sasco Sprague-Dawley rat. Brain Res
1992; 
579: 67–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1623408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koga K, Shiraishi Y, Yamagata R, Tozaki-Saitoh H, Shiratori-Hayashi M, Tsuda M.
Intrinsic braking role of descending locus coeruleus noradrenergic neurons in acute and chronic itch in mice. Mol Brain
2020; 
13: 144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590446</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33109226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawanabe R, Yoshihara K, Hatada I, Tsuda M.
Activation of spinal dorsal horn astrocytes by noxious stimuli involves descending noradrenergic signaling. Mol Brain
2021; 
14: 79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8108464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33971918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster E, Wildner H, Tudeau L, Haueter S, Ralvenius WT, Jegen M, Johannssen H, Hösli L, Haenraets K, Ghanem A, Conzelmann K-K, Bösl M, Zeilhofer HU.
Targeted ablation, silencing, and activation establish glycinergic dorsal horn neurons as key components of a spinal gate for pain and itch. Neuron
2015; 
85: 1289–1304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4372258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25789756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lemberger T, Parlato R, Dassesse D, Westphal M, Casanova E, Turiault M, Tronche F, Schiffmann SN, Schütz G.
Expression of Cre recombinase in dopaminoceptive neurons. BMC Neurosci
2007; 
8: 4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1770923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17201924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang D, Tawfik VL, Corder G, Low SA, François A, Basbaum AI, Scherrer G.
Functional divergence of delta and mu opioid receptor organization in CNS pain circuits. Neuron
2018; 
98: 90–108.e5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5896237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29576387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
