<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34352123</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2591</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International endodontic journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int Endod J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The impact of an enhanced infection control protocol on molar root canal treatment outcome - a randomized clinical trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1993</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2005</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1993-2005</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/iej.13605</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the effect of an enhanced infection control protocol on root canal treatment outcomes and on microbial load within root canals after chemomechanical preparation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 144 molar teeth from 139 healthy patients receiving primary root canal treatment were block randomized to a standard protocol (StP) or an enhanced infection control protocol (EnP). Both treatment arms adhered to current best practice recommendations, while the EnP comprised additional steps that included replacing rubber dams, gloves, files, all instruments and surface barriers at the time of canal filling to reduce the chances of iatrogenic contamination. Patients and radiographic examiners were blinded to the protocol used. Intracanal microbial samples were taken at baseline (S1) and after completion of chemomechanical preparation (S2). Microbial 16S rDNA copy numbers were enumerated by quantitative polymerase chain reaction (qPCR). Cone beam computed tomography (CBCT) scans were taken before treatment and at one-year follow-up. The outcome was assessed clinically and radiographically using CBCT by logistic regression modelling.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At one-year follow-up, 115 teeth were analysed (54 in StP and 61 in EnP). The percentage of favourable outcomes assessed by CBCT was 85.2% in the EnP and 66.7% in the StP. The odds of 12-month success was three times higher in the EnP group compared with the StP group (OR=2.89; p=0.022, CI: 1.17 - 7.15). The median bacterial reads were reduced from 8.1×10<sup>3</sup> in S1 samples to 3.5×10<sup>3</sup> in the StP group and from 8.6×10<sup>3</sup> to 1.3×10<sup>3</sup> in the EnP group. The enhanced protocol significantly reduced bacterial counts in pre-canal filling samples when compared to the standard protocol (p=0.009).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The implementation of a facile, enhanced infection control protocol in primary root canal treatment resulted in less detectable bacterial DNA before canal filling and significantly more successful outcomes at one year.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 International Endodontic Journal. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zahran</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shatha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5016-3690</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endodontics, Centre for Oral, Clinical and Translational Sciences, Faculty of Dentistry, Oral &amp; Craniofacial Sciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endodontics, Faculty of Dentistry, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Patel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shanon</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0614-6951</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endodontics, Centre for Oral, Clinical and Translational Sciences, Faculty of Dentistry, Oral &amp; Craniofacial Sciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Koller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Garrit</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endodontics, Centre for Oral, Clinical and Translational Sciences, Faculty of Dentistry, Oral &amp; Craniofacial Sciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Host Microbiome Interactions, Faculty of Dentistry, Oral &amp; Craniofacial Sciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>LCN - London Centre for Nanotechnology, Bloomsbury, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mannocci</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francesco</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0560-1054</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endodontics, Centre for Oral, Clinical and Translational Sciences, Faculty of Dentistry, Oral &amp; Craniofacial Sciences, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int Endod J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8004996</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0143-2885</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054893" MajorTopicYN="N">Cone-Beam Computed Tomography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003786" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dental Pulp Cavity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017053" MajorTopicYN="N">Infection Control</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008963" MajorTopicYN="N">Molar</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018915" MajorTopicYN="N">Root Canal Preparation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012390" MajorTopicYN="Y">Root Canal Therapy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cone beam computed tomography</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative polymerase chain reaction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized clinical trial</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">root canal treatment outcome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sterile protocol</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352123</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.13605</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Nuaimi, N., Patel, S., Davies, A., Bakhsh, A., Foschi, F. &amp; Mannocci, F. (2018) Pooled analysis of 1-year recall data from three root canal treatment outcome studies undertaken using cone beam computed tomography. International Endodontic Journal, 51, e216-e226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergenholtz, G., Hørsted-Bindslev, P. &amp; Reit, C. (2013) Textbook of Endodontology. New York: NY John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bornstein, M.M., Lauber, R., Sendi, P. &amp; von Arx, T. (2011) Comparison of periapical radiography and limited cone-beam computed tomography in mandibular molars for analysis of anatomical landmarks before apical surgery. Journal of Endodontics, 37, 151-157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brundin, M., Figdor, D., Roth, C., Davies, J.K., Sundqvist, G. &amp; Sjögren, U. (2010) Persistence of dead-cell bacterial DNA in ex vivo root canals and influence of nucleases on DNA decay in vitro. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology and Endodontics, 110, 789-794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bystrom, A., Happonen, R.-P., Sjogren, U. &amp; Sundqvist, G. (1987) Healing of periapical lesions of pulpless teeth after endodontic treatment with controlled asepsis. Dental Traumatology, 3, 58-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies, A., Patel, S., Foschi, F., Andiappan, M., Mitchell, P. J. &amp; Mannocci, F. (2016) The detection of periapical pathoses using digital periapical radiography and cone beam computed tomography in endodontically retreated teeth - part 2: a 1 year post-treatment follow-up. International Endodontic Journal, 49(7), 623-635. http://doi.org/10.1111/iej.12500.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Chevigny, C., Dao, T., Basrani, B., Marquis, V., Farzaneh, M., Abitbol S. et al. (2008) Treatment outcome in endodontics: The Toronto study-phase 4: initial treatment. Journal of Endodontics, 34(3), 258-263. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.joen.2007.10.017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Society of Endodontology (2006) Quality guidelines for endodontic treatment: consensus report of the European Society of Endodontology. International Endodontic Journal, 39, 921-930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedman, S., Abitbol, S. &amp; Lawrence, H.P. (2003) Treatment outcome in endodontics: the Toronto study. phase 1: initial treatment. Journal of Endodontics, 29, 787-793.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hargreaves, K.M., Berman, L.H. &amp; Cohen, S. (2016) Cohen's pathways of the pulp. St. Louis, MO: Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanagasingam, S., Lim, C.x., Yong, C.p., Mannocci, F. &amp; Patel, S. (2017) Diagnostic accuracy of periapical radiography and cone beam computed tomography in detecting apical periodontitis using histopathological findings as a reference standard. International Endodontic Journal, 50, 417-426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kvist, T., Molander, A., Dahlen, G. &amp; Reit, C. (2004) Microbiological evaluation of one- and two-visit endodontic treatment of teeth with apical periodontitis: a randomized, clinical trial. Journal of Endodontics, 30, 572-576.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, Y.-H., Li, G., Shemesh, H., Wesselink, P.R. &amp; Wu, M.-K. (2012) The association between complete absence of post-treatment periapical lesion and quality of root canal filling. Clinical Oral Investigations, 16, 1619-1626.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Low, K.M.T., Dula, K., Bürgin, W. &amp; von Arx, T. (2008) Comparison of periapical radiography and limited cone-beam tomography in posterior maxillary teeth referred for apical surgery. Journal of Endodontics, 34, 557-562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molander, A., Warfvinge, J., Reit, C. &amp; Kvist, T. (2007) Clinical and radiographic evaluation of one- and two-visit endodontic treatment of asymptomatic necrotic teeth with apical periodontitis: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of Endodontics, 33, 1145-1148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Möller, A. (1966) Microbiological examination of root canals and periapical tissues of human teeth. methodological studies. Odontologisk tidskrift, 74, 1-380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagendrababu, V., Duncan, H.F., Bjørndal, L., Kvist, T., Priya, E., Jayaraman, J. et al. (2020) PRIRATE 2020 guidelines for reporting randomized trials in Endodontics: a consensus-based development. International Endodontic Journal, 53, 764-773.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nardello, L.C.L., Vilela, B.G., Fernandes, F.S., Bruno, F.P., Carvalho, A.P.L., Cazares, R.X.R. et al. (2020) Analysis of active bacteria persisting after chemomechanical procedures: an RNA- and DNA-based molecular study. Journal of Endodontics, 46, 1570-1576.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng, Y.L., Mann, V., Rahbaran, S. et al. (2008) Outcome of primary root canal treatment: systematic review of the literature - Part 2. Influence of clinical factors. International Endodontic Journal, 41, 6-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niazi, S., Vincer, L. &amp; Mannocci, F. (2016) Glove contamination during endodontic treatment is one of the sources of nosocomial Endodontic Propionibacterium acnes infections. Journal of Endodontics, 42(8), 1202-1211. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.joen.2016.05.016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ørstavik, D. (1996) Time-course and risk analyses of the development and healing of chronic apical periodontitis in man. International Endodontic Journal, 29, 150-155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ørstavik, D. (2020). Essential endodontology: prevention and treatment of apical periodontitis, 3rd edition. Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel, S., Wilson, R., Dawood, A., Foschi, F. &amp; Mannocci, F. (2012) The detection of periapical pathosis using digital periapical radiography and cone beam computed tomography - part 2: a 1-year post-treatment follow-up. International Endodontic Journal, 45, 711-723.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paula-Silva, F.W.G.d., Wu, M.-K., Leonardo, M.R., Bezerra da Silva, L.A. &amp; Wesselink, P.R. (2009) Accuracy of periapical radiography and cone-beam computed tomography scans in diagnosing apical periodontitis using histopathological findings as a gold standard. Journal of Endodontics, 35, 1009-1012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rotstein, I. &amp; Ingle, J.I. (2019) Ingle's endodontics 7. Raleigh, NC: PMPH. Available from: http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;scope=site&amp;db=nlebk&amp;db=nlabk&amp;AN=2175853.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saeed, M., Koller, G., Niazi, S., Patel, S., Mannocci, F., Bruce, K. &amp; et al. (2017) Bacterial contamination of endodontic materials before and after clinical storage. Journal of Endodontics, 43, 1852-1856.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sathorn, C., Parashos, P. &amp; Messer, H.H. (2007) How useful is root canal culturing in predicting treatment outcome? Journal of Endodontics, 33, 220-225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira, J.F. (2008) On the issue of uncultivated bacteria and dead cell detection by molecular methods: Reply to Dr. Nair's commentary. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontology, 105, 5-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira, J.F. Jr, Alves, F.R. &amp; Rôças, I.N. (2011) Pyrosequencing analysis of the apical root canal microbiota. Journal of Endodontics, 37, 1499-1503.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira, J. &amp; Rôças, I. (2005) Exploiting molecular methods to explore endodontic infections: part 1-current molecular technologies for microbiological diagnosis. Journal of Endodontics, 31(6), 411-423. http://doi.org/10.1097/01.don.0000157989.44949.26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira, J.f., Silva, C.H.F.P., Cerqueira, M.D.D.O., Lopes, H.p. &amp; Uzeda, M. (1998) Effectiveness of four chemical solutions in eliminating Bacillus subtilis spores on gutta-percha cones. Endodontics and Dental Traumatology, 14, 124-126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sjögren, U., Figdor, D., Persson, S. &amp; Sundqvist, G. (1997) Influence of infection at the time of root filling on the outcome of endodontic treatment of teeth with apical periodontitis. International Endodontic Journal, 30, 297-306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sjögren, U., Hägglund, B., Sundqvist, G. &amp; Wing, K. (1990) Factors affecting the long-term results of endodontic treatment. Journal of Endodontics, 16, 498-504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams, H.N., Singh, R. &amp; Romberg, E. (2003) Surface contamination in the dental operatory: a comparison over two decades. Journal of American Dental Association, 134, 325-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi, J., Li, H., Li, Y.u., Li, X., Zheng, W. &amp; Zhao, Z. (2020) Risk of Bias and Its Impact on Intervention Effect Estimates of Randomized Controlled Trials in Endodontics. Journal of Endodontics, 46, 12-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zahran, S., Witherden, E., Mannocci, F. &amp; Koller, G. (2021) Characterization of Root Canal Microbiota in Teeth Diagnosed with Irreversible Pulpitis. Journal of Endodontics, 47, 415-423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zandi, H., Petronijevic, N., Mdala, I. et al. (2019) Outcome of Endodontic Retreatment Using 2 Root Canal Irrigants and Influence of Infection on Healing as Determined by a Molecular Method: A Randomized Clinical Trial. Journal of Endodontics, 45, 1089-98.e5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, M.M., Liang, Y.H., Gao, X.J. et al. (2015) Management of apical periodontitis: healing of post-treatment periapical lesions present 1 year after endodontic treatment. Journal of Endodontics, 41, 1020-1025.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
