<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34365675</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2125</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>88</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>British journal of clinical pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Br J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Edoxaban in cardiovascular disease management: Review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>535</StartPage>
          <EndPage>540</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>535-540</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bcp.15026</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>In the past decade, direct oral anticoagulants (DOACs) have transformed the world of anti-thrombotic therapy. Edoxaban is the most recently approved DOAC. Though intended for use primarily in stroke prevention, it has found applications in various other conditions including thromboembolic and peripheral arterial disease. This review aims to provide a detailed outline of the growing indications, evidence for use in special populations, pharmacogenetics and side-effect profile of edoxaban.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Srinivasan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sharanyah</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8230-2330</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ajmal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2463-3035</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, Sarver Heart Center, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pecci</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cristina</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, University of Arizona, Phoenix, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lassar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tom</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, Sarver Heart Center, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Br J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7503323</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0306-5251</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011725">Pyridines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013844">Thiazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>NDU3J18APO</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C552171">edoxaban</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001281" MajorTopicYN="Y">Atrial Fibrillation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011725" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyridines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013844" MajorTopicYN="N">Thiazoles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">DOACs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">DVT/PE</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">anticoagulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">atrial fibrillation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">bleeding</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">edoxaban</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">thrombosis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>6</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34365675</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15026</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stacy ZA, Call WB, Hartmann AP, Peters GL, Richter SK. Edoxaban: a comprehensive review of the pharmacology and clinical data for the management of atrial fibrillation and venous thromboembolism. Cardiol Therapy. 2016;5(1):1-18. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40119-016-0058-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reiffel JA. Atrial fibrillation and stroke: epidemiology. Am J Med. 2014;127(4):15-e16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2013.06.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, Braunwald E, et al. Edoxaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. New Engl J Med. 2013;369(22):2093-2104. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1310907</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilain K, Li H, Kwong WJ, et al. Cardiovascular- and bleeding-related hospitalization rates with edoxaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation based on results of the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2020;13(11):843-852. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.120.006511</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goette A, Merino JL, Ezekowitz MD, et al. Edoxaban versus enoxaparin-warfarin in patients undergoing cardioversion of atrial fibrillation (ENSURE-AF): a randomised, open-label, phase 3b trial. Lancet. 2016;388(10055):1995-2003. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31474-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hohnloser SH, Camm J, Cappato R, et al. Uninterrupted edoxaban vs. vitamin K antagonists for ablation of atrial fibrillation: the ELIMINATE-AF trial. Eur Heart J. 2019;40(36):3013-3021. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehz190</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S-R, Choi EK, Han KD, Jung JH, Oh S, Lip GYH. Comparison of once-daily administration of edoxaban and rivaroxaban in Asian patients with atrial fibrillation. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):6690-6699. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-43224-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marston XL, Wang R, Yeh YC, et al. Comparison of clinical outcomes with edoxaban versus apixaban, dabigatran, rivaroxaban, and vitamin K antagonist in patients with atrial fibrillation in Germany: a real-world cohort study. Eur Heart J. 2020;41(Supplement_2):ehaa946.0401. https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjci/ehaa946.0401</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kralev S, Schneider K, Lang S, Süselbeck T, Borggrefe M. Incidence and severity of coronary artery disease in patients with atrial fibrillation undergoing first-time coronary angiography. PLoS ONE. 2011;6(9):e24964. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0024964</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopes RD, Heizer G, Aronson R, et al. Antithrombotic therapy after acute coronary syndrome or PCI in atrial fibrillation. New Engl J Med. 2019;380(16):1509-1524. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1817083</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson CM, Mehran R, Bode C, et al. Prevention of bleeding in patients with atrial fibrillation undergoing PCI. New Engl J Med. 2016;375(25):2423-2434. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1611594</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vranckx P, Valgimigli M, Eckardt L, et al. Edoxaban-based versus vitamin K antagonist-based antithrombotic regimen after successful coronary stenting in patients with atrial fibrillation (ENTRUST-AF PCI): a randomised, open-label, phase 3b trial. Lancet. 2019;394(10206):1335-1343. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31872-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tarantini G, Mojoli M, Urena M, Vahanian A. Atrial fibrillation in patients undergoing transcatheter aortic valve implantation: epidemiology, timing, predictors, and outcome. Eur Heart J. 2016;38(17):ehw456. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehw456</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angiolillo DJ, Pineda AM. Oral anticoagulation after TAVR in patients with atrial fibrillation: the certainty of uncertainty. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2019;12(16):1577-1579. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcin.2019.04.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishimura RA, Otto CM, Bonow RO, et al. 2014 AHA/ACC Guideline for the Management of Patients with Valvular Heart Disease: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. Circulation. 2014;129(23):2440-2492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dangas GD, Tijssen JGP, Wöhrle J, et al. A controlled trial of rivaroxaban after transcatheter aortic-valve replacement. New Engl J Med. 2020;382(2):120-129. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1911425</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Memtsoudis SG, Pumberger M, Ma Y, et al. Epidemiology and risk factors for perioperative mortality after total hip and knee arthroplasty. J Orthop Res. 2012;30(11):1811-1821. https://doi.org/10.1002/jor.22139</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eriksson BI, Borris LC, Friedman RJ, et al. Rivaroxaban versus enoxaparin for thromboprophylaxis after hip arthroplasty. New Engl J Med. 2009;358(26):2765-2775. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMOA0800374</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The RE-MOBILIZE Writing Committee. Oral thrombin inhibitor dabigatran etexilate vs North American enoxaparin regimen for prevention of venous thromboembolism after knee arthroplasty surgery. J Arthroplasty. 2009;24(1):1-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.ARTH.2008.01.132</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuji T, Wang CJ, Fujita S, et al. Safety and efficacy of edoxaban, an oral factor Xa inhibitor, versus enoxaparin for thromboprophylaxis after total knee arthroplasty: the STARS E-3 trial. Thromb Res. 2014;134(6):1198-1204. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.thromres.2014.09.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuji T, Fujita S, Kawai Y, et al. Efficacy and safety of edoxaban versus enoxaparin for the prevention of venous thromboembolism following total hip arthroplasty: STARS J-V. Thromb J. 2015;13(1):27-35. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12959-015-0057-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raskob G, Cohen A, Eriksson B, et al. Oral direct factor Xa inhibition with edoxaban for thromboprophylaxis after elective total hip replacement: a randomised double-blind dose-response study. Thromb Haemost. 2010;104(3):642-649. https://doi.org/10.1160/TH10-02-0142</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hokusai-VTE Investigators, Büller HR, Décousus H, Grosso MA, et al. Edoxaban versus warfarin for the treatment of symptomatic venous thromboembolism. New Engl J Med. 2013;369(15):1406-1415. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1306638</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Akl EA, Ornelas J, et al. Antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2016;149(2):315-352. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chest.2015.11.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen AT, Hamilton M, Mitchell SA, et al. Comparison of the novel oral anticoagulants apixaban, dabigatran, edoxaban, and rivaroxaban in the initial and long-term treatment and prevention of venous thromboembolism: systematic review and network meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2015;10(12):e0144856. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0144856</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prandoni P, Lensing AWA, Piccioli A, et al. Recurrent venous thromboembolism and bleeding complications during anticoagulant treatment in patients with cancer and venous thrombosis. Blood. 2002;100(10):3484-3488. https://doi.org/10.1182/blood-2002-01-0108</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Samkari H, Connors JM. The role of direct oral anticoagulants in treatment of cancer-associated thrombosis. Cancer. 2018;10(8):271-281. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers10080271</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young AM, Marshall A, Thirlwall J, et al. Comparison of an oral factor Xa inhibitor with low molecular weight heparin in patients with cancer with venous thromboembolism: results of a randomized trial (SELECT-D). J Clin Oncol. 2018;36(20):2017-2023. https://doi.org/10.1200/JCO.2018.78.8034</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McBane R, Wysokinski WE, Le-Rademacher JG, et al. Apixaban and dalteparin in active malignancy-associated venous thromboembolism: the ADAM VTE trial. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18(2):411-421. https://doi.org/10.1111/jth.14662</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raskob GE, van Es N, Verhamme P, et al. Edoxaban for the treatment of cancer-aassociated venous thromboembolism. New Engl J Med. 2018;378(7):615-624. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1711948</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kraaijpoel N, di Nisio M, Mulder F, et al. Clinical impact of bleeding in cancer-associated venous thromboembolism: results from the Hokusai VTE Cancer study. Thromb Haemost. 2018;118(8):1439-1449. https://doi.org/10.1055/s-0038-1667001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song AB, Rosovsky RP, Connors JM, al-Samkari H. Direct oral anticoagulants for treatment and prevention of venous thromboembolism in cancer patients. Vasc Health Risk Manag. 2019;15:175-186. https://doi.org/10.2147/VHRM.S132556</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liistro F, Grotti S, Porto I, et al. Drug-eluting balloon in peripheral intervention for the superficial femoral artery: the DEBATE-SFA randomized trial (Drug Eluting Balloon in Peripheral Intervention for the Superficial Femoral Artery). JACC: Cardiovasc Intervent. 2013;6(12):1295-1302. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcin.2013.07.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tepe G, Zeller T, Albrecht T, et al. Local delivery of paclitaxel to inhibit restenosis during angioplasty of the leg. New Engl J Med. 2008;358(7):689-699. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMOA0706356</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eikelboom JW, Connolly SJ, Bosch J, et al. Rivaroxaban with or without aspirin in stable cardiovascular disease. New Engl J Med. 2017;377(14):1319-1330. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMOA1709118</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moll F, Baumgartner I, Jaff M, et al. Edoxaban plus aspirin vs dual antiplatelet therapy in endovascular treatment of patients with peripheral artery disease: results of the ePAD trial. J Endovasc Ther. 2018;25(2):158-168. https://doi.org/10.1177/1526602818760488</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson J, Gong L, Whirl-Carrillo M, et al. Clinical Pharmacogenetics Implementation Consortium Guidelines for CYP2C9 and VKORC1 genotypes and warfarin dosing. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2011;90(4):625-629. https://doi.org/10.1038/CLPT.2011.185</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mega JL, Walker JR, Ruff CT, et al. Genetics and the clinical response to warfarin and edoxaban: findings from the randomised, double-blind ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Lancet. 2015;385(9984):2280-2287. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(14)61994-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogata K, Mendell-Harary J, Tachibana M, et al. Clinical safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and pharmacodynamics of the novel factor Xa inhibitor edoxaban in healthy volunteers. J Clin Pharmacol. 2010;50(7):743-753. https://doi.org/10.1177/0091270009351883</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>January CT, Wann LS, Alpert JS, et al. 2014 AHA/ACC/HRS Guideline for the Management of Patients with Atrial Fibrillation: executive summary. Circulation. 2014;130(23):2071-2104. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIR.0000000000000040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohula EA, Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, et al. Impact of renal function on outcomes with edoxaban in the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Circulation. 2016;134(1):24-36. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.116.022361</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel MR, Mahaffey KW, Garg J, et al. Rivaroxaban versus warfarin in nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. New Engl J Med. 2011;365(10):883-891. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1009638</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granger CB, Alexander JH, McMurray JJV, et al. Apixaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. New Engl J Med. 2011;365(11):981-992. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa1107039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. Drug trials snapshot: Savaysa (edoxaban) for prevention of stroke in atrial fibrillation. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-approvals-and-databases/drug-trials-snapshot-savaysa-edoxaban-prevention-stroke-atrial-fibrillation. Accessed August 18, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qamar A, Antman EM, Ruff CT, et al. Edoxaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation and history of liver disease. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;74(2):179-189. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2019.04.061</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato ET, Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, et al. Efficacy and safety of edoxaban in elderly patients with atrial fibrillation in the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5(5):e003432. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.116.003432</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okumura K, Akao M, Yoshida T, et al. Low-dose edoxaban in very elderly patients with atrial fibrillation. New Engl J Med. 2020;383(18):1735-1745. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa2012883</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eikelboom J, Merli G. Bleeding with direct oral anticoagulants vs warfarin: clinical experience. Am J Med. 2016;129(11):S33-S40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.06.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connolly SJ, Ezekowitz MD, Yusuf S, et al. Dabigatran versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. New Engl J Med. 2009;361(12):1139-1151. https://doi.org/10.1056/nejmoa0905561</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corsini A, Ferri N, Proietti M, Boriani G. Edoxaban and the issue of drug-drug interactions: from pharmacology to clinical practice. Drugs. 2020;80(11):1065-1083. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40265-020-01328-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aller SG, Yu J, Ward A, et al. Structure of P-glycoprotein reveals a molecular basis for poly-specific drug binding. Science. 2009;323(5922):1718-1722. https://doi.org/10.1126/SCIENCE.1168750</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendell J, Zahir H, Matsushima N, et al. Drug-drug interaction studies of cardiovascular drugs involving P-glycoprotein, an efflux transporter, on the pharmacokinetics of edoxaban, an oral factor Xa inhibitor. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2013;13(5):331-342. https://doi.org/10.1007/S40256-013-0029-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Groot JR, Weiss TW, Kelly P, et al. Edoxaban for stroke prevention in atrial fibrillation in routine clinical care: 1-year follow-up of the prospective observational ETNA-AF-Europe study. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Pharmacother. 2021;7(FI1):f30-f39. https://doi.org/10.1093/EHJCVP/PVAA079</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
