<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34383219</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-4230</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>21</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cerebellum (London, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cerebellum</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Theories of Gerbrandus Jelgersma (1859-1942) on the Function of the Cerebellum.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>432</StartPage>
          <EndPage>439</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>432-439</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12311-021-01273-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Gerbrandus Jelgersma published extensively on the (pathological) anatomy of the cerebellum between 1886 and 1934. Based on his observations on the double innervation of the Purkinje cells, he formulated a hypothesis on the function of the cerebellum. Both afferent systems of the cerebellum, the mossy fiber-parallel fiber system and the climbing fibers terminate on the Purkinje cell dendrites. According to Jelgersma, the mossy fiber-parallel fiber system is derived from the pontine nuclei and the inferior olive, and would transmit the movement images derived from the cerebral cortex. Spinocerebellar climbing fibers would transmit information about the execution of the movement. When the Purkinje cell compares these inputs and notices a difference between instruction and execution, it sends a correction through the descending limb of the superior cerebellar peduncle to the anterior horn cells. Jelgersma postulates that this cerebro-cerebellar coordination system shares plasticity with other nervous connections because nerve cell dendritic protrusions possess what he called amoeboid mobility: dendritic protrusions can be extended or retracted and are so able to create new connections or to abolish them. Jelgersma's theories are discussed against the background of more recent theories of cerebellar function that, similarly, are based on the double innervation of the Purkinje cells. The amoeboid hypothesis is traced to its roots in the late nineteenth century.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Voogd</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4884-606X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department Neuroscience, Erasmus MC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands. janvoogd@bart.nl.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cerebellum</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101089443</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1473-4222</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002525" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebellar Cortex</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002531" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebellum</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009847" MajorTopicYN="N">Olivary Nucleus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011689" MajorTopicYN="Y">Purkinje Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebellum: anatomy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Golgi Cox method</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Leiden University</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Marr and Albus cerebellar theory</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons: amoeboid movements</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purkinje cell: double innervations</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34383219</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9106615</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12311-021-01273-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12311-021-01273-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carp EADE.  Jelgersma, Leven en werken van een verdienstelijk Nederlander. Lochem: De Tijdscroom; 1942. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Das Kleinhirn in anatomischer, physiologischer und pathologischer Hinsicht. J Psychol U Neurol. 1932;44:505–612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marani E, Roeling TAP, Velders GA, Lakke EAJE. The Jelgersma collection. Prog Neurosci Neuroreg. 1987;1:3–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eling P. Jelgersma, 1859-1942. In: Frederiks JAM, Bruyn G, Eling P, editors. History of neurology in the Netherlands. Amsterdam: Boom; 2002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox WH. De histologie van het cerebellum. Psych Bladen. 1890;8:197–204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox WH. De kennis van het zenuwstelsel na Golgi. Ned Tijdschrift voor Geneeskunde. 1893;29:1135–1144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox WH. Imprägnation des centralen Nervensystems mit Quecksalten. Arch Wiss Mikroskopie. 1891;2:16–21. doi: 10.1007/BF02954290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02954290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. (Over de verhouding van de olijf en de nuclei arciformis tot de pedunculusbaan. Ned Tijdschrift voor Geneeskunde. 1886;23(2):1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. De morphologie en morphogenese van den hersenstam. Ned Tijdschrift voor Geneeskunde. 1887;23:380–399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgrsma G. Over de bouw der zoogdierhersenen. Ned Tijdschrift voor geneeskunde. 1888;24(2):389–399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. 15:61 Ueber den Bau des Säugethiergehirns. Morphol Jahrbuch. 1888;15:61–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. De grote en de kleine hersenen bij zoogdieren en vogels in verband met hun algemene hersenbouw. Handelingen van het 2e Ned. Natuur- en Geneeskundig Congres Leiden; 1889, pp. 121–125</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Over de functiën der kleine hersenen. Psych Bladen. 1890;8:250–262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bechterew W. Über eine bisher unbekannte Verbindung der grossen Oliven mit den Grosshirn. Neurol Centralbl. 1885;4:194–196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stilling B. Untersuchungenüber den Bau und die Verrichtungen des Gehirns. I. Über den Bau des Hirnknotens oder der Varolischen Brücke. Jena, Deuck und Verlag von Friedrich Make; 1846.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flechsig P.  Die Leitungsbahnen im Gehirn und Rückenmark des Menschen auf Grund entwicklungsgeschichtlicher Untersuchungen dargestellt. Leipzig: Wilhelm Engelmann; 1876. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bechterew W.  Die Leitungsbahnen im Gehirn und Rückenmark. Leipzig: Verlag Georgi; 1899. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forel A. Untersuchungen über die Haubenregio und ihre obere Verknüpfungen im Gehirn des Menschen und einiger Säugethiere mit Beiträgen zu den Methoden der Gehirnuntersuchung. Arch f Psychiat. 1877;7:392–495. doi: 10.1007/BF02041873.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02041873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. De kleine hersenen. Physiologie en anatomie. Ned Tijdschrift voor geneeskunde. 1893;29:621–633.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G.  De physiologischebeteekenis van het cerebellum. Amsterdam: Scheltema &amp; Holkema; 1904. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Zur Theorie der zerebellaren Koordination. J Psychol und Neurol. 1918;24:53–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. De functie der kleinehersenen. Psychiat Neurol Bladen. 1915;19:214–249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G.  De kleine hersenen Anatomisch, Physiologisch, en Pathologisch beschouwd. Amsterdam: Scheltema and Holkema; 1920. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Weitere Beitrag zur Funktion des Kleinhirns. J Psychol Und Neurol. 1920;35:12–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reitsma JM. De indirecte atrophie der kleine hersenen. Psychiat Neurol Bladen. 1904;8:347–366.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verhaart WJC, Sie PG. The fasciculus cntralis tegmenti and the reticular formation fibre systems. Acata Anat. 1958;33:257–272. doi: 10.1159/000141362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000141362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voogd J, Ruigrok TJH. Cerebellum and precerebellar nuclei. In: Mai JK, Paxinos G, editors. The human nervous system. Elsevier, Amsterdam; 2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cajal SR y. Histologie du système nerveux de l’homme et des vertebrés. Paris: Maloine; 1909–1911.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Drei Fälle von Cerebellar-Atrphie bei der Katze; nebst Bemerkungen über das cerebro-cerebellare Verbindungssytem. J Psychol Und Neurol. 1918;23:105–134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tokuriki M, Takeuchi A, Sawazaki H. Ideapathic neurological diseases in dogs and cats in Japan from the virewpoint of animal models of human disease. Exp Anim. 1981;30:233–240. doi: 10.1538/expanim1978.30.3_233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1538/expanim1978.30.3_233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verlinde JD. Congenital cerebellar ataxia in cats in conjunction with a probable viral infection of the mother during pregnancy. Tijdschr Diergeneeskunde. 1949;74:659–681.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Over schakelingen. Bijdrage tot de kennis van het cerebro-cerebellaire coördinatie systeem. Ned Tijdshrift voor Geneeskunde. 1928;4:6272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelgersma G. Het cerebellum. Psych Neurol Bladen. 1934;38:828–846.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cajal SRy. Sobra las fibras nerviosas de la capa molecular delcerebelo. Rev Trim Histol Norm Patol. 1888;1:33–49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sherrington CS. in Foster RJ.. M. Textbook of physiology. London: Macmilan; 1897.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duval M. Hypothèse sur la physiologie des centres nerveux , théorie histologique du sommeil. C.R. Soc. De Biol. February 2; 1895, pp. 74–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabl-Rückhard Sind Ganglienzelle amöboid? Eine hypothese zur Mechanik psychicher Vorgänge. Neurol Centralblatt. 1890;9:199–200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marr D. A theory of the cerebellar cortex. J Physiol. 1969;202:437–470. doi: 10.1113/jphysiol.1969.sp008820.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/jphysiol.1969.sp008820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1351491</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5784296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albus JA. A theory of cerebellar function. Math Biosci. 1971;10:25–60. doi: 10.1016/0025-5564(71)90051-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0025-5564(71)90051-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desclin JC. Histological evidence supporting the inferior olive as the major source of cerebellar climbing fibers in the rat. Brain Res. 1974;77:365–381. doi: 10.1016/0006-8993(74)90628-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-8993(74)90628-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4136782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eccles JC, Ito M, Szenta´gothai J.  The cerebellum as a neuronal machine. Berlin: Springer; 1967. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voogd J. Deiters’nucleus: its role in cerebellar ideogenesis. Cerebellum. 2016;15:54–66. doi: 10.1007/s12311-015-0681-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12311-015-0681-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4726724</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26054378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito M. Neurophysiological aspects of the cerebellar motor control system. Int J Neurol. 1970;7:162–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5499516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Zeeuw CI. Bidirectional learning in upbound and downbound microzones of the cerebellum. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2021;22:92–110. doi: 10.1038/s41583-020-00392-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41583-020-00392-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33203932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soededjo R, Kojima Y, Fuchs AF. How cerebellar motor learning keeps saccades accurate. J Neurophysiol. 2019;12:2153–2162. doi: 10.1152/jn.00781.2018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/jn.00781.2018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeo C, Hesslow G. Cerebellum and conditioned reflexes. TINS. 1998;2:322–330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glickstein M, Strata P, Voogd J. Cerebellum: history. Neuroscience. 2009;162:549–559. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroscience.2009.02.054.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroscience.2009.02.054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19272426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voogd J, Koehler PJ. Historic notes on anatomic, physiologic and clinical research on the cerebellum. In: Manto M, Huisman TAGM,editors. Handbook of clinical neurology . Vol. 154 (Ed Series) The cerebelum from embryology to diagnostic investigations; 2018, pp. 4–26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Felipe J. Brain plasticity and mental processes: Cajal again. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2006;7:811–817. doi: 10.1038/nrn2005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn2005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16988656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Binet A. Revue générale sur l’amoeboisme du système nerveux. L’Année psychologique. 1897;4:438–449.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Black SE. “Pseudopods and synapses”: the amoeboid theories of neuronal mobility and the early formulation of the synapse concept, 1894–1900. Bull Hist Med. 1981;55:34–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7011452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lépine JR. Théorie mécanique de paralysie hystérique, du somnabulisme, du sommeil naturel et de la distraction. C.R.Soc. de biol. 9 Février; 1895, 85–86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demoor J. La plasticité morphologique des neurones cérébreux. Trav de l’Institut Solvay. 1897;1:1–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefanowska M. Les appendices terminaux des dendrites cérébraux et leur différents états physiologiques. Trav De Lab de l‘Institut Solvay. 1897;3:1–57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bawden HH. A digest and a criticism of the data upon which is based the theory of the amoeboid movements of the neurone. J Comp Neurol. 1900;10:243–269. doi: 10.1002/cne.910100208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.910100208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González Burgos I. Dendritic spines, plastity and learning, memory processes: theory, evidence and perspectives. Chapter X. In: Baylog R (ed) Dendritic spines: biochemistry, modeling and properties. New York: Nova Biochemical, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boele H-J, Koekkoek SKJ, De Zeeuw CI, Ruigrok TJH. Axonal sprouting and formation of terminals in the adult cerebellum during associative motor learning. J Neurosci. 2013;33:17897–17907. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0511-13.2013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0511-13.2013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6618426</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24198378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
