<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34407041</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5741</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Anti-cancer drugs</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Anticancer Drugs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Risk-tailored treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e36</StartPage>
          <EndPage>e42</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e36-e42</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CAD.0000000000001165</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Splenic marginal zone lymphoma (SMZL) is a rare lymphoproliferative disease involving B-cells and affecting elderly patients. SMZL plague peripheral blood and bone marrow, spleen. Lymph nodes are generally spared. SMZL is due to a protracted antigen stimulation of B lymphocytes and of microenvironment leading B-cell to polyclonal and then oligoclonal/monoclonal growth, promoting lymphoproliferation. Integration of the NOTCH2 and NFk-B signaling has been recently identified as the primary mechanism of neoplastic proliferation in SMZL. In total 20% of cases carry mutations in NOTCH2. Although SMZL has an indolent course, progression to diffuse large B-cell lymphoma occurs in about 10-15% of patients. Establishing the prognosis is a key step in disease management, depending on both individual risk and patients' health status. This review discusses tailored treatment of SMZL patients. Progression risk factors include nodal and extra-nodal involvement, peripheral lymphocytosis, anemia and thrombocytopenia. Patients with two or more score points have a median survival of &lt;5 years. Watch and wait strategy is appropriate in low-risk and asymptomatic patients, whereas treatment of symptomatic patients ranges from splenectomy to rituximab monotherapy or associated with chemotherapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Castelli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberto</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Università degli studi di Sassari, scienze mediche chirurgiche e sperimentali.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Balzarotti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Monica</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Oncology and Hematology Unit, Humanitas Clinical and Research Center - IRCCS, Humanitas Cancer Center, Rozzano.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Salvi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emanuele</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences Luigi Sacco, University of Milan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Simona Rossi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberta</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Service of Pathology, ASST Fatebenefratelli-Sacco, Luigi Sacco, University Hospital Milano.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lambertenghi Deliliers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giorgio</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Fondazione Mattarelli, Milan, Italy and UO e Dipartimento di Medicina Interna IRCCS Istituto Auxologico Italiano, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bergamaschini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luigi</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences Luigi Sacco, University of Milan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gidaro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Antonio</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Clinical Sciences Luigi Sacco, University of Milan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Anticancer Drugs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9100823</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0959-4973</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000970">Antineoplastic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000074322">Antineoplastic Agents, Immunological</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016328">NF-kappa B</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C497764">NOTCH2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051883">Receptor, Notch2</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011947">Receptors, Antigen, B-Cell</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000970" MajorTopicYN="N">Antineoplastic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000074322" MajorTopicYN="N">Antineoplastic Agents, Immunological</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006509" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis B</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006526" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatitis C</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018442" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphoma, B-Cell, Marginal Zone</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016403" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016328" MajorTopicYN="N">NF-kappa B</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009367" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Staging</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051883" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptor, Notch2</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011947" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Antigen, B-Cell</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013156" MajorTopicYN="N">Splenectomy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013160" MajorTopicYN="N">Splenic Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059016" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Microenvironment</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407041</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CAD.0000000000001165</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00001813-900000000-98306</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armitage JO, Weisenburger DD. New approach to classifying non-Hodgkin’s lymphomas: clinical features of the major histologic subtypes. Non-Hodgkin’s Lymphoma Classification Project. J Clin Oncol 1998; 16:2780–2795.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow SH, Campo E, Pileri SA, Harris NL, Stein H, et al. The 2016 revision of the World Health Organization classification of lymphoid neoplasms. Blood. 127:2375–2390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gebhart J, Lechner K, Skrabs C, Sliwa T, Müldür E, Ludwig H, et al. Lupus anticoagulant and thrombosis in splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Thromb Res 2014; 134:980–984.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zibellini S, Capello D, Forconi F, Marcatili P, Rossi D, Rattotti S, et al. Stereotyped patterns of B-cell receptor in splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Haematologica 2010; 95:1792–1796.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castelli R, Wu MA, Arquati M, Zanichelli A, Suffritti C, Rossi D, Cicardi M. High prevalence of splenic marginal zone lymphoma among patients with acquired C1 inhibitor deficiency. Br J Haematol 2016; 172:902–908.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arcaini L, Lazzarino M, Colombo N, Burcheri S, Boveri E, Paulli M, et al.; Integruppo Italiano Linfomi. Splenic marginal zone lymphoma: a prognostic model for clinical use. Blood 2006; 107:4643–4649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olszewski AJ, Castillo JJ. Survival of patients with marginal zone lymphoma: analysis of the Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results database. Cancer 2013; 119:629–638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lenglet J, Traullé C, Mounier N, Benet C, Munoz-Bongrand N, Amorin S, et al. Long-term follow-up analysis of 100 patients with splenic marginal zone lymphoma treated with splenectomy as first-line treatment. Leuk Lymphoma 2014; 55:1854–1860.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conconi A, Franceschetti S, Aprile von Hohenstaufen K, Margiotta-Casaluci G, Stathis A, Moccia AA, et al. Histologic transformation in marginal zone lymphomas†. Ann Oncol 2015; 26:2329–2335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montalbán C, Abraira V, Arcaini L, Domingo-Domenech E, Guisado-Vasco P, Iannitto E, et al.; Splenic Marginal Zone Lymphoma Study Group. Risk stratification for splenic marginal zone lymphoma based on haemoglobin concentration, platelet count, high lactate dehydrogenase level and extrahilar lymphadenopathy: development and validation on 593 cases. Br J Haematol 2012; 159:164–171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zucca E, Arcaini L, Buske C, Johnson PW, Ponzoni M, Raderer M, et al.; ESMO Guidelines Committee. Electronic address:Marginal zone lymphomas: ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol 2020; 31:17–29.clinicalguidelines@esmo.org</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horning SJ, Rosenberg SA. The natural history of initially untreated low-grade non-Hodgkin’s lymphomas. N Engl J Med 1984; 311:1471–1475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matutes E, Oscier D, Montalban C, Berger F, Callet-Bauchu E, Dogan A, et al. Splenic marginal zone lymphoma proposals for a revision of diagnostic, staging and therapeutic criteria. Leukemia 2008; 22:487–495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hermine O, Lefrère F, Bronowicki JP, Mariette X, Jondeau K, Eclache-Saudreau V, et al. Regression of splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes after treatment of hepatitis C virus infection. N Engl J Med 2002; 347:89–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arcaini L, Vallisa D, Rattotti S, Ferretti VV, Ferreri AJM, Bernuzzi P, et al. Antiviral treatment in patients with indolent B-cell lymphomas associated with HCV infection: a study of the Fondazione Italiana Linfomi. Ann Oncol 2014; 25:1404–1410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett M, Schechter GP. Treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma: splenectomy versus rituximab. Semin Hematol 2010; 47:143–147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalpadakis C, Pangalis GA, Vassilakopoulos TP, Sachanas S, Angelopoulou MK. Treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma: should splenectomy be abandoned? Leuk Lymphoma 2014; 55:1463–1470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalpadakis C, Pangalis GA, Angelopoulou MK, Sachanas S, Kontopidou FN, Yiakoumis X, et al. Treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma with rituximab monotherapy: progress report and comparison with splenectomy. Oncologist 2013; 18:190–197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett M, Sharma K, Yegena S, Gavish I, Dave HP, Schechter GP. Rituximab monotherapy for splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Haematologica 2005; 90:856–858.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett M, Yegena S, Dave HP, Schechter GP. Re: Rituximab monotherapy is highly effective in splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Hematol Oncol 2008; 26:114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsimberidou AM, Catovsky D, Schlette E, O’Brien S, Wierda WG, Kantarjian H, et al. Outcomes in patients with splenic marginal zone lymphoma and marginal zone lymphoma treated with rituximab with or without chemotherapy or chemotherapy alone. Cancer 2006; 107:125–135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalpadakis C, Pangalis GA, Dimopoulou MN, Vassilakopoulos TP, Kyrtsonis MC, Korkolopoulou P, et al. Rituximab monotherapy is highly effective in splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Hematol Oncol 2007; 25:127–131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Else M, Marín-Niebla A, de la Cruz F, Batty P, Ríos E, Dearden CE, et al. Rituximab, used alone or in combination, is superior to other treatment modalities in splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Br J Haematol 2012; 159:322–328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulligan SP, Matutes E, Dearden C, Catovsky D. Splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes: natural history and response to therapy in 50 cases. Br J Haematol 1991; 78:206–209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Troussard X, Valensi F, Duchayne E, Garand R, Felman P, Tulliez M, et al. Splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes: clinical presentation, biology and prognostic factors in a series of 100 patients. Groupe Francais d’Hématologie Cellulaire (GFHC). Br J Haematol 1996; 93:731–736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chacón JI, Mollejo M, Muñoz E, Algara P, Mateo M, Lopez L, et al. Splenic marginal zone lymphoma: clinical characteristics and prognostic factors in a series of 60 patients. Blood 2002; 100:1648–1654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thieblemont C, Felman P, Berger F, Dumontet C, Arnaud P, Hequet O, et al. Treatment of splenic marginal zone B-cell lymphoma: an analysis of 81 patients. Clin Lymphoma 2002; 3:41–47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parry-Jones N, Matutes E, Gruszka-Westwood AM, Swansbury GJ, Wotherspoon AC, Catovsky D. Prognostic features of splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes: a report on 129 patients. Br J Haematol 2003; 120:759–764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iannitto E, Ambrosetti A, Ammatuna E, Colosio M, Florena AM, Tripodo C, et al. Splenic marginal zone lymphoma with or without villous lymphocytes. Hematologic findings and outcomes in a series of 57 patients. Cancer 2004; 101:2050–2057.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olszewski AJ. Survival outcomes with and without splenectomy in splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Am J Hematol 2012; 87:E119–E122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xing KH, Kahlon A, Skinnider BF, Connors JM, Gascoyne RD, Sehn LH, et al. Outcomes in splenic marginal zone lymphoma: analysis of 107 patients treated in British Columbia. Br J Haematol 2015; 169:520–527.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pata G, Damiani E, Bartoli M, Solari S, Anastasia A, Pagani C, et al. Peri-operative complications and hematologic improvement after first-line splenectomy for splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Leuk Lymphoma 2016; 57:1467–1470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kennedy ND, Lê GN, Kelly ME, Harding T, Fadalla K, Winter DC. Surgical management of splenic marginal zone lymphoma. Ir J Med Sci 2018; 187:343–347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onisâi M, Vlădăreanu AM, Nica A, Spînu A, Găman M, Bumbea H, et al. Splenectomy in lymphoproliferative disorders: a single eastern European center experience. Medicina (Kaunas) 2019; 56:12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cullingford GL, Watkins DN, Watts AD, Mallon DF. Severe late postsplenectomy infection. Br J Surg 1991; 78:716–721.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubin LG, Schaffner W. Clinical practice. Care of the asplenic patient. N Engl J Med 2014; 371:349–356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cervetti G, Galimberti S, Sordi E, Buda G, Orciuolo E, Cecconi N, Petrini M. Significant efficacy of 2-CdA with or without rituximab in the treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma (SMZL). Ann Oncol 2010; 21:851–854.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cervetti G, Galimberti S, Pelosini M, Ghio F, Cecconi N, Petrini M. Significant efficacy of 2-chlorodeoxyadenosine{+/-} rituximab in the treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma (SMZL): extended follow-up. Ann Oncol 2013; 24:2434–2438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iannitto E, Luminari S, Tripodo C, Mancuso S, Cesaretti M, Marcheselli L, et al. Rituximab with cyclophosphamide, vincristine, non-pegylated liposomal doxorubicin and prednisone as first-line treatment for splenic marginal zone lymphoma: a Fondazione Italiana Linfomi phase II study. Leuk Lymphoma 2015; 56:3281–3287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castelli R, Gidaro A, Deliliers GL. Bendamustine and rituximab, as first line treatment, in intermediate, high risk splenic marginal zone lymphomas of elderly patients. Mediterr J Hematol Infect Dis 2016; 8:e2016030.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castelli R, Bergamaschini L, Deliliers GL. First-line treatment with bendamustine and rituximab, in patients with intermediate-/high-risk splenic marginal zone lymphomas. Med Oncol 2017; 35:15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iannitto E, Bellei M, Amorim S, Ferreri AJM, Marcheselli L, Cesaretti M, et al. Efficacy of bendamustine and rituximab in splenic marginal zone lymphoma: results from the phase II BRISMA/IELSG36 study. Br J Haematol 2018; 183:755–765.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolam S, Orchard J, Oscier D. Fludarabine is effective in the treatment of splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes. Br J Haematol 1997; 99:158–161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasukawa M, Yamauchi H, Azuma T, Takada K, Ishimura M, Fujita S. Dramatic efficacy of fludarabine in the treatment of an aggressive case of splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes. Eur J Haematol 2002; 69:112–114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lefrère F, Hermine O, Belanger C, François S, Tilly H, Lebas de La Cour JC, et al. Fludarabine: an effective treatment in patients with splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes. Leukemia 2000; 14:573–575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riccioni R, Caracciolo F, Galimberti S, Cecconi N, Petrini M. Low dose 2-CdA schedule activity in splenic marginal zone lymphomas. Hematol Oncol 2003; 21:163–168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iannitto E, Minardi V, Calvaruso G, Ammatuna E, Florena AM, Mulè A, et al. Deoxycoformycin (pentostatin) in the treatment of splenic marginal zone lymphoma (SMZL) with or without villous lymphocytes. Eur J Haematol 2005; 75:130–135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lefrère F, Hermine O, François S, Panelatti G, Valensi F, Grosbois B, et al. Lack of efficacy of 2-chlorodeoxyadenoside in the treatment of splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes. Leuk Lymphoma 2000; 40:113–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lefrere F, Lévy V, François S, Delarue R, Ifrah N, Tilly H, et al. Fludarabine therapy in patients with splenic lymphoma with villous lymphocytes: an update. Leukemia 2004; 18:1924–1925.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flinn IW, van der Jagt R, Kahl BS, Wood P, Hawkins TE, Macdonald D, et al. Randomized trial of bendamustine-rituximab or R-CHOP/R-CVP in first-line treatment of indolent NHL or MCL: the BRIGHT study. Blood 2014; 123:2944–2952.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rummel MJ, Niederle N, Maschmeyer G, Banat GA, von Grünhagen U, Losem C, et al.; Study group indolent Lymphomas (StiL). Bendamustine plus rituximab versus CHOP plus rituximab as first-line treatment for patients with indolent and mantle-cell lymphomas: an open-label, multicentre, randomised, phase 3 non-inferiority trial. Lancet 2013; 381:1203–1210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goede V, Fischer K, Engelke A, Schlag R, Lepretre S, Montero LF, et al. Obinutuzumab as frontline treatment of chronic lymphocytic leukemia: updated results of the CLL11 study. Leukemia 2015; 29:1602–1604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sehn LH, Chua N, Mayer J, Dueck G, Trněný M, Bouabdallah K, et al. Obinutuzumab plus bendamustine versus bendamustine monotherapy in patients with rituximab-refractory indolent non-Hodgkin lymphoma (GADOLIN): a randomised, controlled, open-label, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol 2016; 17:1081–1093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gopal AK, Kahl BS, de Vos S, Wagner-Johnston ND, Schuster SJ, Jurczak WJ, et al. PI3Kδ inhibition by idelalisib in patients with relapsed indolent lymphoma. N Engl J Med 2014; 370:1008–1018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown JR, Byrd JC, Coutre SE, Benson DM, Flinn IW, Wagner-Johnston ND, et al. Idelalisib, an inhibitor of phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase p110δ, for relapsed/refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Blood 2014; 123:3390–3397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gopal AK, Kahl BS, de Vos S, Wagner-Johnston ND, Schuster SJ, Jurczak W, et al. Mature follow-up from a phase 2 study of PI3K-delta inhibitor idelalisib in patients with double (rituximab and alkylating agent)-refractory indolent B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Blood 2014; 124:1708. [abstract)].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noy A, de Vos S, Thieblemont C, Martin P, Flowers CR, Morschhauser F, et al. Targeting Bruton tyrosine kinase with ibrutinib in relapsed/refractory marginal zone lymphoma. Blood 2017; 129:2224–2232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fowler NH, Davis RE, Rawal S, Nastoupil L, Hagemeister FB, McLaughlin P, et al. Safety and activity of lenalidomide and rituximab in untreated indolent lymphoma: an open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol 2014; 15:1311–1318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuscano JM, Dutia M, Chee K, Brunson A, Reed-Pease C, Abedi M, et al. Lenalidomide plus rituximab can produce durable clinical responses in patients with relapsed or refractory, indolent non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Br J Haematol 2014; 165:375–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sacchi S, Marcheselli R, Bari A, Buda G, Molinari AL, Baldini L, et al. Safety and efficacy of lenalidomide in combination with rituximab in recurrent indolent non-follicular lymphoma: final results of a phase II study conducted by the Fondazione Italiana Linfomi. Haematologica 2016; 101:e196–e199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirschbaum M, Frankel P, Popplewell L, Zain J, Delioukina M, Pullarkat V, et al. Phase II study of vorinostat for treatment of relapsed or refractory indolent non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma and mantle cell lymphoma. J Clin Oncol 2011; 29:1198–1203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen R, Frankel P, Popplewell L, Siddiqi T, Ruel N, Rotter A, et al. A phase II study of vorinostat and rituximab for treatment of newly diagnosed and relapsed/refractory indolent non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Haematologica 2015; 100:357–362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conconi A, Martinelli G, Lopez-Guillermo A, Zinzani PL, Ferreri AJM, Rigacci L, et al. Clinical activity of bortezomib in relapsed/refractory MALT lymphomas: results of a phase II study of the International Extranodal Lymphoma Study Group (IELSG). Ann Oncol 2011; 22:689–695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Bella N, Taetle R, Kolibaba K, Boyd T, Raju R, Barrera D, et al. Results of a phase 2 study of bortezomib in patients with relapsed or refractory indolent lymphoma. Blood 2010; 115:475–480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baiocchi RA, Alinari L, Lustberg ME, Lin TS, Porcu P, Li X, et al. Phase 2 trial of rituximab and bortezomib in patients with relapsed or refractory mantle cell and follicular lymphoma. Cancer 2011; 1:244251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conconi A, Raderer M, Franceschetti S, Devizzi L, Ferreri AJ, Magagnoli M, et al. Clinical activity of everolimus in relapsed/refractory marginal zone B-cell lymphomas: results of a phase II study of the International Extranodal Lymphoma Study Group. Br J Haematol 2014; 166:69–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
