<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34419602</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3441</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>168</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European journal of pharmaceutics and biopharmaceutics : official journal of Arbeitsgemeinschaft fur Pharmazeutische Verfahrenstechnik e.V</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Pharm Biopharm</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Small scale in vitro method to determine a bioequivalent equilibrium solubility range for fasted human intestinal fluid.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>90</StartPage>
          <EndPage>96</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>90-96</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ejpb.2021.08.002</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0939-6411(21)00206-X</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Drug solubility is a key parameter controlling oral absorption, but intestinal solubility is difficult to assess in vitro. Human intestinal fluid (HIF) aspirates can be applied but they are variable, difficult to obtain and expensive. Simulated intestinal fluids (SIF) are a useful surrogate but multiple recipes are available and the optimum is unknown. A recent study characterised fasted HIF aspirates using a multi-dimensional approach and determined nine bioequivalent SIF media recipes that represented over ninety percent of HIF compositional variability. In this study these recipes have been applied to determine the equilibrium solubility of twelve drugs (naproxen, indomethacin, phenytoin, piroxicam, aprepitant, carvedilol, zafirlukast, tadalafil, fenofibrate, griseofulvin, felodipine, probucol) previously investigated using a statistical design of experiment (DoE) approach. The bioequivalent solubility measurements are statistically equivalent to the previous DoE, enclose literature solubility values in both fasted HIF and SIF, and the solubility range is less than the previous DoE. These results indicate that the system is measuring the same solubility space as literature systems with the lower overall range suggesting improved equivalence to in vivo solubility, when compared to DoEs. Three drugs (phenytoin, tadalafil and griseofulvin) display a comparatively narrow solubility range, a behaviour that is consistent with previous studies and related to the drugs' molecular structure and properties. This solubility behaviour would not be evident with single point solubility measurements. The solubility results can be analysed using a custom DoE to determine the most statistically significant factor within the media influencing solubility. This approach has a lower statistical resolution than a formal DoE and is not appropriate if determination of media factor significance for solubilisation is required. This study demonstrates that it is possible to assess the fasted intestinal equilibrium solubility envelope using a small number of bioequivalent media recipes obtained from a multi-dimensional analysis of fasted HIF. The derivation of the nine bioequivalent SIF media coupled with the lower measured solubility range indicate that the solubility results are more likely to reflect the fasted intestinal solubility envelope than previous DoE studies and highlight that intestinal solubility is a range and not a single value.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abuhassan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qamar</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Strathclyde Institute of Pharmacy and Biomedical Sciences, University of Strathclyde, 161 Cathedral Street, Glasgow G4 0RE, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Khadra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ibrahim</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Strathclyde Institute of Pharmacy and Biomedical Sciences, University of Strathclyde, 161 Cathedral Street, Glasgow G4 0RE, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pyper</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kate</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, University of Strathclyde, Livingstone Tower, 26 Richmond Street, Glasgow G1 1XH, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Halbert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gavin W</ForeName>
            <Initials>GW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Strathclyde Institute of Pharmacy and Biomedical Sciences, University of Strathclyde, 161 Cathedral Street, Glasgow G4 0RE, United Kingdom. Electronic address: g.w.halbert@strath.ac.uk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Pharm Biopharm</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9109778</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0939-6411</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D004364">Pharmaceutical Preparations</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005215" MajorTopicYN="N">Fasting</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D066298" MajorTopicYN="N">In Vitro Techniques</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007408" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intestinal Absorption</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007419" MajorTopicYN="N">Intestinal Secretions</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="Y">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004364" MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmaceutical Preparations</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="Y">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012995" MajorTopicYN="N">Solubility</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013810" MajorTopicYN="N">Therapeutic Equivalency</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aprepitant</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carvedilol</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fasted simulated intestinal fluid</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Felodipine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fenofibrate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Griseofulvin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indomethacin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intestinal solubility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Naproxen</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oral absorption</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Phenytoin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Piroxicam</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Probucol</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Simulated intestinal fluid</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solubility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tadalafil</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zafirlukast</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419602</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8491656</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpb.2021.08.002</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0939-6411(21)00206-X</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amidon G.L., Lennernas H., Shah V.P., Crison J.R. A theoretical basis for a biopharmaceutic drug classification – the correlation of in-vitro drug product dissolution and in-vivo bioavailability. Pharm. Res. 1995;12:413–420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7617530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butler J.M., Dressman J.B. The developability classification system: application of biopharmaceutics concepts to formulation development. J. Pharm. Sci. 2010;99:4940–4954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20821390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenberger J., Butler J., Dressman J. A refined developability classification system. J. Pharm. Sci. 2018;107:2020–2032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29665381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugano K., Okazaki A., Sugimoto S., Tavornvipas S., Omura A., Mano T. Solubility and dissolution profile assessment in drug discovery. Drug Metab. Pharmacokinet. 2007;22:225–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17827779</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindahl A., Ungell A.L., Knutson L., Lennernas H. Characterization of fluids from the stomach and proximal jejunum in men and women. Pharm. Res. 1997;14:497–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9144738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergström C.A., Holm R., Jørgensen S.A., Andersson S.B., Artursson P., Beato S., Borde A., Box K., Brewster M., Dressman J., Feng K.I., Halbert G., Kostewicz E., McAllister M., Muenster U., Thinnes J., Taylor R., Mullertz A. Early pharmaceutical profiling to predict oral drug absorption: current status and unmet needs. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2014;57:173–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen B.L., Brondsted H., Lennernas H., Christensen F.N., Mullertz A., Kristensen H.G. Dissolution of hydrocortisone in human and simulated intestinal fluids. Pharm. Res. 2000;17:183–189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen B.L., Mullertz A., Brondsted H., Kristensen H.G. A comparison of the solubility of danazol in human and simulated gastrointestinal fluids. Pharm. Res. 2000;17:891–894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10990211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarysse S., Brouwers J., Tack J., Annaert P., Augustijns P. Intestinal drug solubility estimation based on simulated intestinal fluids: comparison with solubility in human intestinal fluids. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2011;43:260–269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21570465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Augustijns P., Wuyts B., Hens B., Annaert P., Butler J., Brouwers J. A review of drug solubility in human intestinal fluids: implications for the prediction of oral absorption. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2014;57:322–332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23994640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuchs A., Dressman J.B. Composition and physicochemical properties of fasted-state human duodenal and Jejunal fluid: a critical evaluation of the available data. J. Pharm. Sci. 2014;103:3398–3411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25277073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de la Cruz-Moreno M.P., Montejo C., Aguilar-Ros A., Dewe W., Beck B., Stappaerts J., Tack J., Augustijns P. Exploring drug solubility in fasted human intestinal fluid aspirates: impact of inter-individual variability, sampling site and dilution. Int. J. Pharm. 2017;528:471–484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galia E., Nicolaides E., Horter D., Lobenberg R., Reppas C., Dressman J.B. Evaluation of various dissolution media for predicting in vivo performance of class I and II drugs. Pharm. Res. 1998;15:698–705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9619777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bou-Chacra N., Melo K.J.C., Morales I.A.C., Stippler E.S., Kesisoglou F., Yazdanian M., Lobenberg R. Evolution of choice of solubility and dissolution media after two decades of biopharmaceutical classification system. AAPS J. 2017;19:989–1001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28516359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuchs A., Leigh M., Kloefer B., Dressman J.B. Advances in the design of fasted state simulating intestinal fluids: FaSSIF-V3. Eur. J. Pharm. Biopharm. 2015;94:229–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26032292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennernas H., Aarons L., Augustijns P., Beato S., Bolger M., Box K., Brewster M., Butler J., Dressman J., Holm R., Julia Frank K., Kendall R., Langguth P., Sydor J., Lindahl A., McAllister M., Muenster U., Mullertz A., Ojala K., Pepin X., Reppas C., Rostami-Hodjegan A., Verwei M., Weitschies W., Wilson C., Karlsson C., Abrahamsson B. Oral biopharmaceutics tools – time for a new initiative – an introduction to the IMI project OrBiTo. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2014;57:292–299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24189462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khadra I., Zhou Z., Dunn C., Wilson C.G., Halbert G. Statistical investigation of simulated intestinal fluid composition on the equilibrium solubility of biopharmaceutics classification system class II drugs. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2015;67:65–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25444845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madsen C.M., Feng K.I., Leithead A., Canfield N., Jørgensen S.A., Müllertz A., Rades T. Effect of composition of simulated intestinal media on the solubility of poorly soluble compounds investigated by design of experiments. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28986196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ainousah B.E., Perrier J., Dunn C., Khadra I., Wilson C.G., Halbert G. Dual level statistical investigation of equilibrium solubility in simulated fasted and fed intestinal fluid. Mol. Pharm. 2017;14:4170–4180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29072917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Z., Dunn C., Khadra I., Wilson C.G., Halbert G.W. Statistical investigation of simulated fed intestinal media composition on the equilibrium solubility of oral drugs. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2017;99:95–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5312627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27940083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrier J., Zhou Z., Dunn C., Khadra I., Wilson C.G., Halbert G. Statistical investigation of the full concentration range of fasted and fed simulated intestinal fluid on the equilibrium solubility of oral drugs. Eur. J. Pharm. Sci. 2018;111:247–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McPherson S., Perrier J., Dunn C., Khadra I., Davidson S., Ainousah B.E., Wilson C.G., Halbert G. Small scale design of experiment investigation of equilibrium solubility in simulated fasted and fed intestinal fluid. Eur. J. Pharm. Biopharm. 2020;150:14–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32035969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn C., Perrier J., Khadra I., Wilson C.G., Halbert G.W. Topography of simulated intestinal equilibrium solubility. Mol. Pharm. 2019;16:1890–1905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6505523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30848917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pyper K., Brouwers J., Augustijns P., Khadra I., Dunn C., Wilson C.G., Halbert G.W. Multidimensional analysis of human intestinal fluid composition. Eur. J. Pharm. Biopharm. 2020;153:226–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riethorst D., Mols R., Duchateau G., Tack J., Brouwers J., Augustijns P. Characterization of human duodenal fluids in fasted and fed state conditions. J. Pharm. Sci. 2016;105:673–681.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zughaid H., Forbes B., Martin G.P., Patel N. Bile salt composition is secondary to bile salt concentration in determining hydrocortisone and progesterone solubility in intestinal mimetic fluids. Int. J. Pharm. 2012;422:295–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22101287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fagerberg J.H., Karlsson E., Ulander J., Hanisch G., Bergstrom C.A. Computational prediction of drug solubility in fasted simulated and aspirated human intestinal fluid. Pharm. Res. 2015;32:578–589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4300419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25186438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergstrom C.A.S., Larsson P. Computational prediction of drug solubility in water-based systems: qualitative and quantitative approaches used in the current drug discovery and development setting. Int. J. Pharm. 2018;540:185–193.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5861307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29421301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
