<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34491681</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">0973-3922</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>88</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Season>May-Jun</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Indian journal of dermatology, venereology and leprology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Characteristics of children with leprosy: Factors associated with delay in disease diagnosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>337</StartPage>
          <EndPage>341</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>337-341</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/IJDVL_1382_20</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">10.25259/IJDVL_1382_20</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The objectives of the study were to characterize the clinical profile of childhood leprosy presenting at tertiary leprosy care hospitals in the states of Bihar, West Bengal and Uttar Pradesh in India, and to determine the possible risk factors associated with disabilities at presentation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Subjects were children with newly diagnosed leprosy registered for treatment at tertiary Leprosy Mission Hospitals in Muzaffarpur (Bihar), Purulia (West Bengal) and Faizabad (Uttar Pradesh), India, between June and December 2019. Demographic and leprosy characteristics were collected at the time of diagnosis. Parents/guardians were interviewed on reasons for delay in presenting at the hospital. Associations between various factors and delay in diagnosis were assessed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among the 84 children, the mean (SD) age was 10 (3) years with a range of 4-14 years. There were more boys (58%) and most children were currently in school (93%), resident in rural areas (90%) and belonged to a lower socioeconomic status (68%). More children were diagnosed with multibacillary leprosy (69%), one-third of them being skin smear positive for Mycobacterium leprae. On presentation, 17% had deformity (5% grade 1 deformity and 12% grade 2), 29% had nerve involvement and skin lesions were spread across the body in half of the children. Mean (SD) duration of delay was 10.5 (9.8) months. Delayed presentation was more in boys (43% vs. 17%; P = 0.01), those without a history of migration for work compared to those who had a history of migration (40% vs. 9%; P = 0.008) and in those children who were from a poor economic status compared with those that came from a better economic status (44% vs. 7%; P = 0.001) Limitations: Because our study was conducted at tertiary care hospitals, the findings are not representative of the situation in the field. Furthermore, a comparison group of newly diagnosed adult leprosy patients with disability could have been included in the study.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Childhood leprosy continues to occur in endemic pockets in India and a substantial number present with skin smear positivity and deformity. Guardians of these children cite many reasons for the delay in presentation.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Darlong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Joydeepa</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Leprosy Mission Trust India, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Govindasamy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karthikeyan</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Leprosy Mission Trust India, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Daniel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amrita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Leprosy Mission Trust India, New Delhi, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7701852</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0378-6323</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057210" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delayed Diagnosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006233" MajorTopicYN="N">Disabled Persons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007194" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">India</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007918" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leprosy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056006" MajorTopicYN="N">Leprosy, Multibacillary</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009166" MajorTopicYN="N">Mycobacterium leprae</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="N">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062606" MajorTopicYN="N">Tertiary Care Centers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Children</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leprosy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>52</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34491681</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25259/IJDVL_1382_20</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.25259/IJDVL_1382_20</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Observatory GH Data Repository, GHO By Category Leprosy. Geneva, Switzerland World Health Organization: 2021;</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. WGHO B Category LIS Summary, GHO By Country India. Geneva, Switzerland World Health Organization: 2002;</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reyila VP, Betsy A, Riyaz N, Sasidharanpillai S, Sherjeena PV, Majitha MP, et al. Clinico-epidemiological study of disability due to leprosy at the time of diagnosis among patients attending a tertiary care institution. Indian J Dermatol. 2019; 64:106-11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reed NK, Van Brakel WH, Reed DS,. Progress of impairment scores following commencement of chemotherapy in multibacillary leprosy patients. Int J Lepr Other Mycobact Dis. 1997; 65:328-36</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Oliveira MB, Diniz LM,. Leprosy among children under 15 years of age: Literature review. An Bras Dermatol. 2016; 91:196-203</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naik SS,. Repeat leprosy survey after 7 years in night high schools in greater Bombay. Indian J Lepr. 1996; 68:377-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deb Burman K, Rijall A, Agrawal S, Agarwalla A, Verma KK,. Childhood leprosy in eastern nepal: A hospital-based study. Indian J Lepr. 2003; 75:47-52</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selvasekar A, Geetha J, Nisha K, Manimozhi N, Jesudasan K, Rao PS,. Childhood leprosy in an endemic area. Lepr Rev. 1999; 70:21-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shetty V, Ghate S, Wakade A, Thakar U, Thakur D, D'Souza E,. Clinical, bacteriological, and histopathological characteristics of newly detected children with leprosy: A population based study in a defined rural and urban area of Maharashtra, Western India. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2013; 79:512-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogra S, Narang T, Khullar G, Kumar R, Saikia UN,. Childhood leprosy through the post-leprosy-elimination era: A retrospective analysis of epidemiological and clinical characteristics of disease over eleven years from a tertiary care hospital in North India. Lepr Rev. 2014; 85:296-310</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Government of India. Central Leprosy Division Directorate General of Health Services Ministry of Health and Family Welfare. Nirman Bhawan, New Delhi Government of India: 2017;</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narang T, Kumar B,. Leprosy in children. Indian J Paediatr Dermatol. 2019; 20:12</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Global Leprosy Update-2017: Reducing the Disease Burden Due to Leprosy. Available from: https://www.apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/274290/WER9335-445-456.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y [Last accessed on 2020 Dec 7]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reibel F, Cambau E, Aubry A,. Update on the epidemiology, diagnosis, and treatment of leprosy. Med Mal Infect. 2015; 45:383-93</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srinivas G, Muthuvel T, Lal V, Vaikundanathan K, SchwienhorstStich EM, Kasang C,. Risk of disability among adult leprosy cases and determinants of delay in diagnosis in five states of India: A case-control study. PLoS Negl Trop Dis. 2019; 13:e0007495</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wani RT,. Socioeconomic status scales modified Kuppuswamy and Udai Pareekh's scale updated for 2019. J Family Med Prim Care. 2019; 8:1846-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asia AJ, Tapre V, Joge U,. Profile of childhood leprosy cases attending a tertiary care centre. Indian J Lepr. 2016; 88:111-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sasidharanpillai S, Binitha MP, Riyaz N, Ambooken B, Mariyath OK, George B, et al. Childhood leprosy: A retrospective descriptive study from government medical college, Kozhikode, Kerala, India. Lepr Rev. 2014; 85:100-10</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darlong J, Govindharaj P, Darlong F, Mahato N,. A study of untreated leprosy affected children reporting with Grade 2 disability at a referral centre in West Bengal, India. Lepr Rev. 2017; 88:298-305</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
