<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34510305</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0171-2004</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>269</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Handbook of experimental pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Handb Exp Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>WNT Signalling in Osteoarthritis and Its Pharmacological Targeting.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>337</StartPage>
          <EndPage>356</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>337-356</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/164_2021_525</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Osteoarthritis (OA) is a highly disabling musculoskeletal condition affecting millions of people worldwide. OA is characterised by progressive destruction and irreversible morphological changes of joint tissues and architecture. At molecular level, de-regulation of several pathways contributes to the disruption of tissue homeostasis in the joint. Overactivation of the WNT/β-catenin signalling pathway has been associated with degenerative processes in OA. However, the multiple layers of complexity in the modulation of the signalling and the still insufficient knowledge of the specific molecular drivers of pathogenetic mechanisms have made difficult the pharmacological targeting of this pathway for therapeutic purposes. This review aims to provide an overview of the WNT/β-catenin signalling in OA with a particular focus on its role in the articular cartilage. Pathway components whose targeting showed therapeutic potential will be highlighted and described. A specific section will be dedicated to Lorecivivint, the first inhibitor of the β-catenin-dependent pathway currently in phase III clinical trial as OA-modifying agent.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>De Palma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anna</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Pre-Clinical Sciences, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of Surrey, Guildford, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nalesso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giovanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Pre-Clinical Sciences, School of Veterinary Medicine, University of Surrey, Guildford, UK. g.nalesso@surrey.ac.uk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>MR/S008608/1</GrantID>
            <Acronym>MRC_</Acronym>
            <Agency>Medical Research Council</Agency>
            <Country>United Kingdom</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Handb Exp Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7902231</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0171-2004</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002358" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cartilage, Articular</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006706" MajorTopicYN="N">Homeostasis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D060449" MajorTopicYN="N">Wnt Signaling Pathway</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lorecivivint</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoarthritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacological targets</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WNT signalling</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34510305</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/164_2021_525</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Archer CW, Francis-West P (2003) The chondrocyte. Int J Biochem Cell Biol 35:401–404</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12565700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastakoty D, Saraswati S, Cates J, Lee E, Nanney LB, Young PP (2015) Inhibition of/β-catenin pathway promotes regenerative repair of cutaneous and cartilage injury. FASEB J 29:4881–4892</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26268926</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4653050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blom AB, Brockbank SM, van Lent PL, van Beuningen HM, Geurts J, Takahashi N, van der Kraan PM, van de Loo FA, Schreurs BW, Clements K, Newham P, van den Berg WB (2009) Involvement of the Wnt signaling pathway in experimental and human osteoarthritis: prominent role of Wnt-induced signaling protein 1. Arthritis Rheum 60:501–512</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19180479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouaziz W, Funck-Brentano T, Lin H, Marty C, Ea HK, Hay E, Cohen-Solal M (2015) Loss of sclerostin promotes osteoarthritis in mice via β-catenin-dependent and -independent Wnt pathways. Arthritis Res Ther 17:24</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25656376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4355467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castano-Betancourt MC, Evans DS, Ramos YF, Boer CG, Metrustry S, Liu Y, den Hollander W, van Rooij J, Kraus VB, Yau MS, Mitchell BD, Muir K, Hofman A, Doherty M, Doherty S, Zhang W, Kraaij R, Rivadeneira F, Barrett-Connor E, Maciewicz RA, Arden N, Nelissen RG, Kloppenburg M, Jordan JM, Nevitt MC, Slagboom EP, Hart DJ, Lafeber F, Styrkarsdottir U, Zeggini E, Evangelou E, Spector TD, Uitterlinden AG, Lane NE, Meulenbelt I, Valdes AM, van Meurs JB (2016) Novel genetic variants for cartilage thickness and hip osteoarthritis. PLoS Genet 12:e1006260</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27701424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5049763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan BY, Fuller ES, Russell AK, Smith SM, Smith MM, Jackson MT, Cake MA, Read RA, Bateman JF, Sambrook PN, Little CB (2011) Increased chondrocyte sclerostin may protect against cartilage degradation in osteoarthritis. Osteoarthr Cartil 19:874–885</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang JC, Christiansen BA, Murugesh DK, Sebastian A, Hum NR, Collette NM, Hatsell S, Economides AN, Blanchette CD, Loots GG (2018) SOST/Sclerostin improves posttraumatic osteoarthritis and inhibits MMP2/3 expression after injury. J Bone Miner Res 33:1105–1113</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29377313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clevers H, Nusse R (2012) Wnt/beta-catenin signaling and disease. Cell 149:1192–1205</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22682243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cornelis FMF, de Roover A, Storms L, Hens A, Lories RJ, Monteagudo S (2019) Increased susceptibility to develop spontaneous and post-traumatic osteoarthritis in Dot1l-deficient mice. Osteoarthr Cartil 27:513–525</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui A, Li H, Wang D, Zhong J, Chen Y, Lu H (2020) Global, regional prevalence, incidence and risk factors of knee osteoarthritis in population-based studies. EClinicalMedicine 29–30:100587</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34505846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7704420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dao DY, Yang X, Chen D, Zuscik M, O'Keefe RJ (2007) Axin1 and Axin2 are regulated by TGF- and mediate cross-talk between TGF- and Wnt signaling pathways. Ann N Y Acad Sci 1116:82–99</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2647987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell'Accio F, De Bari C, Luyten FP (2001) Molecular markers predictive of the capacity of expanded human articular chondrocytes to form stable cartilage in vivo. Arthritis Rheum 44:1608–1619</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11465712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell'Accio F, De Bari C, El Tawil NM, Barone F, Mitsiadis TA, O'Dowd J, Pitzalis C (2006) Activation of WNT and BMP signaling in adult human articular cartilage following mechanical injury. Arthritis Res Ther 8:R139</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16893455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1779445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell'accio F, De Bari C, Eltawil NM, Vanhummelen P, Pitzalis C (2008) Identification of the molecular response of articular cartilage to injury, by microarray screening: Wnt-16 expression and signaling after injury and in osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheum 58:1410–1421</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18438861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng Q, Li P, Che M, Liu J, Biswas S, Ma G, He L, Wei Z, Zhang Z, Yang Y, Liu H, Li B (2019) Activation of hedgehog signaling in mesenchymal stem cells induces cartilage and bone tumor formation via Wnt/β-catenin. elife 8:e50208</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31482846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6764825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deshmukh V, Hu H, Barroga C, Bossard C, Kc S, Dellamary L, Stewart J, Chiu K, Ibanez M, Pedraza M, Seo T, Do L, Cho S, Cahiwat J, Tam B, Tambiah JRS, Hood J, Lane NE, Yazici Y (2018) A small-molecule inhibitor of the Wnt pathway (SM04690) as a potential disease modifying agent for the treatment of osteoarthritis of the knee. Osteoarthr Cartil 26:18–27</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickinson SC, Sutton CA, Brady K, Salerno A, Katopodi T, Williams RL, West CC, Evseenko D, Wu L, Pang S, Ferro de Godoy R, Goodship AE, Peault B, Blom AW, Kafienah W, Hollander AP (2017) The Wnt5a receptor, receptor tyrosine kinase-like orphan receptor 2, is a predictive cell surface marker of human mesenchymal stem cells with an enhanced capacity for chondrogenic differentiation. Stem Cells 35:2280–2291</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28833807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5707440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding Z, Lu W, Dai C, Huang W, Liu F, Shan W, Cheng C, Xu J, Yin Z, He W (2020) The CRD of frizzled 7 exhibits chondroprotective effects in osteoarthritis via inhibition of the canonical Wnt3a/β-catenin signaling pathway. Int Immunopharmacol 82:106367</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32151961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eldridge SE, Barawi A, Wang H, Roelofs AJ, Kaneva M, Guan Z, Lydon H, Thomas BL, Thorup AS, Fernandez BF, Caxaria S, Strachan D, Ali A, Shanmuganathan K, Pitzalis C, Whiteford JR, Henson F, McCaskie AW, De Bari C, Dell'Accio F (2020) Agrin induces long-term osteochondral regeneration by supporting repair morphogenesis. Sci Transl Med 12(559):eaax9086</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32878982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elsaid KA, Jay GD, Warman ML, Rhee DK, Chichester CO (2005) Association of articular cartilage degradation and loss of boundary-lubricating ability of synovial fluid following injury and inflammatory arthritis. Arthritis Rheum 52:1746–1755</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15934070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estrada K, Styrkarsdottir U, Evangelou E, Hsu YH, Duncan EL, Ntzani EE, Oei L, Albagha OM, Amin N, Kemp JP, Koller DL, Li G, Liu CT, Minster RL, Moayyeri A, Vandenput L, Willner D, Xiao SM, Yerges-Armstrong LM, Zheng HF, Alonso N, Eriksson J, Kammerer CM, Kaptoge SK, Leo PJ, Thorleifsson G, Wilson SG, Wilson JF, Aalto V, Alen M, Aragaki AK, Aspelund T, Center JR, Dailiana Z, Duggan DJ, Garcia M, Garcia-Giralt N, Giroux S, Hallmans G, Hocking LJ, Husted LB, Jameson KA, Khusainova R, Kim GS, Kooperberg C, Koromila T, Kruk M, Laaksonen M, Lacroix AZ, Lee SH, Leung PC, Lewis JR, Masi L, Mencej-Bedrac S, Nguyen TV, Nogues X, Patel MS, Prezelj J, Rose LM, Scollen S, Siggeirsdottir K, Smith AV, Svensson O, Trompet S, Trummer O, van Schoor NM, Woo J, Zhu K, Balcells S, Brandi ML, Buckley BM, Cheng S, Christiansen C, Cooper C, Dedoussis G, Ford I, Frost M, Goltzman D, Gonzalez-Macias J, Kahonen M, Karlsson M, Khusnutdinova E, Koh JM, Kollia P, Langdahl BL, Leslie WD, Lips P, Ljunggren O, Lorenc RS, Marc J, Mellstrom D, Obermayer-Pietsch B, Olmos JM, Pettersson-Kymmer U, Reid DM, Riancho JA, Ridker PM, Rousseau F, Slagboom PE, Tang NL, Urreizti R, Van Hul W, Viikari J, Zarrabeitia MT, Aulchenko YS, Castano-Betancourt M, Grundberg E, Herrera L, Ingvarsson T, Johannsdottir H, Kwan T, Li R, Luben R, Medina-Gomez C, Palsson ST, Reppe S, Rotter JI, Sigurdsson G, van Meurs JB, Verlaan D, Williams FM, Wood AR, Zhou Y, Gautvik KM, Pastinen T, Raychaudhuri S, Cauley JA, Chasman DI, Clark GR, Cummings SR, Danoy P, Dennison EM, Eastell R, Eisman JA, Gudnason V, Hofman A, Jackson RD, Jones G, Jukema JW, Khaw KT, Lehtimaki T, Liu Y, Lorentzon M, McCloskey E, Mitchell BD, Nandakumar K, Nicholson GC, Oostra BA, Peacock M, Pols HA, Prince RL, Raitakari O, Reid IR, Robbins J, Sambrook PN, Sham PC, Shuldiner AR, Tylavsky FA, van Duijn CM, Wareham NJ, Cupples LA, Econs MJ, Evans DM, Harris TB, Kung AW, Psaty BM, Reeve J, Spector TD, Streeten EA, Zillikens MC, Thorsteinsdottir U, Ohlsson C, Karasik D, Richards JB, Brown MA, Stefansson K, Uitterlinden AG, Ralston SH, Ioannidis JP, Kiel DP, Rivadeneira F (2012) Genome-wide meta-analysis identifies 56 bone mineral density loci and reveals 14 loci associated with risk of fracture. Nat Genet 44:491–501</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22504420</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3338864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farrera-Hernandez A, Marin-Llera JC, Chimal-Monroy J (2021) WNT5A-Ca(2+)-CaN-NFAT signalling plays a permissive role during cartilage differentiation in embryonic chick digit development. Dev Biol 469:86–95</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu HD, Wang BK, Wan ZQ, Lin H, Chang ML, Han GL (2016) Wnt5a mediated canonical Wnt signaling pathway activation in orthodontic tooth movement: possible role in the tension force-induced bone formation. J Mol Histol 47:455–466</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27456852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Funck-Brentano T, Bouaziz W, Marty C, Geoffroy V, Hay E, Cohen-Solal M (2014) Dkk-1-mediated inhibition of Wnt signaling in bone ameliorates osteoarthritis in mice. Arthritis Rheumatol 66:3028–3039</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25080367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Ibarbia C, Perez-Nunez MI, Olmos JM, Valero C, Perez-Aguilar MD, Hernandez JL, Zarrabeitia MT, Gonzalez-Macias J, Riancho JA (2013) Missense polymorphisms of the WNT16 gene are associated with bone mass, hip geometry and fractures. Osteoporos Int 24:2449–2454</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23417354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glasson SS, Blanchet TJ, Morris EA (2007) The surgical destabilization of the medial meniscus (DMM) model of osteoarthritis in the 129/SvEv mouse. Osteoarthr Cartil 15:1061–1069</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldring MB, Marcu KB (2009) Cartilage homeostasis in health and rheumatic diseases. Arthritis Res Ther 11:224</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19519926</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2714092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green J, Nusse R, van Amerongen R (2014) The role of Ryk and Ror receptor tyrosine kinases in Wnt signal transduction. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol 6:a009175</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24370848</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3941236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo X, Day TF, Jiang X, Garrett-Beal L, Topol L, Yang Y (2004) Wnt/beta-catenin signaling is sufficient and necessary for synovial joint formation. Genes Dev 18:2404–2417</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15371327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">522990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo X, Mak KK, Taketo MM, Yang Y (2009) The Wnt/beta-catenin pathway interacts differentially with PTHrP signaling to control chondrocyte hypertrophy and final maturation. PLoS One 4:e6067</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19557172</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2698152</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamada D, Sampson ER, Maynard RD, Zuscik MJ (2014) Surgical induction of posttraumatic osteoarthritis in the mouse. Methods Mol Biol 1130:61–72</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honsawek S, Tanavalee A, Yuktanandana P, Ngarmukos S, Saetan N, Tantavisut S (2010) Dickkopf-1 (Dkk-1) in plasma and synovial fluid is inversely correlated with radiographic severity of knee osteoarthritis patients. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 11:257</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21062498</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2989312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang X, Zhong L, van Helvoort E, Lafeber F, Mastbergen S, Hendriks J, Post JN, Karperien M (2019) The expressions of Dickkopf-related protein 1 and frizzled-related protein are negatively correlated to local inflammation and osteoarthritis severity. Cartilage. https://doi.org/10.1177/1947603519841676</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Karthikeyan C, Moorthy NS, Waiker DK, Jain AK, Trivedi P (2014) Human CDC2-like kinase 1 (CLK1): a novel target for Alzheimer’s disease. Curr Drug Targets 15:539–550</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemp CR, Willems E, Wawrzak D, Hendrickx M, Agbor Agbor T, Leyns L (2007) Expression of Frizzled5, Frizzled7, and Frizzled10 during early mouse development and interactions with canonical Wnt signaling. Dev Dyn 236:2011–2019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17576136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kevorkian L, Young DA, Darrah C, Donell ST, Shepstone L, Porter S, Brockbank SM, Edwards DR, Parker AE, Clark IM (2004) Expression profiling of metalloproteinases and their inhibitors in cartilage. Arthritis Rheum 50:131–141</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14730609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kloppenburg M, Berenbaum F (2020) Osteoarthritis year in review 2019: epidemiology and therapy. Osteoarthr Cartil 28:242–248</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koyama E, Shibukawa Y, Nagayama M, Sugito H, Young B, Yuasa T, Okabe T, Ochiai T, Kamiya N, Rountree RB, Kingsley DM, Iwamoto M, Enomoto-Iwamoto M, Pacifici M (2008) A distinct cohort of progenitor cells participates in synovial joint and articular cartilage formation during mouse limb skeletogenesis. Dev Biol 316:62–73</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18295755</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2373417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laham AJ, Saber-Ayad M, El-Awady R (2021) DYRK1A: a down syndrome-related dual protein kinase with a versatile role in tumorigenesis. Cell Mol Life Sci 78:603–619</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32870330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lane NE, Lian K, Nevitt MC, Zmuda JM, Lui L, Li J, Wang J, Fontecha M, Umblas N, Rosenbach M, de Leon P, Corr M (2006) Frizzled-related protein variants are risk factors for hip osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheum 54:1246–1254</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16572458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leijten JC, Bos SD, Landman EB, Georgi N, Jahr H, Meulenbelt I, Post JN, van Blitterswijk CA, Karperien M (2013) GREM1, FRZB and DKK1 mRNA levels correlate with osteoarthritis and are regulated by osteoarthritis-associated factors. Arthritis Res Ther 15:R126</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24286177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3978825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Newton PT, Bouderlique T, Sejnohova M, Zikmund T, Kozhemyakina E, Xie M, Krivanek J, Kaiser J, Qian H, Dyachuk V, Lassar AB, Warman ML, Barenius B, Adameyko I, Chagin AS (2017) Superficial cells are self-renewing chondrocyte progenitors, which form the articular cartilage in juvenile mice. FASEB J 31:1067–1084</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Xue J, Jing Y, Wang M, Shu R, Xu H, Xue C, Feng J, Wang P, Bai D (2019) SOST deficiency aggravates osteoarthritis in mice by promoting sclerosis of subchondral bone. Biomed Res Int 2019:7623562</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31828128</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6885161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lietman C, Wu B, Lechner S, Shinar A, Sehgal M, Rossomacha E, Datta P, Sharma A, Gandhi R, Kapoor M, Young PP (2018) Inhibition of Wnt/β-catenin signaling ameliorates osteoarthritis in a murine model of experimental osteoarthritis. JCI Insight 3(3):e96308</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5821202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Little CB, Barai A, Burkhardt D, Smith SM, Fosang AJ, Werb Z, Shah M, Thompson EW (2009) Matrix metalloproteinase 13-deficient mice are resistant to osteoarthritic cartilage erosion but not chondrocyte hypertrophy or osteophyte development. Arthritis Rheum 60:3723–3733</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19950295</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2832925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, Li X, Hua B, Yang X, Zheng J, Liu S (2021) WNT16 is upregulated early in mouse TMJ osteoarthritis and protects fibrochondrocytes against IL-1beta induced inflammatory response by regulation of RUNX2/MMP13 cascade. Bone 143:115793</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33301961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lories RJ, Peeters J, Bakker A, Tylzanowski P, Derese I, Schrooten J, Thomas JT, Luyten FP (2007) Articular cartilage and biomechanical properties of the long bones in Frzb-knockout mice. Arthritis Rheum 56:4095–4103</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18050203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loughlin J, Dowling B, Chapman K, Marcelline L, Mustafa Z, Southam L, Ferreira A, Ciesielski C, Carson DA, Corr M (2004) Functional variants within the secreted frizzled-related protein 3 gene are associated with hip osteoarthritis in females. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 101:9757–9762</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15210948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">470747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma L, Liu Y, Zhao X, Li P, Jin Q (2019) Rapamycin attenuates articular cartilage degeneration by inhibiting β-catenin in a murine model of osteoarthritis. Connect Tissue Res 60:452–462</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30782019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martineau X, Abed E, Martel-Pelletier J, Pelletier JP, Lajeunesse D (2017) Alteration of Wnt5a expression and of the non-canonical Wnt/PCP and Wnt/PKC-Ca2+ pathways in human osteoarthritis osteoblasts. PLoS One 12:e0180711</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5544184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason JB, Gurda BL, Hankenson KD, Harper LR, Carlson CS, Wilson JM, Richardson DW (2017) Wnt10b and Dkk-1 gene therapy differentially influenced trabecular bone architecture, soft tissue integrity, and osteophytosis in a skeletally mature rat model of osteoarthritis. Connect Tissue Res 58:542–552</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27937051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazieres J, You L, He B, Xu Z, Lee AY, Mikami I, McCormick F, Jablons DM (2005) Inhibition of Wnt16 in human acute lymphoblastoid leukemia cells containing the t(1;19) translocation induces apoptosis. Oncogene 24:5396–5400</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16007226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendoza-Reinoso V, Beverdam A (2018) Epidermal YAP activity drives canonical WNT16/beta-catenin signaling to promote keratinocyte proliferation in vitro and in the murine skin. Stem Cell Res 29:15–23</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merle P, Kim M, Herrmann M, Gupte A, Lefrancois L, Califano S, Trepo C, Tanaka S, Vitvitski L, de la Monte S, Wands JR (2005) Oncogenic role of the frizzled-7/beta-catenin pathway in hepatocellular carcinoma. J Hepatol 43:854–862</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16098625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miclea RL, Siebelt M, Finos L, Goeman JJ, Cwgm L, Oostdijk W, Weinans H, Wit JM, Robanus-Maandag EC, Karperien M (2011) Inhibition of Gsk3 beta in cartilage induces osteoarthritic features through activation of the canonical Wnt signaling pathway. Osteoarthr Cartil 19:1363–1372</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller RE, Miller RJ, Malfait AM (2014) Osteoarthritis joint pain: the cytokine connection. Cytokine 70:185–193</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25066335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4254338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Min S, Wang C, Lu W, Xu Z, Shi D, Chen D, Teng H, Jiang Q (2017) Serum levels of the bone turnover markers dickkopf-1, osteoprotegerin, and TNF-alpha in knee osteoarthritis patients. Clin Rheumatol 36:2351–2358</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28676900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Min S, Shi T, Han X, Chen D, Xu Z, Shi D, Teng H, Jiang Q (2021) Serum levels of leptin, osteopontin, and sclerostin in patients with and without knee osteoarthritis. Clin Rheumatol 40:287–294</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32588275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteagudo S, Cornelis FMF, Aznar-Lopez C, Yibmantasiri P, Guns LA, Carmeliet P, Cailotto F, Lories RJ (2017) DOT1L safeguards cartilage homeostasis and protects against osteoarthritis. Nat Commun 8:15889</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28627522</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5481839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moverare-Skrtic S, Henning P, Liu X, Nagano K, Saito H, Borjesson AE, Sjogren K, Windahl SH, Farman H, Kindlund B, Engdahl C, Koskela A, Zhang FP, Eriksson EE, Zaman F, Hammarstedt A, Isaksson H, Bally M, Kassem A, Lindholm C, Sandberg O, Aspenberg P, Savendahl L, Feng JQ, Tuckermann J, Tuukkanen J, Poutanen M, Baron R, Lerner UH, Gori F, Ohlsson C (2014) Osteoblast-derived WNT16 represses osteoclastogenesis and prevents cortical bone fragility fractures. Nat Med 20:1279–1288</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25306233</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4392888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musumeci G, Aiello FC, Szychlinska MA, Di Rosa M, Castrogiovanni P, Mobasheri A (2015) Osteoarthritis in the XXIst century: risk factors and behaviours that influence disease onset and progression. Int J Mol Sci 16:6093–6112</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25785564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4394521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nalesso G, Sherwood J, Bertrand J, Pap T, Ramachandran M, De Bari C, Pitzalis C, Dell'accio F (2011) WNT-3A modulates articular chondrocyte phenotype by activating both canonical and noncanonical pathways. J Cell Biol 193:551–564</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21536751</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3087013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nalesso G, Thomas BL, Sherwood JC, Yu J, Addimanda O, Eldridge SE, Thorup AS, Dale L, Schett G, Zwerina J, Eltawil N, Pitzalis C, Dell'Accio F (2017) WNT16 antagonises excessive canonical WNT activation and protects cartilage in osteoarthritis. Ann Rheum Dis 76:218–226</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27147711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nalesso G, Thorup AS, Eldridge SE, De Palma A, Kaur A, Peddireddi K, Blighe K, Rana S, Stott B, Vincent TL, Thomas BL, Bertrand J, Sherwood J, Fioravanti A, Pitzalis C, Dell'Accio F (2021) Calcium calmodulin kinase II activity is required for cartilage homeostasis in osteoarthritis. Sci Rep 11:5682</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33707504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7952598</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nathan E, Tzahor E (2009) sFRPs: a declaration of (Wnt) independence. Nat Cell Biol 11:13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19122594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niida A, Hiroko T, Kasai M, Furukawa Y, Nakamura Y, Suzuki Y, Sugano S, Akiyama T (2004) DKK1, a negative regulator of Wnt signaling, is a target of the beta-catenin/TCF pathway. Oncogene 23:8520–8526</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15378020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh H, Chun CH, Chun JS (2012) Dkk-1 expression in chondrocytes inhibits experimental osteoarthritic cartilage destruction in mice. Arthritis Rheum 64:2568–2578</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22488261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papathanasiou I, Malizos KN, Tsezou A (2012) Bone morphogenetic protein-2-induced Wnt/beta-catenin signaling pathway activation through enhanced low-density-lipoprotein receptor-related protein 5 catabolic activity contributes to hypertrophy in osteoarthritic chondrocytes. Arthritis Res Ther 14:R82</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22513174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3446456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puig-Junoy J, Ruiz Zamora A (2015) Socio-economic costs of osteoarthritis: a systematic review of cost-of-illness studies. Semin Arthritis Rheum 44:531–541</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25511476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothbacher U, Lemaire P (2002) Creme de la Kremen of Wnt signalling inhibition. Nat Cell Biol 4:E172–E173</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12105428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roudier M, Li X, Niu QT, Pacheco E, Pretorius JK, Graham K, Yoon BR, Gong J, Warmington K, Ke HZ, Black RA, Hulme J, Babij P (2013) Sclerostin is expressed in articular cartilage but loss or inhibition does not affect cartilage remodeling during aging or following mechanical injury. Arthritis Rheum 65:721–731</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23233270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saitta B, Elphingstone J, Limfat S, Shkhyan R, Evseenko D (2019) CaMKII inhibition in human primary and pluripotent stem cell-derived chondrocytes modulates effects of TGFbeta and BMP through SMAD signaling. Osteoarthr Cartil 27:158–171</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salazar VS, Gamer LW, Rosen V (2016) BMP signalling in skeletal development, disease and repair. Nat Rev Endocrinol 12:203–221</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26893264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samarzija I, Sini P, Schlange T, Macdonald G, Hynes NE (2009) Wnt3a regulates proliferation and migration of HUVEC via canonical and non-canonical Wnt signaling pathways. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 386:449–454</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19523451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schivo S, Khurana S, Govindaraj K, Scholma J, Kerkhofs J, Zhong L, Huang X, van de Pol J, Langerak R, van Wijnen AJ, Geris L, Karperien M, Post JN (2020) ECHO, the executable CHOndrocyte: a computational model to study articular chondrocytes in health and disease. Cell Signal 68:109471</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31837466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semënov MV, He X (2000–2013) Secreted antagonists/modulators of Wnt signaling. In: Madame Curie bioscience database. Landes Bioscience, Austin</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AJ, Gidley J, Sandy JR, Perry MJ, Elson CJ, Kirwan JR, Spector TD, Doherty M, Bidwell JL, Mansell JP (2005) Haplotypes of the low-density lipoprotein receptor-related protein 5 (LRP5) gene: are they a risk factor in osteoarthritis? Osteoarthr Cartil 13:608–613</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stow JL (2004) ICAT is a multipotent inhibitor of beta-catenin. Focus on “role for ICAT in beta-catenin-dependent nuclear signaling and cadherin functions”. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol 286:C745–C746</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15001424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugita S, Hosaka Y, Okada K, Mori D, Yano F, Kobayashi H, Taniguchi Y, Mori Y, Okuma T, Chang SH, Kawata M, Taketomi S, Chikuda H, Akiyama H, Kageyama R, Chung UI, Tanaka S, Kawaguchi H, Ohba S, Saito T (2015) Transcription factor Hes1 modulates osteoarthritis development in cooperation with calcium/calmodulin-dependent protein kinase 2. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 112:3080–3085</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4364241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takamatsu A, Ohkawara B, Ito M, Masuda A, Sakai T, Ishiguro N, Ohno K (2014) Verapamil protects against cartilage degradation in osteoarthritis by inhibiting Wnt/β-catenin signaling. PLoS One 9:e92699</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24658359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3962439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorup AS, Strachan D, Caxaria S, Poulet B, Thomas BL, Eldridge SE, Nalesso G, Whiteford JR, Pitzalis C, Aigner T, Corder R, Bertrand J, Dell'Accio F (2020) ROR2 blockade as a therapy for osteoarthritis. Sci Transl Med 12(561):eaax3063</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong W, Zeng Y, Chow DHK, Yeung W, Xu J, Deng Y, Chen S, Zhao H, Zhang X, Ho KK, Qin L, Mak KK (2019) Wnt16 attenuates osteoarthritis progression through a PCP/JNK-mTORC1-PTHrP cascade. Ann Rheum Dis 78:551–561</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30745310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van den Bosch MH, Blom AB, van Lent PL, van Beuningen HM, Blaney Davidson EN, van der Kraan PM, van den Berg WB (2014) Canonical Wnt signaling skews TGF-β signaling in chondrocytes towards signaling via ALK1 and Smad 1/5/8. Cell JM 26:951–958</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Lierop AH, Hamdy NA, Hamersma H, van Bezooijen RL, Power J, Loveridge N, Papapoulos SE (2011) Patients with sclerosteosis and disease carriers: human models of the effect of sclerostin on bone turnover. J Bone Miner Res 26:2804–2811</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21786318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent TL (2020) Of mice and men: converging on a common molecular understanding of osteoarthritis. Lancet Rheumatol 2:e633–ee45</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32989436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7511206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Maltzahn J, Renaud J, Parise G, Rudnicki MA (2012) Wnt7a treatment ameliorates muscular dystrophy. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 109:20614–20619</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waller KA, Zhang LX, Elsaid KA, Fleming BC, Warman ML, Jay GD (2013) Role of lubricin and boundary lubrication in the prevention of chondrocyte apoptosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110:5852–5857</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23530215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3625316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weivoda MM, Ruan M, Hachfeld CM, Pederson L, Howe A, Davey RA, Zajac JD, Kobayashi Y, Williams BO, Westendorf JJ, Khosla S, Oursler MJ (2016) Wnt signaling inhibits osteoclast differentiation by activating canonical and noncanonical cAMP/PKA pathways. J Bone Miner Res 31:65–75</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26189772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng LH, Wang CJ, Ko JY, Sun YC, Wang FS (2010) Control of Dkk-1 ameliorates chondrocyte apoptosis, cartilage destruction, and subchondral bone deterioration in osteoarthritic knees. Arthritis Rheum 62:1393–1402</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20131282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiese KE, Nusse R, van Amerongen R (2018) Wnt signalling: conquering complexity. Development 145:dev165902</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29945986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright SC, Kozielewicz P, Kowalski-Jahn M, Petersen J, Bowin C, Slodkowicz G, Marti-Solano M, Rodríguez D, Hot B, Okashah N, Strakova K, Valnohova J, Babu MM, Lambert NA, Carlsson J, Schult G (2019) A conserved molecular switch in Class F receptorsregulates receptor activation and pathway selection. Nat Commun 10:667</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30737406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6368630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xuan F, Yano F, Mori D, Chijimatsu R, Maenohara Y, Nakamoto H, Mori Y, Makii Y, Oichi T, Taketo MM, Hojo H, Ohba S, Chung UI, Tanaka S, Saito T (2019) Wnt/beta-catenin signaling contributes to articular cartilage homeostasis through lubricin induction in the superficial zone. Arthritis Res Ther 21:247</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31771658</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6880374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Z, Zou Y, Guo XM, Tan HS, Denslin V, Yeow CH, Ren XF, Liu TM, Hui JH, Lee EH (2012) Temporal activation of beta-catenin signaling in the chondrogenic process of mesenchymal stem cells affects the phenotype of the cartilage generated. Stem Cells Dev 21:1966–1976</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuhara R, Ohta Y, Yuasa T, Kondo N, Hoang T, Addya S, Fortina P, Pacifici M, Iwamoto M, Enomoto-Iwamoto M (2011) Roles of beta-catenin signaling in phenotypic expression and proliferation of articular cartilage superficial zone cells. Lab Investig 91:1739–1752</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21968810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yazici Y, McAlindon TE, Gibofsky A, Lane NE, Clauw D, Jones M, Bergfeld J, Swearingen CJ, DiFrancesco A, Simsek I, Tambiah J, Hochberg MC (2020) Lorecivivint, a novel intra-articular CLK/DYRK1A inhibitor and Wnt pathway modulator for treatment of knee osteoarthritis: a phase 2 randomized trial. Arthritis Rheumatol 72(10):1694–1706</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7589351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yazici Y, McAlindon TE, Gibofsky A, Lane NE, Lattermann C, Skrepnik N, Swearingen CJ, Simsek I, Ghandehari H, DiFrancesco A, Gibbs J, Tambiah JRS, Hochberg MC (2021) A phase 2b randomized trial of lorecivivint, a novel intra-articular CLK2/DYRK1A inhibitor and Wnt pathway modulator for knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthr Cartil 29(5):654–666</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuasa T, Kondo N, Yasuhara R, Shimono K, Mackem S, Pacifici M, Iwamoto M, Enomoto-Iwamoto M (2009) Transient activation of Wnt/{beta}-catenin signaling induces abnormal growth plate closure and articular cartilage thickening in postnatal mice. Am J Pathol 175:1993–2003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19815716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2774063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng L, Wang W, Rong XF, Zhong Y, Jia P, Zhou GQ, Li RH (2014) Chondroprotective effects and multi-target mechanisms of Icariin in IL-1 beta-induced human SW 1353 chondrosarcoma cells and a rat osteoarthritis model. Int Immunopharmacol 18:175–181</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24295650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng HF, Tobias JH, Duncan E, Evans DM, Eriksson J, Paternoster L, Yerges-Armstrong LM, Lehtimaki T, Bergstrom U, Kahonen M, Leo PJ, Raitakari O, Laaksonen M, Nicholson GC, Viikari J, Ladouceur M, Lyytikainen LP, Medina-Gomez C, Rivadeneira F, Prince RL, Sievanen H, Leslie WD, Mellstrom D, Eisman JA, Moverare-Skrtic S, Goltzman D, Hanley DA, Jones G, Pourcain BS, Xiao Y, Timpson NJ, Smith GD, Reid IR, Ring SM, Sambrook PN, Karlsson M, Dennison EM, Kemp JP, Danoy P, Sayers A, Wilson SG, Nethander M, McCloskey E, Vandenput L, Eastell R, Liu J, Spector T, Mitchell BD, Streeten EA, Brommage R, Pettersson-Kymmer U, Brown MA, Ohlsson C, Richards JB, Lorentzon M (2012) WNT16 influences bone mineral density, cortical bone thickness, bone strength, and osteoporotic fracture risk. PLoS Genet 8:e1002745</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22792071</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3390364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou S, Ge YX, Li YX, Bao ZY, Yao C, Teng HJ, Jiang Q (2017) Accelerated development of instability-induced osteoarthritis in transgenic mice overexpressing SOST. Int J Clin Exp Pathol 10:10830–10840</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31966426</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6965855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu M, Chen M, Zuscik M, Wu Q, Wang YJ, Rosier RN, O'Keefe RJ, Chen D (2008) Inhibition of beta-catenin signaling in articular chondrocytes results in articular cartilage destruction. Arthritis Rheum 58:2053–2064</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18576323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2667964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu M, Tang D, Wu Q, Hao S, Chen M, Xie C, Rosier RN, O'Keefe RJ, Zuscik M, Chen D (2009) Activation of beta-catenin signaling in articular chondrocytes leads to osteoarthritis-like phenotype in adult beta-catenin conditional activation mice. J Bone Miner Res 24:12–21</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18767925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
