<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34580900</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-9613</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of ultrasound in medicine : official journal of the American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Ultrasound Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Incidence and Risk Factors for a Malpositioned Intrauterine Device Detected on Three-Dimensional Ultrasound Within Eight Weeks of Placement.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1525</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1536</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1525-1536</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jum.15836</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To estimate the incidence of intrauterine device (IUD) malpositioning detected on three-dimensional (3D) transvaginal ultrasound within 8 weeks of placement and identify risk factors for malpositioning.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Retrospective study of women who had an IUD placed at a large obstetrics and gynecology practice from January 1, 2015, to December 31, 2020. All patients underwent two-dimensional ultrasound at the time of insertion and routine three-dimensional ultrasound within 8 weeks. Baseline characteristics and potential risk factors were compared between women with correctly positioned and malpositioned IUDs. Odds ratios were calculated by logistic regression to identify risk factors independently associated with malpositioning.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 763 IUD placements were included, and 127 malpositioned IUDs were identified representing an overall rate of malpositioning of 16.6% (95% confidence interval [CI] 14.0-19.3) with 8.8% (95% CI 6.8-10.8) requiring removal. Patients with malpositioned IUD had higher rates of morbid obesity (13.4% versus 3.8%, adjusted odds ratio [aOR] 2.46, 95% CI 1.10-5.50), prior uterine window or rupture (9.0% versus 2.2%, aOR 2.78, 95% CI 1.06-7.30), copper IUD placement (64.2% versus 47.4%, aOR 1.99, 95% CI 1.31-3.03), and symptoms such as bleeding or pain at follow-up (35.8% versus 20.1%, aOR 2.58, 95% CI 1.67-3.98). Parity, breastfeeding, difficult insertion, and uterine size and positioning were not significant.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The incidence of malpositioned IUD within 8 weeks of placement on 3D ultrasound is 16.6%, with 8.8% requiring removal. Significant risk factors for malpositioning include morbid obesity, prior uterine window or rupture, and copper IUD placement. These findings support the importance of routine follow-up 3D ultrasound after seemingly successful IUD placement.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American Institute of Ultrasound in Medicine.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Connolly</LastName>
            <ForeName>Courtney T</ForeName>
            <Initials>CT</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5856-3074</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Science, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fox</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nathan S</ForeName>
            <Initials>NS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Science, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Maternal Fetal Medicine Associates, PLLC, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Ultrasound Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8211547</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0278-4297</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007434" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intrauterine Devices</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity, Morbid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intrauterine device</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intrauterine device malposition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-acting reversible contraception</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">three-dimensional ultrasound</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ultrasound</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>54</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34580900</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jum.15836</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Committee on Practice Bulletins-Gynecology, Long-Acting Reversible Contraception Work Group. Practice bulletin no. 186: long-acting reversible contraception: implants and intrauterine devices. Obstet Gynecol 2017; 130:e251-e269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braaten KP, Benson CB, Maurer R, Goldberg AB. Malpositioned intrauterine contraceptive devices: risk factors, outcomes, and future pregnancies. Obstet Gynecol 2011; 118:1014-1020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerkowicz SA, Fiorentino DG, Kovacs AP, Arheart KL, Verma U. Uterine structural abnormality and intrauterine device malposition: analysis of ultrasonographic and demographic variables of 517 patients. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2019; 220:183.e181-e188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moschos E, Twickler DM. Does the type of intrauterine device affect conspicuity on 2D and 3D ultrasound? AJR Am J Roentgenol 2011; 196:1439-1443.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benacerraf BR, Shipp TD, Bromley B. Three-dimensional ultrasound detection of abnormally located intrauterine contraceptive devices which are a source of pelvic pain and abnormal bleeding. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol 2009; 34:110-115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moshesh M, Saldana T, Deans E, Cooper T, Baird D. Factors associated with low-lying intrauterine devices: a cross-sectional ultrasound study in a cohort of African-American women. Contraception 2018; 98:25-29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anteby E, Revel A, Ben-Chetrit A, Rosen B, Tadmor O, Yagel S. Intrauterine device failure: relation to its location within the uterine cavity. Obstet Gynecol 1993; 81:112-114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreotti RF, Fleischer AC. Practical applications of 3D sonography in gynecologic imaging. Radiol Clin North Am 2014; 52:1201-1213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benacerraf BR. Three-dimensional volume imaging in gynecology. Obstet Gynecol Clin North Am 2019; 46:755-781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans AT, Szlachetka K, Thornburg LL. Ultrasound assessment of the intrauterine device. Obstet Gynecol Clin North Am 2019; 46:661-681.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen XY, Guo QY, Wang W, Huang LL. Three-dimensional ultrasonography versus two-dimensional ultrasonography for the diagnosis of intrauterine device malposition. Int J Gynaecol Obstet 2015; 128:157-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agacayak E, Tunc SY, Icen MS, et al. Evaluation of predisposing factors, diagnostic and treatment methods in patients with translocation of intrauterine devices. J Obstet Gynaecol Res 2015; 41:735-741.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang H, Li L, Yuan W, et al. Dimensions of the endometrial cavity and intrauterine device expulsion or removal for displacement: a nested case-control study. BJOG 2014; 121:997-1004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shipp TD, Bromley B, Benacerraf BR. The width of the uterine cavity is narrower in patients with an embedded intrauterine device (IUD) compared to a normally positioned IUD. J Ultrasound Med 2010; 29:1453-1456.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Çintesun F, Çintesun E, Esenkaya Ü, Günenc O. Uterine dimensions and intrauterine device malposition: can ultrasound predict displacement or expulsion before it happens? Arch Gynecol Obstet 2020; 302:1181-1187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson K, Ryde-Blomqvist E, Lindell K, Odlind V, Milsom I. Perforations with intrauterine devices. Report from a Swedish survey. Contraception 1998; 57:251-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wildemeersch D, Hasskamp T, Nolte K, et al. A multicenter study assessing uterine cavity width in over 400 nulliparous women seeking IUD insertion using 2D and 3D sonography. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 2016; 206:232-238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golightly E, Gebbie AE. Clinicians' views on low-lying intrauterine devices or systems. J Fam Plann Reprod Health Care 2014; 40:113-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
