<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34581911</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>09</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1435-165X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>28</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European child &amp; adolescent psychiatry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A post hoc analysis of the effect of viloxazine extended-release capsules on learning and school problems in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00787-021-01877-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Improvement in attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) symptoms vs. placebo was reported in a series of pediatric clinical trials of viloxazine extended-release capsules (viloxazine ER; Qelbree™). This post hoc analysis of those studies evaluated the effect of viloxazine ER on learning and school problems (LSPs). We used data from four Phase 3 placebo-controlled trials of 100-600 mg/day viloxazine ER (N = 1354; 6-17 years of age). LSPs were evaluated using the School domain of the Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Report (WFIRS-P-S) and the Learning Problems content scale of the Conners 3rd Edition-Parent Short Form (C3PS-LP) at baseline and end of study (≥ Week 6). ADHD symptoms were assessed weekly using the ADHD Rating Scale 5th Edition. The analyses were performed using the general linear mixed model with participant as a random effect. The responder analyses were performed using the Chi-square test. Viloxazine ER demonstrated significantly greater improvements in WFIRS-P-S (p &lt; 0.0001) and C3PS-LP (p = 0.0113) scores vs. placebo. The response rate for the WFIRS-P-S was significantly greater for viloxazine ER vs. placebo (p = 0.001), and the number needed to treat (NNT) was 10.3 (effect size 0.7). Conversely, response rates for C3PS-LP did not differ between groups (p = 0.9069). In addition to ADHD symptoms improvement demonstrated in previous studies, viloxazine ER significantly reduced LSPs in pediatric subjects with ADHD. The responder analyses and NNT estimates indicate that a substantial number of children and adolescents with ADHD treated with viloxazine ER improved in clinically assessed LSPs.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Faraone</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephen V</ForeName>
            <Initials>SV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Psychiatry and of Neuroscience and Physiology, SUNY Upstate Medical University, Syracuse, NY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gomeni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberto</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacometrica, Lieu-dit Longcol, La Fouillade, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hull</LastName>
            <ForeName>Joseph T</ForeName>
            <Initials>JT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., 9715 Key West Ave, Rockville, MD, 20850, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Busse</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gregory D</ForeName>
            <Initials>GD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., 9715 Key West Ave, Rockville, MD, 20850, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Melyan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zare</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., 9715 Key West Ave, Rockville, MD, 20850, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rubin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., 9715 Key West Ave, Rockville, MD, 20850, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nasser</LastName>
            <ForeName>Azmi</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Supernus Pharmaceuticals, Inc., 9715 Key West Ave, Rockville, MD, 20850, USA. anasser@supernus.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9212296</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1018-8827</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ADHD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Learning</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qelbree</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SPN-812</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">School</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Viloxazine</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34581911</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00787-021-01877-5</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00787-021-01877-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baweja R, Mattison RE, Waxmonsky JG (2015) Impact of attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder on school performance: what are the effects of medication? Paediatr Drugs 17(6):459–477</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40272-015-0144-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frazier TW, Youngstrom EA, Glutting JJ, Watkins MW (2007) ADHD and achievement: meta-analysis of the child, adolescent, and adult literatures and a concomitant study with college students. J Learn Disabil 40(1):49–65</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00222194070400010401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breslau J, Miller E, Joanie Chung WJ, Schweitzer JB (2011) Childhood and adolescent onset psychiatric disorders, substance use, and failure to graduate high school on time. J Psychiatr Res 45(3):295–301</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2010.06.014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fried R, Petty C, Faraone SV, Hyder LL, Day H, Biederman J (2016) Is ADHD a risk factor for high school dropout? A controlled study. J Atten Disord 20(5):383–389</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1087054712473180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galera C, Melchior M, Chastang JF, Bouvard MP, Fombonne E (2009) Childhood and adolescent hyperactivity-inattention symptoms and academic achievement 8 years later: the GAZEL Youth study. Psychol Med 39(11):1895–1906</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291709005510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murray DW, Molina BS, Glew K, Houck P, Greiner A, Fong D et al (2014) Prevalence and characteristics of school services for high school students with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. School Ment Health 6(4):264–278</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12310-014-9128-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleming M, Fitton CA, Steiner MFC, McLay JS, Clark D, King A et al (2017) Educational and health outcomes of children treated for attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. JAMA Pediatr 171(7):e170691</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2017.0691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagy P, Hage A, Coghill DR, Caballero B, Adeyi B, Anderson CS et al (2016) Functional outcomes from a head-to-head, randomized, double-blind trial of lisdexamfetamine dimesylate and atomoxetine in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder and an inadequate response to methylphenidate. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry 25(2):141–149</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00787-015-0718-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shang CY, Shih HH, Pan YL, Lin HY, Gau SS (2020) Comparative efficacy of methylphenidate and atomoxetine on social adjustment in youths with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol 30(3):148–158</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2019.0139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown RT, Perwien A, Faries DE, Kratochvil CJ, Vaughan BS (2006) Atomoxetine in the management of children with ADHD: effects on quality of life and school functioning. Clin Pediatr (Phila) 45(9):819–827</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0009922806294219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stein MA, Sikirica V, Weiss MD, Robertson B, Lyne A, Newcorn JH (2015) Does guanfacine extended release impact functional impairment in children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder? Results from a randomized controlled trial. CNS Drugs 29(11):953–962</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-015-0291-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilens TE, Robertson B, Sikirica V, Harper L, Young JL, Bloomfield R et al (2015) A randomized, placebo-controlled trial of guanfacine extended release in adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry 54(11):916–25 e2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2015.08.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coghill DR, Werner-Kiechle T, Farahbakhshian S, Bliss C, Robertson B, Huss M (2020) Functional impairment outcomes in clinical trials of different ADHD medications: post hoc responder analyses and baseline subgroup analyses. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry 30:809–825</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00787-020-01586-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banaschewski T, Soutullo C, Lecendreux M, Johnson M, Zuddas A, Hodgkins P et al (2013) Health-related quality of life and functional outcomes from a randomized, controlled study of lisdexamfetamine dimesylate in children and adolescents with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder. CNS Drugs 27(10):829–840</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-013-0095-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jangmo A, Stalhandske A, Chang Z, Chen Q, Almqvist C, Feldman I et al (2019) Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder, school performance, and effect of medication. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry 58(4):423–432</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2018.11.014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbaresi WJ, Katusic SK, Colligan RC, Weaver AL, Jacobsen SJ (2007) Modifiers of long-term school outcomes for children with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: does treatment with stimulant medication make a difference? Results from a population-based study. J Dev Behav Pediatr 28(4):274–287</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DBP.0b013e3180cabc28</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu C, Garcia-Olivares J, Candler S, Schwabe S, Maletic V (2020) New insights into the mechanism of action of viloxazine: serotonin and norepinephrine modulating properties. J Exp Pharmacol 12:285–300</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JEP.S256586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, Fry N, Hull JT, Chowdhry F et al (2020) A phase III, randomized, placebo-controlled trial to assess the efficacy and safety of once-daily SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in the treatment of attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder in school-age children. Clin Ther 42(8):1452–1466</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2020.05.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, Fry N, Hull JT, Busse GD et al (2021) A phase 3, placebo-controlled trial of once-daily viloxazine extended-release capsules in adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. J Clin Psychopharmacol 41(4):370–380</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/JCP.0000000000001404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, Fry N, Hull JT, Chowdhry F et al (2021) Once-daily SPN-812 200 and 400 mg in the treatment of ADHD in school-aged children: a phase III randomized, controlled trial. Clin Ther 43(4):684–700</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2021.01.027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Liranso T, Adewole T, Fry N, Hull JT, Chowdhry F et al (2021) A phase 3 placebo-controlled trial of once-daily 400-mg and 600-mg SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) in adolescents with ADHD. Psychopharmacol Bull 51(2):43–64</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34092822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Gomeni R, Hull JT, Busse GD, Melyan Z, Rubin J, Nasser A (2021) Executive function outcome of treatment with viloxazine extended-release capsules in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: A post-hoc analysis of four randomized clinical trials. Paediatr Drugs. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40272-021-00470-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coghill DR, Seth S, Pedroso S, Usala T, Currie J, Gagliano A (2014) Effects of methylphenidate on cognitive functions in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder: evidence from a systematic review and a meta-analysis. Biol Psychiatry 76(8):603–615</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2013.10.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biederman J, Monuteaux MC, Doyle AE, Seidman LJ, Wilens TE, Ferrero F et al (2004) Impact of executive function deficits and attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) on academic outcomes in children. J Consult Clin Psychol 72(5):757–766</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-006X.72.5.757</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang HL, Gau SS (2014) Impact of executive functions on school and peer functions in youths with ADHD. Res Dev Disabil 35(5):963–972</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ridd.2014.02.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasser A, Hull JT, Liranso T, Busse GD, Melyan Z, Childress A et al (2021) The effect of viloxazine extended-release capsules on functional impairments associated with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) in children and adolescents in four phase 3 placebo-controlled trials. Neuropsychiatric Dis Treat 17:1751–1762. https://doi.org/10.2147/NDT.S312011 . eCollection 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajria K, Kosinski M, Sikirica V, Huss M, Livote E, Reilly K et al (2015) Psychometric validation of the Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Report Form in children and adolescents with attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder. Health Qual Life Outcomes 13:184</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-015-0379-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson T, Lloyd A, Joseph A, Weiss M (2017) The Weiss Functional Impairment Rating Scale-Parent Form for assessing ADHD: evaluating diagnostic accuracy and determining optimal thresholds using ROC analysis. Qual Life Res 26(7):1879–1885</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-017-1514-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sparrow EP (2010) Essentials of Conners behavior assessments. Wiley, Hoboken</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunnally JC (1978) Psychometric theory. McGraw Hill, New York</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conners CK, Pitkanen J, Rzepa SR (2011) Conners 3rd Edition (Conners 3; Conners 2008). In: Kreutzer JS, DeLuca J, Caplan B (eds) Encyclopedia of clinical neuropsychology. Springer, New York, pp 675–678</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-0-387-79948-3_1534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J (1988) Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences, 2nd edn. Routledge, New York</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss M, Childress A, Mattingly G, Nordbrock E, Kupper RJ, Adjei AL (2018) Relationship between symptomatic and functional improvement and remission in a treatment response to stimulant trial. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol 28(8):521–529</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2017.0166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens J, Johannes LM, Karpenko V (2009) The relation between change in symptoms and functioning in children with ADHD receiving school-based mental health services. Sch Ment Heal 1:183–195</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12310-009-9020-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faraone SV, Gomeni R, Hull JT, Busse GD, Melyan Z, O’Neal W et al (2021) Early response to SPN-812 (viloxazine extended-release) can predict efficacy outcome in pediatric subjects with ADHD: a machine learning post-hoc analysis of four randomized clinical trials. Psychiatry Res 296:113664</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
