<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34599507</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1930-7837</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>86</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of dental education</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Dent Educ</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A comparison of video-based and slide-based teaching before hands-on rubber dam application: A quantitative and qualitative study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>334</StartPage>
          <EndPage>342</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>334-342</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jdd.12800</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE/OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Instructional videos may demonstrate the execution of complex clinical procedures and the cooperation between members of the dental team better than traditional slide-based teaching materials. The aim of the present study was to compare the effect of a procedural video on student ratings to a traditional still-image-based presentation in a course on rubber dam application.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In a randomized, double-blind, parallel arm design, participants (46 dental students) completed a seven-item, five-step Likert-scale questionnaire at baseline (t1), after a video-based or slide-based demonstration of rubber dam application (t2) and after hands-on training (t3). The students' judgement on the benefits of rubber dam (items 1-3), their motivation to use rubber dam (item 4), their self-efficacy (items 5-6) and their expected use of the teaching material (item 7) were assessed. Changes in the students' individual answers were analyzed for each item and comparison between intervention groups made. Moreover, the impact of the teaching format on in-class discussions was analyzed qualitatively using a thematic approach RESULTS: Both interventions arose comparable significant improvement in the students' Likert-scale ratings from t1 to t2, and again from t2 to t3. No significant differences between intervention groups were found in the students' ratings or in the qualitative analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Procedural videos have proven to be a valuable learning aid in a variety of teaching formats, but in the context of a live lecture, they may not constitute an improvement over traditional text- and still-image-based presentations.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American Dental Education Association.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kruse</LastName>
            <ForeName>Casper</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0317-093X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section for Oral Radiology, Department of Dentistry and Oral Health, Aarhus University, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schlafer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2463-1926</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section for Oral Ecology and Caries Control, Department of Dentistry and Oral Health, Aarhus University, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pedersen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kamilla</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Educational Development, Aarhus University, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Dent Educ</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8000150</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-0337</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007858" MajorTopicYN="Y">Learning</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009042" MajorTopicYN="N">Motivation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016733" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rubber Dams</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013663" MajorTopicYN="N">Teaching</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rubber dam</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dental undergraduates</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">education</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">instructional film and video</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lecture</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>23</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34599507</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jdd.12800</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brockfeld T, Müller B, de Laffolie J. Video versus live lecture courses: a comparative evaluation of lecture types and results. Med Educ Online. 2018;23(1):1555434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paegle RD, Wilkinson EJ, Donnelly MB. Videotaped vs traditional lectures for medical students. Med Educ. 1980;14(6):387-393.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selvig D, Holaday LW, Purkiss J, Hortsch M. Correlating students’ educational background, study habits, and resource usage with learning success in medical histology. Anat Sci Educ. 2015;8(1):1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schreiber BE, Fukuta J, Gordon F. Live lecture versus video podcast in undergraduate medical education: a randomised controlled trial. BMC Med Educ. 2010;10(1):387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spickard A, Alrajeh N, Cordray D, Gigante J. Learning about screening using an online or live lecture. J Gen Intern Med. 2002;17(7):540-545.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daud A, Bagria A, Shah K, Puryer J. Should undergraduate lectures be compulsory? The views of dental and medical students from a UK university. D J. 2017;5(2):15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alqahtani ND, Al-Jewair T, AL-Moammar K, Albarakati SF, ALkofide EA. Live demonstration versus procedural video: a comparison of two methods for teaching an orthodontic laboratory procedure. BMC Med Educ. 2015;15(1):133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aragon CE, Zibrowski EM. Does exposure to a procedural video enhance preclinical dental student performance in fixed prosthodontics?. J Dent Educ. 2008;72(1):67-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fakhry A, Dehkordi-Vakil FH. Video-Assisted clinical instruction in dentistry (VACID) enhances real-time visualisation of clinical procedures. Eur J Dent Educ. 2007;11(4):238-244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorucu-Coskuner H, Atik E, Taner T. Comparison of live-video and video demonstration methods in clinical orthodontics education. J Dent Educ. 2019;83:e1-e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikzad S, Azari A, Mahgoli H, Akhoundi N. Effect of a procedural video CD and study guide on the practical fixed prosthodontic performance of Iranian dental students. J Dent Educ. 2012;76(3):354-359.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Packer ME, Rogers JO, Coward TJ, Newman PS, Wakeley R. A comparison between videotaped and live demonstrations, for the teaching of removable partial denture procedures. Eur J Dent Educ. 2001;5(1):17-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson PB, Lee JW. The use of real time video magnification for the pre-clinical teaching of crown preparations. Br Dent J. 2001;190(9):506-510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bock A, Modabber A, Kniha K, Lemos M, Rafai N, Hölzle F. Blended learning modules for lectures on oral and maxillofacial surgery. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2018;56(10):956-961.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slaven C, Wells M, DeSchepper E, Dormois L, Vinall C, Douglas K. Effectiveness of and dental student satisfaction with three teaching methods for behavior guidance techniques in pediatric dentistry. J Dent Educ. 2019;83(8):966-972.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramlogan S, Raman V, Sweet J. A comparison of two forms of teaching instruction: video vs. live lecture for education in clinical periodontology. Eur J Dent Educ. 2014;18(1):31-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77-101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halcomb EJ, Davidson PM. Is verbatim transcription of interview data always necessary? Appl Nurs Res. 2006;19(1):38-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kvale S. Interviews: An Introduction to Qualitative Research Interviewing. 1st ed. SAGE Publications; 1996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>StataCorp LP. Stata Statistical Software: Release 14, College Station, TX, USA; 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noverati N, Naro GR, Fischer RJ, Thompson BM. Using video and virtual patients in problem-based learning: a scoping review. Med Sci Educ. 2020;30(4):1685-1691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen MS, Horrocks EN, Evans RD. Video versus lecture: effective alternatives for orthodontic auxiliary training. Br J Orthod. 1998;25(3):191-195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Price L, Kirkwood A. Enhancing Professional Learning and Teaching through Technology: A Synthesis of Evidence-Based Practice among Teachers in Higher Education. Higher Education Academy; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong G, Apthorpe HC, Ruiz K, Nanayakkara S. An innovative educational approach in using instructional videos to teach dental local anaesthetic skills. Eur J Dent Educ. 2019;23(1):28-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalwitzki M, Meller C, Beyer C. Does teaching method affect students’ perceptions regarding communication patterns in pediatric dentistry? A comparison of lecture and video methods. J Dent Educ. 2011;75(8):1084-1091.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schönwetter DJ, Gareau-Wilson N, Cunha RS, Mello I. Assessing the impact of voice-over screen-captured presentations delivered online on dental students’ learning. J Dent Educ. 2016;80(2):141-148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen K. Preparing to Meet the Patient. Using Video Cases for Teaching Clinical Psychiatry: A Liminal Theory Perspective. 1st ed. Aarhus University; 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlafer S, Pedersen K, Jørgensen JN, Kruse C. Hands-on live demonstration vs. video-supported demonstration of an aesthetic composite restoration in undergraduate dental teaching. J Dent Educ. 2021;85(6):802-811.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggs JB, Tang CS-k. Teaching for Quality Learning at University: What the Student Does. 4th ed. McGraw-Hill/Society for Research into Higher Education/Open University Press; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farooq I, Al-Jandan BA. Effect of video triggering during conventional lectures on final grades of dental students in an oral biology course: a two-year retrospective study. J Dent Educ. 2015;79(12):1467-1470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kruger J, Dunning D. Unskilled and unaware of it: how difficulties in recognizing one's own incompetence lead to inflated self-assessments. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1999;77(6):1121-1134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
