<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34590711</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-8749</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>64</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Developmental medicine and child neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dev Med Child Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of antiseizure medication for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a systematic review and network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>305</StartPage>
          <EndPage>313</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>305-313</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/dmcn.15072</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM">To compare and rank the efficacy and safety of antiseizure medication (ASM) in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (LGS).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD">We included randomized controlled trials (RCTs) assessing the efficacy of ASM for LGS compared with placebo or with each other. The efficacy and safety were reported in terms of an at least 50% monthly seizure frequency reduction in drop seizures, dropout, and serious adverse events. Outcomes were ranked according to the surface under the cumulative ranking curve (SUCRA).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of eight RCTs with 1171 patients were included, involving six ASMs: lamotrigine, rufinamide, cannabidiol, topiramate, clobazam, and felbamate. The calculated SUCRA showed that rufinamide, cannabidiol, and topiramate had the highest probability of achieving a response; however, no significant differences were found among these treatments. Cannabidiol, topiramate, and rufinamide were more likely to result in dropouts; moreover, a significantly greater percentage of patients receiving cannabidiol experienced premature discontinuation as compared to placebo, clobazam, and lamotrigine.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION">All ASMs showed a significantly higher response rate than placebo. SUCRA ranking demonstrated that rufinamide and cannabidiol are more efficacious than other treatments in reducing drop seizures. However, there was no significant difference between these treatments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Mac Keith Press.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lanlan</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9856-8977</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yancheng Maternal and Children's Health Hospital, Yancheng City, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yancheng Maternal and Children's Health Hospital, Yancheng City, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chengzhong</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Yancheng Maternal and Children's Health Hospital, Yancheng City, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Dev Med Child Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0006761</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0012-1622</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014230">Triazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>19GBJ60SN5</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D002185">Cannabidiol</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>WFW942PR79</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C079703">rufinamide</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="Y">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002185" MajorTopicYN="N">Cannabidiol</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D065768" MajorTopicYN="N">Lennox Gastaut Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017063" MajorTopicYN="Y">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014230" MajorTopicYN="N">Triazoles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>48</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34590711</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.15072</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heiskala H. Community-based study of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 1997; 38: 526-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durá-Travé T, Yoldi-Petri ME, Gallinas-Victoriano F. Epilepsy in children in Navarre, Spain: epileptic seizure types and epileptic syndromes. J Child Neurol 2007; 22: 823-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trevathan E, Murphy CC, Yeargin-Allsopp M. Prevalence and descriptive epidemiology of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome among Atlanta children. Epilepsia 1997; 38: 1283-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arzimanoglou A, French J, Blume WT, Cross JH, Ernst J-P, Feucht M, et al. Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a consensus approach on diagnosis, assessment, management, and trial methodology. Lancet Neurol 2009; 8: 82-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asadi-Pooya AA. Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a comprehensive review. Neurol Sci 2018; 39: 403-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Döring JH, Lampert A, Hoffmann GF, Ries M. Thirty years of orphan drug legislation and the development of drugs to treat rare seizure conditions: a cross sectional analysis. PLoS One 2016; 11: e0161660.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Purcarin G, Ng Y-T. Experience in the use of clobazam in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Ther Adv Neurol Disord 2014; 7: 169-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Los Reyes EC, Sharp GB, Williams JP, Hale SE. Levetiracetam in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Pediatr Neurol 2004; 30: 254-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dulac O. Epileptic encephalopathy. Epilepsia 2001; 42(Suppl 3): 23-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huber B, Bömmel W, Hauser I, Horstmann V, Liem S, May Th, et al. Efficacy and tolerability of levetiracetam in patients with therapy-resistant epilepsy and learning disabilities. Seizure 2004; 13: 168-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtahara S. Zonisamide in the management of epilepsy-Japanese experience. Epilepsy Res 2006; 68(Suppl 2): S25-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang HC, Kim YJ, Kim DW, Kim HD. Efficacy and safety of the ketogenic diet for intractable childhood epilepsy: Korean multicentric experience. Epilepsia 2005; 46: 272-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lancman G, Virk M, Shao H, Mazumdar M, Greenfield JP, Weinstein S, et al. Vagus nerve stimulation vs. corpus callosotomy in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a meta-analysis. Seizure 2013; 22: 3-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Douglass LM, Salpekar J. Surgical options for patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2014; 55(Suppl 4): 21-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldsmith IL, Zupanc ML, Buchhalter JR. Long-term seizure outcome in 74 patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: effects of incorporating MRI head imaging in defining the cryptogenic subgroup. Epilepsia 2000; 41: 395-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Douglass LM. Conclusions: long-term management of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: future directions. Epilepsia 2011; 52(Suppl 5): 28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosati A, Ilvento L, Lucenteforte E, Pugi A, Crescioli G, McGreevy KS, et al. Comparative efficacy of antiepileptic drugs in children and adolescents: a network meta-analysis. Epilepsia 2017; 59: 297-314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med 2015; 162: 777-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ClinicalTrials.gov. https://clinicaltrials.gov. Accessed 22 Jun 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. International controlled trials registry. https://www.who.int/clinical-trials-registry-platform. Accessed 22 Jun 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, Gøtzsche PC, Juni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration’s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2011; 343: 889-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Caldwell DM, Ades AE. Checking consistency in mixed treatment comparison meta-analysis. Stat Med 2010; 29: 932-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salanti G, Ades AE, Ioannidis JPA. Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol 2011; 64: 63-171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaimani A, Higgins JPT, Mavridis D, Spyridonos P, Salanti G. Graphical tools for network meta-analysis in STATA. PLoS One 2013; 8: e76654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaimani A, Salanti G. Using network meta-analysis to evaluate the existence of small-study effects in a network of interventions. Res Synth Methods 2012; 3: 161-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MJ, Rosenfeld WE, Vazquez B, Sachdeo R, Perdomo C, Mann A, et al. Rufinamide for the adjunctive treatment of partial seizures in adults and adolescents: a randomized placebo-controlled trial. Epilepsia 2009; 50: 1899-1909.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conry JA, Ng Y-T, Paolicchi JM, Kernitsky L, Mitchell WG, Ritter FJ, et al. Clobazam in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2009; 50: 1158-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eriksson A-S, Nergårdh A, Hoppu K. The efficacy of lamotrigine in children and adolescents with refractory generalized epilepsy: a randomized, double-blind, crossover study. Epilepsia 1998; 39: 495-501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaraba S, Santamarina E, Miró J, Toledo M, Molins A, Burcet J, et al. Rufinamide in children and adults in routine clinical practice. Acta Neurol Scand 2017; 135: 122-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen PK. Felbamate in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 1994; 35(Suppl 5): S54-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SH, Eun S-H, Kang H-C, Kwon EJ, Byeon JH, Lee Y-M, et al. Rufinamide as an adjuvant treatment in children with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Seizure 2012; 21: 288-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Schoonjans A-S, Gammaitoni AR, Galer BS, Ceulemans B. A pilot, open-label study of the effectiveness and tolerability of low-dose ZX008 (fenfluramine HCl) in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia 2018; 59: 1881-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Long-term safety and seizure outcome in Japanese patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome receiving adjunctive rufinamide therapy: an open-label study following a randomized clinical trial. Epilepsy Res 2016; 121: 1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeda. A Phase 2, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study to evaluate the efficacy, safety, and tolerability of TAK-935 as an adjunctive therapy in pediatric patients with developmental and/or epileptic encephalopathies. clinicaltrials.gov; 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03650452. Accessed 19 Jan 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zogenix International Limited, Inc., a subsidiary of Zogenix, Inc. A two-part study of zx008 in children and adults with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (LGS); Part 1: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of two fixed doses of ZX008 (Fenfluramine Hydrochloride) oral solution as adjunctive therapy for seizures in children and adults with LGS, followed by Part 2: an open-label extension to assess long-term safety of ZX008 in children and adults with LGS. clinicaltrials.gov; 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03355209. Accessed 19 Jan 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisai Inc. A multicenter, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial with an open-label extension phase of perampanel as adjunctive treatment in subjects at least 2 years of age with inadequately controlled seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. clinicaltrials.gov; 2020. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02834793. Accessed 19 Jan 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Cross JH, Villanueva V, Wirrell EC, Privitera M, et al. Effect of cannabidiol on drop seizures in the Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome. N Engl J Med 2018; 378: 1888-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felbamate Study Group in Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome. Efficacy of felbamate in childhood epileptic encephalopathy (Lennox-Gastaut syndrome). N Engl J Med 1993; 328: 29-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Motte J, Trevathan E, Arvidsson JF, Barrera MN, Mullens EL, Manasco P. Lamotrigine for generalized seizures associated with the Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Lamictal Lennox-Gastaut Study Group. N Engl J Med 1997; 337: 1807-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Sachdeo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Rufinamide for generalized seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Neurology 2008; 70: 1950-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng YT, Conry JA, Drummond R, Stolle J, Weinberg MA. OV-1012 Study Investigators. Randomized, phase III study results of clobazam in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Neurology 2011; 77: 1473-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Rufinamide as an adjunctive therapy for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial in Japan. Epilepsy Res 2014; 108: 1627-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachdeo RC, Glauser TA, Ritter F, Reife R, Lim P, Pledger G. A double-blind, randomized trial of topiramate in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Topiramate YL Study Group. Neurology 1999; 52: 1882-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Marsh ED, French JA, Mazurkiewicz-Beldzinska M, Benbadis SR, Joshi C, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (GWPCARE4): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet 2018; 391: 1085-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verrotti A, Striano P, Iapadre G, Zagaroli L, Bonanni P, Coppola G, et al. The pharmacological management of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome and critical literature review. Seizure 2018; 63: 17-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borrelli S, El Tahry R. Therapeutic approach to Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a systematic review. Acta Neurol Belg 2019; 119: 315-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hancock EC, Cross JH. Treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2013; 2013: CD003277.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mbuagbaw L, Rochwerg B, Jaeschke R, Heels-Andsell D, Alhazzani W, Thabane L, et al. Approaches to interpreting and choosing the best treatments in network meta-analyses. Syst Rev 2017; 6: 79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
