<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34593713</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-2677</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>38</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <MedlineDate>2022 May-Jun 01</MedlineDate>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ophthalmic plastic and reconstructive surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Optic Nerve Head Vessel Density Changes from Graves' Disease without TED to TED Dysthyroid Optic Neuropathy: Does Optic Nerve Head Ischemia Play a Role?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>250</StartPage>
          <EndPage>257</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>250-257</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/IOP.0000000000002046</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">To compare the retinal peripapillary capillary (RPC) vessel density (VD) between 5 groups of patients on the spectrum of thyroid eye disease (TED).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD">This is a prospective comparative study looking at 5 groups of patients who were consecutively included from January 2018 to March 2021. They were composed of: Healthy volunteers (39 eyes and 20 subjects), patients with Graves' disease without TED (26 eyes and 13 patients), mild TED (28 eyes and 14 patients), moderate-severe TED (30 eyes and 17 patients), and TED with dysthyroid optic neuropathy (DON) (21 eyes and 12 patients). Ocular and periocular examination, visual field indices, RPC-VD (with optical coherence tomography angiography), and retinal nerve fiber layer, and macular ganglion cell complex thickness were recorded.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULT">An initial insignificant (0.5 &lt; p &lt; 0.9) rise in the peripapillary-VD (pp-VD) and whole image-VD (wi-VD) from the healthy subject to the Graves' disease without TED was followed by a significant (p = 0.001) fall in RPC-VD in different severity grades of the TED. Paired comparison between the 5 groups showed that the statistically significant fall from the Graves' disease group occurred in the moderate-severe and DON groups (0.001 ≤ p ≤ 0.04). No variable significantly affected the VD (0.08 ≤ p ≤ 0.9). A lower wi-VD and pp-VD were significantly (0.001 ≤ p ≤ 0.009) correlated with the impaired optic nerve functional and structural tests. The sensitivity and specificity of wi-VD (81% and 76%) and pp-VD (69% and 71%) for detecting the DON were statistically significant (p &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Despite an insignificant rise in the wi- and pp-VD from the healthy volunteers to the patients with Graves' disease without TED, VD showed a declining trend in the course of patients with TED, which was statistically significant in the moderate-severe TED and DON groups.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 The American Society of Ophthalmic Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abdolalizadeh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Parya</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation> Eye Research Center, The Five Senses Institute, Rassoul Akram Hospital, Iran University of Medical Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kashkouli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohsen Bahmani</ForeName>
            <Initials>MB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation> Eye Research Center, The Five Senses Institute, Rassoul Akram Hospital, Iran University of Medical Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moradpasandi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Farideh</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation> Eye Research Center, The Five Senses Institute, Rassoul Akram Hospital, Iran University of Medical Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Falavarjani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Khalil Ghasemi</ForeName>
            <Initials>KG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation> Eye Research Center, The Five Senses Institute, Rassoul Akram Hospital, Iran University of Medical Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mirshahi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Reza</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation> Eye Research Center, The Five Senses Institute, Rassoul Akram Hospital, Iran University of Medical Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Akbarian</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shadi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation> Eye Research Center, The Five Senses Institute, Rassoul Akram Hospital, Iran University of Medical Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8508431</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0740-9303</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005451" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescein Angiography</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006111" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graves Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D049970" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graves Ophthalmopathy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007511" MajorTopicYN="N">Ischemia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009898" MajorTopicYN="Y">Optic Disk</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018917" MajorTopicYN="Y">Optic Neuropathy, Ischemic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012171" MajorTopicYN="N">Retinal Vessels</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D041623" MajorTopicYN="N">Tomography, Optical Coherence</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34593713</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/IOP.0000000000002046</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00002341-202205000-00005</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konuk O, Onaran Z, Ozhan Oktar S, et al. Intraocular pressure and superior ophthalmic vein blood flow velocity in Graves’ orbitopathy: relation with the clinical features. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2009;247:1555–1559.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goncalves ACP, Gebrim EMMS, Monteiro MLR. Imaging studies for diagnosing Graves orbitopathy and dysthyroid optic neuropathy. Clincs (San Paulo). 2012;67:1327–1334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walasik-Szemplińska D, Pauk-Domańska M, Sanocka U, et al. Doppler imaging of orbital vessels in the assessment of the activity and severity of thyroid-associated orbitopathy. J Ultrason. 2015;15:388–397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perri P, Campa C, Costagliola C, et al. Increased retinal blood flow in patients with active Graves’ ophthalmopathy. Curr Eye Res. 2007;32:985–990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yarmohammadi A, Zangwill LM, Diniz-Filho A, et al. Peripapillary and macular vessel density in patients with glaucoma and single-hemifield visual field defect. Ophthalmology. 2017;124:709–719.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang T, Xiao W, Ye H, et al. Peripapillary and macular vessel density in dysthyroid optic neuropathy: an optical coherence tomography angiography study. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2019;60:1863–1869.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henkind P. Radial peripapillary capillaries of the retina. I. Anatomy: human and comparative. Br J Ophthalmol. 1967;51:115–123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fard MA, Yadegari S, Ghahvechian H, et al. Optical coherence tomography angiography of a pale optic disc in demyelinating optic neuritis and ischemic optic neuropathy. J Neuroophthalmol. 2019;39:339–344.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fard MA, Suwan Y, Moghimi S, et al. Pattern of peripapillary capillary density loss in ischemic optic neuropathy compared to that in primary open-angle glaucoma. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0189237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaier ED, Wang M, Gilbert AL, et al. Quantitative analysis of optical coherence tomographic angiography (OCT-A) in patients with non-arteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy (NAION) corresponds to visual function. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0199793.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hata M, Oishi A, Muraoka Y, et al. Structural and functional analyses in nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy: optical coherence tomography angiography study. J Neuroophthalmol. 2017;37:140–148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y, Tu Y, Wu C, et al. Reduced macular inner retinal thickness and microvascular density in the early stage of patients with dysthyroid optic neuropathy. Eye Vis (Lond). 2020;7:16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jamshidian_Tehrani M, Mahdizad Z, Kasaei A, et al. Early macular and peripapillary vasculature dropout in active thyroid eye disease. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalm. 2019;257:2533–2540.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akpolat C, Kurt MM, Yilmaz M, et al. Analysis of foveal and parafoveal microvascular density and retinal vessel caliber alteration in inactive Graves’ ophthalmopathy. J Ophthalmol. 2020;2020:7643737.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis KT, Bullock JR, Drumright RT, et al. Changes in peripapillary blood vessel density in Graves’ orbitopathy after orbital decompression surgery as measured by optical coherence tomography angiography. Orbit. 2019;38:87–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye L, Zhou SS, Yang WL, et al. Retinal microvasculature alteration in active thyroid-associated ophthalmopathy. Endocr Pract. 2018;24:658–667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mihailovic N, Lahme L, Rosenberger F, et al. Altered retinal perfusion in patients with inactive graves ophthalmopathy using optical coherence tomography angiography. Endocr Pract. 2020;26:312–317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartalena L, Baldeschi L, Dickinson A, et al.; European Group on Graves’ Orbitopathy (EUGOGO). Consensus statement of the European Group on Graves’ orbitopathy (EUGOGO) on management of GO. Eur J Endocrinol. 2008;158:273–285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mourits MP, Prummel MF, Wiersinga WM, et al. Clinical activity score as a guide in the management of patients with Graves’ ophthalmopathy. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf). 1997;47:9–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercé J, Ferrás S, Oltra C, et al. Cardiovascular abnormalities in hyperthyroidism: a prospective Doppler echocardiographic study. Am J Med. 2005;118:126–131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurioka Y, Inaba M, Kawagishi T, et al. Increased retinal blood flow in patients with Graves’ disease: influence of thyroid function and ophthalmopathy. Eur J Endocrinol. 2001;144:99–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saeed P, Tavakoli Rad S, Bisschop PHLT. Dysthyroid optic neuropathy. Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg. 2018;34(4S suppl 1):60–67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blandford AD, Zhang D, Chundury RV, et al. Dysthyroid optic neuropathy: update on pathogenesis, diagnosis, and management. Expert Rev Ophthalmol. 2017;12:111–121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu CH, Lee JK, Keng HM, et al. Hyperthyroidism is associated with higher plasma endothelin-1 concentrations. Exp Biol Med (Maywood). 2006;231:1040–1043.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright Mayes E, Cole ED, Dang S, et al. Optical coherence tomography angiography in nonarteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy. J Neuroophthalmol. 2017;37:358–364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forte R, Bonavolontà P, Vassallo P. Evaluation of retinal nerve fiber layer with optic nerve tracking optical coherence tomography in thyroid-associated orbitopathy. Ophthalmologica. 2010;224:116–121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konieczka K, Flammer AJ, Todorova M, et al. Retinitis pigmentosa and ocular blood flow. EPMA J. 2012;3:17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jia Y, Simonett JM, Wang J, et al. Wide-field OCT angiography investigation of the relationship between radial peripapillary capillary plexus density and nerve fiber layer thickness. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2017;58:5188–5194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
