<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34605203</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-8494</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>305</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Anatomical record (Hoboken, N.J. : 2007)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Nuclear organization of serotonergic neurons in the brainstems of a lar gibbon and a chimpanzee.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1500</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1515</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1500-1515</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ar.24795</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>In the current study, we detail, through the analysis of immunohistochemically stained sections, the morphology and nuclear parcellation of the serotonergic neurons present in the brainstem of a lar gibbon and a chimpanzee. In general, the neuronal morphology and nuclear organization of the serotonergic system in the brains of these two species of apes follow that observed in a range of Eutherian mammals and are specifically very similar to that observed in other species of primates. In both of the apes studied, the serotonergic nuclei could be readily divided into two distinct groups, a rostral and a caudal cluster, which are found from the level of the decussation of the superior cerebellar peduncle to the spinomedullary junction. The rostral cluster is comprised of the caudal linear, supralemniscal, and median raphe nuclei, as well as the six divisions of the dorsal raphe nuclear complex. The caudal cluster contains several distinct nuclei and nuclear subdivisions, including the raphe magnus nucleus and associated rostral and caudal ventrolateral (CVL) serotonergic groups, the raphe pallidus, and raphe obscurus nuclei. The one deviation in organization observed in comparison to other primate species is an expansion of both the number and distribution of neurons belonging to the lateral division of the dorsal raphe nucleus in the chimpanzee. It is unclear whether this expansion occurs in humans, thus at present, this expansion sets the chimpanzee apart from other primates studied to date.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American Association for Anatomy.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Williams</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victoria M</ForeName>
            <Initials>VM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, Republic of South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bhagwandin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adhil</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, Republic of South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Clinical Anatomy and Biological Anthropology, Department of Human Biology, University of Cape Town, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Swiegers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jordan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, Republic of South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bertelsen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mads F</ForeName>
            <Initials>MF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Zoo and Wild Animal Health, Copenhagen Zoo, Frederiksberg, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hård</LastName>
            <ForeName>Therese</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Borås Zoo, Borås, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sherwood</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chet C</ForeName>
            <Initials>CC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anthropology and Center for the Advanced Study of Human Paleobiology, The George Washington University, Washington, District of Columbia, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manger</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul R</ForeName>
            <Initials>PR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1881-2854</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, Republic of South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101292775</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1932-8486</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>333DO1RDJY</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D012701">Serotonin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000630435">Hylobates lar</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001933" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Stem</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000033" MajorTopicYN="N">anatomy &amp; histology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006922" MajorTopicYN="N">Hylobates</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008322" MajorTopicYN="N">Mammals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002679" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pan troglodytes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059326" MajorTopicYN="Y">Serotonergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012701" MajorTopicYN="N">Serotonin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">5-hydroxytryptamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ape</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain evolution</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunohistochemistry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primates</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serotonin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34605203</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.24795</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azmitia, E. C., &amp; Gannon, P. J. (1986). The primate serotonergic system: A review of human and animal studies and a report on Macaca fascicularis. Advances in Neurology, 43, 407-468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baker, K. G., Halliday, G. M., &amp; Törk, I. (1990). Cytoarchitecture of the human dorsal raphe nucleus. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 301, 147-161 https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903010202</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakewell, M. A., Shi, P., &amp; Zhang, J. (2007). More genes underwent positive selection in chimpanzee evolution than in human evolution. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 104, 7489-7494. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0701705104</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertelsen, M. F. (2018). Issues surrounding surplus animals in zoos. In R. E. Miller, N. Lamberski, &amp; P. Calle (Eds.), Fowler's zoo and wild animal medicine, current therapy (Vol. 9, pp. 134-137). Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bjarkam, C. R., Sorensen, J. C., &amp; Geneser, F. A. (1997). Distribution and morphology of serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in the brainstem of the New Zealand white rabbit. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 380, 507-519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blenau, W., &amp; Baumann, A. (2001). Molecular and pharmacological properties of insect biogenic amine receptors: Lessons from Drosphila melanogaster and Apis mellifera. Archives of Insect Biochemistry and Physiology, 48, 13-38. https://doi.org/10.1002/arch.1055</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvey, T., Alagaili, A. N., Bertelsen, M. F., Bhagwandin, A., Pettigrew, J. D., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2015). Nuclear organization of some immunohistochemically identifiable neural systems in two species of Euarchontoglires: A Lagomorph, Lepus capensis, and a Scandentia, Tupaia belangeri. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 70, 1-19. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2015.10.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvey, T., Patzke, N., Kaswera-Kyamayaka, C., Gilissen, E., Bertelsen, M. F., Pettigrew, J. D., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2015). Organization of cholinergic, catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic nuclei in three strepsirrhine primates: Galago demidoff, Perodicticus potto and Lemur catta. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 70, 42-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2015.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvey, T., Patzke, N., Kawsera, C., Gilissen, E., Bennett, N. C., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2013). Nuclear organisation of some immunohistochemically identifiable neural systems in three Afrotherian species - Potomogale velox, Amblysomus hottentotus and Petrodromus tetradactylus. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 50-51, 48-65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2013.01.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charara, A., &amp; Parent, A. (1998). Chemoarchitecture of the primate dorsal raphe nucleus. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 72, 111-127. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0891-0618</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chivers, D. (2013). Family Hylobatidae (Gibbons). In R. A. Mittermeier, A. B. Rylands, &amp; D. E. Wilson (Eds.), Handbook of the mammals of the world volume 3: Primates (pp. 754-791). Lynx Edicions.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark, L., Cools, R., &amp; Robbins, T. W. (2004). The neuropsychology of ventral prefrontal cortex: Decision-making and reversal learning. Brain and Cognition, 55, 41-53. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0278-2626</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crutcher, K. A., &amp; Humbertson, A. O. (1978). The organization of monoamine neurons within the brainstem of the North American opossum (Didelphis virginiana). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 179, 195-222. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.901790112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Karlsson, K. AE., Patzke, N., Spocter, M. A., Siegel, J. M., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2016). Organization of the sleep-related neural systems in the brain of the minke whale (Balaenoptera acutorostrata). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524, 2018-2035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Kruger, J. L., Bhagwandin, A., Jillani, N. E., Pettigrew, J. D., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2010). Nuclear organization of cholinergic, putative catecholaminergic and serotonergic systems in the brains of two megachiropteran species. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 40, 177-195. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2010.05.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Patzke, N., Spocter, M. A., Bertelsen, M. F., Siegel, J. M., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2016). Organisation of the sleep related neural systems in the brain of the river hippopotamus (Hippopotamus amphibius): A most unusual cetartiodactyl species. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524, 2036-2058. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne23930</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Patzke, N., Spocter, M. A., Siegel, J. M., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2016). Organization of the sleep-related neural systems in the brain of the harbour porpoise (Phocoena phocoena). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524, 1999-2017. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23929</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eide, P. K., &amp; Hole, K. (1993). The role of 5-hydroxytryptamine (5-HT) receptor subtypes and plasticity in the 5-HT systems in the regulation of nociceptive sensitivity. Cephalalgia, 13, 75-85. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1468-2982.1993.1302075.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felten, D. L., Laties, A. L., &amp; Carpenter, M. B. (1974). Monoamine-containing cell bodies in the squirrel monkey brain. American Journal of Anatomy, 139, 153-166. https://doi.org/10.1002/aja.10011390202</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felten, D. L., &amp; Sladek, J. R. (1983). Monoamine distribution in the primate brain. V. monoaminergic nuclei: Anatomy, pathways and local organisation. Brain Research Bulletin, 9, 253-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/0361-9230</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferguson, I. A., Hardman, C. D., Marotte, L. R., Salardini, A., Halasz, P., Vu, D., &amp; Waite, P. M. E. (1999). Serotonergic neurons in the brainstem of the wallaby, Macropus eugenii. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 411, 535-549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foehring, R. C., &amp; Lorenzon, N. M. (1999). Neuromodulation, development and synaptic plasticity. Canadian Journal of Experimental Psychology, 53, 45-61. https://doi.org/10.1037/h0087299</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallyas, F. (1979). Silver staining of myelin by means of physical development. Neurological Research, 1, 203-209. https://doi.org/10.1080/01616412.1979.11739553</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanley, N. R., &amp; Van de Kar, L. D. (2003). Serotonin and the neuroendocrine regulation of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis in health and disease. Vitamins &amp; Hormones, 66, 189-255. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0083-6729</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopkin, M. (2007). Chimps lead evolutionary race. Nature, 446, 841. https://doi.org/10.1038/446841a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hornung, J. P. (2003). The human raphe nuclei and the serotonergic system. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 26, 331-343. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2003.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hornung, J. P. (2010). The neuroanatomy of the serotonergic system. In C. Müller &amp; B. Jacobs (Eds.), Handbook of the behavioral neurobiology of serotonin Chap. 1.3 (pp. 51-64). Elsevier Academic Press. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-12-374634-4.00003-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hornung, J. P., &amp; Fritschy, J. M. (1988). Serotonergic system in the brainstem of the marmoset: A combined immunocytochemical and three-dimensional reconstruction study. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 270, 471-487 https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902700402</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubbard, J. E., &amp; Di Carlo, V. (1974). Flourescence histochemistry of monoamine containing cell bodies in the brain stem of the squirrel monkey (Saimiri sciureus). III. Serotonin-containing groups. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 153, 385-398. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne/901470409</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imam, A., Bhagwandin, A., Ajao, M. S., Spocter, M. A., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2019). The brain of the tree pangolin (Manis tricuspis). VI. The brainstem and cerebellum. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 527, 2440-2473. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24721</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishiwata, T. (2014). Role of serotonergic system in thermoregulation in rats. Journal of Physical Fitness and Sports Medicine, 3, 445-450. https://doi.org/10.7600/jpfsm.3.445</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobowitz, D. M., &amp; MacLean, P. D. (1978). A brainstem atlas of catecholaminergic neurons and serotonergic perikarya in a pygmy primate (Cebuella pygmaea). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 177, 397-416. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.901770304</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs, B. L. (2002). Adult brain neurogenesis and depression. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 16, 602-609. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0889-1591</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs, B. L., &amp; Azmitia, E. C. (1992). Structure and function of the brain serotonin system. Physiological Reviews, 72, 166-229. https://doi.org/10.1152/physrev.1992.72.1.165</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs, B. L., &amp; Fornal, C. A. (1997). Serotonin and motor activity. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 7, 820-825. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0959-4388</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lesch, K. P. (2001). Serotonergic gene expression and depression: Implications for developing novel antidepressants. Journal of Affective Disorders, 62, 57-76. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-0327</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manger, P. R., Fahringer, H. M., Pettigrew, J. D., &amp; Siegel, J. M. (2002). The distribution and morphological characteristics of serotonergic cells in the brain of monotremes. Brain, Behavior and Evolution, 60, 315-332. https://doi.org/10.1159/000067194</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manger, P. R., Pillay, P., Maseko, B. C., Bhagwandin, A., Gravett, N., Moon, D. J., Jillani, N., &amp; Hemingway, J. (2009). Acquisition of brains from the African elephant (Loxodonta africana): Perfusion-fixation and dissection. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 179, 16-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/j/jneumeth.2009.01.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin, S. L., Power, A., Boyle, Y., Anderson, I. M., Silverdale, M. A., &amp; Jones, A. K. P. (2017). 5-HT modulation of pain perception in humans. Psychopharmocology, 234, 2929-2939. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00213-017-4686-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maseko, B. C., Patzke, N., Fuxe, K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2013). Architectural organization of the African elephant diencephalon and brainstem. Brain, Behavior and Evolution, 82, 83-128. https://doi.org/10.1159/000352004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meguid, M. M., Fetissov, S. O., Varma, M., Sato, T., Zhang, L., Laviano, A., &amp; Rossi-Fanelli, F. (2000). Hypothalamic dopamine and serotonin in the regulation of food intake. Nutrition, 16, 843-857. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0899-9007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mengod, G., Cortes, R., Villaro, M. T., &amp; Hoyer, D. (2010). Distribution of 5HT receptors in the central nervous system. Handbook of Behavioral Neuroscience, 21, 123-138. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1569-7339(10)70074-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mossner, R., &amp; Lesch, K. P. (1998). Role of serotonin in the immune system and in neuroimmune interactions. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 12, 249-271. https://doi.org/10.1006/brbi.1998.0532</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller, C. P., &amp; Cunningham, K. A. (2020). Handbook of the behavioral neurobiology of serotonin (2nd ed.). Academic Press, Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patzke, N., Bertelsen, M. F., Fuxe, K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2014). Nuclear organization of cholinergic, catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic systems in the brain of the Tasmanian devil (Sarcophilus harrisii). Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 61-62, 94-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2014.08.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pillay, S., Bhagwandin, A., Bertelsen, M. F., Patzke, N., Engler, G., Engel, A. K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2017). Regional distribution of cholinergic, catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic neurons in the brain of two carnivore species: The filiform banded mongoose (Mungos mungo) and the caniform domestic ferret (Mustela putorius furo). Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 82, 12-28. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2017.04.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghanti, M. A., Spocter, M. A., Stimpson, C. D., Erwin, J. M., Bonar, C. J., Allman, J. M., Hof, P. R., &amp; Sherwood, C. C. (2009). Species-specific distributions of tyrosine hydroxylase-immunoreactive neurons in the prefrontal cortex of anthropoid primates. Neuroscience, 158, 1551-1559. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2008.10.058</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robbins, T. W. (2000). From arousal to cognition: The integrative position of the prefrontal cortex. Progress in Brain Research, 126, 469-483. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0079-6123</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rüb, U., del Tredici, K., Schultz, C., Thal, D. R., Braak, E., &amp; Braak, H. (2000). The evolution of Alzheimer's disease-related cytoskeletal pathology in the human raphe nuclei. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology, 26, 553-567. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.0305-1846.2000.00291.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sherwood, C. C., Raghanti, M. A., Stimpson, C. D., Spocter, M. A., Uddin, M., Boddy, A. M., Wildman, D. E., Bonar, C. J., Lewandowski, A. H., Phillips, K. A., Erwin, J. M., &amp; Hof, P. R. (2010). Inhibitory interneurons of the human prefrontal cortex display conserved evolution of the phenotype and related genes. Proceedings of the Royal Society B, Biological Sciences, 277, 1011-1020. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2009.1831</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinbusch, H. W. M. (1981). Distribution of serotonin-immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the rat - Cell bodies and terminals. Neuroscience, 6, 557-618. https://doi.org/10.1016/0306-4522</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stockmeier, C. A., Shapiro, L. A., Haycock, J. W., Thompson, P. A., &amp; Lowy, M. T. (1996). Quantitative subregional distribution of serotonin1A receptors and serotonin transporters in the human dorsal raphe. Brain Research, 727, 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sweigers, J., Bhagwandin, A., Spocter, M. A., Kaswera-Kyamakya, C., Gilissen, E., Manger, P. R., &amp; Maseko, B. C. (2017). Nuclear organization of cholinergic, catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic neurons in two relatively large-brained rodent species - The springhare (Pedetes capensis) and Beecroft's scaly-tailed squirrel (Anomalurus beecrofti). Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 86, 78-91. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2017.09.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeuchi, Y., Kimura, H., Matssuura, T., &amp; Sano, Y. (1982). Immunohistochemical demonstration of the organization of serotonergic neurons in the brain of the monkey (Macaca fuscata). Acta Anatomica, 114, 106-124. https://doi.org/10.1159/000145584</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Törk, I. (1990). Anatomy of the serotonergic system. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 600, 9-35. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1990.tb16870.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Underwood, M. D., Khaibulina, A. A., Ellis, S. P., Moran, A., Rice, P. M., Mann, J. J., &amp; Arango, V. (1999). Morphometry of the dorsal raphe nucleus sertonergic neurons in suicide victims. Biological Psychiatry, 46, 473-483. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-3223</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ursin, R. (2002). Serotonin and sleep. Sleep Medicine Reviews, 6, 55-69. https://doi.org/10.1053/smrv.2001.0174</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamson, E. A., Maisels, F. G., &amp; Groves, C. P. (2013). Family Hominidae (Great apes). In R. A. Mittermeier, A. B. Rylands, &amp; D. E. Wilson (Eds.), Handbook of the mammals of the world volume 3: Primates (pp. 792-856). Lynx Edicions.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto, T., &amp; Hirano, A. (1985a). Nucleus raphe dorsalis in Alzheimer's disease: Neurofibrillary tangles and loss of large neurons. Annals of Neurology, 17, 573-577. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.410170608</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto, T., &amp; Hirano, A. (1985b). Nucleus raphe dorsalis in Parkinsonism-dementia complex of Guam. Acta Neuropathologica, 67, 296-299. https://doi.org/10.1007/bf00687815</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, Y., Beyreuther, K., &amp; Schmitt, H. P. (1999). Spatial analysis of the neuronal density of aminergic brainstem nuclei in primary neurodegenerative and vascular dementia: A comparative immunocytochemical and quantitative study using a graph method. Analytical Cellular Pathology, 19, 125-138. https://doi.org/10.1155/1999/256382</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
