<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" VersionID="2" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="2">34629508</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-1155</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>59</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of food science and technology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Food Sci Technol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Preparation and evaluation of novel functional fermented dairy products containing propolis and cinnamon.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2392</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2401</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2392-2401</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13197-021-05255-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Novel functional food products might be an easy accessible and eligible approach to help reduce the risk of severe viral infections including SARS-CoV-2. Hence a product containing probiotics, propolis and cinnamon was developed and interferences of the ingredients were characterized. Yogurts were prepared using starter cultures with propolis (0.03%) and cinnamon in various concentrations (0.3%, 1%, and 2.5%). <i>Bifidobacterium animalis</i> ssp. <i>lactis</i>, <i>Lactobacillus acidophilus, Streptococcus thermophilus</i>, and <i>Lactobacillus delbrueckii</i> subsp. <i>bulgaricus</i> were used as microorganisms for yogurt production. Chemical analysis revealed a decline of fat matter in the presence of propolis and/or cinnamon. Propolis had statistically significant suppressive effects on <i>Bifidobacterium animalis</i> ssp. <i>lactis</i> as well as on <i>Lactobacillus delbrueckii</i> subsp. <i>bulgaricus</i> numbers (<i>p</i> &lt; 0.05). These effects were diminished in the presence of increasing cinnamon concentrations. For <i>Lactobacillus acidophilus</i> a statistically significant reducing effect on the number of colonies was observed in all products investigated. Nevertheless all samples met the standard of recommended level of ≥ 10<sup>6</sup> viable cells/g of a product. Propolis showed an inverse effect on <i>Streptococcus thermophilus</i> by increasing its colony numbers in yogurts. The probiotic yogurt samples containing propolis (0.03%) and cinnamon (2.5%) gained the highest number of points in the sensory evaluation compared to control.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2021.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gunes-Bayir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ayşe</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9993-7850</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bezmialem Vakif University, Silahtarağa Caddesi No: 198, Eyüpsultan, 34065 Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411675.0</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0490 4867</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bilgin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mehmet Gültekin</ForeName>
            <Initials>MG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2695-3953</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bezmialem Vakif University, Eyüpsultan, 34065 Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411675.0</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0490 4867</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guclu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Duygu</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2218-4261</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Res. Assist, Department of Nutrition and Dietetics, Faculty of Health Sciences, Bezmialem Vakif University, Eyüpsultan, 34065 Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.411675.0</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0490 4867</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pogda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sultan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5761-1908</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dietitian, Istanbul, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dadak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Agnes</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0948-4764</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Pharmacology, Department for Biomedical Sciences, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Veterinärplatz 1, 1210 Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.6583.8</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 9686 6466</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Food Sci Technol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0056471</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-1155</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteria</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cinnamon</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Probiotic yogurt</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Propolis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2 infection</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>44</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34629508</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8487671</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-021-05255-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">5255</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alkhatib A. Antiviral Functional Foods and Exercise Lifestyle Prevention of Coronavirus. Nutrients. 2020;12:2633. doi: 10.3390/nu12092633.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12092633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babaei S, Rahimi S, Karimi TMA, Tahmasebi G, Khaleghi Miran SN. Effects of propolis, royal jelly, honey and bee pollen on growth performance and immune system of Japanese quails. Vet Res Forum. 2016;7(1):13–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4867032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berretta AA, Silveira MAD, Cóndor Capcha JM, De Jong D. Propolis and its potential against SARS-CoV-2 infection mechanisms and COVID-19 disease. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;131:110622. doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110622</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7430291</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bukhari HM, Abdelghany AH, Nada IS, Header EA. Effect of yogurt pillared with propolis on hyperglycemic rats. Egypt J Hosp Med. 2012;49:691–705. doi: 10.12816/ejhm.2012.16208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12816/ejhm.2012.16208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Çakmakçi S, Çetin B, Turgut T, Gürses M, Erdoğan A. Probiotic properties, sensory qualities, and storage stability of probiotic banana yogurts. Turk J Vet Anim Sci. 2012;36:231–237. doi: 10.3906/vet-1007-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3906/vet-1007-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso-Ugarte GA, López-Malo A, Sosa-Morales ME.  Essential Oils in Food Preservation, Flavor and Safety; Cinnamon (Cinnamomum zeylanicum) essential oils. 1. Elsevier, UK: Academic Press; 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi YJ, Jin HY, Yang HS, Lee SC, Huh CK. Quality and storage characteristics of yogurt containing Lactobacillus sakei ALI033 and cinnamon ethanol extract. J Anim Tech. 2016;58(1):16. doi: 10.1186/s40781-016-0098-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40781-016-0098-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Food Safety Authority (EFSA)  Outcome of the consultation with member states and EFSA on the basic substance application for propolis extract (admissibility accepted when named water-soluble extract of propolis) for use in plant protection as fungicide and bactericide. EFSA Support Publ. 2018;15(11):1494E. doi: 10.2903/sp.efsa.2018.EN-1494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/sp.efsa.2018.EN-1494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Günes-Bayir A, Bilgin MG. The effect of cinnamon on microbiological, chemical and sensory analyses of probiotic yogurt. Bezmialem Sci. 2019;7(4):311–316. doi: 10.14235/bas.galenos.2018.2628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14235/bas.galenos.2018.2628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Güney, F (2016) Bazı propolis özütlerinin meyveli yoğurtların biyokimyasal, fizikokimyasal ve raf ömrü üzerine etkilerinin araştırılması (Master's thesis, Ordu Üniversitesi Fen Bilimleri Enstitüsü).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu J, Zhang L, LinW TW, Chan FK, Ng SC. Review article: Probiotics, prebiotics and dietary approaches during COVID-19 pandemic. Trends Food Sci Technol. 2021;108:187–196. doi: 10.1016/j.tifs.2020.12.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2020.12.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833886</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irvine SL, Hummelen L, Hekmat S. Probiotic yogurt consumption may improve gastrointestinal symptoms, productivity, and nutritional intake of people living with human immunodeficiency virus in Mwanza. Tanzania Nutr Res. 2011;31(12):875–881. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2011.10.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2011.10.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22153512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kulkarni SA, Nagarajan SK, Ramesh V, Palaniyandi V, Selvam SP, Madhavan T. Computational evaluation of major components from plant essential oils as potent inhibitors of SARS-CoV-2 spike protein. J Molec Struct. 2020;1221:128823. doi: 10.1016/j.molstruc.2020.128823.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.molstruc.2020.128823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7334662</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32834111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lima WG, Brito JCM, da Cruz Nizer WS. Bee products as a source of promising therapeutic and chemoprophylaxis strategies against COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) Phytother Res. 2020;10:1002. doi: 10.1002/ptr.6872.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.6872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindasari F (2013) Characteristic of Goat’s Milk Probiotic Yoghurt with Addition of Cinnamon Extracts as Flavor. Thesis, Bogor-Indonesia: Department of Production Science and Technology Livestock Faculty of Livestock Institute Agricultural Bogor.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourens-Hattingh A, Viljoen BC. Yogurt as probiotic carrier food. Int Dairy J. 2011;11(1–2):1–17. doi: 10.1016/S0958-6946(01)00036-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0958-6946(01)00036-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehmetoğlu, S (2019) Propolis Katkılı Dondurmaların Depolama Süresince Fizikokimyasal Yapısınınin Celenmesi (Master's thesis, Fen Bilimleri Enstitüsü).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller LE, Lehtoranta L, Lehtinen MJ. The Effect of Bifidobacterium animalis ssp. Lactis HN019 on Cellular Immune Function in Healthy Elderly Subjects: Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Nutrients. 2017;9:191. doi: 10.3390/nu9030191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9030191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molania T, Moghadamnia AA, Pouramir M, Aghel S, Moslemi D, Ghassemi L, Motallebnejad M. The effect of Cinnamaldehyde on mucositis and salivary antioxidant capacity in gamma-irradiated rats (a preliminary study) DARU J Pharm Sci. 2012;20(1):89. doi: 10.1186/2008-2231-20-89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2008-2231-20-89</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nematollahi Z, Ebrahimi M, Raeisi M, Dadban Shahamat Y, Ghodsi Moghadam M, Hashemi M, Shirzad H. The Antibacterial Activity of Cinnamon Essential Oil against Foodborne Bacteria: A Mini-Review. J Hum Environ Health Promot. 2020;6(3):101–105. doi: 10.29252/jhehp.6.3.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.29252/jhehp.6.3.1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nigam D.  Probiotics as Functional Foods in Enhancing Gut Immunity. In: Rani V, Yadav U, editors. Functional Food and Human Health. Singapore: Springer; 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polamarasetti P, Martirosyan D. Nutrition planning during the COVID-19 pandemic for aging immunity. Bioact Compd Health Dis. 2020;3(7):109–123. doi: 10.31989/bchd.v3i7.733.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31989/bchd.v3i7.733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarkar S. Potentiality of probiotic yogurt as a functional food–a review. Nutr Food Sci. 2019;49(2):182–202. doi: 10.1108/NFS-05-2018-0139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/NFS-05-2018-0139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sazawal S, Hiremath G, Dhingra U, Malik PC, Deb S, Black RE. Efficacy of probiotics in prevention of acute diarrhoea: a meta-analysis of masked, randomised, placebo-controlled trials. Lancet Infect Dis. 2006;6(6):374–382. doi: 10.1016/S1473-3099(06)70495-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1473-3099(06)70495-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16728323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shori AB, Baba AS. Cinnamomum verum improved the functional properties of bioyogurts made from camel and cow milks. J Saudi Soc Agric Sci. 2011;10:101–110. doi: 10.1016/j.jssas.2011.04.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jssas.2011.04.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh K, Rao A. Probiotics: A potential immunomodulator in COVID-19 infection management. Nutr Res. 2021;87:1–12. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2020.12.014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nutres.2020.12.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7881295</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33592454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turkish Standards (2006). TS 1330, Yogurt. The Institute of Turkish Standards, Ankara.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Süle J, Kõrösi T, Hucker A, Varga L. Evaluation of culture media for selective enumeration of bifidobacteria and lactic acid bacteria. Brazil J Microbiol. 2014;45(3):1023–1030. doi: 10.1590/S1517-83822014000300035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1517-83822014000300035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tavakoli M, Najafi MBH, Mohebbi M. Effect of the milk fat content and starter culture selection on proteolysis and antioxidant activity of probiotic yogurt. Heliyon. 2019;5(2):e01204. doi: 10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e01204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2019.e01204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6360988</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30766933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turkish Food Codex Labeling Regulation/Annex-15, Health Declarations and Declaration Conditions. Available from: URL: https://www.resmigazete.gov.tr/eskiler/2017/01/20170126M1-5.htm (22.02.2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
