<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34622984</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-3673</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>111</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of leukocyte biology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Leukoc Biol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Stem cells from exfoliated deciduous teeth transplantation ameliorates Sjögren's syndrome by secreting soluble PD-L1.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1043</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1055</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1043-1055</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/JLB.6MA0921-752RR</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Mesenchymal stem cell transplantation (MSCT) regulates immune cells, and is a promising therapeutic approach for treating autoimmune diseases. Stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth (SHED) are a unique postnatal stem cell population from the cranial neural crest with high self-renewal, multipotent differentiation, and superior immunomodulatory properties. However, the mechanisms by which SHED can treat autoimmune diseases remain unclear. Sjögren's syndrome (SS) is an autoimmune disease histologically characterized by high lymphocytic infiltration in the salivary and lacrimal glands that results in dryness symptoms. This study explores the potential of systemic transplantation of SHED to ameliorate SS-induced dryness symptoms in mice. Overall, SHED could rescue the balance of regulatory T cell (Treg)/T helper cell 17 (Th17) in the recipient SS mice. Mechanistically, SHED promoted Treg conversion and inhibited Th17 function via paracrine effects, which were related to the secretion of soluble programmed cell death ligand 1 (sPD-L1). Moreover, it directly induced Th17 apoptosis via cell-cell contact, leading to the up-regulation of Treg and down-regulation of Th17 cells. In summary, SHED-mediated rescue of Treg/Th17 balance via the sPD-L1/PD-1 pathway ameliorates the gland inflammation and dryness symptoms in SS mice. These findings suggest that SHED are a promising stem cell source for the treatment of autoimmune diseases in the clinical setting.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©2021 Society for Leukocyte Biology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ning</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Dentistry, School and Hospital of Stomatology, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Oral Diseases, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xuemei</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Dentistry, School and Hospital of Stomatology, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Oral Diseases, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xu</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Dentistry, School and Hospital of Stomatology, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Oral Diseases, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Si</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Dentistry, School and Hospital of Stomatology, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wenxiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Dentistry, School and Hospital of Stomatology, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yao</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Dentistry, School and Hospital of Stomatology, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Liaoning Provincial Key Laboratory of Oral Diseases, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Leukoc Biol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8405628</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0741-5400</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012859" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sjogren's Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D033581" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stem Cell Transplantation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013234" MajorTopicYN="N">Stem Cells</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058504" MajorTopicYN="N">Th17 Cells</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014094" MajorTopicYN="N">Tooth, Deciduous</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Sjögren's syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">T helper cell 17</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">immunomodulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">regulatory T cell</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">soluble PD-L1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">stem cell transplantation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">stem cells from exfoliated deciduous teeth</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>50</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34622984</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/JLB.6MA0921-752RR</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mavragani CP, Nezos A, Moutsopoulos HM. New advances in the classification, pathogenesis and treatment of Sjogren's syndrome. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2013;25:623-629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mariette X, Criswell LA. Primary Sjögren's syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2018;378:931-939.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen CQ, Hu MH, Li Y, Stewart C, Peck AB. Salivary gland tissue expression of interleukin-23 and interleukin-17 in Sjögren's syndrome: findings in humans and mice. Arthritis Rheum. 2008;58:734-743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verstappen GM, Corneth OBJ, Bootsma H, Kroese FGM. Th17 cells in primary Sjögren's syndrome: pathogenicity and plasticity. J Autoimmun. 2018;87:16-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barr JY, Wang X, Kreiger PA, Lieberman SM. Salivary gland-protective regulatory T cell dysfunction underlies female-specific sialadenitis in the non-obese diabetic mouse model of Sjögren syndrome. Immunology. 2018;155:225-237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao L, Chen S, Yang P, Cao H, Li L. The role of mesenchymal stem cells in hematopoietic stem cell transplantation: prevention and treatment of graft-versus-host disease. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2019;10:182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun L, Wang D, Liang J, et al. Umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cell transplantation in severe and refractory systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62:2467-2475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu R, Li X, Zhang Z, et al. Allogeneic mesenchymal stem cells inhibited T follicular helper cell generation in rheumatoid arthritis. Sci Rep. 2015;5:12777.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen W, Yu Y, Ma J, Olsen N, Lin J. Mesenchymal stem cells in primary Sjögren's syndrome: prospective and challenges. Stem Cells Int. 2018;2018:4357865.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Wang D, Liu D, et al. Allogeneic mesenchymal stem cell treatment alleviates experimental and clinical Sjögren syndrome. Blood. 2012;120:3142-3151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miura M, Gronthos S, Zhao M, et al. SHED: stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2003;100:5807-5812.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu S, Min D, Zeng J, Ju Y, Liu Y, Chen X. Transplantation of stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth decreases cognitive impairment from chronic cerebral ischemia by reducing neuronal apoptosis in rats. Stem Cells Int. 2020;2020:6393075.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Wang L, Liu S, et al. Transplantation of SHED prevents bone loss in the early phase of ovariectomy-induced osteoporosis. J Dent Res. 2014;93:1124-1132.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamaza T, Kentaro A, Chen C, et al. Immunomodulatory properties of stem cells from human exfoliated deciduous teeth. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2010;1:5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Chen C, Liu S, et al. Acetylsalicylic acid treatment improves differentiation and immunomodulation of SHED. J Dent Res. 2015;94:209-218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du ZH, Ding C, Zhang Q, et al. Stem cells  from exfoliated  deciduous  teeth alleviate hyposalivation caused by Sjögren syndrome. Oral Dis. 2019;25:1530-1544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin X, Rui K, Deng J, et al. Th17 cells play a critical role in the development of experimental Sjögren's syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74:1302-1310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang R, Yu T, Liu D, Shi S, Zhou Y. Hydrogen sulfide promotes immunomodulation of gingiva-derived mesenchymal stem cells via the Fas/FasL coupling pathway. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2018;9:62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar P, Kolls JK. Lymphocyte isolation, Th17 cell differentiation, activation, and staining. Bio Protoc. 2016;6:e2047.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Y, Nakagawa Y, Purushotham KR, Humphreys-Beher MG. Functional changes in salivary glands of autoimmune disease-prone NOD mice. Am J Physiol. 1992;263:E607-614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alunno A, Carubbi F, Bistoni O, et al. T regulatory and T helper 17 cells in primary Sjögren's syndrome: facts and perspectives. Mediators Inflamm. 2015;2015:243723.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akiyama K, Chen C, Wang D, et al. Mesenchymal stem cell induced immunoregulation involves FAS ligand/FAS mediated T cell apoptosis. Cell Stem Cell. 2012;10:544-555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen C, Akiyama K, Yamaza T, et al. Telomerase governs immunomodulatory properties of mesenchymal stem cells by regulating FAS ligand expression. EMBO Mol Med. 2014;6:322-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Q, Ding G, Xu X. Immunomodulatory functions of mesenchymal stem cells and possible mechanisms. Histol Histopathol. 2016;31:949-959.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedoeem A, Azoulay-Alfaguter I, Strazza M, Silverman GJ, Mor A. Programmed death-1 pathway in cancer and autoimmunity. Clin Immunol. 2014;153:145-152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Jing H, Kou X, et al. PD-1 is required to maintain stem cell properties in human dental pulp stem cells. Cell Death Differ. 2018;25:1350-1360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Copelan EA. Hematopoietic stem-cell transplantation. N Engl J Med. 2006;354:1813-1826.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantovani C, Raimondo S, Haneef MS, et al. Morphological, molecular and functional differences of adult bone marrow- and adipose-derived stem cells isolated from rats of different ages. Exp Cell Res. 2012;318:2034-2048.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Wu Q, Wang Y, Li L, Bu H, Bao J. Senescence of mesenchymal stem cells. Int J Mol Med. 2017;39:775-782.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsui K, Sano H. T helper 17 cells in primary Sjögren's syndrome. J Clin Med. 2017;6:65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakaguchi S, Yamaguchi T, Nomura T, Ono M. Regulatory T cells and immune tolerance. Cell. 2008;133:775-787.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volpe E, Servant N, Zollinger R, et al. A critical function for transforming growth factor-beta, interleukin 23 and proinflammatory cytokines in driving and modulating human T(H)-17 responses. Nat Immunol. 2008;9:650-657.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diller ML, Kudchadkar RR, Delman KA, Lawson DH, Ford ML. Balancing inflammation: the link between Th17 and regulatory T Cells. Mediators Inflamm. 2016;2016:6309219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>You IC, Bian F, Volpe EA, de Paiva CS, Pflugfelder SC. Age-related conjunctival disease in the C57BL/6.NOD-Aec1Aec2 mouse model of Sjögren syndrome develops independent of lacrimal dysfunction. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2015;56:2224-2233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plumas J, Chaperot L, Richard MJ, Molens JP, Bensa JC, Favrot MC. Mesenchymal stem cells induce apoptosis of activated T cells. Leukemia. 2005;19:1597-1604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan Z, Zhuansun Y, Liu G, Chen R, Li J, Ran P. Mesenchymal stem cells suppress T cells by inducing apoptosis and through PD-1/B7-H1 interactions. Immunol Lett. 2014;162:248-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L, Zhao Y, Shi S. Interplay between mesenchymal stem cells and lymphocytes: implications for immunotherapy and tissue regeneration. J Dent Res. 2012;91:1003-1010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen W, Huang Y, Han J, et al. Immunomodulatory effects of mesenchymal stromal cells-derived exosome. Immunol Res. 2016;64:831-840.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman GJ, Long AJ, Iwai Y, et al. Engagement of the PD-1 immunoinhibitory receptor by a novel B7 family member leads to negative regulation of lymphocyte activation. J Exp Med. 2000;192:1027-1034.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latchman Y, Wood CR, Chernova T, et al. PD-L2 is a second ligand for PD-1 and inhibits T cell activation. Nat Immunol. 2001;2:261-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stathopoulou C, Gangaplara A, Mallett G, et al. PD-1 inhibitory receptor downregulates asparaginyl endopeptidase and maintains Foxp3 transcription factor stability in induced regulatory T cells. Immunity. 2018;49:247-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francisco LM, Sage PT, Sharpe AH. The PD-1 pathway in tolerance and autoimmunity. Immunol Rev. 2010;236:219-242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen G, Huang AC, Zhang W, et al. Exosomal PD-L1 contributes to immunosuppression and is associated with anti-PD-1 response. Nature. 2018;560:382-386.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haxhinasto S, Mathis D, Benoist C. The AKT-mTOR axis regulates de novo differentiation of CD4+Foxp3+ cells. J Exp Med. 2008;205:565-574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan CL, Kuchroo JR, Sage PT, et al. PD-1 restraint of regulatory T cell suppressive activity is critical for immune tolerance. J Exp Med. 2021;218:e20182232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu M, Zeng X, Wang J, et al. Immunomodulation by mesenchymal stem cells in treating human autoimmune disease-associated lung fibrosis. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2016;7:63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X, Shao H, Zhi Y, et al. CD73 pathway contributes to the immunosuppressive ability of mesenchymal stem cells in intraocular autoimmune responses. Stem Cells Dev. 2016;25:337-346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almeida L, Lochner M, Berod L, Sparwasser T. Metabolic pathways in T cell activation and lineage differentiation. Semin Immunol. 2016;28:514-524.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang CH, Curtis JD, Maggi LB, et al. Posttranscriptional control of T cell effector function by aerobic glycolysis. Cell. 2013;153:1239-1251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyajima M, Zhang B, Sugiura Y, et al. Metabolic shift induced by systemic activation of T cells in PD-1-deficient mice perturbs brain monoamines and emotional behavior. Nat Immunol. 2017;18:1342-1352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
