<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34630830</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>27</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1937-8688</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>39</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Pan African medical journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pan Afr Med J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Endodontic practice amongst Nigerian dentists undergoing postgraduate training.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>218</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>218</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">218</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.11604/pamj.2021.39.218.23205</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">this study aimed at finding out current practice of endodontics amongst Nigerian dentists undergoing postgraduate training (also referred to as dental resident doctors) in different institutions across the nation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">a questionnaire-based, cross sectional study was conducted amongst dentists undergoing postgraduate training. Questions were asked on demographics, protocol for root canal treatment (RCT), materials employed in different stages. Opinions were also sought on satisfaction with their practice and training needs in endodontics. Data were analyzed with SPSS version 20.0 and presented as tables and charts. Significance level was set at p≤0.05.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">ninety dentists undergoing postgraduate training (57 males and 33 females) with mean age of 34.81 ± 5.9 years participated in the study. Root canal treatment was mostly done in multiple visits in both single and multi-rooted teeth (p=0.01), only about 15% performed the procedure on multi rooted teeth. Sixty-five (72.2%) never used Rubber dam, stainless steel files were being used by 69%, step down technique of preparation by 53.9% and Sodium hypochlorite was the major irrigant (80%) used. Obturation was majorly with Cold lateral compaction technique (94%), 57.2% delayed definitive restoration for maximum of 1 week and amalgam was still the major material used for posterior teeth as reported by 62.9% of the participants. The majority (55.6%) were not satisfied with their current knowledge and practice and most were those that did not have good undergraduate training (p = 0.05).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">the practice of endodontics needs standardization across the nation as it is being advocated in other countries. There is need for hands on-training on endodontics to encourage adoption of new advances in technology, as well as improve the training of postgraduate dentists in endodontics. Also, emphasis should be placed on use of rubber dam in order to minimize the spread of infection and protect the patients from aspiration of small instruments involved in endodontic procedure.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright: Gbadebo Olaide Shakeerah et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gbadebo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shakeerah Olaide</ForeName>
            <Initials>SO</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Restorative Dentistry, Faculty of Dentistry, College of Medicine, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ajayi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deborah Mojirade</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Restorative Dentistry, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>07</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Pan Afr Med J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101517926</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003815" MajorTopicYN="N">Dentists</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004499" MajorTopicYN="Y">Education, Dental, Graduate</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004708" MajorTopicYN="N">Endodontics</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="Y">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009549" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Nigeria</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012390" MajorTopicYN="N">Root Canal Therapy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016733" MajorTopicYN="N">Rubber Dams</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Endodontics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endodontic guidelines</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postgraduate training</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">root canal treatment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rubber dam</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>59</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630830</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8486943</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.2021.39.218.23205</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">PAMJ-39-218</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Küçükkaya S, Görduysus M, Görduysus MO, Anil D. A questionnaire survey on current endodontic practice of dental practitioners in Turkey. Clin Dent Res. 2015;39(3):101–109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishen A, Peters OA, Zehnder M, Diogenes AR, Nair MK. Advances in endodontics: potential applications in clinical practice. J Conserv Dent. 2016 May-Jun;19(3):199–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4872571</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27217630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta R, Rai R. The adoption of new endodontic technology by Indian Dental practitioners: a questionnaire survey. J Clin Diagn Res. 2013;7(11):2610–2614.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879893</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24392420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salehrabi R, Rotstein I. Endodontic treatment outcomes in a large patient population in the USA: an epidemiological study. J Endod. 2004 Dec;30(12):846–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15564861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Society of Endodontology  Consensus report of the European Society of Endodontology on quality guidelines for endodontic treatment. Int Endod J. 1994 May;27(3):115–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7995643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Moor R, Hülsmann M, Kirkevang L-L, Tanalp J, Whitworth J. Undergraduate curriculum guidelines for endodontology. Int Endod J. 2013 Dec;46(12):1105–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24117830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Udoye CI, Sede MA, Jafarzadeh H, Abbott PV. A survey of endodontic practices among dentists in Nigeria. J Contemp Dent Pract. 2013 Mar 1;14(2):293–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23811662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Omari WM. Survey of attitudes, materials and methods employed in endodontic treatment by general dental practitioners in North Jordan. BMC Oral Health. 2004 Sep 10;4(1):1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC518977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15361258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravanshad S, Sahraei S, Akbar K. Survey of endodontic practice amongst Iranian dentists participating restorative dentistry congress in Shiraz, November 2007. Iran Endod J. 2008 Winter;2(4):135–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3834635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24265636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akpata ES. Endodontic treatment in Nigeria. Int Endod J. 1984 Jul;17(3):139–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6381322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grewal MS, Yadav S, Chhabra N, Bali D, Kumar A, Sethi P, et al.  A Questionnaire survey on current trends in Endodontics amongst general dental practitioners of Delhi. J Indian Assoc Public Health Dent. 2011;17(sup II):488–492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrestha D, Dahal M, Karki S. An endodontic practice profile amongst general dental practitioners in Kathmandu: a questionnaire survey. J Coll Med Sci Nepal. 2013;9(4):40–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rani LP. Sterilization protocols in dentistry: a review. J Pharm Sci and Res. 2016;8(6):558–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Association of Endodontists  . ENDODONTIC: colleagues for excellence. Vol. 20. Chicago, IL: 2014. The standard of practice in contemporary endodontics; pp. 1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehta N, Raisingani D, Gupta S, Sharma M. Endodontic trends: where we are and where we should be-a survey report. Virtual Heath Library. 2013;6:30–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenkins SM, Hayes SJ, Dummer PMH. A study of endodontic treatment carried out in dental practice within the UK. Int Endod J. 2001 Jan;34(1):16–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11307376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iqbal A, Akbar I, Qureshi B, Sghaireen MG, Al-Omiri MK. A survey of standard protocols for Endodontic treatment in North of KSA. ISRN Dent. 2014 May 4;2014:865780.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4040192</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24944823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitworth JM, Seccombe GV, Shoker K, Steele JG. Use of rubber dam and irrigant selection in UK general dental practice. IInt Endod J. 2000 Sep;33(5):435–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11307462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitten BH, Gardiner DL, Jeansonne BG, Lemon RR. Current trends in endodontic treatment: report of a national survey. J Am Dent Assoc. 1996 Sep;127(9):1333–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8854609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slaus G, Bottenberg P. A survey of endodontic practice amongst Flemish dentists. Int Endod J. 2002 Sep;35(9):759–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12449027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad IA. Rubber dam usage for endodontic treatment: a review. Int Endod J. 2009 Nov;42(11):963–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19825034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrotte P. Endodontics: part 7 Preparing the root canal. Br Dent J. 2004 Nov 27;197(10):603–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mozayeni MA, Golshah A, Kerdar NN. A survey on NiTi rotary instruments usage by endodontists and general dentist in Tehran. Iran Endod J. 2011 Fall;6(4):168–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3471596</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23130073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manfredi M, Figini L, Gagliani M, Lodi G. Single versus multiple visits for endodontic treatment of permanent teeth. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016 Dec 1;12(12):CD005296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6463951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27905673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Moor RJG, Hommez GMG, Martens LC, De Boever JG. Accuracy of four electronic apex locators: an in vitro evaluation. Endod Dent Traumatol. 1999 Apr;15(2):77–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10379277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan AW, Low D, Cheung GS, Ng RP. Questionnaires survey of endodontic practice profile among dentists in Hong Kong. Hong Kong Dent J. 2006;3:80–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters OA, Peters CI, Basrani B.  In Cohen´s pathways of the pulp. 11th Ed. Elservier; 2016. Cleaning and shaping the root canal; pp. 209–315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segura-Egea JJ, Gould K, Hakan Sen B, Jonasson P, Cotti E, Mazzoni A, et al.  European society of Endodontology position statement: the use of antibiotics in endodontics. Int Endod J. 2018 Jan;51(1):20–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28436043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margelos J, Eliades G, Verdelis C, Palaghias G. Interaction of calcium hydroxide with zinc oxide-eugenol type sealers: a potential clinical problem. J Endod. 1997 Jan;23(1):43–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9594745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Block RM, Lewis RD, Hirsch J, Coffey J, Langeland K. Systemic distribution of 14C-labeled paraformaldehyde incorporated within formocresol following pulpotomies in dogs. J Endod. 1983 May;9(5):176–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6574206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarrami N, Pemberton MN, Thornhill MH, Theaker ED. Adverse reactions associated with the use of eugenol in dentistry. Br Dent J. 2002 Sep 14;193(5):257–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12353045</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johson WT, Kulild JC.  In Cohen´s pathways of the pulp. 10th Ed. Mosby Elservier; 2011. Obturation of the cleaned and shaped root canal system; pp. 359–63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deveaux E, Hildebert P, Neut C, Romond C. Bacterial microleakage of Cavit, IRM, TERM, and fermit: a 21-day in vitro study. J Endod. 1999 Oct;25(10):653–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10687522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coronal Leakage  . American Association of Endodontics, Fall/Winter. 2002. Clinical and biological implications, endodontics: colleagues for Excellence.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dietschi D, Bouillaguet S, Sadan A.  In Cohen´s pathways of the pulp. 11th Ed. Elservier: 2016. Restoration of endodontically treated teeth; pp. 818–848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
