<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34650513</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-2295</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Frontiers in neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Front Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Clinical Features in Patients With PANDAS/PANS and Therapeutic Approaches: A Retrospective Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>741176</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>741176</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">741176</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fneur.2021.741176</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText><b>Objective:</b> The clinical characteristics of patients with PANDAS (pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection) and PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome) and the efficacy of antibiotic therapy with psychotherapy and antipsychotics were investigated to improve neurological symptoms as well as obsessive compulsive disorder (OCD). <b>Methods:</b> We retrospectively analyzed 62 patients with a clinical diagnosis of PANDAS/PANS enrolled from May 14, 2013 to September 15, 2020 in the Neurology Childhood Division, Department of Pediatrics at Sapienza, Rome. Clinical manifestations, neurological and psychiatric, laboratory investigations, and familiar history were collected to evaluate the differences between the two groups. The effects of various therapeutic approaches were examined. Descriptive and comparative statistical analyses were performed. <b>Results:</b> The mean age at onset of PANDAS/PANS symptoms was 6.2 ± 1.2 years. The most common diagnosis was PANDAS, followed by PANS. Neurological and psychiatric symptoms were mostly evident in both groups (&gt;70% of the population), with no significant difference between them (<i>P</i> = 0.52 and <i>P</i> = 0.15, respectively). Irritability, aggressivity, and food restriction were more prevalent in children with PANS than in those with PANDAS (<i>P</i> = 0.024 and <i>P</i> = 0.0023, respectively). The levels of anti-streptolysin O and anti-DNAse B 10-fold higher in PANDAS than those in PANS (<i>P</i> &lt; 0.0001). Antibiotics or psychotherapy were administered in most cases (90.3 and 53.2%, respectively), followed by antipsychotic treatments (24.2%). In the multivariate analysis, among the therapies used, psychotherapy significantly resulted in the most efficacious relief of OCD, reducing stress in patients and their parents (<i>P</i> = 0.042). <b>Conclusion:</b> Our findings confirm a clear clinical difference between the two groups, PANDAS and PANS, using different approaches. In fact, irritability, aggressivity, and food restriction were significantly more frequent in children with PANS and the levels of anti-streptolysin O and anti-DNAse B were higher in PANDAS. Another relevant finding is the efficacy of psychotherapy, especially for obsessive-compulsive disorder, and of antibiotic prophylaxis in managing acute neurological symptoms.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Rea, Guido and Spalice.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rea</LastName>
            <ForeName>Isabella</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Child Neurology Division, Department of Pediatrics, "Sapienza" University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guido</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cristiana Alessia</ForeName>
            <Initials>CA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Child Neurology Division, Department of Pediatrics, "Sapienza" University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spalice</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alberto</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Child Neurology Division, Department of Pediatrics, "Sapienza" University of Rome, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Front Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101546899</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1664-2295</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obsessive compulsive disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection (PANDAS)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatrics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">streptococcus beta hemolytic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tics</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34650513</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8505529</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.741176</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leonard HL, Garvery M, Mittleman B, Allen AJ, Perlmutter S, et al. . Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections: clinical description of the first 50 cases. Am J Psychiatry. (1998) 155:264–71. 10.1176/ajp.155.2.264</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.155.2.264</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9464208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF, King RA, Gilbert DL, Coffey BJ, Singer HS, Dure LS, et al. . Streptococcal upper respiratory tract infections and exacerbations of tic and obsessive-compulsive symptoms: a prospective longitudinal study. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (2011) 50:108–18. 10.1016/j.jaac.2010.10.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2010.10.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3024577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21241948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Leckman JF, Rose NR. From research subgroup to clinical syndrome: modifying the PANDAS criteria to describe PANS (pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome). Pediatr Ther. (2012) 2:3–5. 10.4172/2161-0665.1000113</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-0665.1000113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frankovich J, Thienemann M, Pearlstein J, Crable A, Brown K, Chang K. Multidsciplinary clinic dedicated to treating youth and pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome: presenting characteristics of the first 47 consecutive patients. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2015) 25:38–47. 10.1089/cap.2014.0081</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2014.0081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25695943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orefici G, Cardona F, Cox CJ, Cunningham MW. Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections (PANDAS). In: Ferretti JJ, Stevens Dl, Fischetti VA. editors. Streptococcus pyogenes: Basic Biology to Clinical Manifestation. Oklahoma City, OK: University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center;  (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooperstock MS, Swedo SE, Pasternack MS, Murphy TK. Clinical management of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome part III-treatment and prevention of infections. J Child Adoles Psychopharmacol. (2017) 27:151. 10.1089/cap.2016.0151</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2016.0151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham MW. Post-streptococcal autoimmune sequelae: rheumatic fever and beyond. In: Ferretti JJ, Stevens DL, Fischetti VA. editors. Streptococcus pyogenes: Basic Biology to Clinical Manifestations. Oklahoma City, OK: University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center;  (2016). p. 893–930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Liu R, Fahey S, Frick L, Leckman J, Vaccarino F, et al. . Antibodies from children with PANDAS bind specifically to striatal cholinergic interneurons and alter their activity. Am J Psychiatry. (2021) 178:48–64. 10.1176/appi.ajp.2020.19070698</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2020.19070698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32539528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swedo SE, Seidilitz J, Kovacevic M, Latimer M, Hommer R, Lougee L, et al. . Overview of treatment of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2017) 27:562–65. 10.189/cap.2017.0042</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.189/cap.2017.0042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5610386</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28722464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckman JF, Riddle MA, Hardin MT, Ort SI, Swartz KL, Stevenson J, et al. . The yale global tic severity scale: initianl testing of a clinician-rated scale of tic severity. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (1989) 28:566–73. 10.1097/00004583-198907000-00015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004583-198907000-00015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2768151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scahill L, Riddle MA, McSwiggin-Hardin M, Ort SI, King RA, Goodman WK, et al. . Children's yale-brown obsessive compulsive scale: reliability and validity. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (1997) 36:844–52. 10.1097/00004583-199706000-00023</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004583-199706000-00023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9183141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>March JS, Parker JDA. The multidimensional anxiety scale for children (MASC). In: Maruish ME. editor. The Use of Psychological Testing for Treatment Planning and Outcomes Assessment: Instruments for Children and Adolescents. New York, NY: Routledge;  (2004). p. 39–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wechsler D. Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children-Fourth Edition: Canadian (WISC-IV). Toronto, ON: Psychological Corporation;  (2005).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang K, Frankovich J, Cooperstock M, Cunningham M, Latimer ME, Murphy TK, et al. . Clinical evaluation of youth with pediatric acute onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS): recommendations from the 2013 PANS Consensus Conference. J Child Psychoprmacol. (2014) 25:3–13. 10.1089/cap.2014.0084</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2014.0084</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25325534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hesselmark E, Bejerot S. Biomarkers for diagnosis of pediatric acute neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS)-sensitivity and specificity of the Cunningham panel. J Neuroimmunol. (2017) 312:31–7. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2017.09.002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2017.09.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Parker-Athill EC, Lewin AB, Storch EA, Mutch PJ. Cefdinir for recent-onset pediatric neuropsychiatric disorders: a pilot randomized trial. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2015) 25:57–64. 10.1089/cap.2014.0010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2014.0010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25299463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frick LR, Rapanelli M, Jindachomthong K, Grant P, Leckman JF, Swedo S, et al. . Differential binding of antibodies in PANDAS patients to cholinergic interneurons in the striatum. Brain Behav Immun. (2017) 69:304–11. 10.1016/j.bbi.2017.12.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbi.2017.12.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857467</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29233751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman M, Frankovich J, Nguyen E, Leibold C, Yoon J, Mark Freeman G, et al. . Psychotic symptoms in youth with pediatric aute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS) may reflect syndrome severity and heterogeneity. J Psychiatr Res. (2019) 110:93–102. 10.1016/j.jpsychires.2018.11.013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2018.11.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30605785</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A, Williams MT, Chugani HT. Evaluation of basal ganglia and thalamic inflammation in children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infection and Tourette syndrome: a positron emission tomographic (PET) study using 11C-[R]-PK-11195. J Child Neurol. (2015) 30:749–56. 10.1177/0883073814543303</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073814543303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25117419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng J, Frankovich J, McKenna ES, Rowe NC, MacFachern SJ, Ng NN, et al. . Association of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome with microstructural differences in brain regions detected via diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging. JAMA Netw Open. (2020) 3:e204063. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.4063</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.4063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7199120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32364596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer HS, Loiselle C. PANDAS a commentary. J Psychosom Res. (2003) 55:31–9. 10.1016/s0022-3999(02)00582-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-3999(02)00582-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12842229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murgia F, Gagliano A, Tanca MG, Geva NO, Hendren A, Carucci S, et al. . Metabolomic characterization of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome (PANS). Front Neurosci. (2021) 15:645267. 10.3389/fnins.2021.645267</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2021.645267</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8194687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy TK, Storch E, Turner A, Reid J, Tan J, Lewin A. Maternal history of autoimmune disease in children presenting with tics and/or obsessive–compulsive disorder. J Neuroimmunol. (2010) 229:243–7. 10.1016/j.jneuroim.2010.08.017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2010.08.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2991439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lougee L, Perlmutter SJ, Nicolson R, Garvey MA, Swedo SE. Psychiatric disorders in first-degree relatives of children with pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorders associated with streptococcal infections (PANDAS). J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (2000) 39:1120–6. 10.1097/00004583-200009000-00011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004583-200009000-00011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10986808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider LA, Lougee L, Grant SM, Swedo SE. Antibiotic prophylaxis with azithromycin or penicillin for childhood-onset neuropsychiatric disorders. Biol Psychiatry. (2005) 57:788–93. 10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.035</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2004.12.035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15820236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mink JW. Intravenous immunoglobulin is not an effective treatment for pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric disorder associated with streptococcal infection obsessive-compulsive disorder. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (2016) 55:837–8. 10.1016/j.jaac.2016.07.767</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2016.07.767</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27663937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigra S, Hesselmark E, Bejerot S. Treatment of PANDAS and PANS: a systematic review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. (2018) 86:51–65. 10.1016/j.neurobiorev.2018.01.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiorev.2018.01.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frankovich, Swedo S, Murphy T, Dale RC, Agalliu D, Williams K, et al. . Clinical management of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome: part II-use of immunomodulatory therapies. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2017) 27:574–93. 10.1089/cap.2016.0148</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2016.0148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melamed I, Kobayashi RH, O'Connor M, Kobayashi AL, Schechterman A, Heffron M, et al. . Evaluation of intravenous immunoglobulin in pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2021) 31:118–28. 10.1089/cap.2020.0100</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2020.0100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7984935</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33601937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nadeau JM, Jordan C, Selles RR, Wu MS, King MA, Patel PD, et al. . A pilot trial of cognitive behavioral therapy augmentation of antibiotic treatment in youth with pediatric acute onset neuropsychiatric syndrome- related obsessive compulsive disorder. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2015) 25:337–43. 10.1089/cap.2014.0149</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2014.0149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4442557</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25978743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storch EA, Murphy TK, Geffken GR, Mann G, Adkins J, Merlo LJ, et al. . Cognitive-behavioral therapy for PANDAS-related obsessive-compulsive disorder: findings from a preliminary waitlist controlled open trial. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (2006) 45:1171–8. 10.1097/01.chi.0000231973.43966.a0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.chi.0000231973.43966.a0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17003662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calaprice D, Tona J, Parker-Athill EC, Murphy TK. A survey of pediatric acute-onset neuropsychiatric syndrome characteristics and course. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol. (2017) 27:607–18. 10.1089/cap.2016.0105</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cap.2016.0105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28140619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calkin CV, Carandang CG. Certain eating disorders may be a neuropsychiatric manifestation of PANDAS: case report. J Can Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. (2007) 16:132–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2247422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18421369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
