<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34657327</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0838</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>32</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Scandinavian journal of medicine &amp; science in sports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Scand J Med Sci Sports</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of kinesiotaping in patients with subacromial impingement syndrome: A systematic review with meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>273</StartPage>
          <EndPage>289</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>273-289</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/sms.14084</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine the effectiveness of kinesiotaping (KT) with or without co-interventions for clinical outcomes in patients with subacromial impingement syndrome (SIS).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eight databases (MEDLINE, CENTRAL, EMBASE, PEDro, LILACS, CINAHL, SPORTDiscus, and Web of Science) were searched from inception until March 2021.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="ELIGIBILITY CRITERIA FOR SELECTING STUDIES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Clinical trials that determine the effectiveness of KT with or without co-interventions for clinical outcomes in patients with SIS who are older than 18 years of age.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ten trials for the quantitative analysis were included. For pain intensity at 1-3 weeks, the overall pooled MD was -0.73 cm, 95% CI = -1.50 to 0.04 (p = 0.06), and at 3-6 weeks, it was -0.13 cm, 95% CI = -1.37 to 0.36 (p = 0.25). For shoulder function, the MD was -0.02, 95%CI = -0.30 to 0.26 (p = 0.89). For shoulder Range of Motion (ROM) flexion, the MD was -16.70, 95% CI = -0.52 to 33.92 (p = 0.06). Additionally, there was a low to moderate quality of evidence according to the GRADE rating.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Kinesiotaping with or without co-interventions was not superior to other interventions for improving shoulder pain intensity, function and ROM flexion in patients with SIS.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Araya-Quintanilla</LastName>
            <ForeName>Felipe</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1293-4233</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rehabilitation in Health Research Center (CIRES), Universidad de Las Americas, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gutiérrez-Espinoza</LastName>
            <ForeName>Héctor</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Rehabilitation Sciences, Universidad Andres Bello, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sepúlveda-Loyola</LastName>
            <ForeName>Walter</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Londrina State University (UEL), Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Probst</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vanessa</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiotherapy, Londrina State University (UEL), Londrina, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ramírez-Vélez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robinson</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3075-6960</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Navarrabiomed, IdiSNA, Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geriatric Department, Complejo Hospitalario de Navarra (CHN), Pamplona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Álvarez-Bueno</LastName>
            <ForeName>Celia</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6176-1618</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Health and Social Research Center, Universidad de Castilla-La Mancha Cuenca, Cuenca, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidad Politécnica y Artística del Paraguay, Asunción, Paraguay.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Denmark</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Scand J Med Sci Sports</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9111504</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0905-7188</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019534" MajorTopicYN="Y">Shoulder Impingement Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020069" MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder Pain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">athletic tape</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kinesiotaping</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized clinical trial</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subacromial impingement syndrome</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>3</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657327</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/sms.14084</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witten A, Barfod KW, Thorborg K, Foverskov M, Clausen MB. Subacromial impingement syndrome. Ugeskr Laeger. 2019;181(14):V03180215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bot SD, van der Waal JM, Terwee CB, et al. Incidence and prevalence of complaints of the neck and upper extremity in general practice. Ann Rheum Dis. 2005;64:118-123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhattacharyya R, Edwards K, Wallace AW. Does arthroscopic sub-acromial decompression really work for sub-acromial impingement syndrome: a cohort study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2014;15:324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Umer M, Qadir I, Azam M. Subacromial impingement syndrome. Orthop Rev (Pavia). 2012;4(2):e18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neer CS 2nd. Impingement lesions. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1983;173:70-77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michener LA, McClure PW, Karduna AR. Anatomical and biomechanical mechanisms of subacromial impingement syndrome. Clin Biomech. 2003;18(5):369-379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seitz AL, McClure PW, Finucane S, Boardman ND, Michener LA. Mechanisms or rotator cuff tendinopathy: intrinsic, extrinsic, or both? Clin Biomech. 2011;26(1):1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ludewig PM, Braman JP. Shoulder impingement: biomechanical considerations in rehabilitation. Man Ther. 2011;16(1):33-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steuri R, Sattelmayer M, Elsig S, et al. Effectiveness of conservative interventions including exercise, manual therapy and medical management in adults with shoulder impingement: a systematic review and meta-analysis of RCTs. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51(18):1340-1347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong W, Goost H, Lin XB, et al. Treatments for shoulder impingement syndrome: a PRISMA systematic review and network meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltimore). 2015;94(10):e510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kase K, Wallis J, Kase T. Clinical Therapeutic Applications of the Kinesio Taping Method. 2nd ed. Ken Ikai Co. Ltd; 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaya E, Zinnuroglu M, Tugcu I. Kinesio taping compared to physical therapy modalities for the treatment of shoulder impingement syndrome. Clin Rheumatol. 2011;30(2):201-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halseth T, McChesney JW, DeBeliso M, Vaughn R, Lien J. The effects of KinesioTM taping on proprioception at the ankle. J Sports Sci Med. 2004;3:1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen PL, Hong WH, Lin CH, Chen WC. Biomechanics effects of kinesio taping for persons with patellofemoral pain syndrome during stair climbing. In: Abu Osman NA, Ibrahim F, WanAbas WAB, AbdRahman HS, Ting HN, eds. Biomed 2008, Proceedings 21. Springer; 2008:395-397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu YH, Chen WY, Lin HC, Wang WT, Shih YF. The effects of taping on scapular kinematics and muscle performance in baseball players with shoulder impingement syndrome. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2009;19(6):1092-1099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hume PA, Gerrard DF. Effectiveness of external ankle support. bracing and taping in rugby union. Sports Medicine. 1998;25:285-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Refshauge KM, Kilbreath SL, Raymond J. The effect of recurrent ankle inversion sprain and taping on proprioception at the ankle. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2000;32:10-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lohrer H, Alt W, Gollhofer A. Neuromuscular properties and functional aspects of taped ankles. Am J Sports Med. 1999;27(1):69-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saracoglu I, Emuk Y, Taspinar F. Does taping in addition to physiotherapy improve the outcomes in subacromial impingement syndrome? A systematic review. Physiother Theory Pract. 2018;34(4):251-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montalvo AM, Cara EL, Myer GD. Effect of kinesiology taping on pain in individuals with musculoskeletal injuries: systematic review and meta-analysis. Phys Sportsmed. 2014;42(2):48-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostafavifar M, Wertz J, Borchers J. A systematic review of the effectiveness of kinesiotaping for musculoskeletal injury. Phys Sportsmed. 2012;40(4):33-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA. (editors). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.0 (Updated July 2019). Cochrane. 2019. www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG. PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analysis: the PRISMA statement. J Clin Epidemiol. 2009;62(10):1006-1012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sterne JAC, Savović J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21(11):1539-1558.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furuya-Kanamori L, Barendregt JJ, Doi SAR. A new improved graphical and quantitative method for detecting bias in meta-analysis. Int J Evid Based Healthc. 2018;16(4):195-203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, et al. GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ. 2008;336(7650):924-926.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balshem H, Helfand M, Schunermann HJ, et al. GRADE guidelines: 3. Rating the quality of evidence. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(4):401-406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Oliveira FCL, Pairot de Fontenay B, Bouyer LJ, Desmeules F, Roy J-S. Kinesiotaping for the rehabilitation of rotator cuff-related shoulder pain: a randomized clinical trial. Sports Health. 2021;13(2):161-172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Göksu H, Tuncay F, Borman P. The comparative efficacy of kinesio taping and local injection therapy in patients with subacromial impingement syndrome. Acta Orthop Traumatol Turc. 2016;50(5):483-488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang FJ, Chiu YC, Wu SC, Wang TG, Yang JL, Lin JJ. Kinesiology taping with exercise does not provide additional improvement in round shoulder subjects with impingement syndrome: A single-blinded randomized controlled trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2019;40:99-106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devereaux M, Velanoski KQ, Pennings A, Elmaraghy A. Short-term effectiveness of precut kinesiology tape versus an NSAID as adjuvant treatment to exercise for subacromial impingement: a randomized controlled trial. Clin J Sport Med. 2016;26(1):24-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kul A, Ugur M. Comparison of the efficacy of conventional physical therapy modalities and Kinesio taping treatments in shoulder impingement syndrome. Eurasian J Med. 2019;51(2):139-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller P, Osmotherly P. Does scapula taping facilitate recovery for shoulder impingement symptoms? A pilot randomized controlled trial. J Man Manip Ther. 2009;17(1):E6-E13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thelen MD, Dauber JA, Stoneman PD. The clinical efficacy of kinesio tape for shoulder pain: a randomized, double-blinded, clinical trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2008;38(7):389-395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar N, Nehru A, Rajalakshmi D. Effect of taping as a component of conservative treatment for subacromial impingement syndrome. Health. 2012;4:237-241.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Djordjevic OC, Vukicevic D, Katunac L, Jovic S. Mobilization with movement and kinesiotaping compared with a supervised exercise program for painful shoulder: results of a clinical trial. J Manipulative Physiol Ther. 2012;35(6):454-463.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subaşı V, Çakır T, Arıca Z, et al. Comparison of efficacy of kinesiological taping and subacromial injection therapy in subacromial impingement syndrome. Clin Rheumatol. 2016;35(3):741-746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pekyavas NO, Baltaci G. Short-term effects of high-intensity laser therapy, manual therapy, and Kinesio taping in patients with subacromial impingement syndrome. Lasers Med Sci. 2016;31(6):1133-1141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Şahin Onat Ş, Biçer S, Şahin Z, Küçükali Türkyilmaz A, Kara M, Özbudak DS. Effectiveness of kinesiotaping and subacromial corticosteroid injection in shoulder impingement syndrome. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2016;95(8):553-560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocyigit F, Acar M, Turkmen MB, Kose T, Guldane N, Kuyucu E. Kinesio taping or just taping in shoulder subacromial impingement syndrome? A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Physiother Theory Pract. 2016;32(7):501-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Şimşek HH, Balki S, Keklik SS, Öztürk H, Elden H. Does Kinesio taping in addition to exercise therapy improve the outcomes in subacromial impingement syndrome? A randomized, double-blind, controlled clinical trial. Acta Orthop Traumatol Turc. 2013;47(2):104-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vergili O, Oktas B, Canbeyli ID. Comparison of kinesiotaping, exercise and subacromial injection treatments on functionality and life quality in shoulder impingement syndrome: a randomized controlled study. Indian J Orthop. 2021;55(1):195-202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramírez-Vélez R, Hormazábal-Aguayo I, Izquierdo M, González-Ruíz K, Correa-Bautista JE, García-Hermoso A. Effects of kinesio taping alone versus sham taping in individuals with musculoskeletal conditions after intervention for at least one week: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiotherapy. 2019;105(4):412-420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin S, Zhu B, Huang G, Wang C, Zeng Q, Zhang S. Short-Term effect of kinesiotaping on chronic nonspecific low back pain and disability: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Phys Ther. 2020;100(2):238-254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghozy S, Dung NM, Morra ME, et al. Efficacy of kinesio taping in treatment of shoulder pain and disability: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Physiotherapy. 2020;107:176-188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gianola S, Iannicelli V, Fascio E, et al. Kinesio taping for rotator cuff disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;2021(8):Art. No.: CD012720. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD012720.pub2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Celik D, Karaborklu Argut S, Coban O, Eren I. The clinical efficacy of kinesio taping in shoulder disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Rehabil. 2020;34(6):723-740.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bagheri R, Pourahmadi MR, Sarmadi AR, Takamjani IE, Torkaman G, Fazeli SH. What is the effect and mechanism of kinesiology tape on muscle activity? J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2018;22(2):266-275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander CM, McMullan M, Harrison PJ. What is the effect of taping along or across a muscle on motoneurone excitability? A study using triceps surae. Man Ther. 2008;13(1):57-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim EC, Tay MG. Kinesio taping in musculoskeletal pain and disability that lasts for more than 4 weeks: is it time to peel off the tape and throw it out with the sweat? A systematic review with meta-analysis focused on pain and also methods of tape application. Br J Sports Med. 2015;49(24):1558-1566.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noguera-Iturbe Y, Martínez-Gramage J, Montañez-Aguilera FJ, Casaña J, Lisón JF. Short-term effects of Kinesio taping in the treatment of latent and active upper trapezius trigger points: two prospective, randomized, sham-controlled trials. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):14478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simmonds MJ. Pain and the placebo in physiotherapy: benevolent lie? Physiotherapy. 2000;86:631-637.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dabija DI, Jain NB. Minimal clinically important difference of shoulder outcome measures and diagnoses: a systematic review. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2019;98(8):671-676.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
