<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34657404</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>10</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0019-1442</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>74</Volume>
            <Issue>9-10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
              <Day>30</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ideggyogyaszati szemle</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ideggyogy Sz</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Treatment and new evidences in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>309</StartPage>
          <EndPage>321</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>309-321</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18071/isz.74.0309</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Treatment and new evidences in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder Illés Zs, MD, PhD Ideggyogy Sz 2021;74(9-10):309-321. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) is associated with antibodies against AQP4 in about 80% of the cases. In about one-fourth of seronegative cases, antibodies against the MOG protein are present in the serum (MOG-antibody associated disease, MOGAD). This article discusses off-label azathioprine and mycophenolate mofetil in the treatment of NMOSD and reviews the evidence-based clinical aspects of B/plasma cell depletion, antagonization of IL-6 signaling and blocking the complement pathway. The review also summarizes basic aspects of NMOSD pregnancy focusing on treatment, and the different therapeutic approach in MOGAD. In the recent two years, phase 3 clinical trials provided class I evidence for the efficacy and safety of rituximab (anti-CD20), inebilizumab (anti-CD19), tocilizumab (anti-IL6R), satralizumab (anti-IL6R), and eculizumab (anti-C5) in combination with other immunosuppressants or in monotherapy. The treatment approach in MOGAD is complicated by the monophasic course in about half of the cases and by the potential disappearance of MOG antibody. The necessity of maintenance treatment in MOGAD should be decided after tapered oral steroid. Immunosuppression is recommended in NMOSD during pregnancy and lactation, and this should be considered for optimal selection of treatment in fertile female patients. The new monoclonal antibodies broadened treatment options NMOSD, and the treatment strategy of MOGAD has become more straightforward.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Illés</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zsolt</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9655-0450</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pécsi Tudományegyetem, Neurológiai Klinika, Pécs.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Odense University Hospital, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Dánia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>hun</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Terápiás megközelítés és új evidenciák a neuromyelitis optica spektrum kezelésében.</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Hungary</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ideggyogy Sz</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>17510500R</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0019-1442</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051401">Aquaporin 4</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>YB18NF020M</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C000655944">satralizumab</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051401" MajorTopicYN="N">Aquaporin 4</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuromyelitis Optica</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="hun">
        <AbstractText>A neuromyelitis optica spektrum betegség (NMOSD) az esetek körülbelül 80%-ában AQP4-ellenanyaggal társul. A szeronegatív betegek körülbelül negyedében a központi idegrendszeri myelin oligodendrocyta glikoprotein (MOG) ellen mutatható ki ellenanyag, és ez a kórkép a MOG-ellen­anyag-asszociált betegség (MOGAD) elnevezést kapta. Jelen közlemény áttekinti az off-label azathioprin és myco­phenolat mofetil, valamint az evidenciákon alapuló B- és plazmasejt-depletio, az IL-6-jelátvitel és a komplement útvonal antagonizálás klinikai aspektusait NMOSD-ben. Az összefoglaló tárgyalja az NMOSD-terápia terhességi vonatkozásait, és a MOGAD – NMOSD-től eltérő – kezelési megközelítését. Az NMOSD kezelése kapcsán az utóbbi két évben több, III. fázisú klinikai tanulmányon alapuló I. osztályú evidencia jelent meg. A monoklonális ellenanyagokkal végzett vizsgálatok a rituximab (anti-CD20), az inebilizumab (anti-CD19), a tocilizumab (anti-IL6R), a satralizumab (anti-IL6R) és az eculizumab (anti-C5) hatékonyságát és biztonságosságát jelzik egyéb immunterápiákkal kombinálva vagy monoterápiában. A MOGAD kezelését bonyolítja, hogy az esetek körülbelül fele monofázisos, és a MOG ellenanyag a betegség lefolyása során spontán vagy kezelés hatására eltűnhet. A tartós immunszuppresszió igényét MOGAD-ban a relapsusterápiát követő, leépített orális szteroidkezelés után célszerű eldönteni. NMOSD-ben a fenntartó terápia folytatása javasolt terhesség és szoptatás alatt is, és ezt az optimális kezelés kiválasztásánál fertilis nőbetegeknél figyelembe kell venni. Az új evidenciák terápiarezisztens NMOSD-ben is több lehetőséget kínálnak, és a MOGAD kezelési stratégiája is körvonalazódik.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MOG</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eculizumab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inebilizumab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromyelitis optica</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rituximab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">satralizumab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tocilizumab</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34657404</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18071/isz.74.0309</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
