<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34687561</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0560</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>49</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of cutaneous pathology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Cutan Pathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Potential role of tumor-associated macrophages and CD163/CD68 ratio in mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome in correlation with serum sCD163 and CCL22.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>261</StartPage>
          <EndPage>273</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>261-273</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cup.14155</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Currently, there are no curative treatment options for mycosis fungoides (MF) and Sézary syndrome (SS) other than stem cell transplant. Understanding the interplay between tumor cells and tumor microenvironment could aid in the development of new therapies. Tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) mostly have M2 phenotype that promotes tumor progression. This study investigated CD68+ and CD163+ TAMs as well as CD163/CD68 ratio in skin lesions from different stages of MF, large-plaque parapsoriasis, and SS. Moreover, we analyzed serum levels of sCD163 and CCL22 in correlation with TAMs count and CD163/CD68 ratio. CD68+ and CD163+ TAMs count significantly increased as the disease progressed. CD163/CD68 ratio was highest at MF tumor stage and SS indicating M2 polarization with disease progression. Significant positive correlations were detected between serum levels of sCD163 and CCL22 and CD68+ and CD163+ TAMs count and CD163/CD68 ratio. We concluded that TAMs play an important role in MF progression. High CD163/CD68 ratio in tumor stage MF and SS indicates M2 polarization of TAMs with tumor progression. CD163/CD68 ratio should be considered in assessing TAMs rather than total TAMs count. Also, sCD163 and CCL22 serum levels reflect M2 load and thus could be used as markers to assess disease progression.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 John Wiley &amp; Sons A/S. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>El-Guindy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dina M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3419-0618</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology Department, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elgarhy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lamia H</ForeName>
            <Initials>LH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5277-4751</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology and Venereology Department, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elkholy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rasha A</ForeName>
            <Initials>RA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pathology Department, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ali</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dina A</ForeName>
            <Initials>DA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pathology Department, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Helal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Duaa S</ForeName>
            <Initials>DS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology Department, Faculty of Medicine, Tanta University, Tanta, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Cutan Pathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0425124</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0303-6987</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015703">Antigens, CD</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015214">Antigens, Differentiation, Myelomonocytic</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C515482">CCL22 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C085464">CD163 antigen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C067980">CD68 antigen, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D054422">Chemokine CCL22</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011956">Receptors, Cell Surface</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015703" MajorTopicYN="N">Antigens, CD</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="Y">analysis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015214" MajorTopicYN="N">Antigens, Differentiation, Myelomonocytic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="Y">analysis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054422" MajorTopicYN="N">Chemokine CCL22</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="Y">blood</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018450" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Progression</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009182" MajorTopicYN="N">Mycosis Fungoides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011956" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Cell Surface</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="Y">analysis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012751" MajorTopicYN="N">Sezary Syndrome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000084582" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor-Associated Macrophages</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CCL22</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CD163/CD68 ratio</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sézary syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mycosis fungoides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sCD163</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumor-associated macrophages</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>5</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34687561</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cup.14155</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujii K. New therapies and immunological findings in cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Front Oncol. 2018;8:198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oka T, Miyagaki T. Novel and future therapeutic drugs for advanced mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome. Front Med. 2019;6:116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin Y, Xu J, Lan H. Tumor-associated macrophages in tumor metastasis: biological roles and clinical therapeutic applications. J Hematol Oncol. 2019;12(1):76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mwafy SE, El-Guindy DM. Pathologic assessment of tumor-associated macrophages and their histologic localization in invasive breast carcinoma. J Egypt Natl Canc Inst. 2020;32(1):6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Møller HJ. Soluble CD163. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2012;72(1):1-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Gorp H, Delputte PL, Nauwynck HJ. Scavenger receptor CD163, a jack-of-all-trades and potential target for cell-directed therapy. Mol Immunol. 2010;47(7-8):1650-1660.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>No JH, Moon JM, Kim K, Kim YB. Prognostic significance of serum soluble CD163 level in patients with epithelial ovarian cancer. Gynecol Obstet Invest. 2013;75(4):263-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazankov K, Rode A, Simonsen K, et al. Macrophage activation marker soluble CD163 may predict disease progression in hepatocellular carcinoma. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2016;76(1):64-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersen MN, Abildgaard N, Maniecki MB, Møller HJ, Andersen NF. Monocyte/macrophage-derived soluble CD163: a novel biomarker in multiple myeloma. Eur J Haematol. 2014;93(1):41-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nederby L, Roug AS, Knudsen SS, et al. Soluble CD163 as a prognostic biomarker in B-cell chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Leuk Lymphoma. 2015;56(11):3219-3221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsi ED, Li H, Nixon AB, et al. Serum levels of TARC, MDC, IL-10, and soluble CD163 in Hodgkin lymphoma: a SWOG S0816 correlative study. Blood. 2019;133(16):1762-1765.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayasingam SD, Citartan M, Thang TH, Mat Zin AA, Ang KC, Ch'ng ES. Evaluating the polarization of tumor-associated macrophages into M1 and M2 phenotypes in human cancer tissue: technicalities and challenges in routine clinical practice. Front Oncol. 2020;9:1512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimura T, Kambayashi Y, Fujisawa Y, Hidaka T, Aiba S. Tumor-associated macrophages: therapeutic targets for skin cancer. Front Oncol. 2018;8:3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanita K, Fujimura T, Sato Y, et al. Bexarotene reduces production of CCL22 from tumor-associated macrophages in cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Front Oncol. 2019;9:907.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Röhrle N, Knott MML, Anz D. CCL22 signaling in the tumor environment. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2020;1231:79-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarveswari KN, Yesudian P. The conundrum of parapsoriasis versus patch stage of mycosis fungoides. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2009;75(3):229-235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou J, Tang Z, Gao S, Li C, Feng Y, Zhou X. Tumor-associated macrophages: recent insights and therapies. Front Oncol. 2020;10:188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sánchez-Espiridión B, Martin-Moreno AM, Montalbán C, et al. Immunohistochemical markers for tumor associated macrophages and survival in advanced classical Hodgkin's lymphoma. Haematologica. 2012;97(7):1080-1084.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugaya M, Miyagaki T, Ohmatsu H, et al. Association of the numbers of CD163(+) cells in lesional skin and serum levels of soluble CD163 with disease progression of cutaneous T cell lymphoma. J Dermatol Sci. 2012;68(1):45-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furudate S, Fujimura T, Kakizaki A, et al. The possible interaction between periostin expressed by cancer stroma and tumor-associated macrophages in developing mycosis fungoides. Exp Dermatol. 2016;25(2):107-112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu X, Schulte BC, Zhou Y, et al. Depletion of M2-like tumor-associated macrophages delays cutaneous T-cell lymphoma development in vivo. J Invest Dermatol. 2014;134(11):2814-2822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Y, Song Y, Du W, Gong L, Chang H, Zou Z. Tumor-associated macrophages: an accomplice in solid tumor progression. J Biomed Sci. 2019;26(1):78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Q, Guo N, Zhou Y, Chen J, Wei Q, Han M. The role of tumor-associated macrophages (TAMs) in tumor progression and relevant advance in targeted therapy. Acta Pharm Sin B. 2020;10(11):2156-2170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang C, Wei C, Wang S, et al. Elevated CD163+/CD68+ ratio at tumor invasive front is closely associated with aggressive phenotype and poor prognosis in colorectal cancer. Int J Biol Sci. 2019;15(5):984-998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lan C, Huang X, Lin S, et al. Expression of M2-polarized macrophages is associated with poor prognosis for advanced epithelial ovarian cancer. Technol Cancer Res Treat. 2013;12(3):259-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niino D, Komohara Y, Murayama T, et al. Ratio of M2 macrophage expression is closely associated with poor prognosis for angioimmunoblastic T-cell lymphoma (AITL). Pathol Int. 2010;60(4):278-283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rezaeifard S, Razmkhah M, Robati M, Momtahan M, Ghaderi A. Cytokines, chemokines, and chemokine receptors quantitative expressions in patients with ovarian cancer. Iran J Med Sci. 2015;40(3):225-232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salah El-Din T, Hassab-El-Naby H, El-Hariri M. Study of the role of serum cd163 as a prognostic tool in mycosis fungoides therapy. Al-Azhar Med J. 2020;49(4):2023-2032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura S, Nanbu U, Noguchi H, et al. Macrophage CCL22 expression in the tumor microenvironment and implications for survival in patients with squamous cell carcinoma of the tongue. J Oral Pathol Med. 2019;48(8):677-685.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura S, Noguchi H, Nanbu U, Wang KY, Sasaguri Y, Nakayama T. Relationship between CCL22 expression by vascular smooth muscle cells and macrophage histamine receptors in atherosclerosis. J Atheroscler Thromb. 2018;25(12):1240-1254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamagata Y, Tomioka H, Sakamoto K, et al. CD163-positive macrophages within the tumor stroma are associated with lymphangiogenesis and lymph node metastasis in oral squamous cell carcinoma. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2017;75(10):2144-2153.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohuchi K, Fujimura T, Lyu C, Amagai R, Muto Y, Aiba S. Serum CCL22 levels decreased in parallel with disease activity in CCR4-positive mycosis fungoides treated with mogamulizumab. Dermatol Ther. 2020;33(6):e14099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
