<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34704149</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1459</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>269</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Nationwide incidence of myotonic dystrophy type 1 and the status of multi-organ involvement.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2666</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2672</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2666-2672</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00415-021-10875-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to investigate the incidence of myotonic dystrophy type 1 (DM1) and the status of multi-organ involvement.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a nationwide, population-based, cohort study using data from the Korean National Health Claims database. All patients with DM1 from the entire population aged ≤ 80 years were included. To identify possible systemic diseases along with DM1, we searched for concurrent codes for systemic diseases. To assess the recent status of systemic evaluation, concurrent codes for various diagnostic and treatment modalities were collected. Cumulative incidence during 2016-2019 was first evaluated then systemic evaluation for those patients was assessed during 2010-2019.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 387 patients (47.8% men) during the recent 4-year study period (2016-2019) were diagnosed with DM1. The cumulative incidence in the general population was 0.77 (95% confidence interval: 0.76-0.77) per 100,000 persons. In newly developed incidental cases, cardiac involvement developed in 51.2%, pneumonia in 30.7%, diabetes in 26.9%, brain involvement in 18.1%, cataract in 13.7%, and cancers in 5.4% of total patients. Electrocardiography was performed in 93.8%, Holter in 33.9%, and echocardiography in 31.3% of the total patients for cardiac evaluation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The incidence estimates of DM1 in the Asian population were lower than those of Caucasians. This study provides the real situation of screening and treatment for systemic diseases related to DM1. These detailed estimates could promote an understanding of the current disease status and allow for appropriate planning within the healthcare system.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ju-Yeun</ForeName>
            <Initials>JY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Ophthalmology, Myongji Hospital, Hanyang University College of Medicine, Goyang, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Preventive Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Integrated Major in Innovative Medical Science, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jeong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ha-Neul</ForeName>
            <Initials>HN</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5785-116X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Myongji Hospital, Hanyang University College of Medicine, 55, Hwasu-ro 14, Deogyang-gu, Goyang-si, Gyeonggi-do, 10475, Republic of Korea. hkns8679@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Republic of Korea. hkns8679@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0423161</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0340-5354</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004562" MajorTopicYN="N">Electrocardiography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006321" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015994" MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009223" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myotonic Dystrophy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arrhythmia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiovascular diseases</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Incidence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myotonic dystrophy type 1</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34704149</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-021-10875-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00415-021-10875-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahadevan M, Tsilfidis C, Sabourin L, Shutler G, Amemiya C, Jansen G, Neville C, Narang M, Barceló J, O’Hoy K et al (1992) Myotonic dystrophy mutation: an unstable CTG repeat in the 3’ untranslated region of the gene. Science 255:1253–1255</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1546325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson NE (2019) Myotonic Muscular Dystrophies. Continuum (Minneap Minn) 25:1682–1695</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Die-Smulders CE, Höweler CJ, Thijs C, Mirandolle JF, Anten HB, Smeets HJ, Chandler KE, Geraedts JP (1998) Age and causes of death in adult-onset myotonic dystrophy. Brain 121(Pt 8):1557–1563</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/121.8.1557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petri H, Vissing J, Witting N, Bundgaard H, Kober L (2012) Cardiac manifestations of myotonic dystrophy type 1. Int J Cardiol 160:82–88</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2011.08.037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heatwole CR, Miller J, Martens B, Moxley RT 3rd (2006) Laboratory abnormalities in ambulatory patients with myotonic dystrophy type 1. Arch Neurol 63:1149–1153</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.63.8.1149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaminsky P, Poussel M, Pruna L, Deibener J, Chenuel B, Brembilla-Perrot B (2011) Organ dysfunction and muscular disability in myotonic dystrophy type 1. Medicine (Baltimore) 90:262–268</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0b013e318226046b</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogan C, De Antonio M, Hamroun D, Varet H, Fabbro M, Rougier F, Amarof K, Arne Bes MC, Bedat-Millet AL, Behin A, Bellance R, Bouhour F, Boutte C, Boyer F, Campana-Salort E, Chapon F, Cintas P, Desnuelle C, Deschamps R, Drouin-Garraud V, Ferrer X, Gervais-Bernard H, Ghorab K, Laforet P, Magot A, Magy L, Menard D, Minot MC, Nadaj-Pakleza A, Pellieux S, Pereon Y, Preudhomme M, Pouget J, Sacconi S, Sole G, Stojkovich T, Tiffreau V, Urtizberea A, Vial C, Zagnoli F, Caranhac G, Bourlier C, Riviere G, Geille A, Gherardi RK, Eymard B, Puymirat J, Katsahian S, Bassez G (2016) Gender as a Modifying Factor Influencing Myotonic Dystrophy Type 1 Phenotype Severity and Mortality: A Nationwide Multiple Databases Cross-Sectional Observational Study. PLoS ONE 11:e0148264</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0148264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han J, Park SY, Lee JY (2021) Nationwide population-based incidence and etiologies of pediatric and adult Horner syndrome. J Neurol 268:1276–1283</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-020-10270-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JY, Han J, Yang M, Oh SY (2020) Population-based Incidence of Pediatric and Adult Optic Neuritis and the Risk of Multiple Sclerosis. Ophthalmology 127:417–425</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ophtha.2019.09.032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Theadom A, Rodrigues M, Roxburgh R, Balalla S, Higgins C, Bhattacharjee R, Jones K, Krishnamurthi R, Feigin V (2014) Prevalence of muscular dystrophies: a systematic literature review. Neuroepidemiology 43:259–268</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000369343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson NE, Butterfield RJ, Mayne K, Newcomb T, Imburgia C, Dunn D, Duval B, Feldkamp ML, Weiss RB (2021) Population-based prevalence of myotonic dystrophy type 1 using genetic analysis of statewide blood screening program. Neurology 96:e1045–e1053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindberg C, Bjerkne F (2017) Prevalence of myotonic dystrophy type 1 in adults in western Sweden. Neuromuscul Disord 27:159–162</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nmd.2016.12.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelargonio G, Dello Russo A, Sanna T, De Martino G, Bellocci F (2002) Myotonic dystrophy and the heart. Heart 88:665–670</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/heart.88.6.665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lund M, Diaz LJ, Ranthe MF, Petri H, Duno M, Juncker I, Eiberg H, Vissing J, Bundgaard H, Wohlfahrt J, Melbye M (2014) Cardiac involvement in myotonic dystrophy: a nationwide cohort study. Eur Heart J 35:2158–2164</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehu157</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner C, Hilton-Jones D (2014) Myotonic dystrophy: diagnosis, management and new therapies. Curr Opin Neurol 27:599–606</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0000000000000128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winblad S, Lindberg C, Hansen S (2006) Cognitive deficits and CTG repeat expansion size in classical myotonic dystrophy type 1 (DM1). Behav Brain Funct 2:16</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1744-9081-2-16</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaul C, Schmidt T, Windisch G, Wieser T, Müller T, Vielhaber S, Zierz S, Leplow B (2006) Subtle cognitive dysfunction in adult onset myotonic dystrophy type 1 (DM1) and type 2 (DM2). Neurology 67:350–352</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000225180.27833.c1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minnerop M, Weber B, Schoene-Bake JC, Roeske S, Mirbach S, Anspach C, Schneider-Gold C, Betz RC, Helmstaedter C, Tittgemeyer M, Klockgether T, Kornblum C (2011) The brain in myotonic dystrophy 1 and 2: evidence for a predominant white matter disease. Brain 134:3530–3546</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awr299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romeo V, Pegoraro E, Ferrati C, Squarzanti F, Sorarù G, Palmieri A, Zucchetta P, Antunovic L, Bonifazi E, Novelli G, Trevisan CP, Ermani M, Manara R, Angelini C (2010) Brain involvement in myotonic dystrophies: neuroimaging and neuropsychological comparative study in DM1 and DM2. J Neurol 257:1246–1255</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-010-5498-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Aburakawa Y, Suzuki Y, Kuroda K, Kimura T (2018) The frequency and risk factors for ischemic stroke in myotonic dystrophy type 1 patients. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis 27:914–918</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2017.10.030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emparanza JI, Lopez de Munain A, Greene MH, Matheu A, Fernandez-Torron R, Gadalla SM (2018) Cancer phenotype in myotonic dystrophy patients: Results from a meta-analysis. Muscle Nerve 58:517–522</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.26194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadalla SM, Lund M, Pfeiffer RM, Gørtz S, Mueller CM, Moxley RT 3rd, Kristinsson SY, Björkholm M, Shebl FM, Hilbert JE, Landgren O, Wohlfahrt J, Melbye M, Greene MH (2011) Cancer risk among patients with myotonic muscular dystrophy. JAMA 306:2480–2486</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2011.1796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadalla SM, Pfeiffer RM, Kristinsson SY, Bjorkholm M, Hilbert JE, Moxley RT, Landgren O, Greene MH (2013) Quantifying cancer absolute risk and cancer mortality in the presence of competing events after a myotonic dystrophy diagnosis. PLoS ONE 8:e79851</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0079851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roman BR, Morris LG, Davies L (2017) The thyroid cancer epidemic, 2017 perspective. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes 24:332–336</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MED.0000000000000359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaccarella S, Franceschi S, Bray F, Wild CP, Plummer M, Dal Maso L (2016) Worldwide thyroid-cancer epidemic? the increasing impact of overdiagnosis. N Engl J Med 375:614–617</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp1604412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
