<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34711906</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1759-4766</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>12</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Nature reviews. Neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Nat Rev Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Hope for patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders - from mechanisms to trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>759</StartPage>
          <EndPage>773</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>759-773</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41582-021-00568-8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) is a rare inflammatory CNS disease that primarily manifests as relapsing episodes of severe optic neuritis and myelitis. Diagnosis of NMOSD is supported by the detection of IgG autoantibodies that target the aquaporin 4 (AQP4) water channel, which, in the CNS, is an astrocyte-specific protein. AQP4 antibody binding leads to AQP4 internalization, complement-dependent and antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity, and water channel dysfunction. Cumulative attack-related injury causes disability in NMOSD, so the prevention of attacks is expected to prevent disability accrual. Until recently, no regulator-approved therapies were available for NMOSD. Traditional immunosuppressant therapies, including mycophenolate mofetil, azathioprine and rituximab, were widely used but their benefits have not been assessed in controlled studies. In 2019 and 2020, five phase II and III randomized placebo-controlled trials of four mechanism-based therapies for NMOSD were published and demonstrated that all four effectively prolonged the time to first relapse. All four drugs were monoclonal antibodies: the complement C5 antibody eculizumab, the IL-6 receptor antibody satralizumab, the B cell-depleting antibody inebilizumab, which targets CD19, and rituximab, which targets CD20. We review the pathophysiology of NMOSD, the rationale for the development of these mechanism-based drugs, the methodology and outcomes of the five trials, and the implications of these findings for the treatment of NMOSD.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. Springer Nature Limited.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pittock</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sean J</ForeName>
            <Initials>SJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6140-5584</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA. Pittock.Sean@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA. Pittock.Sean@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Multiple Sclerosis and Autoimmune Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA. Pittock.Sean@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zekeridou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anastasia</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Multiple Sclerosis and Autoimmune Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Weinshenker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brian G</ForeName>
            <Initials>BG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5806-6203</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Multiple Sclerosis and Autoimmune Neurology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Nat Rev Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101500072</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1759-4758</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009471" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromyelitis Optica</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711906</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41582-021-00568-8</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41582-021-00568-8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon, V. A. et al. A serum autoantibody marker of neuromyelitis optica: distinction from multiple sclerosis. Lancet 364, 2106–2112 (2004). This paper reported the discovery of the NMO biomarker NMO-IgG.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15589308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon, V. A., Kryzer, T. J., Pittock, S. J., Verkman, A. S. &amp; Hinson, S. R. IgG marker of optic-spinal multiple sclerosis binds to the aquaporin-4 water channel. J. Exp. Med. 202, 473–477 (2005). This paper reported that AQP4 is the antigenic target of NMO-IgG.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16087714</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2212860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk, D. M. et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Neurology 85, 177–189 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092914</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4515040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk, D. M., Hogancamp, W. F., O’Brien, P. C. &amp; Weinshenker, B. G. The clinical course of neuromyelitis optica (Devic’s syndrome). Neurology 53, 1107–1114 (1999).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10496275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk, D. M., Lennon, V. A., Pittock, S. J., Lucchinetti, C. F. &amp; Weinshenker, B. G. Revised diagnostic criteria for neuromyelitis optica. Neurology 66, 1485–1489 (2006).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk, D. M., Lennon, V. A., Lucchinetti, C. F., Pittock, S. J. &amp; Weinshenker, B. G. The spectrum of neuromyelitis optica. Lancet Neurol. 6, 805–815 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17706564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan, E. P. et al. Epidemiology of aquaporin-4 autoimmunity and neuromyelitis optica spectrum. Ann. Neurol. 79, 775–783 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26891082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4988933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hor, J. Y. et al. Epidemiology of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and its prevalence and incidence worldwide. Front. Neurol. 11, 501 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32670177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7332882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papp, V. et al. Worldwide incidence and prevalence of neuromyelitis optica: a systematic review. Neurology 96, 59–77 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33310876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7905781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apiwattanakul, M. et al. Diagnostic utility of NMO/AQP4-IgG in evaluating CNS inflammatory disease in Thai patients. J. Neurol. Sci. 320, 118–120 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22831763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3423321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagaishi, A. et al. Clinical features of neuromyelitis optica in a large Japanese cohort: comparison between phenotypes. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 82, 1360–1364 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21665917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quek, A. M. et al. Effects of age and sex on aquaporin-4 autoimmunity. Arch. Neurol. 69, 1039–1043 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22507888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3746965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk, D. M., Pittock, S. J., Lucchinetti, C. F., Lennon, V. A. &amp; Weinshenker, B. G. A secondary progressive clinical course is uncommon in neuromyelitis optica. Neurology 68, 603–605 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17310032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacob, A. et al. Treatment of neuromyelitis optica with rituximab: retrospective analysis of 25 patients. Arch. Neurol. 65, 1443–1448 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costanzi, C. et al. Azathioprine: tolerability, efficacy, and predictors of benefit in neuromyelitis optica. Neurology 77, 659–666 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitley, J. et al. Methotrexate is an alternative to azathioprine in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders with aquaporin-4 antibodies. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 84, 918–921 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23467418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elsone, L. et al. Long-term efficacy, tolerability and retention rate of azathioprine in 103 aquaporin-4 antibody-positive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder patients: a multicentre retrospective observational study from the UK. Mult. Scler. 20, 1533–1540 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24647557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacob, A. et al. Treatment of neuromyelitis optica with mycophenolate mofetil: retrospective analysis of 24 patients. Arch. Neurol. 66, 1128–1133 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19752302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, S. H. et al. Clinical efficacy of plasmapheresis in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and effects on circulating anti-aquaporin-4 antibody levels. J. Clin. Neurol. 9, 36–42 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23346159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3543908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, S. H., Huh, S. Y., Lee, S. J., Joung, A. &amp; Kim, H. J. A 5-year follow-up of rituximab treatment in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. JAMA Neurol. 70, 1110–1117 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23897062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitley, J. et al. Prognostic factors and disease course in aquaporin-4 antibody-positive patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder from the United Kingdom and Japan. Brain 135, 1834–1849 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22577216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cree, B. A. C. et al. Inebilizumab for the treatment of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (N-MOmentum): a double-blind, randomised placebo-controlled phase 2/3 trial. Lancet 394, 1352–1363 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock, S. J. et al. Eculizumab in aquaporin-4-positive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. N. Engl. J. Med. 381, 614–625 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31050279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamura, T. et al. Trial of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. N. Engl. J. Med. 381, 2114–2124 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31774956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Traboulsee, A. et al. Safety and efficacy of satralizumab monotherapy in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 19, 402–412 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7935419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahara, M. et al. Safety and efficacy of rituximab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders (RIN-1 study): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 19, 298–306 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32199095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keegan, M. et al. Plasma exchange for severe attacks of CNS demyelination: predictors of response. Neurology 58, 143–146 (2002).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11781423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe, S. et al. Therapeutic efficacy of plasma exchange in NMO-IgG-positive patients with neuromyelitis optica. Mult. Scler. 13, 128–132 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17294622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonnan, M. et al. Plasma exchange in severe spinal attacks associated with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Mult. Scler. 15, 487–492 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19324982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonnan, M. &amp; Cabre, P. Plasma exchange in severe attacks of neuromyelitis optica. Mult. Scler. Int. 2012, 787630 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22474589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3306943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim, Y. M., Pyun, S. Y., Kang, B. H., Kim, J. &amp; Kim, K. K. Factors associated with the effectiveness of plasma exchange for the treatment of NMO-IgG-positive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Mult. Scler. 19, 1216–1218 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23263897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan, S. M., Zantek, N. D. &amp; Carpenter, A. F. Therapeutic plasma exchange in neuromyelitis optica: a case series. J. Clin. Apher. 29, 171–177 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24136389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aungsumart, S. &amp; Apiwattanakul, M. Clinical outcomes and predictive factors related to good outcomes in plasma exchange in severe attack of NMOSD and long extensive transverse myelitis: case series and review of the literature. Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord. 13, 93–97 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28427710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleiter, I. et al. Apheresis therapies for NMOSD attacks: a retrospective study of 207 therapeutic interventions. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm. 5, e504 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30345331</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6192689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumawat, B. L., Choudhary, R., Sharma, C. M., Jain, D. &amp; Hiremath, A. Plasma exchange as a first line therapy in acute attacks of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Ann. Indian Acad. Neurol. 22, 389–394 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31736557</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6839304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Songthammawat, T. et al. A pilot study comparing treatments for severe attacks of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: Intravenous methylprednisolone (IVMP) with add-on plasma exchange (PLEX) versus simultaneous ivmp and PLEX. Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord. 38, 101506 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31731214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ipe, T. S. et al. Therapeutic plasma exchange for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a multicenter retrospective study by the ASFA neurologic diseases subcommittee. J. Clin. Apher. 35, 25–32 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31705563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abboud, H. et al. Treatment of acute relapses in neuromyelitis optica: steroids alone versus steroids plus plasma exchange. Mult. Scler. J. 22, 185–192 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori, S., Kurimoto, T., Ueda, K. &amp; Nakamura, M. Short-term effect of additional apheresis on visual acuity changes in patients with steroid-resistant optic neuritis in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Jpn. J. Ophthalmol. 62, 525–530 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29802557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinshenker, B. G. et al. A randomized trial of plasma exchange in acute central nervous system inflammatory demyelinating disease. Ann. Neurol. 46, 878–886 (1999).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10589540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleiter, I. et al. Neuromyelitis optica: evaluation of 871 attacks and 1,153 treatment courses. Ann. Neurol. 79, 206–216 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26537743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinshenker, B. G. et al. Neuromyelitis optica IgG predicts relapse after longitudinally extensive transverse myelitis. Ann. Neurol. 59, 566–569 (2006).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16453327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matiello, M. et al. NMO-IgG predicts the outcome of recurrent optic neuritis. Neurology 70, 2197–2200 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18434643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>[No authors listed] Neuromyelitis optica. Nat. Rev. Dis. Primers 6, 84 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cree, B. A. et al. An open label study of the effects of rituximab in neuromyelitis optica. Neurology 64, 1270–1272 (2005).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15824362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Damato, V., Evoli, A. &amp; Iorio, R. Efficacy and safety of rituximab therapy in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Neurol. 73, 1342–1348 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27668357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, F. et al. Effectiveness of rituximab in neuromyelitis optica: a meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 19, 36 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30841862</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6402122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeong, I. H. et al. Comparative analysis of treatment outcomes in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder using multifaceted endpoints. Mult. Scler. 22, 329–339 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26041804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, S. H. et al. Treatment outcomes with rituximab in 100 patients with neuromyelitis optica: influence of FCGR3A polymorphisms on the therapeutic response to rituximab. JAMA Neurol. 72, 989–995 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26167726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mealy, M. A., Wingerchuk, D. M., Palace, J., Greenberg, B. M. &amp; Levy, M. Comparison of relapse and treatment failure rates among patients with neuromyelitis optica: multicenter study of treatment efficacy. JAMA Neurol. 71, 324–330 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24445513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nosadini, M. et al. Rituximab monitoring and redosing in pediatric neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm. 3, e188 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26819962</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4723136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poupart, J. et al. Evaluation of efficacy and tolerability of first-line therapies in NMOSD. Neurology 94, e1645–e1656 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32170036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zephir, H. et al. Rituximab as first-line therapy in neuromyelitis optica: efficiency and tolerability. J. Neurol. 262, 2329–2335 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26194198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giovannelli, J. et al. Meta-analysis comparing first-line immunosuppressants in neuromyelitis optica. Ann. Clin. Transl. Neurol. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.51451 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34505407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8528466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greco, R. et al. Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation for neuromyelitis optica. Ann. Neurol. 75, 447–453 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24318127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burt, R. K. et al. Autologous nonmyeloablative hematopoietic stem cell transplantation for neuromyelitis optica. Neurology 93, e1732–e1741 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31578302</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6946475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hau, L. et al. Allogeneic haematopoietic stem cell transplantation in a refractory case of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord. 42, 102110 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32408149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kunchok, A. et al. Application of 2015 seronegative neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder diagnostic criteria for patients with myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein IgG-associated disorders. JAMA Neurol. 77, 1572–1575 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7418041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reindl, M. &amp; Waters, P. Myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein antibodies in neurological disease. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 15, 89–102 (2019). This review provides a clear and concise overview of MOG antibody disease.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30559466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, J. J. et al. Steroid-sparing maintenance immunotherapy for MOG-IgG associated disorder. Neurology 95, e111–e120 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32554760</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7455322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hacohen, Y. B. et al. Disease course and treatment responses in children with relapsing myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein antibody-associated disease. JAMA Neurol. 75, 478–487 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29305608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5885190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramanathan, S. et al. Clinical course, therapeutic responses and outcomes in relapsing MOG antibody-associated demyelination. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 89, 127–137 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29142145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whittam, D. H. et al. Treatment of MOG-IgG-associated disorder with rituximab: an international study of 121 patients. Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord. 44, 102251 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32629363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7895306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobo-Calvo, A. et al. Evaluation of treatment response in adults with relapsing MOG-Ab-associated disease. J. Neuroinflammation 16, 134 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31266527</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6607517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lucchinetti, C. F. et al. A role for humoral mechanisms in the pathogenesis of Devic’s neuromyelitis optica. Brain 125, 1450–1461 (2002).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12076996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howe, C. L. et al. Neuromyelitis optica IgG stimulates an immunological response in rat astrocyte cultures. Glia 62, 692–708 (2014).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24492996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5392242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hinson, S. R. et al. Molecular outcomes of neuromyelitis optica (NMO)-IgG binding to aquaporin-4 in astrocytes. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 109, 1245–1250 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22128336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hinson, S. R. et al. Pathogenic potential of IgG binding to water channel extracellular domain in neuromyelitis optica. Neurology 69, 2221–2231 (2007).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17928579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hinson, S. R. et al. Aquaporin-4-binding autoantibodies in patients with neuromyelitis optica impair glutamate transport by down-regulating EAAT2. J. Exp. Med. 205, 2473–2481 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18838545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2571922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent, T. et al. Functional consequences of neuromyelitis optica-IgG astrocyte interactions on blood-brain barrier permeability and granulocyte recruitment. J. Immunol. 181, 5730–5737 (2008).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18832732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duan, T., Smith, A. J. &amp; Verkman, A. S. Complement-independent bystander injury in AQP4-IgG seropositive neuromyelitis optica produced by antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 7, 112 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31296268</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6621951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujihara, K. et al. Interleukin-6 in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder pathophysiology. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm. 7, e841 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32820020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7455314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sagan, S. A. et al. Tolerance checkpoint bypass permits emergence of pathogenic T cells to neuromyelitis optica autoantigen aquaporin-4. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 113, 14781–14786 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27940915</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5187685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pohl, M. et al. T cell-activation in neuromyelitis optica lesions plays a role in their formation. Acta Neuropathol. Commun. 1, 85 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24367907</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3879999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaknin-Dembinsky, A. et al. T-cell responses to distinct AQP4 peptides in patients with neuromyelitis optica (NMO). Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord. 6, 28–36 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27063619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cotzomi, E. et al. Early B cell tolerance defects in neuromyelitis optica favour anti-AQP4 autoantibody production. Brain 142, 1598–1615 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31056665</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6536857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett, J. L. et al. Intrathecal pathogenic anti-aquaporin-4 antibodies in early neuromyelitis optica. Ann. Neurol. 66, 617–629 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19938104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3180961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobo-Calvo, A. et al. Purified IgG from aquaporin-4 neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder patients alters blood-brain barrier permeability. PLoS ONE 15, e0238301 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7470361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimizu, F. et al. Sera from neuromyelitis optica patients disrupt the blood-brain barrier. J. Neurol. Neurosurg. Psychiatry 83, 288–297 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22100760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, Y. et al. Pathogenic implications of cerebrospinal fluid barrier pathology in neuromyelitis optica. Acta Neuropathol. 133, 597–612 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28184993</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5348570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimizu, F. et al. Glucose-regulated protein 78 autoantibody associates with blood-brain barrier disruption in neuromyelitis optica. Sci. Transl Med. 9, eaai9111 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28679661</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5585784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tedder, T. F. CD19: a promising B cell target for rheumatoid arthritis. Nat. Rev. Rheumatol. 5, 572–577 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19798033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, D. S. W., Rojas, O. L. &amp; Gommerman, J. L. B cell depletion therapies in autoimmune disease: advances and mechanistic insights. Nat. Rev. Drug Discov. 20, 179–199 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33324003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Icoz, S. et al. Enhanced IL-6 production in aquaporin-4 antibody positive neuromyelitis optica patients. Int. J. Neurosci. 120, 71–75 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20128675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uzawa, A. et al. Markedly increased CSF interleukin-6 levels in neuromyelitis optica, but not in multiple sclerosis. J. Neurol. 256, 2082–2084 (2009).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19655191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, H. et al. Notable increased cerebrospinal fluid levels of soluble interleukin-6 receptors in neuromyelitis optica. Neuroimmunomodulation 19, 304–308 (2012).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22777162</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chihara, N. et al. Plasmablasts as migratory IgG-producing cells in the pathogenesis of neuromyelitis optica. PLoS ONE 8, e83036 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24340077</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3858367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chihara, N. et al. Interleukin 6 signaling promotes anti-aquaporin 4 autoantibody production from plasmablasts in neuromyelitis optica. Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA 108, 3701–3706 (2011).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3048150</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uzawa, A. et al. Interleukin-6 analysis of 572 consecutive CSF samples from neurological disorders: A special focus on neuromyelitis optica. Clin. Chim. Acta 469, 144–149 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uzawa, A. et al. Cerebrospinal fluid interleukin-6 and glial fibrillary acidic protein levels are increased during initial neuromyelitis optica attacks. Clin. Chim. Acta 421, 181–183 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uzawa, A. et al. Cytokine and chemokine profiles in neuromyelitis optica: significance of interleukin-6. Mult. Scler. 16, 1443–1452 (2010).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barros, P. O. et al. Prediction of disease severity in neuromyelitis optica by the levels of interleukin (IL)-6 produced during remission phase. Clin. Exp. Immunol. 183, 480–489 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26472479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeshita, Y. et al. Effects of neuromyelitis optica-IgG at the blood-brain barrier in vitro. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm. 4, e311 (2017).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28018943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, R. et al. Condition-dependent generation of aquaporin-4 antibodies from circulating B cells in neuromyelitis optica. Brain 141, 1063–1074 (2018).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29447335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5889028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayzenberg, I. et al. Interleukin 6 receptor blockade in patients with neuromyelitis optica nonresponsive to anti-CD20 therapy. JAMA Neurol. 70, 394–397 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23358868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soltys, J. et al. Membrane assembly of aquaporin-4 autoantibodies regulates classical complement activation in neuromyelitis optica. J. Clin. Invest. 129, 2000–2013 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30958797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6486354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock, S. J. et al. Eculizumab in AQP4-IgG-positive relapsing neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: an open-label pilot study. Lancet Neurol. 12, 554–562 (2013).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23623397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cree, B. A. et al. Placebo-controlled study in neuromyelitis optica-Ethical and design considerations. Mult. Scler. 22, 862–872 (2016).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26666258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy, M. The ethics of placebo controlled clinical trials in NMO-a balance of risks. Mult. Scler. Relat. Disord. 4, 512–514 (2015).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26590656</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4810439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon-Chrimes, S. et al. Characterisation of the PK and PD of satralizumab, a recycling antibody, to support Q4W dosing in patients with NMOSD. Eur. J. Neurol. 27, 930 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berthele, A. et al. Pharmacokinetic/pharmacodynamic properties of eculizumab support established efficacy in patients with NMOSD: findings from the phase 3 PREVENT study. Eur. J. Neurol. 27, 351 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk, D. M. et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of eculizumab in aquaporin-4 IgG-positive NMOSD. Ann. Neurol. 89, 1088–1098 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586143</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8248139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock, S. et al. Long-term efficacy and safety of eculizumab monotherapy in AQP4<sup>+</sup> neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (1578). Neurology 96, 1578 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cree, B. et al. Long term efficacy outcomes with inebilizumab treatment in NMOSD: the N-MOmentum Trial (2329). Neurology 96, 2329 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cree, B. et al. Long term safety outcomes with inebilizumab treatment in NMOSD: the N-MOmentum Trial (2283). Neurology 96, 2283 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waters, P. J. et al. Serologic diagnosis of NMO: a multicenter comparison of aquaporin-4-IgG assays. Neurology 78, 665–671 (2012). This study provided a blinded comparison of various assay methodologies for the detection of AQP4-IgG.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22302543</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3286228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy, M., Fujihara, K. &amp; Palace, J. New therapies for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Lancet Neurol. 20, 60–67 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33186537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marignier, R. et al. Disability outcomes in the N-MOmentum trial of inebilizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Neurol. Neuroimmunol. Neuroinflamm. 8, e978 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33771837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8054974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, C. et al. Safety and efficacy of tocilizumab versus azathioprine in highly relapsing neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (TANGO): an open-label, multicentre, randomised, phase 2 trial. Lancet Neurol. 19, 391–401 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333897</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7935423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock, S. J. et al. Eculizumab monotherapy for NMOSD: data from PREVENT and its open-label extension. Mult. Scler. https://doi.org/10.1177/13524585211038291 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luna, G. et al. Infection risks among patients with multiple sclerosis treated with fingolimod, natalizumab, rituximab, and injectable therapies. JAMA Neurol. 77, 184–191 (2020).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31589278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock, S. J. et al. Response to: Eculizumab package insert recommendations for meningococcal vaccinations: call for clarity and a targeted approach for use of the drug in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. CNS Spectr. 26, 195–196 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32641193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Socie, G. et al. Eculizumab in paroxysmal nocturnal haemoglobinuria and atypical haemolytic uraemic syndrome: 10-year pharmacovigilance analysis. Br. J. Haematol. 185, 297–310 (2019).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30768680</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6594003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aktas, O. et al. Serum glial fibrillary acidic protein: a neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder biomarker. Ann. Neurol. 89, 895–910 (2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33724534</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8252046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
