<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34711792</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-0763</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>92</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The journal of trauma and acute care surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Gastroesophageal resuscitative occlusion of the aorta prolongs survival in a lethal liver laceration model.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>880</StartPage>
          <EndPage>889</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>880-889</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TA.0000000000003444</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Noncompressible torso hemorrhage management remains a challenge especially in the prehospital setting. We evaluated a device designed to occlude the aorta from the stomach (gastroesophageal resuscitative occlusion of the aorta [GROA]) for its ability to stop hemorrhage and improve survival in a swine model of lethal liver laceration and compared its performance to resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta (REBOA) and controls.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Swine (n = 24) were surgically instrumented and a 30% controlled arterial hemorrhage over 20 minutes was followed by liver laceration. Animals received either GROA, REBOA, or control (no treatment) for 60 minutes. Following intervention, devices were deactivated, and animals received whole blood and crystalloid resuscitation. Animals were monitored for an additional 4 hours.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The liver laceration resulted in the onset of class IV shock. Mean arterial blood pressure (MAP) (standard deviation) decreased from 84.5 mm Hg (11.69 mm Hg) to 27.1 mm Hg (5.65 mm Hg) at the start of the intervention. Seven of eight control animals died from injury prior to the end of the intervention period with a median survival (interquartile) time of 10.5 minutes (12 minutes). All GROA and REBOA animals survived the duration of the intervention period (60 minutes) with median survival times of 86 minutes (232 minutes) and 79 minutes (199 minutes) after resuscitation, respectively. The GROA and REBOA animals experienced a significant improvement in survival compared with controls (p = 0.01). Resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta resulted in higher MAP at the end of intervention 114.6 mm Hg (22.9 mm Hg) compared with GROA 88.2 mm Hg (18.72 mm Hg) (p = 0.024), as well as increased lactate compared with GROA 13.2 meq·L-1 (1.56 meq·L-1) versus 10.5 meq·L-1 (1.89 meq·L-1) (p = 0.028). Histological examination of the gastric mucosa in surviving animals revealed mild ischemic injury from both GROA and REBOA.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The GROA and REBOA devices were both effective at temporarily stanching lethal noncompressible torso hemorrhage of the abdomen and prolonging survival.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>McCracken</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brendan M</ForeName>
            <Initials>BM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Emergency Medicine (B.M.M., M.H.T., C.I.C., D.C.L., N.L.G., K.R.W.), Michigan Center for Integrative Research in Critical Care (MCIRCC) (B.M.M., M.H.T., C.I.C., D.C.L., N.L.G., J.S.P., A.J.S., S.C.W., J.L.E., K.R.W.), Department of Biomedical Engineering (J.S.P., A.J.S., K.R.W.), Department of Mechanical Engineering (J.S.P., A.J.S.), and Department of Surgery (S.C.W., J.L.E.), University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tiba</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohamad Hakam</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Colmenero Mahmood</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carmen I</ForeName>
            <Initials>CI</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leander</LastName>
            <ForeName>Danielle C</ForeName>
            <Initials>DC</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Greer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas L</ForeName>
            <Initials>NL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Plott</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeffery S</ForeName>
            <Initials>JS</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shih</LastName>
            <ForeName>Albert J</ForeName>
            <Initials>AJ</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stewart C</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eliason</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonathan L</ForeName>
            <Initials>JL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ward</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kevin R</ForeName>
            <Initials>KR</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101570622</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2163-0755</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001011" MajorTopicYN="N">Aorta</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D022125" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lacerations</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008099" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012771" MajorTopicYN="Y">Shock, Hemorrhagic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013552" MajorTopicYN="N">Swine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>51</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34711792</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000003444</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">01586154-202205000-00014</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eastridge BJ, Holcomb JB, Shackelford S. Outcomes of traumatic hemorrhagic shock and the epidemiology of preventable death from injury. Transfusion. 2019;59(S2):1423–1428.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eastridge BJ, Hardin M, Cantrell J, et al. Died of wounds on the battlefield: causation and implications for improving combat casualty care. J Trauma. 2011;71(Suppl 1):S4–S8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eastridge BJ, Mabry RL, Seguin P, et al. Death on the battlefield (2001–2011): implications for the future of combat casualty care. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012;73(6 Suppl 5):S431–S437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kauvar DS, Lefering R, Wade CE. Impact of hemorrhage on trauma outcome: an overview of epidemiology, clinical presentations, and therapeutic considerations. J Trauma. 2006;60(Suppl 6):S3–S11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrison JJ, Rasmussen TE. Noncompressible torso hemorrhage: a review with contemporary definitions and management strategies. Surg Clin North Am. 2012;92(4):843–58, vii.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klotz JK, Leo M, Anderson BL, et al. First case report of SAM(r) junctional tourniquet use in Afghanistan to control inguinal hemorrhage on the battlefield. J Spec Oper Med. 2014;14(2):1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kisat M, Morrison JJ, Hashmi ZG, Efron DT, Rasmussen TE, Haider AH. Epidemiology and outcomes of non-compressible torso hemorrhage. J Surg Res. 2013;184(1):414–421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holcomb J, Caruso J, McMullin N, et al. Causes of death in US Special Operations Forces in the global war on terrorism: 2001–2004. US Army Med Dep J. 2007;24–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrison JJ, Poon H, Rasmussen TE, Khan MA, Midwinter MJ, Blackbourne LH, Garner JP. Resuscitative thoracotomy following wartime injury. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2013;74(3):825–829.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linnebur M, Inaba K, Haltmeier T, Rasmussen TE, Smith J, Mendelsberg R, Grabo D, Demetriades D. Emergent non-image-guided resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta (REBOA) catheter placement: a cadaver-based study. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2016;81(3):453–457.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore LJ, Brenner M, Kozar RA, Pasley J, Wade CE, Baraniuk MS, Scalea T, Holcomb JB. Implementation of resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta as an alternative to resuscitative thoracotomy for noncompressible truncal hemorrhage. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2015;79(4):523–530; discussion 30-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrison JJ, Galgon RE, Jansen JO, Cannon JW, Rasmussen TE, Eliason JL. A systematic review of the use of resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta in the management of hemorrhagic shock. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2016;80(2):324–334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadek S, Lockey DJ, Lendrum RA, Perkins Z, Price J, Davies GE. Resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta (REBOA) in the pre-hospital setting: an additional resuscitation option for uncontrolled catastrophic haemorrhage. Resuscitation. 2016;107:135–138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiba MH, McCracken BM, Colmenero CI, Plott JS, Leander DC, Greer NL, Wang SC, Shih AJ, Eliason JL, Ward KR. Gastroesophageal resuscitative occlusion of the aorta: physiologic tolerance in a swine model of hemorrhagic shock. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>(U.S.). NRC, Animals CftUotGftCaUoL. Guide for the care and use of laboratory animals. Institute for Laboratory Animal Research (U.S.) NAPUS, editor ed. Washington, DC: National Academies Press; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lada E, Anna M, Patrik M, Zbynek T, Miroslav J, Hynek M, Richard P, Sarah L, Vaclav L. Porcine liver anatomy applied to biomedicine. J Surg Res. 2020;250:70–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kozar RA, Crandall M, Shanmuganathan K, Zarzaur BL, Coburn M, Cribari C, Kaups K, Schuster K, Tominaga GT; AAST Patient Assessment Committee. Organ injury scaling 2018 update: spleen, liver, and kidney. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2018;85(6):1119–1122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrison JJ, Ross JD, Houston R 4th, Watson JD, Sokol KK, Rasmussen TE. Use of resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta in a highly lethal model of noncompressible torso hemorrhage. Shock. 2014;41(2):130–137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duggan MJ, Mejaddam AY, Beagle J, et al. Development of a lethal, closed-abdomen grade V hepato-portal injury model in non-coagulopathic swine. J Surg Res. 2013;182(1):101–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markov NP, Percival TJ, Morrison JJ, Ross JD, Scott DJ, Spencer JR, Rasmussen TE. Physiologic tolerance of descending thoracic aortic balloon occlusion in a swine model of hemorrhagic shock. Surgery. 2013;153(6):848–856.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo RM, Williams TK, Grayson JK, Lamb CM, Cannon JW, Clement NF, Galante JM, Neff LP. Extending the golden hour: partial resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta in a highly lethal swine liver injury model. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2016;80(3):372–378; discussion 8-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andres J, Scott J, Giannoudis PV. Resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta (REBOA): what have we learned?Injury. 2016;47(12):2603–2605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiba MH, McCracken BM, Cummings BC, Colmenero CI, Rygalski CJ, Hsu CH, Sanderson TH, Nallamothu BK, Neumar RW, Ward KR. Use of resuscitative balloon occlusion of the aorta in a swine model of prolonged cardiac arrest. Resuscitation. 2019;140:106–112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Croushorn J. Abdominal aortic and junctional tourniquet controls hemorrhage from a gunshot wound of the left groin. J Spec Oper Med. 2014;14(2):6–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schechtman DW, Kauvar DS, De Guzman R, Polykratis IA, Prince MD, Kheirabadi BS, Dubick MA. Abdominal aortic and junctional tourniquet versus zone III resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta in a swine junctional hemorrhage model. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2020;88(2):292–297.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rall JM, Redman TT, Ross EM, Morrison JJ, Maddry JK. Comparison of zone 3 resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta and the abdominal aortic and junctional tourniquet in a model of junctional hemorrhage in swine. J Surg Res. 2018;226:31–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brede JR, Lafrenz T, Kruger AJ, Sovik E, Steffensen T, Kriesi C, Steinert M, Klepstad P. Resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta (REBOA) in non-traumatic out-of-hospital cardiac arrest: evaluation of an educational programme. BMJ Open. 2019;9(5):e027980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>A. A, B.J. E. Junctional hemorrhage and prehospital time after injury: highlighting the need for novel strategies to control complex sources of hemorrhage and temporize survival to definitive care. In: Military Health System Research Symposium. Washington, DC: UT Health San Antonio; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alarhayem AQ, Myers JG, Dent D, et al. Time is the enemy: mortality in trauma patients with hemorrhage from torso injury occurs long before the "golden hour". Am J Surg. 2016;212(6):1101–1105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner M, Bulger EM, Perina DG, et al. Joint statement from the American College of Surgeons Committee on Trauma (ACS COT) and the American College of Emergency Physicians (ACEP) regarding the clinical use of Resuscitative Endovascular Balloon Occlusion of the Aorta (REBOA). Trauma Surg Acute Care Open. 2018;3(1):e000154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davidson AJ, Russo RM, Reva VA, et al. The pitfalls of REBOA: risk factors and mitigation strategies. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lendrum R, Perkins Z, Chana M, Marsden M, Davenport R, Grier G, Sadek S, Davies G. Pre-hospital resuscitative endovascular balloon occlusion of the aorta (REBOA) for exsanguinating pelvic haemorrhage. Resuscitation. 2019;135:6–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
