<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34727377</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4687</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>283</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of morphology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Morphol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Chemical phenotypes of intrinsic cardiac neurons in the newborn pig (Sus scrofa domesticus Erxleben, 1777).</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>51</StartPage>
          <EndPage>65</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>51-65</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jmor.21426</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Intrinsic cardiac neurons (ICNs) are crucial cells in the neural regulation of heart rhythm, myocardial contractility, and coronary blood flow. ICNs exhibit diversity in their morphology and neurotransmitters that probably are age-dependent. Therefore, neuroanatomical heart studies have been currently focused on the identification of chemical phenotypes of ICNs to disclose their possible functions in heart neural regulation. Employing whole-mount immunohistochemistry, we examined ICNs from atria of the newborn pigs (Sus scrofa domesticus) as ICNs at this stage of development have never been neurochemically characterized so far. We found that the majority of the examined ICNs (&gt;60%) were of cholinergic phenotype. Biphenotypic neuronal somata (NS), that is, simultaneously positive for two neuronal markers, were also rather common and distributed evenly within the sampled ganglia. Simultaneous positivity for cholinergic and adrenergic neuromarkers was specific in 16.4%, for cholinergic and nitrergic-in 3.5% of the examined NS. Purely either adrenergic or nitrergic ICNs were observed at 13% and 3.1%, correspondingly. Purely adrenergic and nitrergic NS were the most frequent in the ventral left atrial subplexus. Similarly to neuronal phenotype, sizes of NS also varied depending on the atrial region providing insights into their functional implications. Axons, but not NS, positive for classic sensory neuronal markers (vesicular glutamate transporter 2 and calcitonin gene-related peptide) were identified within epicardiac nerves and ganglia. Moreover, a substantial number of ICNs could not be attributed to any phenotype as they were not immunoreactive for antisera used in this study. Numerous dendrites with putative peptidergic and adrenergic contacts on cholinergic NS contributed to neuropil of ganglia. Our observations demonstrate that intrinsic cardiac ganglionated plexus is not fully developed in the newborn pig despite of dense network of neuronal processes and numerous signs of neural contacts within ganglia.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ragauskas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tomas</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy, Faculty of Medicine, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rysevaite-Kyguoliene</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kristina</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy, Faculty of Medicine, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pauziene</LastName>
            <ForeName>Neringa</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy, Faculty of Medicine, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Inokaitis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hermanas</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy, Faculty of Medicine, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pauza</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dainius Haroldas</ForeName>
            <Initials>DH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8597-4370</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy, Faculty of Medicine, Lithuanian University of Health Sciences, Kaunas, Lithuania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Morphol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406125</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-2887</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000831" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals, Newborn</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006325" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Atria</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D034421" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sus scrofa</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013552" MajorTopicYN="N">Swine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">epicardiac ganglionated plexus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">heart</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">immunohistochemistry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">innervation morphology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">subplexi</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>31</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34727377</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmor.21426</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akamatsu, W., Fujihara, H., Mitsuhashi, T., Yano, M., Shibata, S., Hayakawa, Y., Okano, H. J., Sakakibara, S., Takano, H., Takano, T., Takahashi, T., Noda, T., &amp; Okano, H. (2005). The RNA-binding protein HuD regulates neuronal cell identity and maturation. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 102, 4625-4630. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0407523102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aksu, T., Gopinathannair, R., Gupta, D., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2021). Intrinsic cardiac autonomic nervous system: What do clinical electrophysiologists need to know about the “heart brain”? Journal of Cardiovascular Electrophysiology, 32, 1737-1747. https://doi.org/10.1111/jce.15058</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora, R. C., Waldmann, M., Hopkins, D. A., &amp; Armour, J. A. (2003). Porcine intrinsic cardiac ganglia. The Anatomical Record, 271A, 249-258. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.a.10030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashton, J. L., Burton, R. A. B., Bub, G., Smaill, B. H., &amp; Montgomery, J. M. (2018). Synaptic plasticity in cardiac innervation and its potential role in atrial fibrillation. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 240. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2018.00240</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azevedo, E. R., &amp; Parker, J. D. (1999). Parasympathetic control of cardiac sympathetic activity. Circulation, 100, 274-279. https://doi.org/10.1161/01</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batulevicius, D., Pauziene, N., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2003). Topographic morphology and age-related analysis of the neuronal number of the rat intracardiac nerve plexus. Annals of Anatomy = Anatomischer Anzeiger: Official Organ of the Anatomische Gesellschaft, 185, 449-459. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0940-9602(03)80105-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batulevicius, D., Pauziene, N., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2005). Architecture and age-related analysis of the neuronal number of the Guinea pig intrinsic cardiac nerve plexus. Annals of Anatomy-Anatomischer Anzeiger, 187, 225-243. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aanat.2005.01.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batulevicius, D., Skripka, V., Pauziene, N., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2008). Topography of the porcine epicardiac nerve plexus as revealed by histochemistry for acetylcholinesterase. Autonomic Neuroscience, 138, 64-75. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.autneu.2007.10.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brack, K. E. (2015). The heart's “little brain” controlling cardiac function in the rabbit. Experimental Physiology, 100, 348-353. https://doi.org/10.1113/expphysiol.2014.080168</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown, K. M., Gillette, T. A., &amp; Ascoli, G. A. (2008). Quantifying neuronal size: Summing up trees and splitting the branch difference. Seminars in Cell and Developmental Biology, 19, 485-493. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semcdb.2008.08.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chanson, P., Timsit, J., Masquet, C., Warnet, A., Guillausseau, P. J., Birman, P., Harris, A. G., &amp; Lubetzki, J. (1990). Cardiovascular effects of the somatostatin analog octreotide in acromegaly. Annals of Internal Medicine, 113, 921-925. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-113-12-921</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choate, J. K., Murphy, S. M., Feldman, R., &amp; Anderson, C. R. (2008). Sympathetic control of heart rate in nNOS knockout mice. American Journal of Physiology-Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 294, 354-361. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00898.2007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crick, S. J., Sheppard, M. N., Ho, S. Y., &amp; Anderson, R. H. (1999). Localisation and quantitation of autonomic innervation in the porcine heart I: Conduction system. Journal of Anatomy, 195, 341-357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Day, I. N. M., &amp; Thompson, R. J. (2010). UCHL1 (PGP 9.5): Neuronal biomarker and ubiquitin system protein. Progress in Neurobiology, 90, 327-362. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2009.10.020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickie, R., Bachoo, R. M., Rupnick, M. A., Dallabrida, S. M., DeLoid, G. M., Lai, J., Depinho, R. A., &amp; Rogers, R. A. (2006). Three-dimensional visualization of microvessel architecture of whole-mount tissue by confocal microscopy. Microvascular Research, 72, 20-26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mvr.2006.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franke-Radowiecka, A., Zmijewska, N., Zubkiewicz, T., Zalecki, M., Klimczuk, M., Listowska, Ż., &amp; Kaleczyc, J. (2020). Nerve structures of the heart and their immunohistochemical characterization in 10-week-old porcine foetuses. Comptes Rendus. Biologies, 343, 53-62. https://doi.org/10.5802/crbiol.4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garg, S., Singh, P., Sharma, A., &amp; Gupta, G. (2013). A gross comparative anatomical study of hearts in human cadavers and pigs. International Journal of Medical and Dental Sciences, 2, 170. https://doi.org/10.19056/ijmdsjssmes/2013/v2i2/86776</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gill, S. S., Pulido, O. M., Mueller, R. W., &amp; McGuire, P. F. (1998). Molecular and immunochemical characterization of the ionotropic glutamate receptors in the rat heart. Brain Research Bulletin, 46, 429-434. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0361-9230(98)00012-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haberberger, R., &amp; Kummer, W. (1996). β2-adrenoreceptor immunoreactivity in cardiac ganglia of the Guinea pig. The Histochemical Journal, 28, 827-833. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02272155</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanna, P., Dacey, M. J., Brennan, J., Moss, A., Robbins, S., Achanta, S., Biscola, N. P., Swid, M. A., Rajendran, P. S., Mori, S., Hadaya, J. E., Smith, E. H., Peirce, S. G., Chen, J., Hafton, L. A., Cheng, Z., Vadigepalli, V., Schwaber, J., Lux, R. L., … Shivkumar, K. (2021). Innervation and neuronal control of the mammalian sinoatrial node: A comprehensive atlas. Circulation Research, 128, 1279-1296. https://doi.org/10.1161/circresaha.120.318458</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasan, W. (2013). Autonomic cardiac innervation: Development and adult plasticity. Organogenesis, 9, 176-193. https://doi.org/10.4161/org.24892</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoover, D. B., Isaacs, E. R., Jacques, F., Hoard, J. L., Pagé, P., &amp; Armour, J. A. (2009). Localization of multiple neurotransmitters in surgically derived specimens of human atrial ganglia. Neuroscience, 164, 1170-1179. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2009.09.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horackova, M., Armour, J. A., &amp; Byczko, Z. (1999). Distribution of intrinsic cardiac neurons in whole-Mount Guinea pig atria identified by multiple neurochemical coding. A confocal microscope study. Cell and Tissue Research, 297, 409-421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inokaitis, H., Pauziene, N., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene, K., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2016). Innervation of sinoatrial nodal cells in the rabbit. Annals of Anatomy, 205, 113-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aanat.2016.03.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karnovsky, M. J., &amp; Roots, L. (1964). A “direct-color” thiocholine method for cholinesterases. The Journal of Histochemistry and Cytochemistry: Official Journal of the Histochemistry Society, 12, 219-221. https://doi.org/10.1177/12.3.219</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kruger, L., Mantyh, P. W., Sternini, C., Brecha, N. C., &amp; Mantyh, C. R. (1988). Calcitonin gene-related peptide (CGRP) in the rat central nervous system: Patterns of immunoreactivity and receptor binding sites. Brain Research, 463, 223-244. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(88)90395-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levett, J. M., Murphy, D. A., Mcguirt, A. S., Ardell, J. L., &amp; Armour, J. A. (1996). Cardiac augmentation can be maintained by continuous exposure of intrinsic cardiac neurons to a β-adrenergic agonist or angiotensin II. Journal of Surgical Research, 66, 167-173. https://doi.org/10.1006/jsre.1996.0390</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muscholl, E. (1980). Peripheral muscarinic control of norepinephrine release in the cardiovascular system. The American Journal of Physiology, 239, 713-720. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.1980.239.6.H713</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patil, J., Stucki, S., Nussberger, J., Schaffner, T., Gygax, S., Bohlender, J., &amp; Imboden, H. (2011). Angiotensinergic and noradrenergic neurons in the rat and human heart. Regulatory Peptides, 167, 31-41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.regpep.2010.11.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pauza, D. H., Skripka, V., Pauziene, N., &amp; Stropus, R. (2000). Morphology, distribution, and variability of the epicardiac neural ganglionated subplexuses in the human heart. The Anatomical Record, 259, 353-382.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pauza, D. H., Pauziene, N., Pakeltyte, G., &amp; Stropus, R. (2002). Comparative quantitative study of the intrinsic cardiac ganglia and neurons in the rat, Guinea pig, dog and human as revealed by histochemical staining for acetylcholinesterase. Annals of Anatomy = Anatomischer Anzeiger: Official Organ of the Anatomische Gesellschaft, 184, 125-136. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0940-9602(02)80005-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pauziene, N., Rysevaite-Kyguoliene, K., Alaburda, P., Pauza, A. G., Skukauskaite, M., Masaityte, A., Laucaityte, G., Saburkina, I., Inokaitis, H., Plisiene, J., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2017). Neuroanatomy of the pig cardiac ventricles. A stereomicroscopic, confocal and electron microscope study. Anatomical Record, 300, 1756-1780. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.23619</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richardson, R. J., Grkovic, I., &amp; Anderson, C. R. (2003). Immunohistochemical analysis of intracardiac ganglia of the rat heart. Cell and Tissue Research, 314, 337-350. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-003-0805-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rysevaite, K., Saburkina, I., Pauziene, N., Vaitkevicius, R., Noujaim, S. F., Jalife, J., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2011). Immunohistochemical characterization of the intrinsic cardiac neural plexus in whole-mount mouse heart preparations. Heart Rhythm, 8, 731-738. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hrthm.2011.01.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saburkina, I., Pauziene, N., &amp; Pauza, D. H. (2009). Prenatal development of the human epicardiac ganglia. Anatomia, Histologia, Embryologia, 38, 194-199. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0264.2008.00919.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwarz, P., Diem, R., Dun, N. J., &amp; Förstermann, U. (1995). Endogenous and exogenous nitric oxide inhibits norepinephrine release from rat heart sympathetic nerves. Circulation Research, 77, 841-848. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.res.77.4.841</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh, S., Johnson, P. I., Javed, A., Gray, T. S., Lonchyna, V. A., &amp; Wurster, R. D. (1999). Monoamine- and histamine-synthesizing enzymes and neurotransmitters within neurons of adult human cardiac ganglia. Circulation, 99, 411-419. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.CIR.99.3.411</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, F. M. (1999). Extrinsic inputs to intrinsic neurons in the porcine heart in vitro. American Journal of Physiology-Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 276(2), 455-467. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpregu.1999.276.2.R455</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki, Y., Yeung, A. C., &amp; Ikeno, F. (2011). The representative porcine model for human cardiovascular disease. Journal of Biomedicine and Biotechnology, 2011, 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1155/2011/195483</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Végh, A., Duim, S., Smits, A., Poelmann, R., ten Harkel, A., DeRuiter, M., Goumans, M. J., &amp; Jongbloed, M. (2016). Part and parcel of the cardiac autonomic nerve system: Unravelling its cellular building blocks during development. Journal of Cardiovascular Development and Disease, 3, 28. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcdd3030028</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, L., Li, D., Plested, C. P., Dawson, T., Teschemacher, A. G., &amp; Paterson, D. J. (2006). Noradrenergic neuron-specific overexpression of nNOS in cardiac sympathetic nerves decreases neurotransmission. Journal of Molecular and Cellular Cardiology, 41, 364-370. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yjmcc.2006.05.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, L., Li, D., Dawson, T. A., &amp; Paterson, D. J. (2009). Long-term effect of neuronal nitric oxide synthase over-expression on cardiac neurotransmission mediated by a lentiviral vector. The Journal of Physiology, 587, 3629-3637. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2009.172866</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods, J. R., Dandavino, A., Murayama, K., Brinkman, C. R., &amp; Assali, N. S. (1977). Autonomic control of cardiovascular functions during neonatal development and in adult sheep. Circulation Research, 40, 401-407. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.RES.40.4.401</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yiallourou, S. R., Sands, S. A., Walker, A. M., &amp; Horne, R. S. C. (2012). Maturation of heart rate and blood pressure variability during sleep in term-born infants. Sleep, 35, 177-186. https://doi.org/10.5665/sleep.1616</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
