<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34779110</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>11</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1755-3768</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
              <Day>14</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Acta ophthalmologica</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Acta Ophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Associations between systemic medications and development of wet age-related macular degeneration.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/aos.15056</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine whether systemic medications are associated with the subsequent development of wet age-related macular degeneration (AMD).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective study of 259 562 individuals based on registry data, from January 1, 2001, to December 31, 2017. End-point event was the International Classification of Diseases (ICD)-10 diagnosis for wet AMD. Association between use of systemic medication covering 85 generic drugs categorized according to Anatomical Therapeutic Chemical (ATC) codes and the incidence of wet AMD was evaluated using multivariate Poisson regression model (adjusted for age, sex, diabetes, cancer and socioeconomic group) and nested case-control design.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mean length of follow-up was 9.84 years. The number of cases with wet AMD was 2947 and incidence rate was 1.15 per 1000 person-years. After adjustment, we observed an increased risk for the development of wet AMD for patients exposed to amlodipine (IRR 1.33, 95% CI 1.16-1.53), or felodipine (1.24, 95% CI 1.02-1.50). Similarly, an increased risk of wet AMD was associated with the use of bicalutamide (2.14, 95% CI 1.14-4.02), estradiol (1.20, 95% CI 1.03-1.40) and atorvastatin (1.22, 95% CI 1.05-1.43). Of note, digoxin (0.72, 95% CI 0.57-0.91), and ramipril (0.80, 95% CI 0.65-0.99) users had a lower incidence of wet AMD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings suggest that the use of second-generation calcium channel blockers could be associated with an increased risk for wet AMD development. Of note, the incidence of wet AMD seemed to be lower in patients using ramipril and digoxin. More studies are needed to elucidate the associations further.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Acta Ophthalmologica Scandinavica Foundation. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Loukovaara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sirpa</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2506-3900</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unit of Vitreoretinal Surgery, Department of Ophthalmology, Helsinki University Hospital, and Individualized Drug Therapy Research Program, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Auvinen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anssi</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1125-4818</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Social Sciences, Health Sciences, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Haukka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jari</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1450-6208</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Public Health, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Health Technology, Tampere University, Tampere, Finland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Acta Ophthalmol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101468102</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1755-375X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atorvastatin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bicalutamide</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcium channel blockers</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">estradiol</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacoepidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">real-world evidence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wet age-related macular degeneration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34779110</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aos.15056</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Holou SN, Tucker WR, Agrón E et al. (2015): Age-Related Eye Disease Study 2 Research Group. The association of statin use with age-related macular degeneration progression: the age-related eye disease study 2 report number 9. Ophthalmology 122(12): 2490-2496.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ammar MJ, Hsu J, Chiang A, Ho AC &amp; Regillo CD (2020): Age-related macular degeneration therapy: a review. Curr Opin Ophthalmol 31: 215-221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blitzer AL, Ham SA, Colby KA &amp; Skondra D (2021): Association of metformin use with age-related macular degeneration: a case-control study. JAMA Ophthalmol 139: 302-309. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaophthalmol.2020.6331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung CM &amp; Wong TY (2014): Is age-related macular degeneration a manifestation of systemic disease? New prospects for early intervention and treatment. J Intern Med 276: 140-153.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho BJ, Heo JW, Shin JP, Ahn J, Kim TW &amp; Chung H (2014): Association between reproductive factors and age-related macular degeneration in postmenopausal women: the Korea national health and nutrition examination survey 2010-2012. PLoS One 9: 2010-2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colijn JM, Buitendijk GHS, Prokofyeva E et al. (2017): EYE-RISK consortium; European Eye Epidemiology (E3) consortium. Prevalence of age-related macular degeneration in Europe: the past and the future. Ophthalmology 124: 1753-1763.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delcoigne B, Støer NC &amp; Reilly M (2018): Valid and efficient subgroup analyses using nested case-control data. Int J Epidemiol 47: 841-849. https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyx282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dryja TP (2016): Early insight into neovascular age-related macular degeneration. JAMA Ophthalmol 134: 1281-1282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliott WJ &amp; Ram CV (2011): Calcium channel blockers. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 13: 687-689.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinosa-Heidmann DG, Marin-Castano ME, Pereira-Simon S, Hernandez EP, Elliot S &amp; Cousins SW (2005): Gender and estrogen supplementation increases severity of experimental choroidal neovascularization. Exp Eye Res 80: 413-423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans AJ (2018): Treatment effects in prostate cancer. Mod Pathol 31(S1): S110-121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraser-Bell S, Symes R &amp; Vaze A (2017): Hypertensive eye disease: a review. Clin Exp Ophthalmol 45: 45-53. https://doi.org/10.1111/ceo.12905.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gail MH, Altman DG, Cadarette SM et al. (2019): Design choices for observational studies of the effect of exposure on disease incidence. BMJ Open 9: e031031.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galappatthy P, Waniganayake YC, Sabeer MIM et al. (2016): Leg edema with (S)-amlodipine vs conventional amlodipine given in triple therapy for hypertension: a randomized double blind controlled clinical trial. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 16: 168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gehlbach P, Li T &amp; Hatef E (2015): Statins for age-related macular degeneration. Cochrane Database Syst Rev (2): CD006927.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gehlbach P, Li T &amp; Hatef E (2016): Statins for age-related macular degeneration. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 3: CD006927. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD006927.pub5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gissler M &amp; Haukka J (2004): Finnish health and social welfare registers in epidemiological research. Nor Epidemiol 14: 113-120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaffe GJ, Westby K, Csaky KG et al. (2021): C5 inhibitor avacincaptad pegol for geographic atrophy due to age-related macular degeneration: a randomized pivotal phase 2/3 trial. Ophthalmology 128(4): 576-586. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ophtha.2020.08.027.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keenan TD, Wiley HE, Agrón E et al. (2019): Age-related eye disease study and age-related eye disease study 2 research groups. The association of aspirin use with age-related macular degeneration progression in the age-related eye disease studies: age-related eye disease study 2 report no. 20. Ophthalmology 126:1647-1656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khotcharrat R, Patikulsila D, Hanutsaha P et al. (2015): Epidemiology of age-related macular degeneration among the elderly population in Thailand. J Med Assoc Thai 98: 790-797.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolomeyer AM, Maguire MG, Pan W &amp; VanderBeek BL (2019): Systemic beta-blockers and risk of progression to neovascular age-related macular degeneration. Retina 39: 918-925.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langholz B &amp; Thomas DC (1991): Efficiency of cohort sampling designs: some surprising results. Biometrics 47: 1563-1571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawlor DA, Tilling K &amp; Davey Smith G (2016): Triangulation in aetiological epidemiology. Int J Epidemiol 45: 1866-1886. https://doi.org/10.1093/ije/dyw314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim LS, Mitchell P, Seddon JM, Holz FG &amp; Wong TY (2012): Age-related macular degeneration. Lancet 379(9827): 1728-1738. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(12)60282-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Kanda A, Wu D et al. (2019): Suppression of choroidal neovascularization and fibrosis by a novel RNAi therapeutic agent against (pro)renin receptor. Mol Ther Nucleic Acids 17: 113-125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loukovaara S &amp; Haukka J (2020): Cancer is associated with a 2.7 higher risk for intravitreal injection therapy in patients with age-related, diabetic, or vascular occlusive macular edema. Acta Ophthalmol. https://doi.org/10.1111/aos.14546. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 32833293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma L, Wang Y, Du J, Wang M, Zhang R &amp; Fu Y (2015): The association between statin use and risk of age-related macular degeneration. Sci Rep 14: 18280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montero JA, Ruiz-Moreno JM, Sanchis-Merino E &amp; Perez-Martin S (2013): Systemic beta-blockers may reduce the need for repeated intravitreal injections in patients with wet age-related macular degeneration treated by bevacizumab. Retina 33: 508-512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolò M, Ferro Desideri L, Vagge A &amp; Traverso CE (2021): Faricimab: an investigational agent targeting the Tie-2/angiopoietin pathway and VEGF-A for the treatment of retinal diseases. Expert Opin Investig Drugs 30: 193-200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niskanen L, Partonen T, Auvinen A et al. (2020): Trends and predictors in all-cause and cause-specific mortality in diabetic and reference populations during 21 years of follow-up. J Epidemiol Community Health 74: 950-956.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NOMESCO Classification of Surgical Procedures (NSCP), version 1.16 (2011): Nordic Centre for Classifications in Health Care WHO Collaborating centre for the family of International Classifications in the Nordic Countries Norwegian Directorate of Health.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R Core Team (2019): R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. Vienna, Austria: R Foundation for Statistical Computing. Available at: https://www.r-project.org/.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren C, Liu W, Yin X, Zhang B &amp; Lu P (2020): Renin-angiotensin system inhibitor usage and age-related macular degeneration among hypertensive patients: results from the national health and nutrition examination survey, 2005-2008. J Ophthalmol 2020: 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1155/2020/4252031. eCollection 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt-Erfurth U, Sadeghipour A, Gerendas BS, Waldstein SM &amp; Bogunović H (2018): Artificial intelligence in retina. Prog Retin Eye Res 67: 1-29. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.preteyeres.2018.07.004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snow KK, Cote J, Yang W, Davis NJ &amp; Seddon JM (2002): Association between reproductive and hormonal factors and age-related maculopathy in postmenopausal women. Am J Ophthalmol 134: 842-848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan JS, Mitchell P, Smith W &amp; Wang JJ (2007): Cardiovascular risk factors and the long-term incidence of age-related macular degeneration: the Blue Mountains Eye Study. Ophthalmology 114: 1143-1150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teppo L, Pukkala E &amp; Lehtonen M (1994): Data quality and quality control of a population-based cancer registry. Experience in Finland. Acta Oncol 33: 365-369.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VanderBeek BL, Zacks DN, Talwar N, Nan B &amp; Stein JD (2013): Role of statins in the development and progression of age-related macular degeneration. Retina 33: 414-422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang SV, Kulldorff M, Poor S et al. (2021): Screening medications for association with progression to wet age-related macular degeneration. Ophthalmology 128(2): 248-255. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ophtha.2020.08.004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilkinson-Berka JL, Suphapimol V, Jerome JR, Deliyanti D &amp; Allingham MJ (2019): Angiotensin II and aldosterone in retinal vasculopathy and inflammation. Exp Eye Res 187: 107766. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exer.2019.107766.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida T, Zhang H, Iwase T, Shen J, Semenza GL &amp; Campochiaro PA (2010): Digoxin inhibits retinal ischemia-induced HIF-1alpha expression and ocular neovascularization. FASEB J 24: 1759-1767.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H, Qian DZ, Tan YS et al. (2008): Digoxin and other cardiac glycosides inhibit HIF-1alpha synthesis and block tumor growth. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 105: 19579-19586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
