<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34799790</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1615-2573</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>37</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Heart and vessels</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Heart Vessels</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The impact of plaque morphology in patients with peripheral artery disease on vessel dissection: an intravascular ultrasound observational study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>961</StartPage>
          <EndPage>968</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>961-968</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00380-021-01994-w</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Drug-coated balloon (DCB) is now available for endovascular treatment (EVT) of superficial femoral arteries (SFA). Although it has been reported that severe vessel dissection after balloon angioplasty was risk of restenosis, it is difficult to predict the vessel dissection patterns before balloon angioplasty. We investigated the correlation between plaque morphology and vessel dissection pattern after balloon angioplasty using the intravascular ultrasound (IVUS). A total of 73 de novo SFA lesions were enrolled in this study. IVUS examinations were measured at the minimum lumen area in the control angiogram. Plaque morphology, minimum lumen area (MLA) and vessel diameter at the same point were evaluated before and after the initial balloon angioplasty. Vessel dissection patterns after the initial balloon angioplasty were classified into 7 types (A to F). There were no severe dissection patterns which were more than type D dissection in this study. All patients were treated with DCB without any bailout stenting. No dissection was found in 35.6% (26/73). Type A, B and C dissections were seen in 17.8% (13/73), 40% (27/73) and 9.6% (7/73), respectively. Although there were no relations between plaque morphology and vessel dissection patterns (p = 0.547), the MLA with dissection was larger than that without dissection (5.78 mm<sup>2</sup> versus 4.63 mm<sup>2</sup>, p = 0.032). Although the dissection patterns could not be predicted in non-severe (Non or A to C) dissection, our result might suggest that IVUS image has the potential to reduce severe dissection.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. Springer Japan KK, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aya</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Engineering, Morinomiya Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fukunaga</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Morinomiya Hospital, 2-1-88 Morinomiya Joto-ku, Osaka, Osaka, 5360025, Japan. fukunagahothot@yahoo.co.jp.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kawasaki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daizo</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Morinomiya Hospital, 2-1-88 Morinomiya Joto-ku, Osaka, Osaka, 5360025, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Japan</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Heart Vessels</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8511258</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0910-8327</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000800" MajorTopicYN="Y">Angioplasty, Balloon</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015906" MajorTopicYN="Y">Angioplasty, Balloon, Coronary</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018376" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Abnormalities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005263" MajorTopicYN="N">Femoral Artery</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058729" MajorTopicYN="Y">Peripheral Arterial Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018084" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography, Interventional</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Catheterization</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug-coated balloon</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intravascular ultrasound</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vessel dissection pattern</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34799790</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00380-021-01994-w</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00380-021-01994-w</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steering Committee TASC, Jaff MR, White CJ, Hiatt WR, Fowkes GR, Dormandy J, Razavi M, Reekers J, Norgren L (2015) An Update on Methods for Revascularization and Expansion of the TASC Lesion Classification to Include Below-the-Knee Arteries: A Supplement to the Inter-Society Consensus for the Management of Peripheral Arterial Disease (TASC II). Vasc Med 20(5):465–478</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1358863X15597877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tepe G, Laird J, Schneider P, Brodmann M, Krishnan P, Micari A, Metzger C, Scheinert D, Zeller T, Cohen DJ, Snead DB, Alexander B, Landini M, Jaff MR, Trial Investigators INPACTSFA (2015) Drug-coated balloon versus standard percutaneous transluminal angioplasty for the treatment of superficial femoral and popliteal peripheral artery disease: 12-month results from the IN.PACT SFA randomized trial. Circulation 131:495–502</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.114.011004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iida O, Soga Y, Urasawa K, Saito S, Jaff MR, Wang H, Ookubo H, Yokoi H; MDT-2113 SFA Japan Investigators (2018) Drug-coated balloon vs standard percutaneous transluminal angioplasty for the treatment of atherosclerotic lesions in the superficial femoral and proximal popliteal arteries: one-year results of the MDT-2113 SFA Japan randomized trial. J Endovasc Ther 25:109–117</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1526602817745565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider PA, Laird JR, Tepe G, Brodmann M, Zeller T, Scheinert D, Metzger C, Micari A, Sachar R, Jaff MR, Wang H, Hasenbank MS, Krishnan P; IN.PACT SFA Trial Investigators (2018) Treatment effect of drug-coated balloons is durable to 3 years in the femoropopliteal arteries: long-term results of the IN.PACT SFA randomized trial. Circ Cardiovasc Interv 11(1):e005891</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenfield K, Jaff MR, White CJ, Rocha-Singh K, Mena-Hurtado C, Metzger DC, Brodmann M, Pilger E, Zeller T, Krishnan P, Gammon R, Müller-Hülsbeck S, Nehler MR, Benenati JF, Scheinert D; LEVANT 2 Investigators (2015) Trial of a paclitaxel-coated balloon for femoropopliteal artery disease. N Engl J Med 373:145–153</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1406235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogt KC, Just S, Rasmussen JG, Schroeder TV (1997) Prediction of outcome after femoropopliteal balloon angioplasty by intravascular ultrasound. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 13:563–568</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1078-5884(97)80065-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerritsen GP, Gussenhoven EJ, The SHK, Pieterman H, v d Lugt A, Li W, Bom N, van Dijk LC, Du Bois NA, Urk H (1993) Intravascular ultrasonography before and after intervention: in vivo comparison with angiography. J Vasc Surg 18:31–40</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mva.1993.41957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norgren L, Hiatt WR, Dormandy JA, Nehler MR, Harris KA, Fowkes FG; TASC II Working Group, Bell K, Caporusso J, Durand-Zaleski I, Komori K, Lammer J, Liapis C, Novo S, Razavi M, Robbs J, Schaper N, Shigematsu H, Sapoval M, White C, White J, Clement D, Creager M, Jaff M, Mohler E 3rd, Rutherford RB, Sheehan P, Sillesen H, Rosenfield K (2007) Inter-society consensus for the management of peripheral arterial disease (TASC II). Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg 33(Suppl 1):S1-75</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujihara M, Takahara M, Sasaki S, Nanto K, Utsunomiya M, Iida O, Yokoi Y (2017) Angiographic dissection patterns and patency outcomes after balloon angioplasty for superficial femoral artery disease. J Endovasc Ther 24(3):367–375</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1526602817698634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rocha-Singh KJ, Zeller T, Jaff MR (2014) Peripheral arterial calcification: prevalence, mechanism, detection, and clinical implications. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv 83(6):E212–E220</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ccd.25387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mintz GS, Nissen SE, Anderson WD, Bailey SR, Erbel R, Fitzgerald PJ, Pinto FJ, Rosenfield K, Siegel RJ, Tuzcu EM, Yock PG (2001) American college of cardiology clinical expert consensus document on standards for acquisition, measurement and reporting of intravascular ultrasound studies (IVUS). A report of the American college of cardiology task force on clinical expert consensus documents. J Am Coll Cardiol 37(5):1478–1492</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0735-1097(01)01175-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujihara M, Kozuki A, Tsubakimoto Y, Takahara M, Shintani Y, Fukunaga M, Iwasaki Y, Nakama T, Yokoi Y (2019) Lumen gain after endovascular therapy in calcified superficial femoral artery occlusive disease assessed by intravascular ultrasound (CODE Study). J Endovasc Ther 26(3):322–330</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1526602819836095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aihara H, Higashitani M, Takimura H, Tobita K, Jujo K, Hozawa K, Yamaguchi T, Iwata Y, Tokuyama H, Sakurai M, Murata N, Fujimoto Y, Kikuchi A, Koganei H, Sato A, Noguchi Y, Ieda M (2020) Differences in intravascular ultrasound measurement values between treatment modalities for restenosis in femoropopliteal lesions. Circ J 84(8):1320–1329</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.CJ-20-0218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kozuki A, Takahara M, Shimizu M, Kijima Y, Nagoshi R, Fujiwara R, Shibata H, Suzuki A, Soga F, Miyata T, Sakamoto Y, Seo H, Asada H, Isawa K, Higuchi K, Shite J (2021) Outcomes of dissection angles as predictor of restenosis after drug-coated balloon treatment. J Atheroscler Thromb 28(9):954–962</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5551/jat.59774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
