<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34816453</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-1136</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>70</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Glia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Glia</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Astrocytes as essential time-keepers of the central pacemaker.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>808</StartPage>
          <EndPage>819</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>808-819</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/glia.24121</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Since the early observations made by Santiago Ramon y Cajal more than a century ago till now, astrocytes have gradually gained protagonism as essential partners of neurons in building brain circuits that regulate complex behavior. In mammals, processes such as sleep-wake cycle, locomotor activity, cognition and memory consolidation, homeostatic and hedonic appetite and stress response (among others), are synchronized in 24-h rhythms by the circadian system. In such a way, physiology efficiently anticipates and adapts to daily recurring changes in the environment. The hypothalamic suprachiasmatic nucleus (SCN) is considered the central pacemaker, it has been traditionally described as a nucleus of around 10,000 neurons nearly all GABAergic able to be entrained by light and to convey time information through multiple neuronal and hormonal pathways. Only recently, this neuro-centered view was challenged by breakthrough discoveries implicating astrocytes as essential time-keepers. In the present review, we will describe the current view on the SCN circuit and discuss whether astrocytic functions described in other brain regions and state-of-the-art experimental approaches, could help explaining better those well- and not so well-known features of the central pacemaker.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Astiz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mariana</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9912-1686</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neurobiology, Center of Brain, Behavior and Metabolism (CBBM), University of Lübeck, Lübeck, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Delgado-García</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lina Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>LM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7515-769X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Universidade Federal de São Paulo UNIFESP, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>López-Mascaraque</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laura</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7154-5687</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Cajal, Consejo Superior de Investigaciones Científicas-CSIC, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Glia</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8806785</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0894-1491</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001253" MajorTopicYN="Y">Astrocytes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002940" MajorTopicYN="N">Circadian Rhythm</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008322" MajorTopicYN="N">Mammals</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pacemaker, Artificial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013493" MajorTopicYN="N">Suprachiasmatic Nucleus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">astrocytes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">circadian clock</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">circuit</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">heterogeneity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">rodents</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">suprachiasmatic nucleus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34816453</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.24121</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrahamson, E. E., &amp; Moore, R. Y. (2001). Suprachiasmatic nucleus in the mouse: Retinal innervation, intrinsic organization and efferent projections. Brain Research, 916, 172-191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali, A. A. H., Stahr, A., Ingenwerth, M., Theis, M., Steinhäuser, C., &amp; Von Gall, C. (2019). Connexin30 and Connexin43 show a time-of-day dependent expression in the mouse suprachiasmatic nucleus and modulate rhythmic locomotor activity in the context of chronodisruption. Cell Communication and Signaling, 17, 61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araque, A., Carmignoto, G., &amp; Haydon, P. G. (2001). Dynamic signaling between astrocytes and neurons. Annual Review of Physiology, 63, 795-813.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araque, A., Carmignoto, G., Haydon, P. G., Oliet, S. H. R., Robitaille, R., &amp; Volterra, A. (2014). Gliotransmitters travel in time and space. Neuron, 81, 728-739.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araque, A., Parpura, V., Sanzgiri, R. P., &amp; Haydon, P. G. (1999). Tripartite synapses: Glia, the unacknowledged partner. Trends in Neuroscience, 22, 208-215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Astiz, M., Heyde, I., Fortmann, M. I., Bossung, V., Roll, C., Stein, A., Grüttner, B., Göpel, W., Härtel, C., Obleser, J., &amp; Oster, H. (2020). The circadian phase of antenatal glucocorticoid treatment affects the risk of behavioral disorders. Nature Communications, 11, 3593.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Astiz, M., Heyde, I., &amp; Oster, H. (2019). Mechanisms of Communication in the Mammalian Circadian Timing System. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20, 343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Astiz, M., &amp; Oster, H. (2018). Perinatal programming of circadian clock-stress crosstalk. Neural Plasticity, 5689165, e108614. https://doi.org/10.1155/2018/5689165</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barca-Mayo, O., Pons-Espinal, M., Follert, P., Armirotti, A., Berdondini, L., &amp; De Pietri Tonelli, D. (2017). Astrocyte deletion of Bmal1 alters daily locomotor activity and cognitive functions via GABA signalling. Nature Communications, 8, 14336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barca-Mayo, O., &amp; López, M. (2021). Astrocyte clocks and glucose homeostasis. Frontiers in Endocrinology, 12. 1-12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2021.662017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bazargani, N., &amp; Attwell, D. (2016). Astrocyte calcium signaling: The third wave. Nature Neuroscience, 19, 182-189. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4201</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becquet, D., Girardet, C., Guillaumond, F., François-Bellan, A.-M., &amp; Bosler, O. (2008). Ultrastructural plasticity in the rat suprachiasmatic nucleus. Possible involvement in clock entrainment. Glia, 56, 294-305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedont, J. L., &amp; Blackshaw, S. (2015). Constructing the suprachiasmatic nucleus: A watchmaker's perspective on the central clockworks. Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience, 9, 74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bojarskaite, L., Bjørnstad, D. M., Pettersen, K. H., Cunen, C., Hermansen, G. H., Åbjørsbråten, K. S., Chambers, A. R., Sprengel, R., Vervaeke, K., Tang, W., Enger, R., &amp; Nagelhus, E. A. (2020). Astrocytic Ca2+ signaling is reduced during sleep and is involved in the regulation of slow wave sleep. Nature Communications, 11, 3240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brancaccio, M., Edwards, M. D., Patton, A. P., Smyllie, N. J., Chesham, J. E., Maywood, E. S., &amp; Hastings, M. H. (2019). Cell-autonomous clock of astrocytes drives circadian behavior in mammals. Science, 363, 187-192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brancaccio, M., Patton, A. P., Chesham, J. E., Maywood, E. S., &amp; Hastings, M. H. (2017). Astrocytes control circadian timekeeping in the suprachiasmatic nucleus via glutamatergic signaling. Neuron, 93, 1420-1435.e5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bribián, A., Figueres-Oñate, M., Martín-López, E., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2016). Decoding astrocyte heterogeneity: New tools for clonal analysis. Neuroscience, 323, 10-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buijs, F. N., León-Mercado, L., Guzmán-Ruiz, M., Guerrero-Vargas, N. N., Romo-Nava, F., &amp; Buijs, R. M. (2016). The circadian system: A regulatory feedback network of periphery and brain. Physiology (Bethesda), 31, 170-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buijs, R. M., Escobar, C., &amp; Swaab, D. F. (2013). The circadian system and the balance of the autonomic nervous system. Handbook of Clinical Neurology, 117, 173-191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buijs, R. M., La Fleur, S. E., Wortel, J., Van Heyningen, C., Zuiddam, L., Mettenleiter, T. C., Kalsbeek, A., Nagai, K., &amp; Niijima, A. (2003). The suprachiasmatic nucleus balances sympathetic and parasympathetic output to peripheral organs through separate preautonomic neurons. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 464, 36-48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burkeen, J. F., Womac, A. D., Earnest, D. J., &amp; Zoran, M. J. (2011). Mitochondrial calcium signaling mediates rhythmic extracellular ATP accumulation in suprachiasmatic nucleus astrocytes. Journal of Neuroscience, 31, 8432-8440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busada, J. T., &amp; Cidlowski, J. A. (2017). Mechanisms of glucocorticoid action during development. Current Topics in Developmental Biology, 125, 147-170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butt, A., &amp; Verkhratsky, A. (2018). Neuroglia: Realising their true potential. Brain and Neuroscience Advances, 2, 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1177/2398212818817495</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cajal, S. R. (1895). Algunas conjeturas sobre el mecanismo anatómico de la ideación, asociación y atención. Revista de Medicina y Cirugía Prácticas, 36, 497-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canal, M. M., Mohammed, N. M., &amp; Rodríguez, J. J. (2009). Early programming of astrocyte organization in the mouse suprachiasmatic nuclei by light. Chronobiology International, 26, 1545-1558.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmona-Alcocer, V., Abel, J. H., Sun, T. C., Petzold, L. R., Doyle, F. J., Simms, C. L., &amp; Herzog, E. D. (2018). Ontogeny of circadian rhythms and synchrony in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Journal of Neuroscience, 38, 1326-1334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng, X., Wang, J., Sun, X., Shao, L., Guo, Z., &amp; Li, Y. (2019). Morphological and functional alterations of astrocytes responding to traumatic brain injury. Journal of Integrative Neuroscience, 18(2), 203-215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarke, B. E., Taha, D. M., Tyzack, G. E., &amp; Patani, R. (2020). Regionally encoded functional heterogeneity of astrocytes in health and disease: A perspective. Glia, 69, 20-27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins, B., Pierre-Ferrer, S., Muheim, C., Lukacsovich, D., Cai, Y., Spinnler, A., Herrera, C. G., Wen, S., Winterer, J., Belle, M. D. C., Piggins, H. D., Hastings, M., Loudon, A., Yan, J., Földy, C., Adamantidis, A., &amp; Brown, S. A. (2020). Circadian VIPergic neurons of the suprachiasmatic nuclei sculpt the sleep-wake cycle. Neuron, 108, 486-499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colombo, J. A., &amp; Reisin, H. D. (2004). Interlaminar astroglia of the cerebral cortex: A marker of the primate brain. Brain Research, 1006, 126-131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cornell-Bell, A. H., Finkbeiner, S. M., Cooper, M. S., &amp; Smith, S. J. (1990). Glutamate induces calcium waves in cultured astrocytes: Long-range glial signaling. Science, 247, 470-473.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Carlos, J. A., &amp; Borrell, J. (2007). A historical reflection of the contributions of Cajal and Golgi to the foundations of neuroscience. Brain Research Reviews, 55, 8-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vivo, L., Bellesi, M., Marshall, W., Bushong, E. A., Ellisman, M. H., Tononi, G., &amp; Cirelli, C. (2017). Ultrastructural evidence for synaptic scaling across the wake/sleep cycle. Science, 355, 507-510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dibner, C., Schibler, U., &amp; Albrecht, U. (2010). The mammalian circadian timing system: Organization and coordination of central and peripheral clocks. The Annual Review of Physiology, 72, 517-549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emsley, J. G., &amp; Macklis, J. D. (2006). Astroglial heterogeneity closely reflects the neuronal-defined anatomy of the adult murine CNS. Neuron Glia Biology, 2, 175-186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Figueres-Oñate, M., Gutiérrez, Y., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2014). Unraveling Cajal's view of the olfactory system. Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 8, 55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Marín, V., García-López, P., &amp; Freire, M. (2007). Cajal's contributions to glia research. Trends in Neuroscience, 30, 479-487.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Marqués, J., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2017). Clonal mapping of astrocytes in the olfactory bulb and rostral migratory stream. Cerebral Cortex, 27, 2195-2209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Marqués, J., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2013). Clonal identity determines astrocyte cortical heterogeneity. Cerebral Cortex, 23, 1463-1472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Genoud, C., Quairiaux, C., Steiner, P., Hirling, H., Welker, E., &amp; Knott, G. W. (2006). Plasticity of astrocytic coverage and glutamate transporter expression in adult mouse cortex. PLoS Biology, 4, e343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girardet, C., Becquet, D., Blanchard, M. P., François-Bellan, A. M., &amp; Bosler, O. (2010). Neuroglial and synaptic rearrangements associated with photic entrainment of the circadian clock in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. European Journal of Neuroscience, 32, 2133-2142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Götz, S., Bribian, A., López-Mascaraque, L., Götz, M., Grothe, B., &amp; Kunz, L. (2021). Heterogeneity of astrocytes: Electrophysiological properties of juxtavascular astrocytes before and after brain injury. Glia, 69, 346-361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green, D. J., &amp; Gillette, R. (1982). Circadian rhythm of firing rate recorded from single cells in the rat suprachiasmatic slice. Brain Research, 245, 283-288. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(82)90361-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griemsmann, S., Höft, S. P., Bedner, P., Zhang, J., Von Staden, E., Beinhauer, A., Degen, J., Dublin, P., Cope, D. W., Richter, N., Crunelli, V., Jabs, R., Willecke, K., Theis, M., Seifert, G., Kettenmann, H., &amp; Steinhäuser, C. (2015). Characterization of Panglial gap junction networks in the thalamus, neocortex, and hippocampus reveals a unique population of glial cells. Cerebral Cortex, 25(10), 3420-3433. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhu157</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gutiérrez, Y., García-Marques, J., Liu, X., Fortes-Marco, L., Sánchez-González, R., Giaume, C., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2019). Sibling astrocytes share preferential coupling via gap junctions. Glia, 67, 1852-1858.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hablitz, L. M., Gunesch, A. N., Cravetchi, O., Moldavan, M., &amp; Allen, C. N. (2020). Cannabinoid signaling recruits astrocytes to modulate presynaptic function in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. eNeuro, 7(1), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1523/ENEURO.0081-19.2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haim, L. B., &amp; Rowitch, D. H. (2017). Functional diversity of astrocytes in neural circuit regulation. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 18, 31-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hastings, M. H., Maywood, E. S., &amp; Brancaccio, M. (2018). Generation of circadian rhythms in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 19, 453-469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatori, M., Vollmers, C., Zarrinpar, A., DiTacchio, L., Bushong, E. A., Gill, S., Leblanc, M., Chaix, A., Joens, M., Fitzpatrick, J. A. J., Ellisman, M. H., &amp; Panda, S. (2012). Time-restricted feeding without reducing caloric intake prevents metabolic diseases in mice fed a high-fat diet. Cell Metabolism, 15, 848-860.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herrero-Navarro, Á., Puche-Aroca, L., Moreno-Juan, V., Sempere-Ferràndez, A., Espinosa, A., Susín, R., Torres-Masjoan, L., Leyva-Díaz, E., Karow, M., Figueres-Oñate, M., López-Mascaraque, L., López-Atalaya, J. P., Berninger, B., &amp; López-Bendito, G. (2021). Astrocytes and neurons share brain region-specific transcriptional signatures. Science Advances, 7, eabe8978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Höft, S., Griemsmann, S., Seifert, G., &amp; Steinhäuser, C. (2014). Heterogeneity in expression of functional ionotropic glutamate and GABA receptors in astrocytes across brain regions: Insights from the thalamus. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B, 369(1654), 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2013.0602</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu, P., Fabyanic, E., Kwon, D. Y., Tang, S., Zhou, Z., &amp; Wu, H. (2017). Dissecting cell-type composition and activity-dependent transcriptional state in mammalian brains by massively parallel single-nucleus RNA-Seq. Molecular Cell, 68, 1006-1015.e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyden, H., &amp; Lange, P. W. (1965). Rhythmic enzyme changes in neurons and glia during sleep. Science, 149, 654-656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeda, T., Iijima, N., Munekawa, K., Ishihara, A., Ibata, Y., &amp; Tanaka, M. (2003). Functional retinal input stimulates expression of astroglial elements in the suprachiasmatic nucleus of postnatal developing rat. Neuroscience Research, 47, 39-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingiosi, A. M., Hayworth, C. R., Harvey, D. O., Singletary, K. G., Rempe, M. J., Wisor, J. P., &amp; Frank, M. G. (2020). A role for Astroglial calcium in mammalian sleep and sleep regulation. Current Biology, 30, 4373-4383.e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inouye, S. T., &amp; Kawamura, H. (1979). Persistence of circadian rhythmicity in a mammalian hypothalamic “Island” containing the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 76, 5962-5966.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson, F. R., Ng, F. S., Sengupta, S., You, S., &amp; Huang, Y. (2015). Glial cell regulation of rhythmic behavior. Methods in Enzymology, 552, 45-73. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.mie.2014.10.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson, F. R. (2011). Glial cell modulation of circadian rhythms. Glia, 59, 1341-1350. https://doi.org/10.1002/glia.21097</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kettenmann, H., &amp; Verkhratsky, A. (2008). Neuroglia: The 150 years after. Trends in Neuroscience, 31, 653-659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koch, C. E., Begemann, K., Kiehn, J. T., Griewahn, L., Mauer, J., Hess, M. E., Moser, A., Schmid, S. M., Brüning, J. C., &amp; Oster, H. (2020). Circadian regulation of hedonic appetite in mice by clocks in dopaminergic neurons of the VTA. Nature Communications, 11, 3071.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kramer, A., Yang, F. C., Snodgrass, P., Li, X., Scammell, T. E., Davis, F. C., &amp; Weitz, J. (2001). Regulation of daily locomotor activity and sleep by hypothalamic EGF receptor signaling. Science, 294, 2511-2515. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1067716</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landgraf, D., Achten, C., Dallmann, F., &amp; Oster, H. (2015). Embryonic development and maternal regulation of murine circadian clock function. Chronobiology International, 32, 416-427.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavialle, M., Aumann, G., Anlauf, E., Pröls, F., Arpin, M., &amp; Derouiche, A. (2011). Structural plasticity of perisynaptic astrocyte processes involves ezrin and metabotropic glutamate receptors. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108, 12915-12919.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavialle, M., &amp; Servière, J. (1993). Circadian fluctuations in GFAP distribution in the Syrian hamster suprachiasmatic nucleus. Neuroreport, 4, 1243-1246. https://doi.org/10.1097/00001756-199309000-00008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavialle, M., &amp; Servière, J. (1995). Developmental study in the circadian clock of the golden hamster: A putative role of astrocytes. Developmental Brain Research, 86, 275-282. https://doi.org/10.1016/0165-3806(95)00039-g</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lehre, K. P., Levy, L. M., Ottersen, O. P., Storm-Mathisen, J., &amp; Danbolt, N. C. (1995). Differential expression of two glial glutamate transporters in the rat brain: Quantitative and immunocytochemical observations. Journal of Neuroscience, 15, 1835-1853.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, X., Sankrithi, N., &amp; Davis, F. C. (2002). Transforming growth factor-alpha is expressed in astrocytes of the suprachiasmatic nucleus in hamster: Role of glial cells in circadian clocks. Neuroreport, 13, 2143-2147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Logan, R. W., &amp; McClung, C. A. (2019). Rhythms of life: Circadian disruption and brain disorders across the lifespan. Nature Reviews Neurosciences, 20, 49-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marpegan, L., Krall, T. J., &amp; Herzog, E. D. (2009). Vasoactive intestinal polypeptide entrains circadian rhythms in astrocytes. Journal of Biological Rhythms, 24, 135-143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marpegan, L., Swanstrom, A. E., Chung, K., Simon, T., Haydon, P. G., Khan, S. K., Liu, A. C., Herzog, E. D., &amp; Beaulé, C. (2011). Circadian regulation of ATP release in astrocytes. Journal of Neuroscience, 31, 8342-8350. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6537-10.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martín-López, E., García-Marques, J., Núñez-Llaves, R., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2013). Clonal astrocytic response to cortical injury. PLoS One, 8, e74039.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matyash, V., &amp; Kettenmann, H. (2010). Heterogeneity in astrocyte morphology and physiology. Brain Research Review, 63, 2-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller, R. H., &amp; Raff, M. C. (1984). Fibrous and protoplasmic astrocytes are biochemically and developmentally distinct. Journal of Neuroscience, 4, 585-592. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.04-02-00585.1984</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moisiadis, V. G., &amp; Matthews, S. G. (2014). Glucocorticoids and fetal programming part 2: Mechanisms. Nature Reviews Endocrinology, 10, 403-411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moldavan, M., Cravetchi, O., Williams, M., Irwin, R. P., Aicher, S. A., &amp; Allen, C. N. (2015). Localization and expression of GABA transporters in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. European Journal of Neuroscience, 42, 3018-3032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moldavan, M., Cravetchi, O., &amp; Allen, C. N. (2017). GABA transporters regulate tonic and synaptic GABA a receptor-mediated currents in the suprachiasmatic nucleus neurons. Journal of Neurophysiology, 118, 3092-3106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore, R. Y., &amp; Bernstein, M. E. (1989). Synaptogenesis in the rat suprachiasmatic nucleus demonstrated by electron microscopy and synapsin I immunoreactivity. Journal of Neuroscience, 9, 2151-2162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore, R. Y., &amp; Eichler, V. B. (1972). Loss of a circadian adrenal corticosterone rhythm following suprachiasmatic lesions in the rat. Brain Research, 42, 201-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morel, L., Chiang, M. S. R., Higashimori, H., Shoneye, T., Iyer, L. K., Yelick, J., Tai, A., &amp; Yang, Y. (2017). Molecular and functional properties of regional astrocytes in the adult brain. Journal of Neuroscience, 37(36), 8706-8717.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris, E. L., Patton, A. P., Chesham, J. E., Crisp, A., Adamson, A., &amp; Hastings, M. H. (2021). Single-cell transcriptomics of suprachiasmatic nuclei reveal a Prokineticin-driven circadian network. EMBO Journal, 40(20), e108614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moulson, A. J., Squair, J. W., Franklin, R. J. M., Tetzlaff, W., &amp; Assinck, P. (2021). Diversity of reactive Astrogliosis in CNS pathology: Heterogeneity or plasticity? Frontiers in Cell Neuroscience, 15, 703810.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagy, J. I., Patel, D., Ochalski, P. A., &amp; Stelmack, G. L. (1999). Connexin30 in rodent, cat and human brain: Selective expression in gray matter astrocytes, co-localization with connexin43 at gap junctions and late developmental appearance. Neuroscience, 88, 447-468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarrete, M., &amp; Araque, A. (2014). The Cajal school and the physiological role of astrocytes: A way of thinking. Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 8, 33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng, F. S., Tangredi, M. M., &amp; Jackson, F. R. (2011). Glial cells physiologically modulate clock neurons and circadian behavior in a calcium-dependent manner. Current Biology, 21, 625-634. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2011.03.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nimmerjahn, A., Mukamel, E. A., &amp; Schnitzer, M. J. (2009). Motor behavior activates Bergmann glial networks. Neuron, 62, 400-412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oberheim, N. A., Takano, T., Han, X., He, W., Lin, J. H. C., Wang, F., Xu, Q., Wyatt, J. D., Pilcher, W., Ojemann, J. G., Ransom, B. R., Goldman, S. A., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2009). Uniquely hominid features of adult human astrocytes. Journal of Neuroscience, 29, 3276-3287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogata, K., &amp; Kosaka, T. (2002). Structural and quantitative analysis of astrocytes in the mouse hippocampus. Neuroscience, 113, 221-233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ono, D., Honma, S., &amp; Honma, K. I. (2016). Differential roles of AVP and VIP signaling in the postnatal changes of neural networks for coherent circadian rhythms in the SCN. Science Advances, 2, e1600960.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oster, H., Damerow, S., Kiessling, S., Jakubcakova, V., Abraham, D., Tian, J., Hoffmann, M. W., &amp; Eichele, G. (2006). The circadian rhythm of glucocorticoids is regulated by a gating mechanism residing in the adrenal cortical clock. Cell Metabolism, 4, 163-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patton, A. P., &amp; Hastings, M. H. (2018). The suprachiasmatic nucleus. Current Biology, 28, R816-R822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perea, G., &amp; Araque, A. (2007). Astrocytes potentiate transmitter release at single hippocampal synapses. Science, 317, 1083-1086.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perea, G., Navarrete, M., &amp; Araque, A. (2009). Tripartite synapses: Astrocytes process and control synaptic information. Trends in Neuroscience, 32, 421-431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perea, G., Gómez, R., Mederos, S., Covelo, A., Ballesteros, J. J., Schlosser, L., Hernández-Vivanco, A., Martín-Fernández, M., Quintana, R., Rayan, A., Díez, A., Fuenzalida, M., Agarwal, A., Bergles, D. E., Bettler, B., Manahan-Vaughan, D., Martín, E. D., Kirchhoff, F., &amp; Araque, A. (2016). Activity-dependent switch of GABAergic inhibition into glutamatergic excitation in astrocyte-neuron networks. eLife, 5, e20362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poopalasundaram, S., Knott, C., Shamotienko, O. G., Foran, P. G., Dolly, J. O., Ghiani, C. A., Gallo, V., &amp; Wilkin, G. P. (2000). Glial heterogeneity in expression of the inwardly rectifying K(+) channel, Kir4.1, in adult rat CNS. Glia, 30, 362-372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prolo, L. M., Takahashi, J. S., &amp; Herzog, E. D. (2005). Circadian rhythm generation and entrainment in astrocytes. Journal of Neuroscience, 25, 404-408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prosser, R. A., &amp; Gillette, M. U. (1989). The mammalian circadian clock in the suprachiasmatic nuclei is reset in vitro by cAMP. Journal of Neuroscience, 9, 1073-1081.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prosser, R. A., Edgar, D. M., Heller, H. C., &amp; Miller, J. D. (1994). A possible glial role in the mammalian circadian clock. Brain Research, 643, 296-301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ralph, M. R., &amp; Menaker, M. (1988). A mutation of the circadian system in golden hamsters. Science, 241, 1225-1227. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.3413487</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ralph, M. R., Foster, R. G., Davis, F. C., &amp; Menaker, M. (1990). Transplanted suprachiasmatic nucleus determines circadian period. Science, 247, 975-978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reppert, S. M., &amp; Schwartz, W. J. (1984). The suprachiasmatic nuclei of the fetal rat: Characterization of a functional circadian clock using 14C-labeled deoxyglucose. Journal of Neuroscience, 4, 1677-1682.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sánchez-González, R., Salvador, N., &amp; López-Mascaraque, L. (2020). Unraveling the adult cell progeny of early postnatal progenitor cells. Scientific Reports, 10, 19058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schibler, U., Gotic, I., Saini, C., Gos, P., Curie, T., Emmenegger, Y., Sinturel, F., Gosselin, P., Gerber, A., Fleury-Olela, F., Rando, G., Demarque, M., &amp; Franken, P. (2015). Clock-talk: Interactions between central and peripheral circadian oscillators in mammals. Cold Spring Harbor Symposia on Quantitative Biology, 80, 223-232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schibler, U., Ripperger, J., &amp; Brown, S. A. (2003). Peripheral circadian oscillators in mammals: Time and food. Journal of Biological Rhythms, 18, 250-260.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinohara, K., Honma, S., Katsuno, Y., Abe, H., &amp; Honma, K. (1995). Two distinct oscillators in the rat suprachiasmatic nucleus in vitro. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 92, 7396-7400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shirakawa, T., Honma, S., &amp; Honma, K. (2001). Multiple oscillators in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Chronobiology International, 18, 371-387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shibata, S., Oomura, Y., Kita, H., &amp; Hattori, K. (1982). Circadian rhythmic changes in neuronal activity in the suprachiasmatic nucleus of the rat hypothalamic slice. Brain Research, 247, 154-158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz, W. J., &amp; Gainer, H. (1977). Suprachiasmatic nucleus: Use of 14C-labeled deoxyglucose uptake as a functional marker. Science, 197, 1089-1091. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(82)91041-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silver, R., Lehman, M. N., Gibson, M., Gladstone, W. R., &amp; Bittman, E. L. (1990). Dispersed cell suspensions of fetal SCN restore circadian rhythmicity in SCN-lesioned adult hamsters. Brain Research, 525, 45-58. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(90)91319-c</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silver, R., LeSauter, J., Tresco, P. A., &amp; Lehman, M. N. (1996). A diffusible coupling signal from the transplanted suprachiasmatic nucleus controlling circadian locomotor rhythms. Nature, 382, 810-813.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephan, F. K., &amp; Zucker, I. (1972). Circadian rhythms in drinking behavior and locomotor activity of rats are eliminated by hypothalamic lesions. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 69, 1583-1586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suh, J., &amp; Jackson, F. R. (2007). Drosophila ebony activity is required in glia for the circadian regulation of locomotor activity. Neuron, 55, 435-447.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Svobodova, I., Bhattaracharya, A., Ivetic, M., Bendova, Z., &amp; Zemkova, H. (2018). Circadian ATP release in Organotypic cultures of the rat suprachiasmatic nucleus is dependent on P2X7 and P2Y receptors. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 9, 192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi, J. S. (2017). Transcriptional architecture of the mammalian circadian clock. Nature Reviews Genetics, 18, 164-179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tso, C. F., Simon, T., Greenlaw, A. C., Puri, T., Mieda, M., &amp; Herzog, E. D. (2017). Astrocytes regulate daily rhythms in the suprachiasmatic nucleus and behavior. Current Biology, 27, 1055-1061.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Den Pol, A. N., Finkbeiner, S. M., &amp; Cornell-Bell, A. H. (1992). Calcium excitability and oscillations in suprachiasmatic nucleus neurons and glia in vitro. Journal of Neuroscience, 12, 2648-2664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varadarajan, S., Tajiri, M., Jain, R., Holt, R., Ahmed, Q., LeSauter, J., &amp; Silver, R. (2018). Connectome of the suprachiasmatic nucleus: New Evidence of the Core-Shell Relationship. eNeuro, 5, 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1523/ENEURO.0205-18.2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vardjan, N., Parpura, V., Verkhratsky, A., &amp; Zorec, R. (2019). Gliocrine system: Astroglia as secretory cells of the CNS. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology, 1175, 93-115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky, A., Matteoli, M., Parpura, V., Mothet, J.-P., &amp; Zorec, R. (2016). Astrocytes as secretory cells of the central nervous system: Idiosyncrasies of vesicular secretion. EMBO Journal, 35, 239-257.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky, A., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2014). Astroglial cradle in the life of the synapse. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 369, 20130595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky, A., &amp; Nedergaard, M. (2018). Physiology of Astroglia. Physiological Reviews, 98, 239-389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsh, D. K., Takahashi, J. S., &amp; Kay, S. A. (2010). Suprachiasmatic nucleus: Cell autonomy and network properties. The Annual Review of Physiology, 72, 551-577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen, S., Ma, D., Zhao, M., Xie, L., Wu, Q., Gou, L., Zhu, C., Fan, Y., Wang, H., &amp; Yan, J. (2020). Spatiotemporal single-cell analysis of gene expression in the mouse suprachiasmatic nucleus. Nature Neuroscience, 23, 456-467. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-020-0586-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Womac, A. D., Burkeen, J. F., Neuendorff, N., Earnest, D. J., &amp; Zoran, M. J. (2009). Circadian rhythms of extracellular ATP accumulation in suprachiasmatic nucleus cells and cultured astrocytes. European Journal of Neuroscience, 30, 869-876. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2009.06874.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>You, S., Yu, A. M., Roberts, M. A., Joseph, I. J., &amp; Jackson, F. R. (2021). Circadian regulation of the drosophila astrocyte transcriptome. PLoS Genetics, 17, e1009790.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Y., &amp; Barres, B. A. (2010). Astrocyte heterogeneity: An underappreciated topic in neurobiology. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 20, 588-594.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ziemens, D., Oschmann, F., Gerkau, N. J., &amp; Rose, C. R. (2019). Heterogeneity of activity-induced sodium transients between astrocytes of the mouse hippocampus and neocortex: Mechanisms and consequences. Journal of Neuroscience, 39, 2620-2634. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2029-18.2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
