<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34837528</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1254</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>66</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of biometeorology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Biometeorol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparison of the effectiveness of peloid therapy and kinesio taping in tennis elbow patients: a single-blind controlled study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>661</StartPage>
          <EndPage>668</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>661-668</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00484-021-02225-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study aimed to compare the peloid therapy and kinesio tape treatments in chronic lateral epicondylitis. While home exercise program and cold application were applied to the control group, peloid therapy (5 days a week for 3 weeks at 45 °C for 30 min each day, a total of 15 treatment days) was applied in addition to the first group, and kinesio taping (6 treatment days 2 times a week) was applied to the second group. Patients were evaluated with visual analog scale (VAS), grip strength with Jamar hydraulic dynamometer, Arm, Shoulder, and Hand Disabilities (DASH), quality of life in Short Form-36 (SF-36), and Patient-Rated Forearm Evaluation Questionnaire (PRFEQ) was recorded before treatment, after treatment (third week), and 1 month after the end of treatment. In this study, 156 patients with chronic lateral epicondylitis were included. In the follow-up of the patients, there was a statistically significant improvement in the hand grip strength, DASH, PRFEQ, VAS, and SF-36 scores in the 1st month follow-up after the treatment compared to the pre-treatment control in all groups (p &lt; 0.001). At the end of the treatment, the hand grip strength (p = 0.002), DASH (p &lt; 0.001), PRFEQ pain (p &lt; 0.001) and function (p = 0.007), SF-36 physical health (p = 0.002) scores were statistically significant in the peloid therapy group compared to the control group. At the 1st month after the end of treatment, hand grip strength, VAS, DASH, PRFEQ pain, function, daily activities, and SF-36 physical health scores (all of p &lt; 0.001) were statistically significant in the peloid treatment group compared to the control group. Peloid treatment was found to be more effective than kinesio taping in SF-36 physical health (p = 0.007) and PRFEQ pain (p = 0.003) scores in the 1st month follow-up after treatment. Peloid therapy in addition to exercise seems more effective in chronic lateral epicondylitis. Randomized controlled long-term studies are needed.ClinicalTrials ID: NCT04687943.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. ISB.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gül</LastName>
            <ForeName>Süleyman</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8621-7707</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Konya City Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Konya, Turkey. drsuleymangul@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yılmaz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Halim</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5521-1214</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Konya City Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Konya, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Karaarslan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fatih</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1107-5887</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Ecology and Hydroclimatology, Gulhane Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT04687943</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D018848">Controlled Clinical Trial</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Biometeorol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0374716</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0020-7128</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018737" MajorTopicYN="N">Hand Strength</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009094" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mud Therapy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013716" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tennis Elbow</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Home exercise</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesio tape</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lateral epicondylitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Peloid therapy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>5</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34837528</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00484-021-02225-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00484-021-02225-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Au IP, Fan PCP, Lee WY, Leong MW, Tang OY, An WW, Cheung RT (2017) Effects of kinesio tape in individuals with lateral epicondylitis: a deceptive crossover trial. Physiother Theory Pract 33:914–919. https://doi.org/10.1080/09593985.2017.1359871</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrington J, Hage WD (2003) Lateral epicondylitis (tennis elbow): nonoperative, open, or arthroscopic treatment? Curr Opin Orthop 14:291–295</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beer A-M, Junginger H, Lukanov J, Sagorchev P (2003) Evaluation of the permeation of peat substances through human skin in vitro. Int J Pharm 253:169–175. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0378-5173(02)00706-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernetti A, Mangone M, Alviti F, Paolucci T, Attanasi C, Murgia M, Di Sante L, Agostini F, Vitale M, Paoloni M (2020) Spa therapy and rehabilitation of musculoskeletal pathologies: a proposal for best practice in Italy. Int J Biometeorol 64(6):905–914. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-019-01731-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheleschi S, Gallo I, Tenti S (2020) A comprehensive analysis to understand the mechanism of action of balneotherapy: why, how, and where they can be used? Evidence from in vitro studies performed on human and animal samples. Int J Biometeorol 64:1247–1261. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-020-01890-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho Y-T, Hsu W-Y, Lin L-F, Lin Y-N (2018) Kinesio taping reduces elbow pain during resisted wrist extension in patients with chronic lateral epicondylitis: a randomized, double-blinded, cross-over study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 19:1–8. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12891-018-2118-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cullinane FL, Boocock MG, Trevelyan FC (2014) Is eccentric exercise an effective treatment for lateral epicondylitis? A systematic review. Clin Rehabil 28:3–19. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269215513491974</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demiral Y, Ergor G, Unal B, Semin S, Akvardar Y, Kıvırcık B, Alptekin K (2006) Normative data and discriminative properties of short form 36 (SF-36) in Turkish urban population. BMC Public Health 6:247. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-6-247</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derebery VJ, Devenport JN, Giang GM, Fogarty WT (2005) the effects of splinting on outcomes for epicondylitis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 86:1081–1088. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apmr.2004.11.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Düger T, Coauthors (2006) Kol, omuz ve el sorunları (disabilities of the arm, shoulder and hand-DASH) anketi Türkçe uyarlamasının güvenirliği ve geçerliği. Fizyoterapi Rehabilitasyon 17:99–107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fioravanti A, Tenti S, Giannitti C, Fortunati NA, Galeazzi M (2014) Short-and long-term effects of mud-bath treatment on hand osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Int J Biometeorol 58:79–86. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-016-1250-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>George CE, Heales LJ, Stanton R, Wintour S-A, Kean CO (2019) Sticking to the facts: a systematic review of the effects of therapeutic tape in lateral epicondylalgia. Phys Ther Sport 40:117–127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ptsp.2019.08.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giray E, Karali-Bingul D, Akyuz G (2019) The effectiveness of kinesiotaping, sham taping or exercises only in lateral epicondylitis treatment: a randomized controlled study. Pm&amp;r 11:681–693. https://doi.org/10.1002/pmrj.12067</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guler T, Yıldırım P (2020) Comparison of the efficacy of kinesiotaping and extracorporeal shock wave therapy in patients with newly diagnosed lateral epicondylitis: a prospective randomized trial. Niger J Clin Pract 23:704–710. https://doi.org/10.4103/njcp.njcp_45_19</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karaarslan F, Yılmaz H, Akkurt HE, Gül S, Kardeş S (2021) Effectiveness of peloid therapy in patients with chronic low back pain: a single-blind controlled study. Int J Biometeorol 1–11. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-021-02137-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kase KJA (2003) Clinical therapeutic applications of the Kinesio (! R) taping method. Albuquerque</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landesa-Martínez L, Leirós-Rodríguez R (2021) Physiotherapy treatment of lateral epicondylitis: a systematic review. J Back Musculoskelet Rehabil. https://doi.org/10.3233/BMR-210053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manias P, Stasinopoulos D (2006) A controlled clinical pilot trial to study the effectiveness of ice as a supplement to the exercise programme for the management of lateral elbow tendinopathy. Br J Sports Med 40:81–85. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsm.2005.020909</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Massy-Westropp NM, Gill TK, Taylor AW, Bohannon RW, Hill CL (2011) Hand grip strength: age and gender stratified normative data in a population-based study. BMC Res Notes 4:127. https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-0500-4-127</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Odabasi E, Turan M, Erdem H, Tekbas F (2008) Does mud pack treatment have any chemical effect? A randomized controlled clinical study. J Alternat Complement Med 14:559–565. https://doi.org/10.1089/acm.2008.0003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ökmen BM, Eröksüz R, Altan L, Aksoy MKJ (2017a) Efficacy of peloid therapy in patients with chronic lateral epicondylitis: a randomized, controlled, single blind study. Int J Biometeorol. 61:1965–1972</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ökmen BM, Eröksüz R, Altan L, Aksoy MK (2017b) Efficacy of peloid therapy in patients with chronic lateral epicondylitis: a randomized, controlled, single blind study. Int J Biometeorol 61:1965–1972. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-017-1386-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ölmez N, Memis AJTKTBD (2010) Lateral Epikondilit Tedavisinde Kanita Dayali Veriler/Evidence based data for management of lateral epicondylitis, Turkiye Klinikleri. J Med Sci 30:303–311</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orchard J, Kountouris A (2011) The management of tennis elbow. BMJ 10(342):d2687. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.d2687</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Overend TJ, Wuori-Fearn JL, Kramer JF, MacDermid JC (1999) Reliability of a patient-rated forearm evaluation questionnaire for patients with lateral epicondylitis. J Hand Ther 12:31–37. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0894-1130(99)80031-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Özkuk K, Gürdal H, Karagülle M, Barut Y, Eröksüz R, Karagülle MZ (2017) Balneological outpatient treatment for patients with knee osteoarthritis; an effective non-drug therapy option in daily routine? Int J Biometeorol 61:719–728. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00484-016-1250-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson M, Butler S, Eriksson M, Svärdsudd K (2011) A randomized controlled trial of exercise versus wait-list in chronic tennis elbow (lateral epicondylosis). Upsala J Med Sci 116:269–279. https://doi.org/10.3109/03009734.2011.600476</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson M, Butler S, Eriksson M, Svärdsudd K (2014) A randomized controlled trial of eccentric vs. concentric graded exercise in chronic tennis elbow (lateral elbow tendinopathy). Clin Rehabil 28:862–872. https://doi.org/10.1177/0269215514527595</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter PL, González VM, Laurent DD, Lorig KR (2006) Measurement of pain using the visual numeric scale. J Rheumatol 33:574–580</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shakeri H, Soleimanifar M, Arab A, Behbahani SH (2018) The effects of KinesioTape on the treatment of lateral epicondylitis. J Hand Ther 31:35–41. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jht.2017.01.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shiri R, Viikari-Juntura E, Varonen H, Heliövaara MJA (2006) Prevalence and determinants of lateral and medial epicondylitis: a population study. Am J Epidemiol 164:1065–1074. https://doi.org/10.1093/aje/kwj325</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wegener RL, Brown T, O’Brien LJHT (2016) A randomized controlled trial of comparative effectiveness of elastic therapeutic tape, sham tape or eccentric exercises alone for lateral elbow tendinosis. Hand Therapy 21:131–139. https://doi.org/10.1177/1758998316656660</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson JJ, Best TMJ (2005) Common overuse tendon problems: a review and recommendations for treatment. Am Fam Phys 72:811–818</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong Y, Zheng C, Zheng J, Xu S (2020) Kinesio tape reduces pain in patients with lateral epicondylitis: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Int J Surg. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsu.2020.02.044</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
