<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34837339</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-8494</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>305</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Anatomical record (Hoboken, N.J. : 2007)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Distribution of cholinergic neurons in the brains of a lar gibbon and a chimpanzee.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1516</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1535</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1516-1535</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ar.24844</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Using choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry, we describe the nuclear parcellation of the cholinergic system in the brains of two apes, a lar gibbon (Hylobates lar) and a chimpanzee (Pan troglodytes). The cholinergic nuclei observed in both apes studied are virtually identical to that observed in humans and show very strong similarity to the cholinergic nuclei observed in other primates and mammals more generally. One specific difference between humans and the two apes studied is that, with the specific choline acetyltransferase antibody used, the cholinergic pyramidal neurons observed in human cerebral cortex were not labeled. When comparing the two apes studied and humans to other primates, the presence of a greatly expanded cholinergic medullary tegmental field, and the presence of cholinergic neurons in the intermediate and dorsal horns of the cervical spinal cord are notable variations of the distribution of cholinergic neurons in apes compared to other primates. These neurons may play an important role in the modulation of ascending and descending neural transmissions through the spinal cord and caudal medulla, potentially related to the differing modes of locomotion in apes compared to other primates. Our observations also indicate that the average soma volume of the neurons forming the laterodorsal tegmental nucleus (LDT) is larger than those of the pedunculopontine nucleus (PPT) in both the lar gibbon and chimpanzee. This variability in soma volume appears to be related to the size of the adult derivatives of the alar and basal plate across mammalian species.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American Association for Anatomy.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Williams</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victoria M</ForeName>
            <Initials>VM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bhagwandin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adhil</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Clinical Anatomy and Biological Anthropology, Department of Human Biology, University of Cape Town, Cape Town, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Swiegers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jordan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bertelsen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mads F</ForeName>
            <Initials>MF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Zoo and Wild Animal Health, Copenhagen Zoo, Frederiksberg, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hård</LastName>
            <ForeName>Therese</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Borås Zoo, Borås, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sherwood</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chet C</ForeName>
            <Initials>CC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anthropology and Center for the Advanced Study of Human Paleobiology, The George Washington University, Washington, District of Columbia, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manger</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul R</ForeName>
            <Initials>PR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1881-2854</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Anatomical Sciences, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Anat Rec (Hoboken)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101292775</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1932-8486</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018678">Cholinergic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.3.1.6</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D002795">Choline O-Acetyltransferase</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000630435">Hylobates lar</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002795" MajorTopicYN="Y">Choline O-Acetyltransferase</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018678" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinergic Agents</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059329" MajorTopicYN="N">Cholinergic Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006922" MajorTopicYN="N">Hylobates</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008322" MajorTopicYN="N">Mammals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002679" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pan troglodytes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acetylcholine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ape</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain evolution</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">choline acetyltransferase</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunohistochemistry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primates</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34837339</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ar.24844</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avendaño, C., Umbriaco, D., Dykes, R. W., &amp; Descarries, L. (1996). Acetylcholine innervation of sensory and motor neocortical areas in adult cat: A choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemical study. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 11, 113-130. https://doi.org/10.1016/0891-0618(96)00132-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baghdoyan, H. A., Rodrigo-Angulo, M. L., McCarley, R. W., &amp; Hobson, J. A. (1984). Site-specific enhancement and suppression of desynchronised sleep signs following cholinergic stimulation of three brainstem regions. Brain Research, 306, 39-52. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(84)90354-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartus, R. T. (2000). On neurodegenerative diseases, models and treatment strategies: Lessons learned and lessons forgotten a generation following the cholinergic hypothesis. Experimental Neurology, 163, 495-529. https://doi.org/10.1006/exnr.2000.7397</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benagiano, V., Virgintino, D., Flace, P., Girolamo, F., Errede, M., Roncali, L., &amp; Ambrosi, G. (2003). Choline acetyltransferase-containing neurons in the human parietal neocortex. European Journal of Histochemistry, 47, 253-256. https://doi.org/10.4081/835</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benzing, W. C., Kordower, J. H., &amp; Mufson, E. J. (1993). Galanin immunoreactivity within the primate basal forebrain: Evolutionary change between monkeys and apes. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 336, 31-39. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903360103</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertelsen, M. F. (2018). Issues surrounding surplus animals in zoos. In R. E. Miller, N. Lamberski, &amp; P. Calle (Eds.), Fowler's zoo and wild animal medicine, current therapy (Vol. 9, pp. 134-137). Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhagwandin, A., Fuxe, K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2006). Choline acetyltransferase immunoreactive cortical interneurons do not occur in all rodents: A study of the phylogenetic occurrence of this neural characteristic. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 32, 208-216. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2006.09.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bux, F., Bhagwandin, A., Fuxe, K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2010). Organization of cholinergic, putative catecholaminergic and serotonergic nuclei in the diencephalon, midbrain and pons of sub-adult male giraffes. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 39, 189-203. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2009.09.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvey, T., Patzke, N., Kaswera-Kyamakya, C., Gilissen, E., Bertelsen, M. F., Pettigrew, J. D., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2015). Organisation of cholinergic, catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic nuclei in three strepsirrhine primates: Galago demidoff, Perodicticus potto and Lemur catta. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 70, 42-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2015.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvey, T., Patzke, N., Kawsera, C., Gilissen, E., Bennett, N. C., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2013). Nuclear organisation of some immunohistochemically identifiable neural systems in three Afrotherian species - Potomogale velox, Amblysomus hottentotus and Petrodromus tetradactylus. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 50-51, 48-65. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2013.01.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chubykin, A. A., Roach, E. B., Bear, M. F., &amp; Shuler, M. G. H. (2013). A cholinergic mechanism for reward timing within primary visual cortex. Neuron, 77, 723-735. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2012.12.039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davimes, J. G., Alagaili, A. N., Bennett, N. C., Mohammed, O. B., Bhagwandin, A., Manger, P. R., &amp; Gravett, N. (2017). Neurochemical organization and morphology of the sleep related nuclei in the brain of the Arabian oryx, Oryx leucoryx. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 81, 53-70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2017.02.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Karlsson, K. AE., Patzke, N., Spocter, M. A., Siegel, J. M., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2016). Organization of the sleep-related neural systems in the brain of the minke whale (Balaenoptera acutorostrata). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524, 2018-2035. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne23931</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Kruger, J. L., Bhagwandin, A., Jillani, N. E., Pettigrew, J. D., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2010). Nuclear organization of cholinergic, putative catecholaminergic and serotonergic systems in the brains of two megachiropteran species. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 40, 177-195. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2010.05.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Patzke, N., Spocter, M. A., Bertelsen, M. F., Siegel, J. M., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2016). Organisation of the sleep related neural systems in the brain of the river hippopotamus (Hippopotamus amphibius): A most unusual cetartiodactyl species. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524, 2036-2058. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne23930</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dell, L. A., Patzke, N., Spocter, M. A., Siegel, J. M., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2016). Organization of the sleep-related neural systems in the brain of the harbour porpoise (Phocoena phocoena). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524, 1999-2017. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23929</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delucchi, M. R. (1965). A stereotaxic atlas of the chimpanzee brain - Pan satyrus. University of California Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Everitt, B. J., &amp; Robbins, T. W. (1997). Central cholinergic systems and cognition. Annual Review of Psychology, 48, 649-684. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.psych.48.1.649</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Everitt, B. J., Sirkiä, T. E., Roberts, A. C., Jones, G. H., &amp; Robbins, T. W. (1988). Distribution and some projections of cholinergic neurons in the brain of the common marmoset, Callithrix jacchus. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 271, 533-558. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902710406</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallyas, F. (1979). Silver staining of myelin by means of physical development. Neurological Research, 1, 203-209. https://doi.org/10.1080/01616412.1979.11739553</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gratton, C., Yousef, S., Aarts, E., Wallace, D. L., D'Esposito, M., &amp; Silver, M. A. (2017). Cholinergic, but not dopaminergic or noradrenergic, enhancement sharpens visual spatial perception in humans. Journal of Neuroscience, 37, 4405-4415. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2405-16.2017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gravett, N., Bhagwandin, A., Fuxe, K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2009). Nuclear organisation and morphology of cholinergic, putative catecholaminergic and serotonergic neurons in the brain of the rock hyrax, Procavia capensis. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 38, 57-74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j/jchemneu.2009.02.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gundersen, H. J. (1988). The nucleator. Journal of Microscopy, 151, 3-21. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2818.1988.tb04609.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hampel, H., Mesulam, M. M., Cuello, A. C., Farlow, M. R., Giacobini, E., Grossberg, G. T., Khachaturian, A. S., Vergallo, A., Cavedo, E., Snyder, P. J., &amp; Khachaturian, Z. S. (2018). The cholinergic system in the pathophysiology and treatment of Alzheimer's disease. Brain, 141, 1917-1933. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awy132</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasselmo, M. E., &amp; McGaughy, J. (2004). High acetylcholine levels set circuit dynamics for attention and encoding and low acetylcholine levels set dynamics for consolidation. Progress in Brain Research, 145, 207-231. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0079-6123(03)45015-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ichikawa, T., &amp; Shimizu, T. (1998). Organisation of choline acetyltransferase-containing structures in the cranial nerve motor nuclei and spinal cord of the monkey. Brain Research, 779, 96-103. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-8993(97)01090-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jasper, H., &amp; Tessier, J. (1971). Acetylcholine liberation from cerebral cortex during paradoxical (REM) sleep. Science, 172, 601-602. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.172.3983.601</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaiser, A., Alexandrova, O., &amp; Grothe, B. (2011). Urocortin-expressing olivocochlear neurons exhibit tonotopic and developmental changes in the auditory brainstem and in the innervation of the cochlea. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 519, 2758-2778. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22650</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kruger, J. L., Patzke, N., Fuxe, K., Bennett, N. C., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2012). Nuclear organization of cholinergic, putative catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic systems in the brain of the African pygmy mouse (Mus minutoides): Organizational complexity is preserved in small brains. Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 44, 45-56. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2012.04.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laux, A., Delalande, F., Mouheiche, J., Stuber, D., van Dorsselaer, A., Bianchi, E., Bezard, E., Poisbeau, P., &amp; Goumon, Y. (2012). Localization of endogenous morphine-like compounds in the mouse spinal cord. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 520, 1547-1561. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22811</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavoie, B., &amp; Parent, A. (1994). Pedunculopontine nucleus in the squirrel monkey: Distribution of cholinergic and monoaminergic neurons in the mesopontine tegmentum with evidence for the presence of glutamate in cholinergic neurons. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 344, 190-209. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903440203</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis, D. A. (1991). Distribution of choline acetyltransferase-immunoreactive axons in monkey frontal cortex. Neuroscience, 40, 363-374. https://doi.org/10.1016/0306-4522(91)90126-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahady, L. J., Perez, S. E., Emerich, D. F., Wahlberg, L. U., &amp; Mufson, E. J. (2017). Cholinergic profiles in the Goettingen miniature pig (Sus scrofa domesticus) brain. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525, 553-573. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24087</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malungo, I. B., Gravett, N., Bhagwandin, A., Davimes, J. G., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2020). A preliminary description of the sleep-related neural systems in the brain of the blue wildebeest, Connochaetes taurinus. The Anatomical Record, 303, 1977-1997. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.24265</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manger, P. R., Cort, J., Ebrahim, N., Goodman, A., Henning, J., Karolia, M., Rodrigues, S. L., &amp; Štrkalj, G. (2008). Is 21st century neuroscience too focussed on the rat/mouse model of brain function and dysfunction? Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 2, 5. https://doi.org/10.3389/neuro.05.005.2008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manger, P. R., Pillay, P., Maseko, B. C., Bhagwandin, A., Gravett, N., Moon, D. J., Jillani, N., &amp; Hemingway, J. (2009). Acquisition of brains from the African elephant (Loxodonta africana): Perfusion-fixation and dissection. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 179, 16-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/j/jneumeth.2009.01.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mesulam, M., Mufson, E. J., Levey, A. I., &amp; Wainer, B. H. (1984). Atlas of cholinergic neurons in the forebrain and upper brainstem of the macaque based on monoclonal choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry. Neuroscience, 12, 669-686. https://doi.org/10.1016/0306-4522(84)90163-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mesulam, M. M., &amp; Geula, C. (1988). Nucleus basalis (Ch4) and cortical cholinergic innervation in the human brain: Observations based on distribution of acetylcholinesterase and choline acetyltransferase. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 275, 216-240. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902750205</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mesulam, M. M., Geula, C., Bothwell, M. A., &amp; Hersch, L. B. (1989). Human reticular formation: Cholinergic neurons of the pedunculopontine tegmental nuclei and some cytochemical comparisons of forebrain cholinergic neurons. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 281, 611-633. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902830414</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mesulam, M. M., Hersh, L. B., Mash, D. C., &amp; Geula, C. (1992). Differential cholinergic innervation within functional subdivisions of the human cerebral cortex: A choline acetyltransferase study. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 318, 316-328. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903180308</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mizukawa, K., McGeer, P. L., Tago, H., Peng, J. H., McGeer, E. G., &amp; Kimura, H. (1986). The cholinergic system of the human hindbrain studied by choline acetyltransferase immunohistochemistry and acetylcholinesterase histochemistry. Brain Research, 379, 39-55. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(86)90253-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muir, J. L., Dunnet, S. B., Robbins, T. W., &amp; Everitt, B. J. (1992). Attentional functions of the forebrain cholinergic system: Effects of intraventricular hemicholinium physotigmine, basal forebrain lesions and intracortical grafts on a multiple-choice serial reaction time task. Experimental Brain Research, 89, 611-622. https://doi.org/10.1007/bf00229886</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oda, Y., &amp; Nakanishi, I. (2000). The distribution of cholinergic neurons in the human central nervous system. Histology and Histopathology, 15, 825-834. https://doi.org/10.14670/HH-15.825</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parent, M. B., &amp; Baxter, M. G. (2004). Septohippocampal acetylcholine: Involved in but not necessary for learning and memory? Learning Memory, 11, 9-20. https://doi.org/10.1101/lm.69104</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patzke, N., Bertelsen, M. F., Fuxe, K., &amp; Manger, P. R. (2014). Nuclear organization of cholinergic, catecholaminergic, serotonergic and orexinergic systems in the brain of the Tasmanian devil (Sarcophilus harrisii). Journal of Chemical Neuroanatomy, 61-62, 94-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchemneu.2014.08.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pawlowski, S. A., Gaillard, S., Ghorayeb, I., Ribeiro-da-Silva, A., Schlichter, R., &amp; Cordero-Erausquin, M. (2013). A novel population of cholinergic neurons in the macaque spinal dorsal horn of potential clinical relevance for pain therapy. The Journal of Neuroscience, 33, 3727-3737. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3954-12.2013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paxinos, G., &amp; Watson, C. (2013). The rat brain in stereotaxic coordinates (7th ed.). Academic Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puelles, L., Harrison, M., Paxinos, G., &amp; Watson, C. (2013). A developmental ontology for the mammalian brain based on the prosomeric model. Trends in Neurosciences, 36, 570-578. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2013.06.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghanti, M. A., Simic, G., Watson, S., Stimpson, C. D., Hof, P. R., &amp; Sherwood, C. C. (2011). Comparative analysis of the nucleus basalis of Meynert among primates. Neuroscience, 184, 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2011.04.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghanti, M. A., Stimpson, C. D., Marcinkiewicz, J. L., Erwin, J. M., Hof, P. R., &amp; Sherwood, C. C. (2008). Cholinergic innervation of the frontal cortex: Differences among humans, chimpanzees, and macaque monkeys. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 506, 409-424. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21546</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rico, B., &amp; Cavada, C. (1998). A population of cholinergic neurons is present in the macaque monkey thalamus. European Journal of Neuroscience, 10, 2346-2352. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1460-9568.1998.00246.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarter, M., Hasselmo, M. E., Bruno, J. P., &amp; Givens, B. (2005). Unravelling the attentional functions of cortical cholinergic inputs: Interactions between signal-driven and cognitive modulation of signal detection. Brain Research Reviews, 48, 98-111. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainresrev.2004.08.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satoh, K., &amp; Fibiger, H. C. (1985). Distribution of central cholinergic neurons in the baboon (Papio papio). I. General morphology. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 236, 197-214. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne902360205</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephenson, A. R., Edler, M. K., Erwin, J. M., Jacobs, B., Hopkins, W. D., Hof, P. R., Sherwood, C. C., &amp; Raghanti, M. A. (2017). Cholinergic innervation of the basal ganglion in humans and other anthropoid primates. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525, 319-332. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne24067</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tago, H., McGeer, P. L., Bruce, G., &amp; Hersh, L. B. (1987). Distribution of choline acetyltransferase-containing neurons of the hypothalamus. Brain Research, 415, 49-62. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(87)90268-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tata, A. M., Velluto, L., D'Angelo, C., &amp; Reale, M. (2014). Cholinergic system dysfunction and neurodegenerative diseases: Cause or effect? CNS &amp; Neurological Disorders - Drug Targets, 13, 1294-1303. https://doi.org/10.2174/1871527313666140917121132</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomás-Roca, L., Corral-San-Miguel, R., Aroca, P., Puelles, L., &amp; Marín, F. (2016). Crypto-rhombomeres of the mouse medulla oblongata, defined by molecular and morphological features. Brain Structure and Function, 221, 815-838. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-014-0938-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virgo, L., de Belleroche, J., Rossi, M., &amp; Steiner, T. J. (1992). Characterisation of the distribution of choline acetyltransferase messenger RNA in human spinal cord and its depletion in motor neuron disease. Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 112, 126-132. https://doi.org/10.1016/0022-510x(92)90141-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson, C., Bartholomaeus, C., &amp; Puelles, L. (2019). Time for radical changes in brain stem nomenclature - Applying the lessons from developmental gene patterns. Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 13, 10. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2019.00010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson, C., Kirkcaldie, M., &amp; Puelles, L. (2017). Developmental gene expression redefines the mammalian brain stem. In J. H. Kaas (Ed.), Evolution of nervous systems (2nd ed., pp. 467-475). Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson, C., Mitchelle, A., &amp; Puelles, L. (2017). A new mammalian brain ontology based on developmental gene expression. In J. H. Kaas (Ed.), Evolution of nervous systems (2nd ed., pp. 53-75). Elsevier.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinberger, N. M. (2003). The nucleus basalis and memory codes: Auditory cortical plasticity and the induction of specific, associative behavioural memory. Neurobiology of Learning and Memory, 80, 264-284. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1074-7427(03)00072-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West, M. J., Slomianka, L., &amp; Gundersen, H. J. (1991). Unbiased stereological estimation of the total number of neurons in the subdivisions of the rat hippocampus using the optical fractionator. Anatomical Record, 231, 482-497. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.1092310411</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woolf, N. J. (1991). Cholinergic systems in mammalian brain and spinal cord. Progress in Neurobiology, 37, 475-524. https://doi.org/10.1016/0301-0082(91)90006-m</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woolf, N. J., &amp; Butcher, L. L. (2011). Cholinergic systems mediate action for movement to higher consciousness. Behavioural Brain Research, 221, 488-498. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2009.12.046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, C. K., Hersh, L. B., &amp; Geula, C. (2000). Cyto- and chemoarchitecture of basal forebrain cholinergic neurons in the common marmoset (Callithrix jacchus). Experimental Neurology, 165, 306-326. https://doi.org/10.1006/exnr.2000.7468</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
