<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34843626</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>530</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Local olfactory interneurons provide the basis for neurochemical regionalization of olfactory glomeruli in crustaceans.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1399</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1422</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1399-1422</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25283</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The primary olfactory centers of metazoans as diverse as arthropods and mammals consist of an array of fields of dense synaptic neuropil, the olfactory glomeruli. However, the neurochemical structure of crustacean olfactory glomeruli is largely understudied when compared to the insects. We analyzed the glomerular architecture in selected species of hermit crabs using immunohistochemistry against presynaptic proteins, the neuropeptides orcokinin, RFamide and allatostatin, and the biogenic amine serotonin. Our study reveals an unexpected level of structural complexity, unmatched by what is found in the insect olfactory glomeruli. Peptidergic and aminergic interneurons provide the structural basis for a regionalization of the crustacean glomeruli into longitudinal and concentric compartments. Our data suggest that local olfactory interneurons take a central computational role in modulating the information transfer from olfactory sensory neurons to projection neurons within the glomeruli. Furthermore, we found yet unknown neuronal elements mediating lateral inhibitory interactions across the glomerular array that may play a central role in modulating the transfer of sensory input to the output neurons through presynaptic inhibition. Our study is another step in understanding the function of crustacean olfactory glomeruli as highly complex units of local olfactory processing.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. The Journal of Comparative Neurology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Harzsch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Steffen</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8645-3320</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology and Evolutionary Biology, Zoological Institute and Museum, University of Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Evolutionary Neuroethology, Max-Planck-Institute for Chemical Ecology, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dircksen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heinrich</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Zoology, Stockholm University, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hansson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bill S</ForeName>
            <Initials>BS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Evolutionary Neuroethology, Max-Planck-Institute for Chemical Ecology, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D033381" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anomura</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007395" MajorTopicYN="N">Interneurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008322" MajorTopicYN="N">Mammals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019581" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropil</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009830" MajorTopicYN="N">Olfactory Bulb</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009833" MajorTopicYN="N">Olfactory Pathways</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018034" MajorTopicYN="Y">Olfactory Receptor Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Coenobita clypeatus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Crustacea</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Pagurus bernhardus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">neuropeptides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">olfactory glomeruli</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">olfactory interneurons</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">olfactory system</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>26</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34843626</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25283</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonsen, B. L., &amp; Paul, D. H. (2001). Serotonergic and octopaminergic systems in the squat lobster Munida quadrispina (anomura, galatheidae). The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 439(4), 450-468. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.1362</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bates, A. S., Schlegel, P., Roberts, R. J. V., Drummond, N., Tamimi, I. F. M., Turnbull, R., Zhao, X., Marin, E. C., Popovici, P. D., Dhawan, S., Jamasb, A., Javier, A., Serratosa Capdevila, L., Li, F., Rubin, G. M., Waddell, S., Bock, D. D., Costa, M., &amp; Jefferis, G. S. X. E. (2020). Complete connectomic reconstruction of olfactory projection neurons in the fly brain. Current Biology, 30(16), 3183-3199.e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2020.06.042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltz, B. S. (1999). Distribution and functional anatomy of amine-containing neurons in decapod crustaceans. Microscopy Research and Technique, 44(2-3), 105-120. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19990115/01)44:2/3&lt;105::AID-JEMT5&gt;3.0.CO;2-K</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltz, B. S., Kordas, K., Lee, M. M., Long, J. B., Benton, J. L., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (2003). Ecological, evolutionary, and functional correlates of sensilla number and glomerular density in the olfactory system of decapod crustaceans. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 455(2), 260-269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltz, B. S., Pontes, M., Helluy, S. M., &amp; Kravitz, E. A. (1990). Patterns of appearance of serotonin and proctolin immunoreactivities in the developing nervous system of the American lobster. Journal of Neurobiology, 21(4), 521-542. https://doi.org/10.1002/neu.480210402</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benton, J. L., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (2007). Nitric oxide in the crustacean brain: Regulation of neurogenesis and morphogenesis in the developing olfactory pathway. Developmental Dynamics, 236(11), 3047-3060. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvdy.21340</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaustein, D. N., Derby, C. D., Simmons, R. B., &amp; Beall, A. C. (1988). Structure of the brain and medulla terminalis of the spiny lobster Panulirus argus and the crayfish Procambarus clarkii, with an emphasis on olfactory centers. Journal of Crustacean Biology, 8, 493-519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bungart, D., Dircksen, H., &amp; Keller, R. (1994). Quantitative determination and distribution of the myotropic neuropeptide orcokinin in the nervous system of astacidean crustaceans. Peptides, 15(3), 393-400. https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(94)90194-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bungart, D., Hilbich, C., Dircksen, H., &amp; Keller, R. (1995). Occurrence of analogues of the myotropic neuropeptide orcokinin in the shore crab, Carcinus maenas: Evidence for a novel neuropeptide family. Peptides, 16(1), 67-72. https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(94)00145-v</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cape, S. S., Rehm, K. J., Ma, M., Marder, E., &amp; Li, L. (2008). Mass spectral comparison of the neuropeptide complement of the stomatogastric ganglion and brain in the adult and embryonic lobster, Homarus americanus. Journal of Neurochemistry, 105(3), 690-702. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2007.05154.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E. (2014). Expansion of the Litopenaeus vannamei and Penaeus monodon peptidomes using transcriptome shotgun assembly sequence data. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 206, 235-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2014.04.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E. (2016). Expansion of the neuropeptidome of the globally invasive marine crab Carcinus maenas. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 235, 150-169. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2016.05.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E., &amp; Chi, M. (2015). Neuropeptide discovery in the Araneae (Arthropoda, Chelicerata, Arachnida): Elucidation of true spider peptidomes using that of the Western black widow as a reference. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 213, 90-109. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2015.02.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E., Sousa, G. L., Rus, S., Smith, C. M., Towle, D. W., Hartline, D. K., &amp; Dickinson, P. S. (2008). Identification of A-type allatostatins possessing −YXFGI/Vamide carboxy-termini from the nervous system of the copepod crustacean Calanus finmarchicus. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 155(3), 526-533. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2007.09.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E., Stemmler, E. A., &amp; Dickinson, P. S. (2010). Crustacean neuropeptides. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences: CMLS, 67(24), 4135-4169. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-010-0482-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derby, C. D., Kozma, M. T., Senatore, A., &amp; Schmidt, M. (2016). Molecular mechanisms of reception and perireception in crustacean chemoreception: A comparative review. Chemical Senses, 1-18. https://doi.org/10.1093/chemse/bjw057</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derby, C. D., &amp; Weissburg, M. J. (2014). The chemical senses and chemosensory ecology of crustaceans. In C. D. Derby &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.), Crustacean nervous systems and their control of behavior (pp. 263-292). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dircksen, H., Burdzik, S., Sauter, A., &amp; Keller, R. (2000). Two orcokinins and the novel octapeptide orcomyotropin in the hindgut of the crayfish Orconectes limosus: Identified myostimulatory neuropeptides originating together in neurones of the terminal abdominal ganglion. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 203(Pt 18), 2807-2818.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dircksen, H., Neupert, S., Predel, R., Verleyen, P., Huybrechts, J., Strauss, J., Hauser, F., Stafflinger, E., Schneider, M., Pauwels, K., Schoofs, L., &amp; Grimmelikhuijzen, C. J. P. (2011). Genomics, transcriptomics, and peptidomics of Daphnia pulex Neuropeptides and protein hormones. Journal of Proteome Research, 10(10), 4478-4504. https://doi.org/10.1021/pr200284e</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dircksen, H., Skiebe, P., Abel, B., Agricola, H., Buchner, K., Muren, J. E., &amp; Nässel, D. R. (1999). Structure, distribution, and biological activity of novel members of the allatostatin family in the crayfish Orconectes limosus. Peptides, 20(6), 695-712. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0196-9781(99)00052-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dockray, G. (2004). The expanding family of -RFamide peptides and their effects on feeding behaviour. Experimental Physiology, 89(3), 229-235. https://doi.org/10.1113/expphysiol.2004.027169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duve, H., Johnsen, A. H., Scott, A. G., &amp; Thorpe, A. (2002). Allatostatins of the tiger prawn, Penaeus monodon (Crustacea: Penaeidea). Peptides, 23(6), 1039-1051. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0196-9781(02)00035-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahrbach, S. E., &amp; Van Nest, B. N. (2016). Synapsin-based approaches to brain plasticity in adult social insects. Current Opinion in Insect Science, 18, 27-34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cois.2016.08.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahrenbach, W. (1979). The brain of the horseshoe crab (Limulus polyphemus). III. Cellular and synaptic organization of the corpora pedunculata. Tissue &amp; Cell, 11, 163-199. https://doi.org/10.1016/0040-8166(79)90016-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuscà, D., &amp; Kloppenburg, P. (2021). Odor processing in the cockroach antennal lobe-The network components. Cell and Tissue Research, 383(1), 59-73. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03387-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia, C. G. (2014). Olfactory coding in the insect brain: Data and conjectures. European Journal of Neuroscience, 39(11), 1784-1795. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.12558</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia, C. G., &amp; Rössler, W. (2010). Parallel olfactory systems in insects: Anatomy and function. Annual Review of Entomology, 55(1), 399-420. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-ento-112408-085442</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Groh, C., &amp; Rössler, W. (2020). Analysis of synaptic microcircuits in the mushroom bodies of the honeybee. Insects, 11(1), 43. https://doi.org/10.3390/insects11010043</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallberg, E., &amp; Skog, M. (2011). Chemosensory sensilla in crustaceans. In T. Breithaupt &amp; M. Thiel, (Eds.), Chemical communication in crustaceans (pp. 103-21). Springer.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson, B. S., &amp; Anton, S. (2000). Function and morphology of the antennal lobe: New developments. Annual Review of Entomology, 45(1), 203-231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson, B. S., Harzsch, S., Knaden, M., &amp; Stensmyr, M. C. (2011). The neural and behavioral basis of chemical communication in terrestrial crustaceans. In T. Breithaupt &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.), Chemical communication in crustaceans (pp. 149-173). Springer.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S. (2002). The phylogenetic significance of crustacean optic neuropils and chiasmata: A re-examination. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 453(1), 10-21. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2008). Brain architecture in the terrestrial hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomura, Coenobitidae), a crustacean with a good aerial sense of smell. BMC Neuroscience, 9(1), 58. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2202-9-58</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Krieger, J. (2018). Crustacean olfactory systems: A comparative review and a crustacean perspective on insect olfactory systems. Progress in Neurobiology, 161, 23-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Krieger, J. (2021). Genealogical relationships of mushroom bodies, hemiellipsoid bodies, and their afferent pathways in the brains of Pancrustacea: Recent progress and open questions. Arthropod Structure and Development, 65, 101100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., Miller, J., Benton, J. L., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (1999). From embryo to adult: Persistent neurogenesis and apoptotic cell death shape the lobster deutocerebrum. The Journal of Neuroscience, 19(9), 3472-3485.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., Miller, J., Benton, J. L., Dawirs, R. R., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (1998). Neurogenesis in the thoracic neuromeres of two crustaceans with different types of metamorphic development. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 201(17), 2465-2479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helluy, S., Sandeman, R. E., Beltz, B. S., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (1993). Comparative brain ontogeny of the crayfish and clawed lobster: Implications of direct and larval development. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 335(3), 343-354. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903350305</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer, S., Dircksen, H., Tollbäck, P., &amp; Homberg, U. (2005). Novel insect orcokinins: Characterization and neuronal distribution in the brains of selected dicondylian insects. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 490(1), 57-71. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.20650</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer, S., &amp; Homberg, U. (2006a). Evidence for a role of orcokinin-related peptides in the circadian clock controlling locomotor activity of the cockroach Leucophaea maderae. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 209(Pt 14), 2794-2803. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.02307</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer, S., &amp; Homberg, U. (2006b). Orcokinin immunoreactivity in the accessory medulla of the cockroach Leucophaea maderae. Cell and Tissue Research, 325(3), 589-600. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-006-0155-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huybrechts, J., Nusbaum, M. P., Bosch, L. V., Baggerman, G., De Loof, A., &amp; Schoofs, L. (2003). Neuropeptidomic analysis of the brain and thoracic ganglion from the Jonah crab. Cancer borealis. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 308(3), 535-544. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-291x(03)01426-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imai, T. (2014). Construction of functional neuronal circuitry in the olfactory bulb. Seminars in Cell &amp; Developmental Biology, 35, 180-188. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semcdb.2014.07.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson, K. U. I. (1991). Identification of different types of serotonin-like immunoreactive olfactory interneurons in four infraorders of decapod crustaceans. Cell and Tissue Research, 264(2), 357-362. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00313974</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson, K. U. I., Lundquist, C. T., Hallberg, E., &amp; Nässel, D. R. (1999). Tachykinin-related neuropeptide in the crayfish olfactory midbrain. Cell and Tissue Research, 296(2), 405-415. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004410051300</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson, K. U. I., &amp; Mellon, D. (1998). Nitric oxide as a putative messenger molecule in the crayfish olfactory midbrain. Brain Research, 807(1), 237-242. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0006-8993(98)00826-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klagges, B. R., Heimbeck, G., Godenschwege, T. A., Hofbauer, A., Pflugfelder, G. O., Reifegerste, R., Reisch, D., Schaupp, M., Buchner, S., &amp; Buchner, E. (1996). Invertebrate synapsins: A single gene codes for several isoforms in Drosophila. The Journal of Neuroscience, 16(10), 3154-3165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobierski, L. A., Beltz, B. S., Trimmer, B. A., &amp; Kravitz, E. A. (1987). FMRFamidelike peptides of homarus americanus: Distribution, immunocytochemical mapping, and ultrastructural localization in terminal varicosities. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 266(1), 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902660102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotsyuba, E., &amp; Dyachuk, V. (2021). Localization of neurons expressing choline acetyltransferase, serotonin and/or FMRFamide in the central nervous system of the decapod shore crab Hemigrapsus sanguineus. Cell and Tissue Research, 383(3), 959-977. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03309-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotsyuba, E., Dyuizen, I., &amp; Lamash, N. (2010). Stress-induced changes in the nitric oxide system of shore crabs living under different ecological conditions. Russian Journal of Marine Biology, 36, 201-208. https://doi.org/10.1134/S1063074010030065</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotsyuba, E. P. (2012). Distribution of neurons containing catecholamines in brain of hermit crab Pagurus middendorffii and of king crab Paralithodes camtschaticus (Anomura, Decapoda). Cell and Tissue Biology, 6(4), 376-382. https://doi.org/10.1134/S1990519x12040074</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreissl, S., Strasser, C., &amp; Galizia, C. G. (2010). Allatostatin immunoreactivity in the honeybee brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 518(9), 1391-1417. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22343</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kress, T., Harzsch, S., &amp; Dircksen, H. (2016). Neuroanatomy of the optic ganglia and central brain of the water flea Daphnia magna (Crustacea, Cladocera). Cell and Tissue Research, 363(3), 649-677. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-015-2279-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Braun, P., Rivera, N. T., Schubart, C. D., Müller, C. H. G., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2015). Comparative analyses of olfactory systems in terrestrial crabs (Brachyura): Evidence for aerial olfaction? PeerJ, 3, e1433. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.1433</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Hörnig, M. K., Kenning, M., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2021). More than one way to smell ashore-Evolution of the olfactory pathway in terrestrial malacostracan crustaceans. Arthropod Structure and Development.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Sandeman, R. E., Sandeman, D. C., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2010). Brain architecture of the largest living land arthropod, the giant robber crab Birgus latro (Crustacea, Anomura, Coenobitidae): Evidence for a prominent central olfactory pathway? Frontiers in Zoology, 7(1), 1-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Sombke, A., Seefluth, F., Kenning, M., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2012). Comparative brain architecture of the European shore crab Carcinus maenas (Brachyura) and the common hermit crab Pagurus bernhardus (Anomura) with notes on other marine hermit crabs. Cell and Tissue Research, 348(1), 47-69. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-012-1353-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladislav, R., Ladislav, Š., Akira, M., Mirko, S., Yoonseong, P., &amp; Dušan, Ž. (2015). Orcokinin-like immunoreactivity in central neurons innervating the salivary glands and hindgut of ixodid ticks. Cell and Tissue Research, 360(2), 209-222. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-015-2121-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langworthy, K., Helluy, S., Benton, J., &amp; Beltz, B. (1997). Amines and peptides in the brain of the American lobster: Immunocytochemical localization patterns and implications for brain function. Cell and Tissue Research, 288(1), 191-206. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004410050806</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, F., Lindsey, J. W., Marin, E. C., Otto, N., Dreher, M., Dempsey, G., Stark, I., Bates, A. S., Pleijzier, M. W., Schlegel, P., Nern, A., Takemura, S., Eckstein, N., Yang, T., Francis, A., Braun, A., Parekh, R., Costa, M., Scheffer, L. K., … Rubin, G. M. (2020). The connectome of the adult Drosophila mushroom body provides insights into function. eLife, 9, e62576. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.62576</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, L., Pulver, S. R., Kelley, W. P., Thirumalai, V., Sweedler, J. V., &amp; Marder, E. (2002). Orcokinin peptides in developing and adult crustacean stomatogastric nervous systems and pericardial organs. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 444(3), 227-244. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10139</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lozano-Fernandez, J., Carton, R., Tanner, A. R., Puttick, M. N., Blaxter, M., Vinther, J., Olesen, J., Giribet, G., Edgecombe, G. D., &amp; Pisani, D. (2016). A molecular palaeobiological exploration of arthropod terrestrialization. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 371(1699), 20150133. https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2015.0133</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin, J. P., Beyerlein, A., Dacks, A. M., Reisenman, C. E., Riffell, J. A., Lei, H., &amp; Hildebrand, J. G. (2011). The neurobiology of insect olfaction: Sensory processing in a comparative context. Progress in Neurobiology, 95(3), 427-447. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2011.09.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maza, F. J., Sztarker, J., Shkedy, A., Peszano, V. N., Locatelli, F. F., &amp; Delorenzi, A. (2016). Context-dependent memory traces in the crab's mushroom bodies: Functional support for a common origin of high-order memory centers. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 113(49), E7957-E7965. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1612418113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellon, D., &amp; Alones, V. (1993). Cellular organization and growth-related plasticity of the crayfish olfactory midbrain. Microscopy Research and Technique, 24(3), 231-259. https://doi.org/10.1002/jemt.1070240304</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellon, D., &amp; Munger, S. D. (1990). Nontopographic projection of olfactory sensory neurons in the crayfish brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 296(2), 253-262. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902960205</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercier, A. J., Friedrich, R., &amp; Boldt, M. (2003). Physiological functions of FMRFamide-like peptides (FLPs) in crustaceans. Microscopy Research and Technique, 60(3), 313-324. https://doi.org/10.1002/jemt.10270</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misof, B., Liu, S., Meusemann, K., Peters, R. S., Donath, A., Mayer, C., Frandsen, P. B., Ware, J., Flouri, T., Beutel, R. G., Niehuis, O., Petersen, M., Izquierdo-Carrasco, F., Wappler, T., Rust, J., Aberer, A. J., Aspöck, U., Aspöck, H., Bartel, D., … Zhou, X. (2014). Phylogenomics resolves the timing and pattern of insect evolution. Science, 346(6210), 763-767. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1257570</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mombaerts, P. (2006). Axonal wiring in the mouse olfactory system. Annual Review of Cell and Developmental Biology, 22(1), 713-737. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.cellbio.21.012804.093915</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nässel, D. R., &amp; Homberg, U. (2006). Neuropeptides in interneurons of the insect brain. Cell and Tissue Research, 326(1), 1-24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-006-0210-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ollivaux, P. (2002). Enkephalinergic control of the secretory activity of neurons producing stereoisomers of crustacean hyperglycemic hormone in the eyestalk of the crayfish Orconectes limosus-Ollivaux-2002. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 444, 1-9. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/cne.1426?sid=nlm%3Apubmed</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orona, E., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1992). Physiological and pharmacological evidence for histamine as a neurotransmitter in the olfactory CNS of the spiny lobster. Brain Research, 590(1-2), 136-143. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(92)91089-W</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orona, E., Batelle, B. A., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1990). Immunohistochemical and biochemical evidence for the putative inhibitory neurotransmitters histamine and GABA in lobster olfactory lobes. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 294(4), 633-646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polanska, M. A., Kirchhoff, T., Dircksen, H., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2020). Functional morphology of the primary olfactory centers in the brain of the hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomala, Coenobitidae). Cell and Tissue Research, 380(3), 449-467. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03199-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polanska, M. A., Tuchina, O., Agricola, H., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2012). Neuropeptide complexity in the crustacean central olfactory pathway: Immunolocalization of A-type allatostatins and RFamide-like peptides in the brain of a terrestrial hermit crab. Molecular Brain, 5(1), 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-6606-5-29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puñal, V. M., Ahmed, M., Thornton-Kolbe, E. M., &amp; Clowney, E. J. (2021). Untangling the wires: Development of sparse, distributed connectivity in the mushroom body calyx. Cell and Tissue Research, 383(1), 91-112. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03386-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak, J. (2013). Exploring brain connectivity in insect model systems of learning and memory. In Invertebrate learning and memory (pp. 26-40). Elsevier. http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/B9780124158238000046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak, J., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2018). Olfactory microcircuits in Drosophila melanogaster. In Handbook of brain microcircuits (2nd ed., pp. 361-367). Oxford University Press. https://pure.mpg.de/pubman/faces/ViewItemOverviewPage.jsp?itemId=item_2565272</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak, J., Talarico, G., Ruiz, S., Arnold, C., Cantera, R., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2016). Synaptic circuitry of identified neurons in the antennal lobe of Drosophila melanogaster. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524(9), 1920-1956. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23966</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saetan, J., Senarai, T., Tamtin, M., Weerachatyanukul, W., Chavadej, J., Hanna, P. J., Parhar, I., Sobhon, P., &amp; Sretarugsa, P. (2013). Histological organization of the central nervous system and distribution of a gonadotropin-releasing hormone-like peptide in the blue crab, Portunus pelagicus. Cell and Tissue Research, 353(3), 493-510. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-013-1650-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Denburg, J. L. (1976). The central projections of chemoreceptor axons in the crayfish revealed by axoplasmic transport. Brain Research, 115(3), 492-496.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., Kenning, M., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2014). Adaptive trends in malacostracan brain form and function related to behaviour. In C. D. Derby &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.) The natural history of crustacea. Vol. 3: Nervous systems and their control of behaviour (pp. 11-48). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Luff, S. E. (1973). The structural organization of glomerular neuropile in the olfactory and accessory lobes of an Australian freshwater crayfish, Cherax destructor. Zeitschrift für Zellforschung und Mikroskopische Anatomie, 142, 37-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Mellon, D. (2002). Olfactory centers in the brain of freshwater crayfish. In The crustacean nervous system. Wiese K (Ed.), (pp. 386-404). Springer-Verlag.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Sandeman, R. E. (1994). Electrical responses and synaptic connections of giant serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in crayfish olfactory and accessory lobes. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 341(1), 130-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., Sandeman, R. E., &amp; Aitken, A. R. (1988). Atlas of serotonin-containing neurons in the optic lobes and brain of the crayfish, Cherax destructor. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 269(4), 465-478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., Sandeman, R. E., Derby, C. D., &amp; Schmidt, M. (1992). Morphology of the brain of crayfish, crabs, and spiny lobsters: A common nomenclature for homologous structures. Biological Bulletin, 183, 304-326. https://doi.org/10.2307/1542217</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, R. E., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (1987). Serotonin-like immunoreactivity of giant olfactory interneurons in the crayfish brain. Brain Research, 403(2), 371-374. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(87)90078-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, R. E., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Watson, A. H. D. (1990). Substance P antibody reveals homologous neurons with axon terminals among somata in the crayfish and crab brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 294(4), 569-582. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902940405</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, R. E., Watson, A. H. D., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (1995). Ultrastructure of the synaptic terminals of the dorsal giant serotonin-IR neuron and deutocerebral commissure interneurons in the accessory and olfactory lobes of the crayfish. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 361(4), 617-632. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903610406</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schachtner, J., Schmidt, M., &amp; Homberg, U. (2005). Organization and evolutionary trends of primary olfactory brain centers in Tetraconata (Crustacea+Hexapoda). Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 34(3), 257-299. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2005.04.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scheffer, L. K., Xu, C. S., Januszewski, M., Lu, Z., Takemura, S., Hayworth, K. J., Huang, G. B., Shinomiya, K., Maitlin-Shepard, J., Berg, S., Clements, J., Hubbard, P. M., Katz, W. T., Umayam, L., Zhao, T., Ackerman, D., Blakely, T., Bogovic, J., Dolafi, T., … Plaza, S. M. (2020). A connectome and analysis of the adult Drosophila central brain. eLife, 9, e57443. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.57443</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M. (1997a). Distribution of centrifugal neurons targeting the soma clusters of the olfactory midbrain among decapod crustaceans. Brain Research, 752(1-2), 15-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M. (1997b). Distribution of presumptive chemosensory afferents with FMRFamide-or substance P-like immunoreactivity in decapod crustaceans. Brain Research, 746(1-2), 71-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M. (2007). The olfactory pathway of decapod crustaceans-An invertebrate model for life-long neurogenesis. Chemical Senses, 32(4), 365-384. https://doi.org/10.1093/chemse/bjm008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1992). Antennular projections to the midbrain of the spiny lobster. II. sensory innervation of the olfactory lobe. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 318(3), 291-303. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903180306</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1994). Descending neurons with dopamine-like or with substance P/FMRFamide-like immunoreactivity target the somata of olfactory interneurons in the brain of the spiny lobster, Panulirus argus. Cell and Tissue Research, 278(2), 337-352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1996). Processing of antennular input in the brain of the spiny lobster, Panulirus argus. II. The olfactory pathway. Journal of Comparative Physiology A: Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 178(5), 605-628. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00227375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1997). Immunocytochemical analysis of glomerular regionalization and neuronal diversity in the olfactory deutocerebrum of the spiny lobster. Cell and Tissue Research, 287(3), 541-563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Mellon, D. (2011). Neuronal processing of chemical information in crustaceans. In T. Breithaupt &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.), Chemical communication in crustaceans (pp. 123-147). Springer. http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-0-387-77101-4_7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scholz, N. L., Chang, E. S., Graubard, K., &amp; Truman, J. W. (1998). The NO/cGMP pathway and the development of neural networks in postembryonic lobsters. Journal of Neurobiology, 34(3), 208-226. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-4695(19980215)34:3&lt;208::AID-NEU2&gt;3.0.CO;2-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schürmann, F.-W., Sandeman, R., &amp; Sandeman, D. (1991). Dense-core vesicles and non-synaptic exocytosis in the central body of the crayfish brain. Cell and Tissue Research, 265(3), 493-501. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00340872</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwentner, M., Combosch, D. J., Pakes Nelson, J., &amp; Giribet, G. (2017). A Phylogenomic Solution to the Origin of Insects by Resolving Crustacean-Hexapod Relationships. Current Biology, 27(12), 1818-1824. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2017.05.040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinakevitch, I., Bjorklund, G. R., Newbern, J. M., Gerkin, R. C., &amp; Smith, B. H. (2017). Comparative study of chemical neuroanatomy of the olfactory neuropil in mouse, honey bee, and human. Biological Cybernetics, 112, 1-14. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00422-017-0728-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skiebe, P. (1999). Allatostatin-like immunoreactivity in the stomatogastric nervous system and the pericardial organs of the crab Cancer pagurus, the lobster Homarus americanus, and the crayfish Cherax destructor and Procambarus clarkii. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 403(1), 85-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke, A., Harzsch, S., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2011). Organization of Deutocerebral Neuropils and Olfactory Behavior in the Centipede Scutigera coleoptrata (Linnaeus, 1758) (Myriapoda: Chilopoda). Chemical Senses, 36(1), 43-61. https://doi.org/10.1093/chemse/bjq096</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stangier, J., Hilbich, C., Burdzik, S., &amp; Keller, R. (1992). Orcokinin: A novel myotropic peptide from the nervous system of the crayfish, Orconectes limosus. Peptides, 13(5), 859-864. https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(92)90041-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stay, B., Chan, K. K., &amp; Woodhead, A. P. (1992). Allatostatin-immunoreactive neurons projecting to the corpora allata of adult Diploptera punctata. Cell and Tissue Research, 270(1), 15-23. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00381875</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stay, B., &amp; Tobe, S. S. (2007). The role of allatostatins in juvenile hormone synthesis in insects and crustaceans. Annual Review of Entomology, 52, 277-299. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.ento.51.110104.151050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan, J. M., Benton, J. L., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (2007). Adult neurogenesis: A common strategy across diverse species. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 500(3), 574-584. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21187</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szyszka, P., &amp; Galizia, C. G. (2015). Olfaction in insects. In R. L. Doty (Ed.), Handbook of olfaction and gustation (pp. 531-546). John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118971758.ch22</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeuchi, H., &amp; Sakano, H. (2014). Neural map formation in the mouse olfactory system. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 71(16), 3049-3057. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-014-1597-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuchina, O., Koczan, S., Harzsch, S., Rybak, J., Wolff, G., Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2015). Central projections of antennular chemosensory and mechanosensory afferents in the brain of the terrestrial hermit crab (Coenobita clypeatus; Coenobitidae, Anomura). Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 9(94), 1-13. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2015.00094</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Utting, M., Agricola, H.-J., Sandeman, R., &amp; Sandeman, D. (2000). Central complex in the brain of crayfish and its possible homology with that of insects. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 416(2), 245-261. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(20000110)416:2&lt;245::AID-CNE9&gt;3.0.CO;2-A</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vitzthum, H., Homberg, U., &amp; Agricola, H. (1996). Distribution of Dip-allatostatin I-like immunoreactivity in the brain of the locust Schistocerca gregaria with detailed analysis of immunostaining in the central complex. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 369(3), 419-437. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19960603)369:3&lt;419::AID-CNE7&gt;3.0.CO;2-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wachowiak, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1997). Dual inhibitory pathways mediated by GABA-and histaminergic interneurons in the lobster olfactory lobe. Journal of Comparative Physiology A: Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 180(4), 357-372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wachowiak, M., &amp; Cohen, L. B. (1999). Presynaptic inhibition of primary olfactory afferents mediated by different mechanisms in lobster and turtle. Journal of Neuroscience, 19(20), 8808-8817. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.19-20-08808.1999</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wachowiak, M., Diebel, C. E., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1997). Local interneurons define functionally distinct regions within lobster olfactory glomeruli. Journal of Experimental Biology, 200(6), 989-1001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, C. H., &amp; Christie, A. E. (2010). Distribution of C-type allatostatin (C-AST)-like immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the copepod Calanus finmarchicus. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 167(2), 252-260. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2010.03.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, R. I. (2013). Early olfactory processing in Drosophila: Mechanisms and principles. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 36(1), 217-241. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-062111-150533</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wipfler, B., Letsch, H., Frandsen, P. B., Kapli, P., Mayer, C., Bartel, D., Buckley, T. R., Donath, A., Edgerly-Rooks, J. S., Fujita, M., Liu, S., Machida, R., Mashimo, Y., Misof, B., Niehuis, O., Peters, R. S., Petersen, M., Podsiadlowski, L., Schütte, K., … Simon, S. (2019). Evolutionary history of Polyneoptera and its implications for our understanding of early winged insects. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 116(8), 3024-3029. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1817794116</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wittfoth, C., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2018). Adult neurogenesis in the central olfactory pathway of dendrobranchiate and caridean shrimps: New insights into the evolution of the deutocerebral proliferative system in reptant decapods. Developmental Neurobiology, 78(8), 757-774. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22596</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood, D. E., Nishikawa, M., &amp; Derby, C. D. (1996). Proctolinlike immunoreactivity and identified neurosecretory cells as putative substrates for modulation of courtship display behavior in the blue crab, Callinectes sapidus. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 368(1), 153-163. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19960422)368:1&lt;153::AID-CNE10&gt;3.0.CO;2-S</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodhead, A. P., Stoltzman, C. A., &amp; Stay, B. (1992). Allatostatins in the nerves of the antennal pulsatile organ muscle of the cockroach Diploptera punctata. Archives of Insect Biochemistry and Physiology, 20(4), 253-263. https://doi.org/10.1002/arch.940200403</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamanaka, N., Roller, L., Zitňan, D., Satake, H., Mizoguchi, A., Kataoka, H., &amp; Tanaka, Y. (2011). Bombyx orcokinins are brain-gut peptides involved in the neuronal regulation of ecdysteroidogenesis. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 519(2), 238-246. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22517</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuda-Kamatani, Y., &amp; Yasuda, A. (2000). Identification of orcokinin gene-related peptides in the brain of the crayfish Procambarus clarkii by the Combination of MALDI-TOF and on-line capillary HPLC/Q-Tof mass spectrometries and molecular cloning. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 118(1), 161-172. https://doi.org/10.1006/gcen.1999.7453</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuda-Kamatani, Y., &amp; Yasuda, A. (2006). Characteristic expression patterns of allatostatin-like peptide, FMRFamide-related peptide, orcokinin, tachykinin-related peptide, and SIFamide in the olfactory system of crayfish Procambarus clarkii. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 496(1), 135-147. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.20903</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin, G.-L., Yang, J.-S., Cao, J.-X., &amp; Yang, W.-J. (2006). Molecular cloning and characterization of FGLamide allatostatin gene from the prawn, Macrobrachium rosenbergii. Peptides, 27(6), 1241-1250. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2005.11.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoon, J. G., &amp; Stay, B. (1995). Immunocytochemical localization of Diploptera punctata allatostatin-like peptide in Drosophila melanogaster. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 363(3), 475-488. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903630310</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zajac, M., &amp; Mollereau, J. (2006). RFamide peptides. Introduction. Peptides, 27(5), 941-942. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2005.12.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng, Z., Lauritzen, J. S., Perlman, E., Robinson, C. G., Nichols, M., Milkie, D., Torrens, O., Price, J., Fisher, C. B., Sharifi, N., Calle-Schuler, S. A., Kmecova, L., Ali, I. J., Karsh, B., Trautman, E. T., Bogovic, J. A., Hanslovsky, P., Jefferis, G. S. X. E., Kazhdan, M., … Bock, D. D. (2018). A complete electron microscopy volume of the brain of adult Drosophila melanogaster. Cell, 174(3), 730-743. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2018.06.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng, Z., Li, F., Fisher, C., Ali, I. J., Sharifi, N., Calle-Schuler, S., Hsu, J., Masoodpanah, N., Kmecova, L., Kazimiers, T., Perlman, E., Nichols, M., Li, P. H., Jain, V., &amp; Bock, D. D. (2020). Structured sampling of olfactory input by the fly mushroom body. BioRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.04.17.047167</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34843626</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>530</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Local olfactory interneurons provide the basis for neurochemical regionalization of olfactory glomeruli in crustaceans.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1399</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1422</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1399-1422</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25283</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The primary olfactory centers of metazoans as diverse as arthropods and mammals consist of an array of fields of dense synaptic neuropil, the olfactory glomeruli. However, the neurochemical structure of crustacean olfactory glomeruli is largely understudied when compared to the insects. We analyzed the glomerular architecture in selected species of hermit crabs using immunohistochemistry against presynaptic proteins, the neuropeptides orcokinin, RFamide and allatostatin, and the biogenic amine serotonin. Our study reveals an unexpected level of structural complexity, unmatched by what is found in the insect olfactory glomeruli. Peptidergic and aminergic interneurons provide the structural basis for a regionalization of the crustacean glomeruli into longitudinal and concentric compartments. Our data suggest that local olfactory interneurons take a central computational role in modulating the information transfer from olfactory sensory neurons to projection neurons within the glomeruli. Furthermore, we found yet unknown neuronal elements mediating lateral inhibitory interactions across the glomerular array that may play a central role in modulating the transfer of sensory input to the output neurons through presynaptic inhibition. Our study is another step in understanding the function of crustacean olfactory glomeruli as highly complex units of local olfactory processing.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. The Journal of Comparative Neurology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Harzsch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Steffen</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8645-3320</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology and Evolutionary Biology, Zoological Institute and Museum, University of Greifswald, Greifswald, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Evolutionary Neuroethology, Max-Planck-Institute for Chemical Ecology, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dircksen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heinrich</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Zoology, Stockholm University, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hansson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bill S</ForeName>
            <Initials>BS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Evolutionary Neuroethology, Max-Planck-Institute for Chemical Ecology, Jena, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D033381" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anomura</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007395" MajorTopicYN="N">Interneurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008322" MajorTopicYN="N">Mammals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019581" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropil</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009830" MajorTopicYN="N">Olfactory Bulb</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009833" MajorTopicYN="N">Olfactory Pathways</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018034" MajorTopicYN="Y">Olfactory Receptor Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Coenobita clypeatus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Crustacea</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Pagurus bernhardus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">neuropeptides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">olfactory glomeruli</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">olfactory interneurons</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">olfactory system</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>26</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34843626</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25283</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonsen, B. L., &amp; Paul, D. H. (2001). Serotonergic and octopaminergic systems in the squat lobster Munida quadrispina (anomura, galatheidae). The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 439(4), 450-468. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.1362</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bates, A. S., Schlegel, P., Roberts, R. J. V., Drummond, N., Tamimi, I. F. M., Turnbull, R., Zhao, X., Marin, E. C., Popovici, P. D., Dhawan, S., Jamasb, A., Javier, A., Serratosa Capdevila, L., Li, F., Rubin, G. M., Waddell, S., Bock, D. D., Costa, M., &amp; Jefferis, G. S. X. E. (2020). Complete connectomic reconstruction of olfactory projection neurons in the fly brain. Current Biology, 30(16), 3183-3199.e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2020.06.042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltz, B. S. (1999). Distribution and functional anatomy of amine-containing neurons in decapod crustaceans. Microscopy Research and Technique, 44(2-3), 105-120. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19990115/01)44:2/3&lt;105::AID-JEMT5&gt;3.0.CO;2-K</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltz, B. S., Kordas, K., Lee, M. M., Long, J. B., Benton, J. L., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (2003). Ecological, evolutionary, and functional correlates of sensilla number and glomerular density in the olfactory system of decapod crustaceans. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 455(2), 260-269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beltz, B. S., Pontes, M., Helluy, S. M., &amp; Kravitz, E. A. (1990). Patterns of appearance of serotonin and proctolin immunoreactivities in the developing nervous system of the American lobster. Journal of Neurobiology, 21(4), 521-542. https://doi.org/10.1002/neu.480210402</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benton, J. L., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (2007). Nitric oxide in the crustacean brain: Regulation of neurogenesis and morphogenesis in the developing olfactory pathway. Developmental Dynamics, 236(11), 3047-3060. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvdy.21340</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaustein, D. N., Derby, C. D., Simmons, R. B., &amp; Beall, A. C. (1988). Structure of the brain and medulla terminalis of the spiny lobster Panulirus argus and the crayfish Procambarus clarkii, with an emphasis on olfactory centers. Journal of Crustacean Biology, 8, 493-519.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bungart, D., Dircksen, H., &amp; Keller, R. (1994). Quantitative determination and distribution of the myotropic neuropeptide orcokinin in the nervous system of astacidean crustaceans. Peptides, 15(3), 393-400. https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(94)90194-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bungart, D., Hilbich, C., Dircksen, H., &amp; Keller, R. (1995). Occurrence of analogues of the myotropic neuropeptide orcokinin in the shore crab, Carcinus maenas: Evidence for a novel neuropeptide family. Peptides, 16(1), 67-72. https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(94)00145-v</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cape, S. S., Rehm, K. J., Ma, M., Marder, E., &amp; Li, L. (2008). Mass spectral comparison of the neuropeptide complement of the stomatogastric ganglion and brain in the adult and embryonic lobster, Homarus americanus. Journal of Neurochemistry, 105(3), 690-702. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-4159.2007.05154.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E. (2014). Expansion of the Litopenaeus vannamei and Penaeus monodon peptidomes using transcriptome shotgun assembly sequence data. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 206, 235-254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2014.04.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E. (2016). Expansion of the neuropeptidome of the globally invasive marine crab Carcinus maenas. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 235, 150-169. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2016.05.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E., &amp; Chi, M. (2015). Neuropeptide discovery in the Araneae (Arthropoda, Chelicerata, Arachnida): Elucidation of true spider peptidomes using that of the Western black widow as a reference. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 213, 90-109. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2015.02.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E., Sousa, G. L., Rus, S., Smith, C. M., Towle, D. W., Hartline, D. K., &amp; Dickinson, P. S. (2008). Identification of A-type allatostatins possessing −YXFGI/Vamide carboxy-termini from the nervous system of the copepod crustacean Calanus finmarchicus. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 155(3), 526-533. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2007.09.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie, A. E., Stemmler, E. A., &amp; Dickinson, P. S. (2010). Crustacean neuropeptides. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences: CMLS, 67(24), 4135-4169. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-010-0482-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derby, C. D., Kozma, M. T., Senatore, A., &amp; Schmidt, M. (2016). Molecular mechanisms of reception and perireception in crustacean chemoreception: A comparative review. Chemical Senses, 1-18. https://doi.org/10.1093/chemse/bjw057</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derby, C. D., &amp; Weissburg, M. J. (2014). The chemical senses and chemosensory ecology of crustaceans. In C. D. Derby &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.), Crustacean nervous systems and their control of behavior (pp. 263-292). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dircksen, H., Burdzik, S., Sauter, A., &amp; Keller, R. (2000). Two orcokinins and the novel octapeptide orcomyotropin in the hindgut of the crayfish Orconectes limosus: Identified myostimulatory neuropeptides originating together in neurones of the terminal abdominal ganglion. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 203(Pt 18), 2807-2818.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dircksen, H., Neupert, S., Predel, R., Verleyen, P., Huybrechts, J., Strauss, J., Hauser, F., Stafflinger, E., Schneider, M., Pauwels, K., Schoofs, L., &amp; Grimmelikhuijzen, C. J. P. (2011). Genomics, transcriptomics, and peptidomics of Daphnia pulex Neuropeptides and protein hormones. Journal of Proteome Research, 10(10), 4478-4504. https://doi.org/10.1021/pr200284e</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dircksen, H., Skiebe, P., Abel, B., Agricola, H., Buchner, K., Muren, J. E., &amp; Nässel, D. R. (1999). Structure, distribution, and biological activity of novel members of the allatostatin family in the crayfish Orconectes limosus. Peptides, 20(6), 695-712. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0196-9781(99)00052-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dockray, G. (2004). The expanding family of -RFamide peptides and their effects on feeding behaviour. Experimental Physiology, 89(3), 229-235. https://doi.org/10.1113/expphysiol.2004.027169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duve, H., Johnsen, A. H., Scott, A. G., &amp; Thorpe, A. (2002). Allatostatins of the tiger prawn, Penaeus monodon (Crustacea: Penaeidea). Peptides, 23(6), 1039-1051. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0196-9781(02)00035-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahrbach, S. E., &amp; Van Nest, B. N. (2016). Synapsin-based approaches to brain plasticity in adult social insects. Current Opinion in Insect Science, 18, 27-34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cois.2016.08.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahrenbach, W. (1979). The brain of the horseshoe crab (Limulus polyphemus). III. Cellular and synaptic organization of the corpora pedunculata. Tissue &amp; Cell, 11, 163-199. https://doi.org/10.1016/0040-8166(79)90016-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuscà, D., &amp; Kloppenburg, P. (2021). Odor processing in the cockroach antennal lobe-The network components. Cell and Tissue Research, 383(1), 59-73. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03387-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia, C. G. (2014). Olfactory coding in the insect brain: Data and conjectures. European Journal of Neuroscience, 39(11), 1784-1795. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.12558</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galizia, C. G., &amp; Rössler, W. (2010). Parallel olfactory systems in insects: Anatomy and function. Annual Review of Entomology, 55(1), 399-420. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-ento-112408-085442</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Groh, C., &amp; Rössler, W. (2020). Analysis of synaptic microcircuits in the mushroom bodies of the honeybee. Insects, 11(1), 43. https://doi.org/10.3390/insects11010043</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallberg, E., &amp; Skog, M. (2011). Chemosensory sensilla in crustaceans. In T. Breithaupt &amp; M. Thiel, (Eds.), Chemical communication in crustaceans (pp. 103-21). Springer.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson, B. S., &amp; Anton, S. (2000). Function and morphology of the antennal lobe: New developments. Annual Review of Entomology, 45(1), 203-231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansson, B. S., Harzsch, S., Knaden, M., &amp; Stensmyr, M. C. (2011). The neural and behavioral basis of chemical communication in terrestrial crustaceans. In T. Breithaupt &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.), Chemical communication in crustaceans (pp. 149-173). Springer.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S. (2002). The phylogenetic significance of crustacean optic neuropils and chiasmata: A re-examination. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 453(1), 10-21. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2008). Brain architecture in the terrestrial hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomura, Coenobitidae), a crustacean with a good aerial sense of smell. BMC Neuroscience, 9(1), 58. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2202-9-58</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Krieger, J. (2018). Crustacean olfactory systems: A comparative review and a crustacean perspective on insect olfactory systems. Progress in Neurobiology, 161, 23-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Krieger, J. (2021). Genealogical relationships of mushroom bodies, hemiellipsoid bodies, and their afferent pathways in the brains of Pancrustacea: Recent progress and open questions. Arthropod Structure and Development, 65, 101100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., Miller, J., Benton, J. L., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (1999). From embryo to adult: Persistent neurogenesis and apoptotic cell death shape the lobster deutocerebrum. The Journal of Neuroscience, 19(9), 3472-3485.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., Miller, J., Benton, J. L., Dawirs, R. R., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (1998). Neurogenesis in the thoracic neuromeres of two crustaceans with different types of metamorphic development. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 201(17), 2465-2479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helluy, S., Sandeman, R. E., Beltz, B. S., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (1993). Comparative brain ontogeny of the crayfish and clawed lobster: Implications of direct and larval development. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 335(3), 343-354. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903350305</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer, S., Dircksen, H., Tollbäck, P., &amp; Homberg, U. (2005). Novel insect orcokinins: Characterization and neuronal distribution in the brains of selected dicondylian insects. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 490(1), 57-71. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.20650</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer, S., &amp; Homberg, U. (2006a). Evidence for a role of orcokinin-related peptides in the circadian clock controlling locomotor activity of the cockroach Leucophaea maderae. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 209(Pt 14), 2794-2803. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.02307</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer, S., &amp; Homberg, U. (2006b). Orcokinin immunoreactivity in the accessory medulla of the cockroach Leucophaea maderae. Cell and Tissue Research, 325(3), 589-600. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-006-0155-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huybrechts, J., Nusbaum, M. P., Bosch, L. V., Baggerman, G., De Loof, A., &amp; Schoofs, L. (2003). Neuropeptidomic analysis of the brain and thoracic ganglion from the Jonah crab. Cancer borealis. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 308(3), 535-544. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0006-291x(03)01426-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imai, T. (2014). Construction of functional neuronal circuitry in the olfactory bulb. Seminars in Cell &amp; Developmental Biology, 35, 180-188. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.semcdb.2014.07.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson, K. U. I. (1991). Identification of different types of serotonin-like immunoreactive olfactory interneurons in four infraorders of decapod crustaceans. Cell and Tissue Research, 264(2), 357-362. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00313974</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson, K. U. I., Lundquist, C. T., Hallberg, E., &amp; Nässel, D. R. (1999). Tachykinin-related neuropeptide in the crayfish olfactory midbrain. Cell and Tissue Research, 296(2), 405-415. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004410051300</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson, K. U. I., &amp; Mellon, D. (1998). Nitric oxide as a putative messenger molecule in the crayfish olfactory midbrain. Brain Research, 807(1), 237-242. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0006-8993(98)00826-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klagges, B. R., Heimbeck, G., Godenschwege, T. A., Hofbauer, A., Pflugfelder, G. O., Reifegerste, R., Reisch, D., Schaupp, M., Buchner, S., &amp; Buchner, E. (1996). Invertebrate synapsins: A single gene codes for several isoforms in Drosophila. The Journal of Neuroscience, 16(10), 3154-3165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobierski, L. A., Beltz, B. S., Trimmer, B. A., &amp; Kravitz, E. A. (1987). FMRFamidelike peptides of homarus americanus: Distribution, immunocytochemical mapping, and ultrastructural localization in terminal varicosities. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 266(1), 1-15. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902660102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotsyuba, E., &amp; Dyachuk, V. (2021). Localization of neurons expressing choline acetyltransferase, serotonin and/or FMRFamide in the central nervous system of the decapod shore crab Hemigrapsus sanguineus. Cell and Tissue Research, 383(3), 959-977. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03309-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotsyuba, E., Dyuizen, I., &amp; Lamash, N. (2010). Stress-induced changes in the nitric oxide system of shore crabs living under different ecological conditions. Russian Journal of Marine Biology, 36, 201-208. https://doi.org/10.1134/S1063074010030065</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotsyuba, E. P. (2012). Distribution of neurons containing catecholamines in brain of hermit crab Pagurus middendorffii and of king crab Paralithodes camtschaticus (Anomura, Decapoda). Cell and Tissue Biology, 6(4), 376-382. https://doi.org/10.1134/S1990519x12040074</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreissl, S., Strasser, C., &amp; Galizia, C. G. (2010). Allatostatin immunoreactivity in the honeybee brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 518(9), 1391-1417. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22343</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kress, T., Harzsch, S., &amp; Dircksen, H. (2016). Neuroanatomy of the optic ganglia and central brain of the water flea Daphnia magna (Crustacea, Cladocera). Cell and Tissue Research, 363(3), 649-677. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-015-2279-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Braun, P., Rivera, N. T., Schubart, C. D., Müller, C. H. G., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2015). Comparative analyses of olfactory systems in terrestrial crabs (Brachyura): Evidence for aerial olfaction? PeerJ, 3, e1433. https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.1433</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Hörnig, M. K., Kenning, M., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2021). More than one way to smell ashore-Evolution of the olfactory pathway in terrestrial malacostracan crustaceans. Arthropod Structure and Development.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Sandeman, R. E., Sandeman, D. C., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2010). Brain architecture of the largest living land arthropod, the giant robber crab Birgus latro (Crustacea, Anomura, Coenobitidae): Evidence for a prominent central olfactory pathway? Frontiers in Zoology, 7(1), 1-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Sombke, A., Seefluth, F., Kenning, M., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2012). Comparative brain architecture of the European shore crab Carcinus maenas (Brachyura) and the common hermit crab Pagurus bernhardus (Anomura) with notes on other marine hermit crabs. Cell and Tissue Research, 348(1), 47-69. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-012-1353-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladislav, R., Ladislav, Š., Akira, M., Mirko, S., Yoonseong, P., &amp; Dušan, Ž. (2015). Orcokinin-like immunoreactivity in central neurons innervating the salivary glands and hindgut of ixodid ticks. Cell and Tissue Research, 360(2), 209-222. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-015-2121-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langworthy, K., Helluy, S., Benton, J., &amp; Beltz, B. (1997). Amines and peptides in the brain of the American lobster: Immunocytochemical localization patterns and implications for brain function. Cell and Tissue Research, 288(1), 191-206. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004410050806</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, F., Lindsey, J. W., Marin, E. C., Otto, N., Dreher, M., Dempsey, G., Stark, I., Bates, A. S., Pleijzier, M. W., Schlegel, P., Nern, A., Takemura, S., Eckstein, N., Yang, T., Francis, A., Braun, A., Parekh, R., Costa, M., Scheffer, L. K., … Rubin, G. M. (2020). The connectome of the adult Drosophila mushroom body provides insights into function. eLife, 9, e62576. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.62576</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, L., Pulver, S. R., Kelley, W. P., Thirumalai, V., Sweedler, J. V., &amp; Marder, E. (2002). Orcokinin peptides in developing and adult crustacean stomatogastric nervous systems and pericardial organs. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 444(3), 227-244. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10139</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lozano-Fernandez, J., Carton, R., Tanner, A. R., Puttick, M. N., Blaxter, M., Vinther, J., Olesen, J., Giribet, G., Edgecombe, G. D., &amp; Pisani, D. (2016). A molecular palaeobiological exploration of arthropod terrestrialization. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 371(1699), 20150133. https://doi.org/10.1098/rstb.2015.0133</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin, J. P., Beyerlein, A., Dacks, A. M., Reisenman, C. E., Riffell, J. A., Lei, H., &amp; Hildebrand, J. G. (2011). The neurobiology of insect olfaction: Sensory processing in a comparative context. Progress in Neurobiology, 95(3), 427-447. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pneurobio.2011.09.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maza, F. J., Sztarker, J., Shkedy, A., Peszano, V. N., Locatelli, F. F., &amp; Delorenzi, A. (2016). Context-dependent memory traces in the crab's mushroom bodies: Functional support for a common origin of high-order memory centers. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 113(49), E7957-E7965. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1612418113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellon, D., &amp; Alones, V. (1993). Cellular organization and growth-related plasticity of the crayfish olfactory midbrain. Microscopy Research and Technique, 24(3), 231-259. https://doi.org/10.1002/jemt.1070240304</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellon, D., &amp; Munger, S. D. (1990). Nontopographic projection of olfactory sensory neurons in the crayfish brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 296(2), 253-262. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902960205</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercier, A. J., Friedrich, R., &amp; Boldt, M. (2003). Physiological functions of FMRFamide-like peptides (FLPs) in crustaceans. Microscopy Research and Technique, 60(3), 313-324. https://doi.org/10.1002/jemt.10270</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misof, B., Liu, S., Meusemann, K., Peters, R. S., Donath, A., Mayer, C., Frandsen, P. B., Ware, J., Flouri, T., Beutel, R. G., Niehuis, O., Petersen, M., Izquierdo-Carrasco, F., Wappler, T., Rust, J., Aberer, A. J., Aspöck, U., Aspöck, H., Bartel, D., … Zhou, X. (2014). Phylogenomics resolves the timing and pattern of insect evolution. Science, 346(6210), 763-767. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1257570</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mombaerts, P. (2006). Axonal wiring in the mouse olfactory system. Annual Review of Cell and Developmental Biology, 22(1), 713-737. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.cellbio.21.012804.093915</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nässel, D. R., &amp; Homberg, U. (2006). Neuropeptides in interneurons of the insect brain. Cell and Tissue Research, 326(1), 1-24. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-006-0210-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ollivaux, P. (2002). Enkephalinergic control of the secretory activity of neurons producing stereoisomers of crustacean hyperglycemic hormone in the eyestalk of the crayfish Orconectes limosus-Ollivaux-2002. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 444, 1-9. https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/cne.1426?sid=nlm%3Apubmed</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orona, E., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1992). Physiological and pharmacological evidence for histamine as a neurotransmitter in the olfactory CNS of the spiny lobster. Brain Research, 590(1-2), 136-143. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(92)91089-W</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orona, E., Batelle, B. A., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1990). Immunohistochemical and biochemical evidence for the putative inhibitory neurotransmitters histamine and GABA in lobster olfactory lobes. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 294(4), 633-646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polanska, M. A., Kirchhoff, T., Dircksen, H., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2020). Functional morphology of the primary olfactory centers in the brain of the hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomala, Coenobitidae). Cell and Tissue Research, 380(3), 449-467. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03199-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polanska, M. A., Tuchina, O., Agricola, H., Hansson, B. S., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2012). Neuropeptide complexity in the crustacean central olfactory pathway: Immunolocalization of A-type allatostatins and RFamide-like peptides in the brain of a terrestrial hermit crab. Molecular Brain, 5(1), 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-6606-5-29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puñal, V. M., Ahmed, M., Thornton-Kolbe, E. M., &amp; Clowney, E. J. (2021). Untangling the wires: Development of sparse, distributed connectivity in the mushroom body calyx. Cell and Tissue Research, 383(1), 91-112. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-020-03386-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak, J. (2013). Exploring brain connectivity in insect model systems of learning and memory. In Invertebrate learning and memory (pp. 26-40). Elsevier. http://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/B9780124158238000046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak, J., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2018). Olfactory microcircuits in Drosophila melanogaster. In Handbook of brain microcircuits (2nd ed., pp. 361-367). Oxford University Press. https://pure.mpg.de/pubman/faces/ViewItemOverviewPage.jsp?itemId=item_2565272</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak, J., Talarico, G., Ruiz, S., Arnold, C., Cantera, R., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2016). Synaptic circuitry of identified neurons in the antennal lobe of Drosophila melanogaster. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524(9), 1920-1956. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23966</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saetan, J., Senarai, T., Tamtin, M., Weerachatyanukul, W., Chavadej, J., Hanna, P. J., Parhar, I., Sobhon, P., &amp; Sretarugsa, P. (2013). Histological organization of the central nervous system and distribution of a gonadotropin-releasing hormone-like peptide in the blue crab, Portunus pelagicus. Cell and Tissue Research, 353(3), 493-510. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-013-1650-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Denburg, J. L. (1976). The central projections of chemoreceptor axons in the crayfish revealed by axoplasmic transport. Brain Research, 115(3), 492-496.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., Kenning, M., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2014). Adaptive trends in malacostracan brain form and function related to behaviour. In C. D. Derby &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.) The natural history of crustacea. Vol. 3: Nervous systems and their control of behaviour (pp. 11-48). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Luff, S. E. (1973). The structural organization of glomerular neuropile in the olfactory and accessory lobes of an Australian freshwater crayfish, Cherax destructor. Zeitschrift für Zellforschung und Mikroskopische Anatomie, 142, 37-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Mellon, D. (2002). Olfactory centers in the brain of freshwater crayfish. In The crustacean nervous system. Wiese K (Ed.), (pp. 386-404). Springer-Verlag.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Sandeman, R. E. (1994). Electrical responses and synaptic connections of giant serotonin-immunoreactive neurons in crayfish olfactory and accessory lobes. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 341(1), 130-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., Sandeman, R. E., &amp; Aitken, A. R. (1988). Atlas of serotonin-containing neurons in the optic lobes and brain of the crayfish, Cherax destructor. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 269(4), 465-478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, D. C., Sandeman, R. E., Derby, C. D., &amp; Schmidt, M. (1992). Morphology of the brain of crayfish, crabs, and spiny lobsters: A common nomenclature for homologous structures. Biological Bulletin, 183, 304-326. https://doi.org/10.2307/1542217</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, R. E., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (1987). Serotonin-like immunoreactivity of giant olfactory interneurons in the crayfish brain. Brain Research, 403(2), 371-374. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(87)90078-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, R. E., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Watson, A. H. D. (1990). Substance P antibody reveals homologous neurons with axon terminals among somata in the crayfish and crab brain. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 294(4), 569-582. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902940405</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandeman, R. E., Watson, A. H. D., &amp; Sandeman, D. C. (1995). Ultrastructure of the synaptic terminals of the dorsal giant serotonin-IR neuron and deutocerebral commissure interneurons in the accessory and olfactory lobes of the crayfish. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 361(4), 617-632. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903610406</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schachtner, J., Schmidt, M., &amp; Homberg, U. (2005). Organization and evolutionary trends of primary olfactory brain centers in Tetraconata (Crustacea+Hexapoda). Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 34(3), 257-299. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2005.04.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scheffer, L. K., Xu, C. S., Januszewski, M., Lu, Z., Takemura, S., Hayworth, K. J., Huang, G. B., Shinomiya, K., Maitlin-Shepard, J., Berg, S., Clements, J., Hubbard, P. M., Katz, W. T., Umayam, L., Zhao, T., Ackerman, D., Blakely, T., Bogovic, J., Dolafi, T., … Plaza, S. M. (2020). A connectome and analysis of the adult Drosophila central brain. eLife, 9, e57443. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.57443</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M. (1997a). Distribution of centrifugal neurons targeting the soma clusters of the olfactory midbrain among decapod crustaceans. Brain Research, 752(1-2), 15-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M. (1997b). Distribution of presumptive chemosensory afferents with FMRFamide-or substance P-like immunoreactivity in decapod crustaceans. Brain Research, 746(1-2), 71-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M. (2007). The olfactory pathway of decapod crustaceans-An invertebrate model for life-long neurogenesis. Chemical Senses, 32(4), 365-384. https://doi.org/10.1093/chemse/bjm008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1992). Antennular projections to the midbrain of the spiny lobster. II. sensory innervation of the olfactory lobe. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 318(3), 291-303. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903180306</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1994). Descending neurons with dopamine-like or with substance P/FMRFamide-like immunoreactivity target the somata of olfactory interneurons in the brain of the spiny lobster, Panulirus argus. Cell and Tissue Research, 278(2), 337-352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1996). Processing of antennular input in the brain of the spiny lobster, Panulirus argus. II. The olfactory pathway. Journal of Comparative Physiology A: Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 178(5), 605-628. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00227375</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1997). Immunocytochemical analysis of glomerular regionalization and neuronal diversity in the olfactory deutocerebrum of the spiny lobster. Cell and Tissue Research, 287(3), 541-563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, M., &amp; Mellon, D. (2011). Neuronal processing of chemical information in crustaceans. In T. Breithaupt &amp; M. Thiel (Eds.), Chemical communication in crustaceans (pp. 123-147). Springer. http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-0-387-77101-4_7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scholz, N. L., Chang, E. S., Graubard, K., &amp; Truman, J. W. (1998). The NO/cGMP pathway and the development of neural networks in postembryonic lobsters. Journal of Neurobiology, 34(3), 208-226. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-4695(19980215)34:3&lt;208::AID-NEU2&gt;3.0.CO;2-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schürmann, F.-W., Sandeman, R., &amp; Sandeman, D. (1991). Dense-core vesicles and non-synaptic exocytosis in the central body of the crayfish brain. Cell and Tissue Research, 265(3), 493-501. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00340872</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwentner, M., Combosch, D. J., Pakes Nelson, J., &amp; Giribet, G. (2017). A Phylogenomic Solution to the Origin of Insects by Resolving Crustacean-Hexapod Relationships. Current Biology, 27(12), 1818-1824. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2017.05.040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinakevitch, I., Bjorklund, G. R., Newbern, J. M., Gerkin, R. C., &amp; Smith, B. H. (2017). Comparative study of chemical neuroanatomy of the olfactory neuropil in mouse, honey bee, and human. Biological Cybernetics, 112, 1-14. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00422-017-0728-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skiebe, P. (1999). Allatostatin-like immunoreactivity in the stomatogastric nervous system and the pericardial organs of the crab Cancer pagurus, the lobster Homarus americanus, and the crayfish Cherax destructor and Procambarus clarkii. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 403(1), 85-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke, A., Harzsch, S., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2011). Organization of Deutocerebral Neuropils and Olfactory Behavior in the Centipede Scutigera coleoptrata (Linnaeus, 1758) (Myriapoda: Chilopoda). Chemical Senses, 36(1), 43-61. https://doi.org/10.1093/chemse/bjq096</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stangier, J., Hilbich, C., Burdzik, S., &amp; Keller, R. (1992). Orcokinin: A novel myotropic peptide from the nervous system of the crayfish, Orconectes limosus. Peptides, 13(5), 859-864. https://doi.org/10.1016/0196-9781(92)90041-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stay, B., Chan, K. K., &amp; Woodhead, A. P. (1992). Allatostatin-immunoreactive neurons projecting to the corpora allata of adult Diploptera punctata. Cell and Tissue Research, 270(1), 15-23. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00381875</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stay, B., &amp; Tobe, S. S. (2007). The role of allatostatins in juvenile hormone synthesis in insects and crustaceans. Annual Review of Entomology, 52, 277-299. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.ento.51.110104.151050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan, J. M., Benton, J. L., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Beltz, B. S. (2007). Adult neurogenesis: A common strategy across diverse species. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 500(3), 574-584. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21187</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szyszka, P., &amp; Galizia, C. G. (2015). Olfaction in insects. In R. L. Doty (Ed.), Handbook of olfaction and gustation (pp. 531-546). John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118971758.ch22</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeuchi, H., &amp; Sakano, H. (2014). Neural map formation in the mouse olfactory system. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 71(16), 3049-3057. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00018-014-1597-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuchina, O., Koczan, S., Harzsch, S., Rybak, J., Wolff, G., Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2015). Central projections of antennular chemosensory and mechanosensory afferents in the brain of the terrestrial hermit crab (Coenobita clypeatus; Coenobitidae, Anomura). Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 9(94), 1-13. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2015.00094</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Utting, M., Agricola, H.-J., Sandeman, R., &amp; Sandeman, D. (2000). Central complex in the brain of crayfish and its possible homology with that of insects. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 416(2), 245-261. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(20000110)416:2&lt;245::AID-CNE9&gt;3.0.CO;2-A</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vitzthum, H., Homberg, U., &amp; Agricola, H. (1996). Distribution of Dip-allatostatin I-like immunoreactivity in the brain of the locust Schistocerca gregaria with detailed analysis of immunostaining in the central complex. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 369(3), 419-437. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19960603)369:3&lt;419::AID-CNE7&gt;3.0.CO;2-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wachowiak, M., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1997). Dual inhibitory pathways mediated by GABA-and histaminergic interneurons in the lobster olfactory lobe. Journal of Comparative Physiology A: Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 180(4), 357-372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wachowiak, M., &amp; Cohen, L. B. (1999). Presynaptic inhibition of primary olfactory afferents mediated by different mechanisms in lobster and turtle. Journal of Neuroscience, 19(20), 8808-8817. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.19-20-08808.1999</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wachowiak, M., Diebel, C. E., &amp; Ache, B. W. (1997). Local interneurons define functionally distinct regions within lobster olfactory glomeruli. Journal of Experimental Biology, 200(6), 989-1001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, C. H., &amp; Christie, A. E. (2010). Distribution of C-type allatostatin (C-AST)-like immunoreactivity in the central nervous system of the copepod Calanus finmarchicus. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 167(2), 252-260. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ygcen.2010.03.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, R. I. (2013). Early olfactory processing in Drosophila: Mechanisms and principles. Annual Review of Neuroscience, 36(1), 217-241. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-neuro-062111-150533</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wipfler, B., Letsch, H., Frandsen, P. B., Kapli, P., Mayer, C., Bartel, D., Buckley, T. R., Donath, A., Edgerly-Rooks, J. S., Fujita, M., Liu, S., Machida, R., Mashimo, Y., Misof, B., Niehuis, O., Peters, R. S., Petersen, M., Podsiadlowski, L., Schütte, K., … Simon, S. (2019). Evolutionary history of Polyneoptera and its implications for our understanding of early winged insects. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 116(8), 3024-3029. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1817794116</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wittfoth, C., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2018). Adult neurogenesis in the central olfactory pathway of dendrobranchiate and caridean shrimps: New insights into the evolution of the deutocerebral proliferative system in reptant decapods. Developmental Neurobiology, 78(8), 757-774. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.22596</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood, D. E., Nishikawa, M., &amp; Derby, C. D. (1996). Proctolinlike immunoreactivity and identified neurosecretory cells as putative substrates for modulation of courtship display behavior in the blue crab, Callinectes sapidus. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 368(1), 153-163. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19960422)368:1&lt;153::AID-CNE10&gt;3.0.CO;2-S</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodhead, A. P., Stoltzman, C. A., &amp; Stay, B. (1992). Allatostatins in the nerves of the antennal pulsatile organ muscle of the cockroach Diploptera punctata. Archives of Insect Biochemistry and Physiology, 20(4), 253-263. https://doi.org/10.1002/arch.940200403</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamanaka, N., Roller, L., Zitňan, D., Satake, H., Mizoguchi, A., Kataoka, H., &amp; Tanaka, Y. (2011). Bombyx orcokinins are brain-gut peptides involved in the neuronal regulation of ecdysteroidogenesis. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 519(2), 238-246. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22517</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuda-Kamatani, Y., &amp; Yasuda, A. (2000). Identification of orcokinin gene-related peptides in the brain of the crayfish Procambarus clarkii by the Combination of MALDI-TOF and on-line capillary HPLC/Q-Tof mass spectrometries and molecular cloning. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 118(1), 161-172. https://doi.org/10.1006/gcen.1999.7453</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuda-Kamatani, Y., &amp; Yasuda, A. (2006). Characteristic expression patterns of allatostatin-like peptide, FMRFamide-related peptide, orcokinin, tachykinin-related peptide, and SIFamide in the olfactory system of crayfish Procambarus clarkii. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 496(1), 135-147. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.20903</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin, G.-L., Yang, J.-S., Cao, J.-X., &amp; Yang, W.-J. (2006). Molecular cloning and characterization of FGLamide allatostatin gene from the prawn, Macrobrachium rosenbergii. Peptides, 27(6), 1241-1250. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2005.11.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoon, J. G., &amp; Stay, B. (1995). Immunocytochemical localization of Diploptera punctata allatostatin-like peptide in Drosophila melanogaster. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 363(3), 475-488. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903630310</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zajac, M., &amp; Mollereau, J. (2006). RFamide peptides. Introduction. Peptides, 27(5), 941-942. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2005.12.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng, Z., Lauritzen, J. S., Perlman, E., Robinson, C. G., Nichols, M., Milkie, D., Torrens, O., Price, J., Fisher, C. B., Sharifi, N., Calle-Schuler, S. A., Kmecova, L., Ali, I. J., Karsh, B., Trautman, E. T., Bogovic, J. A., Hanslovsky, P., Jefferis, G. S. X. E., Kazhdan, M., … Bock, D. D. (2018). A complete electron microscopy volume of the brain of adult Drosophila melanogaster. Cell, 174(3), 730-743. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2018.06.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng, Z., Li, F., Fisher, C., Ali, I. J., Sharifi, N., Calle-Schuler, S., Hsu, J., Masoodpanah, N., Kmecova, L., Kazimiers, T., Perlman, E., Nichols, M., Li, P. H., Jain, V., &amp; Bock, D. D. (2020). Structured sampling of olfactory input by the fly mushroom body. BioRxiv. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.04.17.047167</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
