<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34840291</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0358</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
              <Day>22</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Diseases of the colon and rectum</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dis Colon Rectum</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Unbundling Bundles: Evaluating the Association of Individual Colorectal Surgical Site Infection Reduction Bundle Elements on Infection Rates in a Statewide Collaborative.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/DCR.0000000000002223</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Surgical site infection reduction bundles are effective but can be complex and resource intensive. Understanding which bundle elements are associated with reduced surgical site infections may guide concise bundle implementation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the association of individual surgical site infection reduction bundle elements with infection rates.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Post-hoc analysis of a prospective cohort study.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Illinois Surgical Quality Improvement Collaborative hospitals.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Elective colorectal resections at participating hospitals from 2016-2017.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">16-element colorectal surgical site infection reduction bundle.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Surgical site infection rates were compared among patients by adherence with each bundle element using Chi-squared tests and multivariable logistic regression. Principal component analysis identified composites of correlated bundle elements. Coincidence analysis identified combinations of bundle elements or principal component composites associated with the absence of surgical site infection.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 2,722 patients, 192 (7.1%) developed a surgical site infection. Infections were less likely when oral antibiotics (OR 0.63 [95% CI 0.41-0.97]), wound protectors (OR 0.55 [95% CI 0.37-0.81]), and occlusive dressings (OR 0.71 [95% CI 0.51-1.00]) were used. Bundle elements were reduced into 5 principal component composites. Adherence with the combination of (1) oral antibiotics, (2) wound protector, or (3) redosing intravenous antibiotic prophylaxis plus chlorhexidine-alcohol intraoperative skin preparation were associated with the absence of infection (consistency=0.94, coverage=0.96). Four of the five principal component composites in various combinations were associated with the absence of surgical site infection, while the composite consisting of occlusive dressing placement, postoperative dressing removal, and daily postoperative chlorhexidine incisional cleansing had no association with the outcome.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The inclusion of hospitals engaged in quality improvement initiatives may limit the generalizability of these data.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Bundle elements had varying association with infection reduction. Implementation of colorectal surgical site infection reduction bundles should focus on the specific elements associated with low surgical site infections. See Video Abstract at http://links.lww.com/DCR/B808.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 The American Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schlick</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cary Jo R</ForeName>
            <Initials>CJR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Illinois Surgical Quality Improvement Collaborative, Chicago, Illinois Surgical Outcomes and Quality Improvement Center (SOQIC), Department of Surgery, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois Center for Healthcare Studies, Institute for Public Health and Medicine, Feinberg School of Medicine, Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Reiping</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brajcich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brian C</ForeName>
            <Initials>BC</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Halverson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amy L</ForeName>
            <Initials>AL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anthony D</ForeName>
            <Initials>AD</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kreutzer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lindsey</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bilimoria</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karl Y</ForeName>
            <Initials>KY</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>McGee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael F</ForeName>
            <Initials>MF</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <CollectiveName>Illinois Surgical Quality Improvement Collaborative</CollectiveName>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>K08 HL145139</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HL</Acronym>
            <Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 HS024516</GrantID>
            <Acronym>HS</Acronym>
            <Agency>AHRQ HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Dis Colon Rectum</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372764</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0012-3706</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
        <AbstractText Label="ANTECEDENTES:">Los paquetes de reducción de infecciones del sitio quirúrgico son efectivos pero pueden ser complejos y requieren muchos recursos. Comprender qué elementos del paquete están asociados con la reducción de las infecciones del sitio quirúrgico puede guiar la implementación concisa del paquete.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="OBJETIVO:">Evaluar la asociación de los elementos individuales del paquete de reducción de infecciones del sitio quirúrgico con las tasas de infección.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="DISEÑO:">Análisis post-hoc de un estudio de cohorte prospectivo.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="ESCENARIO:">Hospitales colaborativos para la mejora de la calidad quirúrgica de Illinois</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="PACIENTES:">Resecciones colorrectales electivas en los hospitales participantes entre 2016 y 2017.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="INTERVENCIONES:">Paquete de reducción de infección del sitio quirúrgico colorrectal de 16 elementos</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="PRINCIPALES MEDIDAS DE RESULTADO:">Se compararon las tasas de infección del sitio quirúrgico entre los pacientes según la adherencia con cada elemento del paquete mediante pruebas de Chi cuadrado y regresión logística multivariable. El análisis de componentes principales identificó compuestos de elementos de paquete correlacionados. El análisis de coincidencia identificó combinaciones de elementos del haz o compuestos de componentes principales asociados con la ausencia de infección del sitio quirúrgico.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="RESULTADOS:">Entre 2,722 pacientes, 192 (7.1%) desarrollaron una infección del sitio quirúrgico. Las infecciones fueron menos probables cuando se administraron antibióticos orales (OR 0.63 [IC 95% 0.41–0.97]), protectores de heridas (OR 0.55 [IC 95% 0.37–0.81]) y vendajes oclusivos (OR 0.71 [IC 95% 0.51–1.00]) fueron usados. Los elementos del paquete se redujeron a 5 grupos de componentes principales. La adherencia a la combinación de (1) antibióticos orales, (2) protector de heridas o (3) redosificación de profilaxis antibiótica intravenosa más preparación de la piel intraoperatoria con clorhexidina-alcohol se asoció con la ausencia de infección (consistencia = 0.94, cobertura = 0.96). Cuatro de los cinco grupos de componentes principales en varias combinaciones se asociaron con la ausencia de infección del sitio quirúrgico, mientras que el grupo que consiste en la colocación del apósito oclusivo, la remosión del apósito en posoperatorio y la limpieza incisional posoperatoria diaria con clorhexidina no tuvo asociación con el resultado.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="LIMITACIONES:">La inclusión de hospitales que participan en iniciativas de mejora de la calidad puede limitar la generalización de estos datos.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIÓN:">Los elementos del paquete tuvieron una asociación variable con la reducción de la infección. La implementación de paquetes de reducción de infecciones del sitio quirúrgico colorrectal debe centrarse en los elementos específicos asociados con pocas infecciones del sitio quirúrgico. Consulte <b>Video Resumen</b> en http://links.lww.com/DCR/Bxxx. <i>(Traducción—Juan Carlos Reyes)</i></AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 The American Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2023</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34840291</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1756318</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9124224</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DCR.0000000000002223</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00003453-900000000-99255</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith RL, Bohl JK, McElearney ST, et al.
Wound infection after elective colorectal
resection. Ann Surg.
2004;239:599–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1356267</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15082963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young H, Knepper B, Moore EE, Johnson JL, Mehler P, Price CS. Surgical site infection after colon surgery: national
Healthcare Safety Network risk factors and modeled rates compared with
published risk factors and rates. J Am Coll Surg.
2012;214:852–859.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22440056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Lissovoy G, Fraeman K, Hutchins V, Murphy D, Song D, Vaughn BB. Surgical site infection: incidence and impact on
hospital utilization and treatment costs. Am J Infect Control.
2009;37:387–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19398246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gantz O, Zagadailov P, Merchant AM. The cost of surgical site infections after colorectal
surgery in the United States from 2001 to 2012: a longitudinal
analysis. Am Surg.
2019;85:142–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30819289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merkow RP, Ju MH, Chung JW, et al.
Underlying reasons associated with hospital readmission following
surgery in the United States. JAMA.
2015;313:483–495.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25647204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sajankila N, Como JJ, Claridge JA. Upcoming rules and benchmarks concerning the monitoring
of and the payment for surgical infections. Surg Clin North Am.
2014;94:1219–1231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25440120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patterson P
SCIP measures to weigh in Medicare pay starting in
2013. OR Manager.
2011;27:1,
7–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawson EH, Ko CY, Adams JL, Chow WB, Hall BL. Reliability of evaluating hospital quality by colorectal
surgical site infection type. Ann Surg.
2013;258:994–1000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23657082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cima R, Dankbar E, Lovely J, et al.; Colorectal Surgical Site Infection Reduction
Team. Colorectal surgery surgical site infection reduction program: a
national surgical quality improvement program--driven multidisciplinary
single-institution experience. J Am Coll Surg.
2013;216:23–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23127793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dellinger EP, Hausmann SM, Bratzler DW, et al.
Hospitals collaborate to decrease surgical site
infections. Am J Surg.
2005;190:9–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15972163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waits SA, Fritze D, Banerjee M, et al.
Developing an argument for bundled interventions to reduce
surgical site infection in colorectal surgery.
Surgery.
2014;155:602–606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24468041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keenan JE, Speicher PJ, Thacker JK, Walter M, Kuchibhatla M, Mantyh CR. The preventive surgical site infection bundle in
colorectal surgery: an effective approach to surgical site infection
reduction and health care cost savings. JAMA Surg.
2014;149:1045–1052.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25163027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorgun E, Rencuzogullari A, Ozben V, et al.
An Effective bundled approach reduces surgical site infections in
a high-outlier colorectal unit. Dis Colon Rectum.
2018;61:89–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29215475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson KM, Oldenburg WA, Deschamps C, Rupp WC, Smith CD. Chasing zero: the drive to eliminate surgical site
infections. Ann Surg.
2011;254:430–436.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21817888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell TA, Chung H, Riad C, et al.
Sustaining improvement: implementation and spread of a surgical
site infection bundle. Am Surg.
2018;84:1665–1669.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vu JV, Collins SD, Seese E, et al.
Evidence that a regional surgical collaborative can transform
care: surgical site infection prevention practices for colectomy in
Michigan. J Am Coll Surg.
2018;226:91–99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29111416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zywot A, Lau CSM, Stephen Fletcher H, Paul S. Bundles prevent surgical site infections after
colorectal surgery: meta-analysis and systematic review.
J Gastrointest Surg.
2017;21:1915–1930.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28620749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmichael JC, Keller DS, Baldini G, et al.
Clinical Practice Guidelines for Enhanced Recovery After Colon
and Rectal Surgery From the American Society of Colon and Rectal Surgeons
and Society of American Gastrointestinal and Endoscopic
Surgeons. Dis Colon Rectum.
2017;60:761–784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28682962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGee MF, Kreutzer L, Quinn CM, et al.; Illinois Surgical Quality Improvement
Collaborative (ISQIC). Leveraging a comprehensive program to implement a
colorectal surgical site infection reduction bundle in a statewide quality
improvement collaborative. Ann Surg.
2019;270:701–711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7775039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31503066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Losh JM, Gough A, Rutherford R, Romero J, Diaz G, Schweitzer J. Surgical site infection reduction bundle: implementation
and challenges at Ventura County Medical Center. Am Surg.
2017;83:1147–1151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29391113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Odell DD, Quinn CM, Matulewicz RS, et al.
Association between hospital safety culture and surgical outcomes
in a statewide surgical quality improvement collaborative.
J Am Coll Surg.
2019;229:175–183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6661205</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wandling MW, Minami CA, Johnson JK, et al.
Development of a conceptual model for surgical quality
improvement collaboratives: facilitating the implementation and evaluation
of collaborative quality improvement. JAMA Surg.
2016;151:1181–1183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8944346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27604075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger ER, Kreutzer L, Halverson A, et al.
Evaluation of Changes in Quality Improvement Knowledge Following
a Formal Educational Curriculum Within a Statewide Learning
Collaborative. J Surg Educ.
2020;S1931–7204:30133–30131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berian JR, Thomas JM, Minami CA, et al.
Evaluation of a novel mentor program to improve surgical care for
US hospitals. Int J Qual Health Care.
2017;29:234–242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28453822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuce TK, Yang AD, Johnson JK, et al.
Association Between implementing comprehensive learning
collaborative strategies in a statewide collaborative and changes in
hospital safety culture. JAMA Surg.
2020;155:934–940.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424544</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32805054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang AD, Hewitt DB, Blay E Jr, et al.; Illinois Surgical Quality Improvement
Collaborative (ISQIC). Multi-institution evaluation of adherence to
comprehensive postoperative VTE chemoprophylaxis.
Ann Surg.
2020;271:1072–1079.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6904538</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30632990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis RJ, Hewitt DB, Hu YY, et al.
An empirical national assessment of the learning environment and
factors associated with program culture. Ann Surg.
2019;270:585–592.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6896212</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31425291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner M
Inferring causal complexity. Sociol Methods Res.
2009;38:71–101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner M, Ambuhl M. Optimizing Consistency and Coverage in Configurational Causal Modeling. 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner M, Thiem A. Identifying complex causal dependencies in
configurational data with coincidence analysis. The R Journal.
2015;7:176–184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner M, Ambuhl M. Causal modeling with multi-value and fuzzy-set
Coincidence Analysis. Political Science Research and Methods.
2018:1–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragin CC. Fuzzy Sets: Calibration Versus Measurement.
2006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ambuehl M, Baumgartner M, Epple R, Parkkinen VP, Thiem A. Causal Modeling with Coincidence Analysis.
2020; https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/cna/cna.pdf.
Accessed November, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiran RP, Murray AC, Chiuzan C, Estrada D, Forde K. Combined preoperative mechanical bowel preparation with
oral antibiotics significantly reduces surgical site infection, anastomotic
leak, and ileus after colorectal surgery. Ann Surg.
2015;262:416–425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26258310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scarborough JE, Mantyh CR, Sun Z, Migaly J. Combined Mechanical and oral antibiotic bowel
preparation reduces incisional surgical site infection and anastomotic leak
rates after elective colorectal resection: an analysis of colectomy-targeted
ACS NSQIP. Ann Surg.
2015;262:331–337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26083870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edmiston CEJ Jr, Lee CJ, Krepel CJ, et al.
Evidence for a standardized preadmission showering regimen to
achieve maximal antiseptic skin surface concentrations of chlorhexidine
gluconate, 4%, in surgical patients. JAMA Surg.
2015;150:1027–1033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26308490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner M, Epple R. A coincidence analysis of a causal chain: The Swiss
Minaret vote. Sociol Methods Res.
2013;43:280–312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reiss J
Causation in the social sciences: evidence, inference, and
purpose. Philos Soc Sci.
2009;39:20–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
