<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34865300</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-0528</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>129</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BJOG : an international journal of obstetrics and gynaecology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BJOG</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the short-term host response and biomechanics of an absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate scaffold in a sheep model following vaginal implantation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1039</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1049</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1039-1049</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1471-0528.17040</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the host- and biomechanical response to a fully absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate (P4HB) scaffold in comparison with the response to polypropylene (PP) mesh.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN">In vivo animal experiment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SETTING">KU Leuven Center for Surgical Technologies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="POPULATION">Fourteen parous female Mule sheep.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">P4HB scaffolds were surgically implanted in the posterior vaginal wall of sheep. The comparative PP mesh data were obtained from an identical study protocol performed previously.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOME MEASURES">Gross necropsy, host response and biomechanical evaluation of explants, and the in vivo P4HB scaffold degradation were evaluated at 60- and 180-days post-implantation. Data are reported as mean ± standard deviation (SD) or standard error of the mean (SEM).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Gross necropsy revealed no implant-related adverse events using P4HB scaffolds. The tensile stiffness of the P4HB explants increased at 180-days (12.498 ± 2.66 N/mm SEM [p =0.019]) as compared to 60-days (4.585 ± 1.57 N/mm) post-implantation, while P4HB degraded gradually. P4HB scaffolds exhibited excellent tissue integration with dense connective tissue and a moderate initial host response. P4HB scaffolds induced a significantly higher M2/M1 ratio (1.70 ± 0.67 SD, score 0-4), as compared to PP mesh(0.99 ± 0.78 SD, score 0-4) at 180-days.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">P4HB scaffold facilitated a gradual load transfer to vaginal tissue over time. The fully absorbable P4HB scaffold, in comparison to PP mesh, has a favorable host response with comparable load-bearing capacity. If these results are also observed at longer follow-up in-vivo, a clinical study using P4HB for vaginal POP surgery may be warranted to demonstrate efficacy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="TWEETABLE ABSTRACT">Degradable vaginal P4HB implant might be a solution for treatment of POP.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. BJOG: An International Journal of Obstetrics and Gynaecology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Diedrich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chantal M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0579-3535</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Center for Reproductive Medicine (AMC), Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zeliha</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7293-8151</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Center for Reproductive Medicine (AMC), Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hympanova</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lucie</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Surgical Technologies, Biomedical Sciences Group, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Third Faculty of Medicine, Institute for the Care of Mother and Child, Charles University, Prague, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vodegel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eva</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6897-9495</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Center for Reproductive Medicine (AMC), Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zündel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manuel</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Mechanical Systems, ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Science and Technology, EMPA, Dübendorf, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mazza</LastName>
            <ForeName>Edoardo</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Mechanical Systems, ETH Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Swiss Federal Laboratories for Materials Science and Technology, EMPA, Dübendorf, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Deprest</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4920-945X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Surgical Technologies, Biomedical Sciences Group, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roovers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology, Center for Reproductive Medicine (AMC), Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>BJOG</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100935741</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1470-0328</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D006885">Hydroxybutyrates</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011126">Polypropylenes</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001696" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomechanical Phenomena</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006885" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxybutyrates</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011126" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polypropylenes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012756" MajorTopicYN="N">Sheep</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013526" MajorTopicYN="Y">Surgical Mesh</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014621" MajorTopicYN="N">Vagina</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">biomechanics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">degradable scaffold</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">host response</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">pelvic organ prolapse</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">poly-4-hydroxybutyrate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">vaginal surgery</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34865300</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1471-0528.17040</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lakeman MM, van der Vaart CH, Laan E, Roovers JPW. The effect of prolapse surgery on vaginal sensibility. J Sex Med. 2011;8(4):1239-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber MA, Lakeman MM, Laan E, Roovers JPW. The effects of vaginal prolapse surgery using synthetic mesh on vaginal wall sensibility, vaginal vasocongestion, and sexual function: a prospective single-center study. J Sex Med. 2014;11(7):1848-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang R, Abramowitch S, Knight K, Palcsey S, Nolfi A, Feola A, et al. Vaginal degeneration following implantation of synthetic mesh with increased stiffness. BJOG. 2013;120(2):233-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hympanova L, Rynkevic R, Roman S, Mori da Cunha M, Mazza E, Zundel M, et al. Assessment of electrospun and ultra-lightweight polypropylene meshes in the sheep model for vaginal surgery. Eur Urol Focus. 2020;6(1):190-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birch C, Fynes MM. The role of synthetic and biological prostheses in reconstructive pelvic floor surgery. Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol. 2002;14(5):527-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barone WR, Moalli PA, Abramowitch SD. Textile properties of synthetic prolapse mesh in response to uniaxial loading. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2016;215(3):326.e1-e9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelly M, Macdougall K, Olabisi O, McGuire N. In vivo response to polypropylene following implantation in animal models: a review of biocompatibility. Int Urogynecol J. 2017;28(2):171-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones KA, Shepherd JP, Oliphant SS, Wang L, Bunker CH, Lowder JL. Trends in inpatient prolapse procedures in the United States, 1979-2006. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2010;202(5):501.e1-e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reinier M, Groep G. Final opinion on the use of meshes in urogynecological surgery. Brussels, Belgium: SCENIHR-European Commission; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diedrich CM, Roovers JP, Smit TH, Guler Z. Fully absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate implants exhibit more favorable cell-matrix interactions than polypropylene. Mater Sci Eng C, Mater Biol Appl. 2021;120: 111702.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Shaughnessy D, Grande D, El-Neemany D, Sajjan S, Pillalamarri N, Shalom D, et al. Evaluation of the histological and biomechanical properties of poly-4-hydroxybutyrate scaffold for pelvic organ prolapse, compared with polypropylene mesh in a rabbit model. Int Urogynecol J. 2021. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00192-021-04851-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huisman GW, Skraly F, Martin DP, Peoples OP. Biological systems for manufacture of polyhydroxyalkanoate polymers containing 4-hydroxyacids. Google Patents; 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson T, Kaufman E, Kline J, Sokoloff L. The extraneural distribution of γ-hydroxybutyrate. J Neurochem. 1981;37(5):1345-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin DP, Williams SF. Medical applications of poly-4-hydroxybutyrate: a strong flexible absorbable biomaterial. Biochem Eng J. 2003;16(2):97-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin DP, Badhwar A, Shah DV, Rizk S, Eldridge SN, Gagne DH, et al. Characterization of poly-4-hydroxybutyrate mesh for hernia repair applications. J Surg Res. 2013;184(2):766-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couri BM, Lenis AT, Borazjani A, Paraiso MFR, Damaser MS. Animal models of female pelvic organ prolapse: lessons learned. Exp Rev Obstet Gynecol. 2012;7(3):249-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young N, Rosamilia A, Arkwright J, Lee J, Davies-Tuck M, Melendez J, et al. Vaginal wall weakness in parous ewes: a potential preclinical model of pelvic organ prolapse. Int Urogynecol J. 2017;28(7):999-1004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozog Y, Konstantinovic ML, Werbrouck E, De Ridder D, Edoardo M, Deprest J. Shrinkage and biomechanical evaluation of lightweight synthetics in a rabbit model for primary fascial repair. Int Urogynecol J. 2011;22(9):1099-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hympanova L, Rynkevic R, Wach RA, Olejnik AK, Dankers PY, Arts B, et al. Experimental reconstruction of an abdominal wall defect with electrospun polycaprolactone-ureidopyrimidinone mesh conserves compliance yet may have insufficient strength. J Mech Behav Biomed Mater. 2018;88:431-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deeken CR, Matthews BD. Characterization of the mechanical strength, resorption properties, and histologic characteristics of a fully absorbable material (Poly-4-hydroxybutyrate-PHASIX Mesh) in a porcine model of hernia repair. ISRN Surg. 2013;2013: 238067.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roman S, Urbankova I, Callewaert G, Lesage F, Hillary C, Osman NI, et al. Evaluating alternative materials for the treatment of stress urinary incontinence and pelvic organ prolapse: a comparison of the in vivo response to meshes implanted in rabbits. J Urol. 2016;196(1):261-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hympanova L, Mori da Cunha M, Rynkevic R, Zundel M, Gallego MR, Vange J, et al. Physiologic musculofascial compliance following reinforcement with electrospun polycaprolactone-ureidopyrimidinone mesh in a rat model. J Mech Behav Biom Mat. 2017;74:349-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hjort H, Mathisen T, Alves A, Clermont G, Boutrand J. Three-year results from a preclinical implantation study of a long-term resorbable surgical mesh with time-dependent mechanical characteristics. Hernia. 2012;16(2):191-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang R, Knight K, Abramowitch S, Moalli PA. Exploring the basic science of prolapse meshes. Curr Opin Obstet Gynecol. 2016;28(5):413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolfi AL, Brown BN, Liang R, Palcsey SL, Bonidie MJ, Abramowitch SD, et al. Host response to synthetic mesh in women with mesh complications. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2016;215(2):206.e1-e8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sand PK, Koduri S, Lobel RW, Winkler HA, Tomezsko J, Culligan PJ, et al. Prospective randomized trial of polyglactin 910 mesh to prevent recurrence of cystoceles and rectoceles. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2001;184(7):1357-64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Tayrac R, Deffieux X, Gervaise A, Chauveaud-Lambling A, Fernandez H. Long-term anatomical and functional assessment of trans-vaginal cystocele repair using a tension-free polypropylene mesh. Int Urogynecol J. 2006;17(5):483-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramanah R, Mairot J, Clement M-C, Parratte B, Maillet R, Riethmuller D. Evaluating the porcine dermis graft InteXen® in three-compartment transvaginal pelvic organ prolapse repair. Int Urogynecol J. 2010;21(9):1151-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armitage S, Seman EI, Keirse MJ. Use of surgisis for treatment of anterior and posterior vaginal prolapse. Obstet Gynecol Int. 2012;2012: 376251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams SF, Martin DP, Moses AC. The history of GalaFLEX P4HB Scaffold. Aesthet Surg J. 2016;36(suppl 2):S33-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Utsunomia C, Ren Q, Zinn M. Poly(4-Hydroxybutyrate): current state and perspectives. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2020;8:257.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feola A, Abramowitch S, Jallah Z, Stein S, Barone W, Palcsey S, et al. Deterioration in biomechanical properties of the vagina following implantation of a high-stiffness prolapse mesh. BJOG: an International Journal of Obstetrics &amp; Gynaecology. 2013;120(2):224-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feola A, Endo M, Urbankova I, Vlacil J, Deprest T, Bettin S, et al. Host reaction to vaginally inserted collagen containing polypropylene implants in sheep. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2015;212(4):474.e1-e8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cima LG. Polymer substrates for controlled biological interactions. J Cell Biochem. 1994;56(2):155-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown BN, Londono R, Tottey S, Zhang L, Kukla KA, Wolf MT, et al. Macrophage phenotype as a predictor of constructive remodeling following the implantation of biologically derived surgical mesh materials. Acta Biomater. 2012;8(3):978-87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hachim D, LoPresti ST, Yates CC, Brown BN. Shifts in macrophage phenotype at the biomaterial interface via IL-4 eluting coatings are associated with improved implant integration. Biomaterials. 2017;112:95-107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vashaghian M, Ruiz-Zapata AM, Kerkhof MH, Zandieh-Doulabi B, Werner A, Roovers JP, et al. Toward a new generation of pelvic floor implants with electrospun nanofibrous matrices: a feasibility study. Neurourol Urodyn. 2017;36(3):565-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wynn TA, Ramalingam TR. Mechanisms of fibrosis: therapeutic translation for fibrotic disease. Nat Med. 2012;18(7):1028.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burden N, Chapman K, Sewell F, Robinson V. Pioneering better science through the 3Rs: an introduction to the national centre for the replacement, refinement, and reduction of animals in research (NC3Rs). J Am Assoc Lab Anim Sci. 2015;54(2):198-208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
