<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34860458</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1527-6473</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Liver transplantation : official publication of the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases and the International Liver Transplantation Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Liver Transpl</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Secondary Prophylaxis of Gastric Variceal Bleeding: A Systematic Review and Network Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>945</StartPage>
          <EndPage>958</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>945-958</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/lt.26383</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>There is no clear consensus regarding the optimal approach for secondary prophylaxis of gastric variceal bleeding (GVB) in patients with cirrhosis. We conducted a systematic review and network meta-analysis (NMA) to compare the efficacy of available treatments. A comprehensive search of several databases from each database's inception to March 23, 2021, was conducted to identify relevant randomized controlled trials (RCTs). Outcomes of interest were rebleeding and mortality. Results were expressed as relative risk (RR) and 95% confidence interval (CI). We followed the Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation approach to rate the certainty of evidence. We included 9 RCTs with 647 patients who had histories of GVB and follow-ups &gt;6 weeks. A total of 9 interventions were included in the NMA. Balloon-occluded retrograde transvenous obliteration (BRTO) was associated with a lower risk of rebleeding when compared with β-blockers (RR, 0.04; 95% CI, 0.01-0.26; low certainty), and endoscopic injection sclerotherapy (EIS)-cyanoacrylate (CYA) (RR, 0.18; 95% CI, 0.04-0.77; low certainty). β-blockers were associated with a higher risk of rebleeding compared with most interventions and with increased mortality compared with EIS-CYA (RR, 4.12, 95% CI, 1.50-11.36; low certainty), and EIS-CYA + nonselective β-blockers (RR, 5.61; 95% CI, 1.91-16.43; low certainty). Analysis based on indirect comparisons suggests that BRTO may be the best intervention in preventing rebleeding, whereas β-blocker monotherapy is likely the worst in preventing rebleeding and mortality. Head-to-head RCTs are needed to validate these results.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 by the American Association for the Study of Liver Diseases.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Osman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karim T</ForeName>
            <Initials>KT</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0453-9831</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Lahey Hospital and Medical Center, Beth Israel Lahey Clinic, Burlington, MA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nayfeh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tarek</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Evidence-Based Practice Center, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abdelfattah</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ahmed M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Lahey Hospital and Medical Center, Beth Israel Lahey Clinic, Burlington, MA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Gastroenterology, University of Massachusetts Medical School, Worcester, MA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alabdallah</LastName>
            <ForeName>Khaled</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Lincoln Medical Center, Bronx, NY.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hasan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bashar</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Evidence-Based Practice Center, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Firwana</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Evidence-Based Practice Center, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alabaji</LastName>
            <ForeName>Homam</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Wertachklinik Schwabmünchen, Bavaria, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elkhabiry</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lina</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Alexandria, Alexandria, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mousa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jehan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Damascus University, Damascus, Syria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prokop</LastName>
            <ForeName>Larry J</ForeName>
            <Initials>LJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Library Services, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Murad</LastName>
            <ForeName>M Hassan</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Evidence-Based Practice Center, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gordon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fredric</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Lahey Hospital and Medical Center, Beth Israel Lahey Clinic, Burlington, MA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Transplantation and Hepatobiliary Diseases, Lahey Hospital and Medical Center, Beth Israel Lahey Health, Burlington, MA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Liver Transpl</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100909185</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1527-6465</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000319">Adrenergic beta-Antagonists</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000319" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenergic beta-Antagonists</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004932" MajorTopicYN="Y">Esophageal and Gastric Varices</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006471" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Hemorrhage</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016031" MajorTopicYN="Y">Liver Transplantation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000071076" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Meta-Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015911" MajorTopicYN="N">Sclerotherapy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34860458</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lt.26383</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarin SK, Lahoti D, Saxena SP, Murthy NS, Makwana UK. Prevalence, classification and natural history of gastric varices: a long-term follow-up study in 568 portal hypertension patients. Hepatology 1992;16:1343-1349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim T, Shijo H, Kokawa H, Tokumitsu H, Kubara K, Ota K, et al. Risk factors for hemorrhage from gastric fundal varices. Hepatology 1997;25:307-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christodoulou D, Tsianos E, Kortan P, Marcon N. Gastric and ectopic varices-newer endoscopic options. Ann Gastroenterol 2007;20:95-109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Tsao G, Abraldes JG, Berzigotti A, Bosch J. Portal hypertensive bleeding in cirrhosis: risk stratification, diagnosis, and management: 2016 practice guidance by the American Association for the study of liver diseases. Hepatology 2017;65:310-335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry Z, Patel K, Patton H, Saad W. AGA clinical practice update on management of bleeding gastric varices: expert review. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021;19:1098-1107.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Franchis R. Expanding consensus in portal hypertension: report of the Baveno VI Consensus Workshop: stratifying risk and individualizing care for portal hypertension. J Hepatol 2015;63:743-752.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarin SK, Jain AK, Jain M, Gupta R. A randomized controlled trial of cyanoacrylate versus alcohol injection in patients with isolated fundic varices. Am J Gastroenterol 2002;97:1010-1015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo G-H, Lin C-W, Tai C-M, Perng D-S, Chen I-L, Yeh J-H, Lin H-C. A prospective, randomized trial of thrombin versus cyanoacrylate injection in the control of acute gastric variceal hemorrhage. Endoscopy 2020;52:548-555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuo M-J, Yeh H-Z, Chen G-H, Poon S-K, Yang S-S, Lien H-C, Chang C-S. Improvement of tissue-adhesive obliteration of bleeding gastric varices using adjuvant hypertonic glucose injection: a prospective randomized trial. Endoscopy 2007;39:487-491.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang KY, Wu CS, Chen PC. Endoscopic treatment of bleeding fundic varices with 50% glucose injection. Endoscopy 1996;28:398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee YT, Chan FKL, Ng EKW, Leung VKS, Law KB, Yung MY, et al. EUS-guided injection of cyanoacrylate for bleeding gastric varices. Gastrointest Endosc 2000;52:168-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhat YM, Weilert F, Fredrick RT, Kane SD, Shah JN, Hamerski CM, et al. EUS-guided treatment of gastric fundal varices with combined injection of coils and cyanoacrylate glue: a large U.S. experience over 6 years (with video). Gastrointest Endosc 2016;83:1164-1172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe K, Kimura K, Matsutani S, Ohto M, Okuda K. Portal hemodynamics in patients with gastric varices. A study in 230 patients with esophageal and/or gastric varices using portal vein catheterization. Gastroenterology 1988;95:434-440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mishra SR, Chander Sharma B, Kumar A, Sarin SK. Endoscopic cyanoacrylate injection versus beta-blocker for secondary prophylaxis of gastric variceal bleed: a randomised controlled trial. Gut 2010;59:729-735.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park JK, Saab S, Kee ST, Busuttil RW, Kim HJ, Durazo F, et al. Balloon-occluded retrograde transvenous obliteration (BRTO) for treatment of gastric varices: review and meta-analysis. Dig Dis Sci 2015;60:1543-1553.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohan BP, Chandan S, Khan SR, Kassab LL, Trakroo S, Ponnada S, et al. Efficacy and safety of endoscopic ultrasound-guided therapy versus direct endoscopic glue injection therapy for gastric varices: systematic review and meta-analysis. Endoscopy 2020;52:259-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarty TR, Bazarbashi AN, Hathorn KE, Thompson CC, Ryou M. Combination therapy versus monotherapy for EUS-guided management of gastric varices: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Endosc Ultrasound 2020;9:6-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ZW, Liu JC, Zhao F, Zhang WG, Duan XH, Chen PF, et al. Comparison of the effects of TIPS versus BRTO on bleeding gastric varices: a meta-analysis. Can J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2020;2020:1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med 2015;162:777-784.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JPTSJ, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Sterne JAC. Assessing risk of bias in a randomized trial. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA, editors. Chichester (UK): John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2019: Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Version 6.2. Cochrane; 2021:205-228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DerSimonian R, Laird N. Meta-analysis in clinical trials. Control Clin Trials 1986;7:177-188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ 2003;327:557-560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwarzer GCJ, Rücker G. Meta-Analysis With R. 1st ed. Cham: Springer; 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rücker G, Schwarzer G, Krahn U, König J, Schwarzer MG. Package ‘netmeta’. Network meta-analysis using frequentist methods (version 0.7-0). 2015. https://cran.microsoft.com/snapshot/2018-05-19/web/packages/netmeta/netmeta.pdf. Accessed March 15, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rücker G. Network meta-analysis, electrical networks and graph theory. Res Synth Methods 2012;3:312-324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rücker G, Schwarzer G. Ranking treatments in frequentist network meta-analysis works without resampling methods. BMC Med Res Methodol 2015;15:58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brignardello-Petersen R, Bonner A, Alexander PE, Siemieniuk RA, Furukawa TA, Rochwerg B, et al. Advances in the GRADE approach to rate the certainty in estimates from a network meta-analysis. J Clin Epidemiol 2018;93:36-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Sultan S, Brozek J, Glasziou P, Alonso-Coello P, et al. GRADE guidelines: 11. Making an overall rating of confidence in effect estimates for a single outcome and for all outcomes. J Clin Epidemiol 2013;66:151-157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo X, Xiang T, Wu J, Wang X, Zhu Y, Xi X, et al. Endoscopic cyanoacrylate injection vs BRTO for prevention of gastric variceal bleeding: a randomized controlled trial. Hepatology 2021;74:2074-2084.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo G-H, Liang H-L, Chen W-C, Chen M-H, Lai K-H, Hsu P-I, et al. A prospective, randomized controlled trial of transjugular intrahepatic portosystemic shunt versus cyanoacrylate injection in the prevention of gastric variceal rebleeding. Endoscopy 2007;39:679-685.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hung H-H, Chang C-J, Hou M-C, Liao W-C, Chan C-C, Huang H-C, et al. Efficacy of non-selective β-blockers as adjunct to endoscopic prophylactic treatment for gastric variceal bleeding: a randomized controlled trial. J Hepatol 2012;56:1025-1032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen W-C, Hsin I-F, Chen P-H, Hsu P-I, Wang Y-P, Cheng J-S, et al. Addition of carvedilol to gastric variceal obturation does not decrease recurrence of gastric variceal bleeding in patients with cirrhosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2019;17:2356-2363.e2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen H, Wang Y, Jiang L, Chen W, Weng H, Xu G. A randomized controlled trial of endoscopic ultrasound guided selective variceal devascularization versus standard endoscopic variceal obturation for secondary prophylaxis of gastroesophageal variceal bleeding in a tertiary teaching hospital. Gastroenterology 2019;156:S-1511-S-1512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hashizume M, Kitano S, Yamaga H, Koyanagi N, Sugimachi K. Endoscopic classification of gastric varices. Gastrointest Endosc 1990;36:276-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feu F, García-Pagán JC, Bosch J, Luca A, Escorsell A, Rodés J, Terés J. Relation between portal pressure response to pharmacotherapy and risk of recurrent variceal haemorrhage in patients with cirrhosis. Lancet 1995;346:1056-1059.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu X, Guo X, Tacke F, Shao X, Qi X. Use of nonselective β blockers after variceal eradication in cirrhotic patients undergoing secondary prophylaxis of esophageal variceal bleeding: a critical review of current evidence. Ther Adv Chronic Dis 2019;10:2040622319862693.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rios Castellanos E, Seron P, Gisbert J, Bonfill Cosp X. Endoscopic injection of cyanoacrylate glue versus other endoscopic procedures for acute bleeding gastric varices in people with portal hypertension. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2015:CD010180. https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD010180.pub2/full</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angeli P, Bernardi M, Villanueva C, Francoz C, Mookerjee RP, Trebicka J, et al. EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines for the management of patients with decompensated cirrhosis. J Hepatol 2018;69:406-460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Association HBoCM, Association GBoCM, Association EBoCM. Guideline for the diagnosis and treatment of esophageal and gastric variceal bleeding in cirrhotic portal hypertension. Zhongguo Ganzangbing Zazhi 2016;8:1-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi YS, Lee JH, Sinn DH, Song YB, Gwak G-Y, Choi MS, et al. Effect of balloon-occluded retrograde transvenous obliteration on the natural history of coexisting esophageal varices. J Clin Gastroenterol 2008;42:974-979.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyamoto Y, Oho K, Kumamoto M, Toyonaga A, Sata M. Balloon-occluded retrograde transvenous obliteration improves liver function in patients with cirrhosis and portal hypertension. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2003;18:934-942.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chau TN, Patch D, Chan YW, Nagral A, Dick R, Burroughs AK. “Salvage” transjugular intrahepatic portosystemic shunts: gastric fundal compared with esophageal variceal bleeding. Gastroenterology 1998;114:981-987.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barange K, Péron J-M, Imani K, Otal P, Payen J-L, Rousseau H, et al. Transjugular intrahepatic portosystemic shunt in the treatment of refractory bleeding from ruptured gastric varices. Hepatology 1999;30:1139-1143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robles-Medranda C, Oleas R, Valero M, Puga-Tejada M, Baquerizo-Burgos J, Ospina J, Pitanga-Lukashok H. Endoscopic ultrasonography-guided deployment of embolization coils and cyanoacrylate injection in gastric varices versus coiling alone: a randomized trial. Endoscopy 2020;52:268-275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lôbo MRDA, Chaves DM, De moura DTH, Ribeiro IB, Ikari E, De moura EGH. Safety and efficacy of EUS-guided coil plus cyanoacrylate versus conventional cyanoacrylate technique in the treatment of gastric varices: a randomized controlled trial. Arq Gastroenterol 2019;56:99-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiruvengadam SS, Sedarat A. The role of endoscopic ultrasound (EUS) in the management of gastric varices. Curr Gastroenterol Rep 2021;23:1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin L, Xing A, Kofler MJ, Murad MH. Borrowing of strength from indirect evidence in 40 network meta-analyses. J Clin Epidemiol 2019;106:41-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brignardello-Petersen R, Mustafa RA, Siemieniuk RAC, Murad MH, Agoritsas T, Izcovich A, et al. GRADE approach to rate the certainty from a network meta-analysis: addressing incoherence. J Clin Epidemiol 2019;108:77-85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brignardello-Petersen R, Murad MH, Walter SD, McLeod S, Carrasco-Labra A, Rochwerg B, et al. GRADE approach to rate the certainty from a network meta-analysis: avoiding spurious judgments of imprecision in sparse networks. J Clin Epidemiol 2019;105:60-67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolff M, Hirner A. Current state of portosystemic shunt surgery. Langenbecks Arch Surg 2003;388:141-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
