<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34861050</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>530</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Structural changes in the neocortex as correlates of variations in EEG spectra and seizure susceptibility in rat brains with different degrees of dysplasia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1379</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1398</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1379-1398</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25282</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Disturbances of the early stages of neurogenesis lead to irreversible changes in the structure of the mature brain and its functional impairment, including increased excitability, which may be the basis for drug-resistant epilepsy. The range of possible clinical symptoms is as wide as the different stages of disturbed neurogenesis may be. In this study, we used a quadruple model of brain dysplasia by comparing structural and functional disorders in animals whose neurogenesis was disturbed with a single dose of 1 Gy of gamma rays at one of the four stages of neurogenesis, that is, on days 13, 15, 17, or 19 of prenatal development. When reached adulthood, the prenatally irradiated rats received EEG teletransmitter implantation. Thereafter, pilocarpine was administered and significant differences in susceptibility to seizure behavioral symptoms were detected depending on the degree of brain dysplasia. Before, during, and after the seizures significant correlations were found between the density of parvalbumin-immunopositive neurons located in the cerebral cortex and the intensity of behavioral seizure symptoms or increases in the power of particular EEG bands. Neurons expressing calretinin or NPY showed also dysplasia-related increases without, however, correlations with parameters of seizure intensity. The results point to significant roles of parvalbumin-expressing interneurons, and also to expression of NPY-an endogenous anticonvulsant and neuroprotectant reducing susceptibility to seizures and supporting neuronal survival.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. The Journal of Comparative Neurology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Setkowicz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zuzanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Experimental Neuropathology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Faculty of Biology, Jagiellonian University, Kraków, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gzielo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kinga</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Experimental Neuropathology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Faculty of Biology, Jagiellonian University, Kraków, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kielbinski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michal</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Experimental Neuropathology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Faculty of Biology, Jagiellonian University, Kraków, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Janeczko</LastName>
            <ForeName>Krzysztof</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9544-918X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Experimental Neuropathology, Institute of Zoology and Biomedical Research, Faculty of Biology, Jagiellonian University, Kraków, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <Agency>CIHR</Agency>
            <Country>Canada</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010320">Parvalbumins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004569" MajorTopicYN="N">Electroencephalography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019579" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neocortex</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010320" MajorTopicYN="N">Parvalbumins</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012640" MajorTopicYN="N">Seizures</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">NPY</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">calcium-binding proteins</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">calretinin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">disorders of neurogenesis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">dysplastic brain</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">epilepsy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gamma irradiation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">parvalbumin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861050</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25282</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali, I., Gandrathi, A., Zheng, T., Morris, M. J., O'Brien, T. J., &amp; French, C. (2018). Neuropeptide Y affects thalamic reticular nucleus neuronal firing and network synchronization associated with suppression of spike-wave discharges. Epilepsia, 59, 1444-1454. https://doi.org/10.1111/epi.14451</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arkan, S., Kasap, M., Akman, O., Akpinar, G., Ateş, N., &amp; Karson, A. (2019). The lower expression of parvalbumin in the primary somatosensory cortex of WAG/Rij rats may facilitate the occurrence of absence seizures. Neuroscience Letters, 709, 134299. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2019.134299</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aronica, E., Redeker, S., Boer, K., Spliet, W. G., van Rijen, P. C., Gorter, J. A., &amp; Troost, D. (2007). Inhibitory networks in epilepsy-associated gangliogliomas and in the perilesional epileptic cortex. Epilepsy Research, 74, 33-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baraban, S. C. (2004). Neuropeptide Y and epilepsy: Recent progress, prospects and controversies. Neuropeptides, 38, 261-265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baraban, S. C., Wenzel, H. J., Hochman, D. W., &amp; Schwartzkroin, P. A. (2000). Characterization of heterotopic cell clusters in the hippocampus of rats exposed to methylazoxymethanol in utero. Epilepsy Research, 39, 87-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barinka, F., &amp; Druga, R. (2010). Calretinin expression in the mammalian neocortex: A review. Physiological Research, 59, 665-677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barinka, F., Druga, R., Marusic, P., Krsek, P., &amp; Zamecnik, J. (2010). Calretinin immunoreactivity in focal cortical dysplasias and in non-malformed epileptic cortex. Epilepsy Research, 88, 76-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barkovich, A. J., Dobyns, W. B., &amp; Guerrini, R. (2015). Malformations of cortical development and epilepsy. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 5, a022392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartholome, O., de la Brassinne Bonardeaux, O., Neirinckx, V., &amp; Rogister, B. (2020). A composite sketch of fast-spiking parvalbumin-positive neurons. Cerebral Cortex Communications, 1, tgaa026.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Battaglia, G., Colciaghi, F., Finardi, A., &amp; Nobili, P. (2013). Intrinsic epileptogenicity of dysplastic cortex: Converging data from experimental models and human patients. Epilepsia, 54(Suppl 6), 33-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Battaglia, G., Pagliardini, S., Saglietti, L., Cattabeni, F., Di Luca, M., Bassanini, S., &amp; Setola, V. (2003). Neurogenesis in cerebral heterotopia induced in rats by prenatal methylazoxymethanol treatment. Cerebral Cortex, 13, 736-48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayer, S. A., Altman, J., Russo, R. J., &amp; Zhang, X. (1993). Timetables of neurogenesis in the human brain based on experimentally determined patterns in the rat. Neurotoxicology, 14, 83-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benardete, E. A., &amp; Kriegstein, A. R. (2002). Increased excitability and decreased sensitivity to GABA in an animal model of dysplastic cortex. Epilepsia, 43, 970-982.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blümcke, I., Beck, H., Suter, B., Hoffmann, D., Födisch, H. J., Wolf, H. K., Schramm, J., Elger, C. E., &amp; Wiestler, O. D. (1999). An increase of hippocampal calretinin-immunoreactive neurons correlates with early febrile seizures in temporal lobe epilepsy. Acta Neuropathologica, 97, 31-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blümcke, I., Thom, M., Aronica, E., Armstrong, D. D., Vinters, H. V., Palmini, A., Jacques, T. S., Avanzini, G., Barkovich, A. J., Battaglia, G., Becker, A., Cepeda, C., Cendes, F., Colombo, N., Crino, P., Cross, J. H., Delalande, O., Dubeau, F., Duncan, J., … Spreafico, R. (2011). The clinicopathologic spectrum of focal cortical dysplasias: A consensus classification proposed by an ad hoc task force of the ILAE diagnostic methods commission. Epilepsia, 52, 158-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardin, J. A. (2018). Inhibitory interneurons regulate temporal precision and correlations in cortical circuits. Trends in Neuroscience, 41, 689-700.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cataldi, M., &amp; Vigliotti, C. (2018). The evolving concept of the intrinsic hippocampal theta/gamma oscillator. Frontiers in Bioscience (Schol Ed), 10, 143-165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cavanagh, M. E., &amp; Parnavelas, J. G. (1990). Development of neuropeptide Y (NPY) immunoreactive neurons in the rat occipital cortex: A combined immunohistochemical-autoradiographic study. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 297, 553-563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, H. X., &amp; Roper, S. N. (2003). Reduction of spontaneous inhibitory synaptic activity in experimental heterotopic gray matter. Journal of Neurophysiology, 89, 150-158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark, R. M., Blizzard, C. A., Young, K. M., King, A. E., &amp; Dickson, T. C. (2017). Calretinin and Neuropeptide Y interneurons are differentially altered in the motor cortex of the SOD1G93A mouse model of ALS. Scientific Reports, 7, 44461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen, M. X. (2017). Where does EEG come from and what does it mean? Trends in Neuroscience, 40, 208-218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colciaghi, F., Finardi, A., Frasca, A., Balosso, S., Nobili, P., Carriero, G., Locatelli, D., Vezzani, A., &amp; Battaglia, G. (2011). Status epilepticus-induced pathologic plasticity in a rat model of focal cortical dysplasia. Brain, 134, 2828-2843.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Covolan, L., &amp; Mello, L. E. A. M. (2000). Temporal profile of neuronal injury following pilocarpine or kainic acid-induced status epilepticus. Epilepsy Research, 39, 133-152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curia, G., Longo, D., Biagini, G., Jones, R. S., &amp; Avoli, M. (2008). The pilocarpine model of temporal lobe epilepsy. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 172, 143-157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decressac, M., &amp; Barker, R. A. (2012). Neuropeptide Y and its role in CNS disease and repair. Experimental Neurology, 238, 265-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeFelipe, J. (1999). Chandelier cells and epilepsy. Brain, 122, 1807-1822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Quidt, M. E., &amp; Emson, P. C. (1986). Distribution of neuropeptide Y-like immunoreactivity in the rat central nervous system-II. Immunohistochemical analysis. Neuroscience, 18, 545-618.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deukmedjian, A. J., King, M. A., Cuda, C., &amp; Roper, S. N. (2004). The GABAergic system of the developing neocortex has a reduced capacity to recover from in utero injury in experimental cortical dysplasia. Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology, 12, 1265-1273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobolyi, A., Kékesi, K. A., Juhász, G., Székely, A. D., Lovas, G., &amp; Kovács, Z. (2014). Neuropeptides in epilepsy. Current Medicinal Chemistry, 21, 1-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Druga, R. (2009). Neocortical inhibitory system. Folia Biologica (Praha), 55, 201-217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fairén, A., Cobas, A., &amp; Fonseca, M. (1986). Times of generation of glutamic acid decarboxylase immunoreactive neurons in mouse somatosensory cortex. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 251, 67-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fairless, R., Williams, S. K., &amp; Diem, R. (2019). Calcium-binding proteins as determinants of central nervous system neuronal vulnerability to disease. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20, E2146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fazzari, P., Mortimer, N., Yabut, O., Vogt, D., &amp; Pla, R. (2020). Cortical distribution of GABAergic interneurons is determined by migration time and brain size. Development (Cambridge, England), 147, dev185033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldmeyer, D., Qi, G., Emmenegger, V., &amp; Staiger, J., &amp; F. (2018). Inhibitory interneurons and their circuit motifs in the many layers of the barrel cortex. Neuroscience, 368, 132-151. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2017.05.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filice, F., Vorckel, K. J., Sungur, A. O., Wöhr, M., &amp; Schwaller, B. (2016). Reduction in parvalbumin expression not loss of the parvalbumin-expressing GABA interneuron subpopulation in genetic parvalbumin and shank mouse models of autism. Molecular Brain, 9, 1-17. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13041-016-0192-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujisawa, S., &amp; Buzsáki, G. (2011). A 4 Hz oscillation adaptively synchronizes prefrontal, VTA, and hippocampal activities. Neuron, 72, 153-165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gall, D., Roussel, C., Susa, I., D'Angelo, E., Rossi, P., Bearzatto, R. P., Galas, M. C., Blum, D., Schurmans, S., &amp; Schiffmann, S. N. (2003). Altered neuronal excitability in cerebellar granule cells of mice lacking calretinin. Journal of Neuroscience, 23, 9320-9327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gelman, D. M., Marin, O., &amp; Rubenstein, L. R. (2012). The generation of cortical interneurons. In Jasper's basic mechanisms of the epilepsies (4th edn., pp. 1171-1186). Bethesda: National Center for Biotechnology Information (US). ISBN-13: 978-0199746545.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsieh, T.-H., Lee, H. H. C., Hameed, M. Q., Pascual-Leone, A., Hensch, T. K., &amp; Rotenberg, A. (2017). Trajectory of parvalbumin cell impairment and loss of cortical inhibition in traumatic brain injury. Cerebral Cortex, 27(12), 5509-5524. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhw318</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu, J. S., Vogt, D., Sandberg, M., &amp; Rubenstein, J. L. (2017). Cortical interneuron development a tale of time and space. Development (Cambridge, England), 144, 3867-3878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inouye, M., Hayasaka, S., Sun, X. Z., &amp; Yamamura, H. (1993). Disturbance of neuronal migration in mouse cerebral cortex by low-dose gamma-radiation. Journal of Radiation Research, 34, 204-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen, K. F., &amp; Killackey, H. P. (1984). Subcortical projections from ectopic neocortical neurons. Proceedings of National Acadademy of Science USA, 81, 964-968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jing, W., Wang, Y., Fang, G., Chen, M., Xue, M., Guo, D., Yao, D., &amp; Xia, Y. (2016). EEG bands of wakeful rest, slow-wave and rapid-eye-movement sleep at different brain areas in rats. Frontiers in Computational Neuroscience, 10, 79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawaguchi, Y., Otsuka, T., Morishima, M., Ushimaru, M., &amp; Kubota, Y. (2019). Control of excitatory hierarchical circuits by parvalbumin-FS basket cells in layer 5 of the frontal cortex: Insights for cortical oscillations. Journal of Neurophysiology, 121, 2222-2236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kellinghaus, C., Kunieda, T., Ying, Z., Pan, A., Lüders, H. O., &amp; Najm, I. M. (2004). Severity of histopathologic abnormalities and in vivo epileptogenicity in the in utero radiation model of rats is dose dependent. Epilepsia, 45, 583-591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kielbinski, M., Setkowicz, Z., Gzielo, K., Węglarz, W., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2018). Altered electroencephalography spectral profiles in rats with different patterns of experimental brain dysplasia. Birth Defects Research, 110, 303-316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondo, S., Najm, I., Kunieda, T., Perryman, S., Yacubova, K., &amp; Lüders, H. O. (2001). Electroencephalographic characterization of an adult rat model of radiation-induced cortical dysplasia. Epilepsia, 42, 1221-1227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubota, Y., Shigematsu, N., Karube, F., Sekigawa, A., Kato, S., Yamaguchi, N., Hirai, Y., Morishima, M., &amp; Kawaguchi, Y. (2011). Selective coexpression of multiple chemical markers defines discrete populations of neocortical GABAergic neurons. Cerebral Cortex, 21, 1803-1817. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhq252</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuchukhidze, G., Koppelstaetter, F., Unterberger, I., Dobesberger, J., Walser, G., Höfler, J., Zamarian, L., Haberlandt, E., Rostasy, K., Ortler, M., Czech, T., Feucht, M., Bauer, G., Delazer, M., Felber, S., &amp; Trinka, E. (2013). Midbrain-hindbrain malformations in patients with malformations of cortical development and epilepsy: A series of 220 patients. Epilepsy Research, 106, 181-190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luhmann, H. J. (2015). Models of cortical malformation-chemical and physical. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 260, 62-72. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneumeth.2015.03.034</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machin, D., Campbell, M., Fayers, P., &amp; Pinol, A. (2009). Sample size tables for clinical studies (3rd edn.). Oxford Singapore: Wiley-Blackwell. ISBN 978-1-4051-4650-0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacMullin, P., Hodgson, N., Damar, U., Lee, H. H. C., Hameed, M. Q., Dhamne, S. C., Hyde, D., Conley, G. M., Morriss, N., Qiu, J., Mannix, R., Hensch, T. K., &amp; Rotenberg, A. (2020). Increase in seizure susceptibility after repetitive concussion results from oxidative stress, parvalbumin-positive interneuron dysfunction and biphasic Increases in glutamate/GABA Ratio. Cerebral Cortex, 30, 6108-6120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mann, E. O., &amp; Paulsen, O. (2007). Role of GABAergic inhibition in hippocampal network oscillations. Trends in Neuroscience, 30, 343-349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marx, M., Haas, C. A., &amp; Haussler, U. (2013). Differential vulnerability of interneurons in the epileptic hippocampus. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 7, 167. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncel.2013.00167</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marksteiner, J., Sperk, G., &amp; Maas, D. (1989). Differential increases in brain levels of neuropeptide Y and vasoactive intestinal polypeptide after kainic acid-induced seizures in the rat. Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's Archives of Pharmacology, 339, 173-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyoshi, G., Butt, S. J. B., Takebayashi, H., &amp; Fishell, G. (2007). Physiologically distinct temporal cohorts of cortical interneurons arise from telencephalic Olig2-expressing precursors. Journal of Neuroscience, 27, 7786-7798.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyoshi, G., &amp; Fishell, G. (2011). GABAergic interneuron lineages selectively sort into specific cortical layers during early postnatal development. Cerebral Cortex, 21, 845-852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moroni, R. F., Inverardi, F., Regondi, M. C., Panzica, F., Spreafico, R., &amp; Frassoni, C. (2008). Altered spatial distribution of PV-cortical cells and dysmorphic neurons in the somatosensory cortex of BCNU-treated rat model of cortical dysplasia. Epilepsia, 49, 872-887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neske, G. T., Patrick, S. L., &amp; Connors, B. W. (2015). Contributions of diverse excitatory and inhibitory neurons to recurrent network activity in cerebral cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 35(3), 1089-1105. https://doi.org/10.1523/jneurosci.2279-14.2015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neske, G. T., &amp; Connors, B. W. (2016). Synchronized gamma-frequency inhibition in neocortex depends on excitatory-inhibitory interactions but not electrical synapses. Journal of Neurophysiology, 116, 351-368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orzeł-Gryglewska, J., Matulewicz, P., &amp; Jurkowlaniec, E. (2015). Brainstem system of hippocampal theta induction: The role of the ventral tegmental area. Synapse, 69, 553-575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papp, P., Kovács, Z., Szocsics, P., Juhász, G., &amp; Maglóczky, Z. (2018). Alterations in hippocampal and cortical densities of functionally different interneurons in rat models of absence epilepsy. Epilepsy Research, 145, 40-50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paxinos, G., &amp; Watson, C. (1998). The rat brain in stereotaxic coordinates (2nd edn.). London, San Diego: Academic Press, Inc. ISBN 0-12-547617-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfeffer, C. K., Xue, M., He, M., Huang, Z. J., &amp; Scanziani, M. (2013). Inhibition of inhibition in visual cortex: The logic of connections between molecularly distinct interneurons. Nature Neuroscience, 16, 1068-1076.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pignatelli, M., Beyeler, A., &amp; Leinekugel, X. (2012). Neural circuits underlying the generation of theta oscillations. Journal of Physiology-Paris, 106, 81-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rankin-Gee, E. K., McRae, P. A., Baranov, E., Rogers, S., Wandrey, L., &amp; Porter, B. E. (2015). Perineuronal net degradation in epilepsy. Epilepsia, 56, 1124-1133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roper, S. N., Eisenschenk, S., &amp; King, M. A. (1999). Reduced density of parvalbumin- and calbindin D28-immunoreactive neurons in experimental cortical dysplasia. Epilepsy Research, 37, 63-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rymar, V. V., &amp; Sadikot, A. F. (2007). Laminar fate of cortical GABAergic interneurons is dependent on both birthdate and phenotype. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 501, 369-380. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21250</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rudy, B., Fishell, G., Lee, S., &amp; Hjerling-Leffler, J. (2011). Three groups of interneurons account for nearly 100% of neocortical GABAergic neurons. Developmental Neurobiology, 71, 45-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saito, S., Sawada, K., Hirose, M., Mori, Y., Yoshioka, Y., &amp; Murase, K. (2014). Diffusion tensor imaging of brain abnormalities induced by prenatal exposure to radiation in rodents. Plos One, 9, e107368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwaller, B., Tetko, I. V., Tandon, P., Silveira, D. C., Vreugdenhil, M., Henzi, T., Potier, M. C., Celio, M. R., &amp; Villa, A. E. (2004). Parvalbumin deficiency affects network properties resulting in increased susceptibility to epileptic seizures. Molecular and Cellular Neuroscience, 25, 650-663.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., Gzieło-Jurek, K., Uram, Ł., Janicka, D., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2014). Brain dysplasia evoked by gamma irradiation at different stages of prenatal development leads to different tonic and clonic seizure reactivity. Epilepsy Research, 108, 66-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2003). Long-term changes in susceptibility to pilocarpine-induced status epilepticus following neocortical injuries in the rat at different developmental stages. Epilepsy Research, 53, 216-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2005). A strong epileptogenic effect of mechanical injury can be reduced in the dysplastic rat brain. Long-term consequences of early prenatal gamma-irradiation. Epilepsy Research, 66, 165-172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., Janicka, D., Kowalczyk, A., Turlej, A., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2005). Congenital brain dysplasias of different genesis can differently affect susceptibility to pilocarpine- or kainic acid-induced seizures in the rat. Epilepsy Research, 67, 123-131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., Klak, K., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2003). Long-term changes in postnatal susceptibility to pilocarpine-induced seizures in rats exposed to gamma radiation at different stages of prenatal development. Epilepsia, 44, 1267-1273. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1528-1157.2003.08203.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., Majcher, K., Janicka, D., Sułek, Z., Skórka, T., Jasiński, A., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2006). Brains with different degrees of dysplasia show different patterns of neurodegenerative changes following pilocarpine-induced seizures. Histological evidence of tissue damage correlated with MRI data. Neurological Research, 28, 453-460. https://doi.org/10.1179/016164106X115062</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setkowicz, Z., Kiełbinski, M., Gzieło, K., Węglarz, W., &amp; Janeczko, K. (2020). Changes of EEG spectra in rat brains with different patterns of dysplasia in response to pilocarpine-induced seizures. Epilepsy and Behavior, 111, 107288.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sohal, V. S., Zhang, F., Yizhar, O., &amp; Deisseroth, K. (2009). Parvalbumin neurons and gamma rhythms enhance cortical circuit performance. Nature, 459, 698-702.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun, X. Z., Takahashi, S., Fukui, Y., Hisano, S., Kuboda, Y., Sato, H., &amp; Inouye, M. (1999). Different patterns of abnormal neuronal migration in the cerebral cortex of mice prenatally exposed to irradiation. Brain Research, Developmental Brain Research, 114, 99-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taniguchi, H., Lu, J., &amp; Huang, Z. J. (2013). The spatial and temporal origin of chandelier cells in mouse neocortex. Science, 339, 70-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tewari, B. P., Chaunsali, L., Campbell, S. L., Patel, D. C., Goode, A. E., &amp; Sontheimer, H. (2018). Perineuronal nets decrease membrane capacitance of peritumoral fast spiking interneurons in a model of epilepsy. Nature Communications, 9, 4724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toth, K., &amp; Magloczky, Z. (2014). The vulnerability of calretinin-containing hippocampal interneurons to temporal lobe epilepsy. Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 8, 100. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2014.00100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tremblay, R., Lee, S., &amp; Rudy, B. (2016). GABAergic interneurons in the neocortex: From cellular properties to circuits. Neuron, 91, 260-292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tschuluun, N., Jürgen Wenzel, H., Doisy, E. T., &amp; Schwartzkroin, P. A. (2011). Initiation of epileptiform activity in a rat model of periventricular nodular heterotopia. Epilepsia, 52, 2304-2314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turski, W. A., Cavalheiro, E. A., Schwarz, M., Czuczwar, S. J., Kleinrok, Z., &amp; Turski, L. (1983). Limbic seizures produced by pilocarpine in rats: Behavioural, electroencephalographic and neuropathological study. Behavioral Brain Research, 9, 315-335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Raay, L., Jovanovska, V., Morris, M. J., &amp; O'Brien, T. J. (2012). Focal administration of neuropeptide Y into the S2 somatosensory cortex maximally suppresses absence seizures in a genetic rat model. Epilepsia, 53, 477-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verreet, T., Verslegers, M., Quintens, R., Baatout, S., &amp; Benotmane, M. A. (2016). Current evidence for developmental, structural, and functional brain defects following prenatal radiation exposure. Neural Plasticity, 2016, 1243527.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vezzani, A., &amp; Sperk, G. (2004) Overexpression of NPY and Y2 receptors in epileptic brain tissue: An endogenous neuroprotective mechanism in temporal lobe epilepsy? Neuropeptides, 38, 245-252,</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wahlestedt, C., Blendy, J. A., Kellar, K. J., Heilig, M., Widerlöv, E., &amp; Ekman, R. (1990). Electroconvulsive shocks increase the concentration of neocortical and hippocampal neuropeptide Y (NPY)-like immunoreactivity in the rat. Brain Research, 507, 65-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West, M. J., &amp; Gundersen, H. J. G. (1990). Unbiased stereological estimation of the number of neurons in the human hippocampus. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 296, 1-22. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.902960102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whittington, M. A., Cunningham, M. O., LeBeau, F. E., Racca, C., &amp; Traub, R. D. (2011). Multiple origins of the cortical? rhythm. Developmental Neurobiology, 71, 92-106. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.20814</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xapelli, S., Silva, A. P., Ferreira, R., &amp; Malva, J. O. (2007). Neuropeptide Y can rescue neurons from cell death following the application of an excitotoxic insult with kainate in rat organotypic hippocampal slice cultures. Peptides, 28, 288-294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamecnik, J., Krsek, P., Druga, R., Marusic, P., Benes, V., Tichy, M., &amp; Komarek, V. (2006). Densities of parvalbumin-immunoreactive neurons in non-malformed hippocampal sclerosis-temporal neocortex and in cortical dysplasias. Brain Research Bulletin, 68, 474-481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, F. W., &amp; Roper, S. N. (2010a). Densities of glutamatergic and GABAergic presynaptic terminals are altered in experimental cortical dysplasia. Epilepsia, 51, 1468-1476. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1528-1167.2010.02583.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, F. W., &amp; Roper, S. N. (2010b). Altered firing rates and patterns in interneurons in experimental cortical dysplasia. Cerebral Cortex, 21, 1645-1658. https://doi.org/10.1093/cercor/bhq234</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
