<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34882594</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2163-0763</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>92</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The journal of trauma and acute care surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The tight rope act: A multicenter regional experience of tourniquets in acute trauma resuscitation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>890</StartPage>
          <EndPage>896</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>890-896</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/TA.0000000000003491</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">As tourniquets have become more prevalent, device use has been questioned. This study sought to characterize the incidence, indication, and efficacy of tourniquet placement in acute trauma resuscitation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Nine regional level 1 trauma centers prospectively enrolled for 12 months adult patients (18 years or older) who had a tourniquet placed. Age, sex, mechanism, tourniquet type, indication, applying personnel, location placed, level of occlusion, and degree of hemostasis were collected. Major vascular injury, imaging and operations performed, and outcomes were assessed. Analyses were performed with significance at p &lt; 0.05.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 216 tourniquet applications were reported on 209 patients. There were significantly more male patients (183 [88%]) and penetrating injuries (186 [89%]) with gunshots being most common (127 [61%]). Commercial tourniquets were most often used (205 [95%]). Ninety-two percent were placed in the prehospital setting (by fire/paramedics, 56%; police, 33%; bystanders, 2%). The most common indications were pooling (47%) and pulsatile (32%) hemorrhage. Only 2% were for amputation. The most frequent location was high proximal extremity (70%). Four percent were placed over the wound, and 0.5% were distal to the wound. Only 61% of applications were arterial occlusive. Median application time was 30 minutes (interquartile range, 20-40 minutes). Imaging was performed in 54% of patients. Overall, 36% had a named arterial injury. Tourniquet application failed to achieve hemostasis in 22% of patients with a named vascular injury. There was no difference in hemostasis between those with and without vascular injury (p = 0.12) or between who placed the tourniquet (p = 0.07). Seventy patients (34%) required vascular operations. Thirty-four percent of patients were discharged home without admission.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Discerning which injuries require tourniquets over pressure dressings remains elusive. Trained responders had high rates of superfluous and inadequate deployments. As tourniquets continue to be disseminated, emphasis should be placed on improving education, device development, and quality control.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">Prognostic/Epidemiologic, Level III.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tatebe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Leah Carey</ForeName>
            <Initials>LC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Trauma and Burn Surgery (L.C.T., V.S., A.D.), Cook County Health, Rush University, Midwestern University, Chicago, Illinois; Department of Surgery (D.H.), University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois; Department of Surgery (G.C., I.H.), Mount Sinai Hospital, Chicago, Illinois; Department of Surgery (J.D.), Advocate Christ Medical Center, Oak Lawn, Illinois; Department of Surgery (N.I.), Northwestern University, Chicago, Illinois; Department of Surgery (H.G., S.K.), Advocate Illinois Masonic Medical Center, Chicago, Illinois; Department of Surgery (A.S.), Advocate Lutheran General Hospital, Park Ridge, Illinois; and Department of Surgery (M.A.), Loyola University, Maywood, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schlanser</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victoria</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hampton</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Grace</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hanson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Isaac</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Doherty</LastName>
            <ForeName>James</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Issa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nabil</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghandour</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hani</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kingsley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samuel</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stewart</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amy</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Anstadt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dennis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrew</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Trauma Acute Care Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101570622</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2163-0755</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004632" MajorTopicYN="Y">Emergency Medical Services</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012151" MajorTopicYN="N">Resuscitation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014111" MajorTopicYN="N">Tourniquets</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057772" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vascular System Injuries</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34882594</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TA.0000000000003491</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">01586154-202205000-00015</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs LM Jr; Joint Committee to Create a National Policy to Enhance Survivability from Intentional Mass-Casualty and Active Shooter Events. The Hartford Consensus III. Implementation of bleeding control. J Spec Oper Med. 2015;15(4):136–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kragh JF Jr, Dubick MA, Aden JK, McKeague AL, Rasmussen TE, Baer DG, Blackbourne LH. U.S. Military use of tourniquets from 2001 to 2010. Prehosp Emerg Care. 2015;19(2):184–190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AA, Ochoa JE, Wong S, Beatty S, Elder J, Guidry C, McGrew P, McGinness C, Duchesne J, Schroll R. Prehospital tourniquet use in penetrating extremity trauma: decreased blood transfusions and limb complications. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2019;86(1):43–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scerbo MH, Holcomb JB, Taub E, Gates K, Love JD, Wade CE, Cotton BA. The trauma center is too late: major limb trauma without a pre-hospital tourniquet has increased death from hemorrhagic shock. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2017;83(6):1165–1172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ode G, Studnek J, Seymour R, Bosse MJ, Hsu JR. Emergency tourniquets for civilians: can military lessons in extremity hemorrhage be translated?J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2015;79(4):586–591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroll R, Smith A, McSwain NE Jr, Myers J, Rocchi K, Inaba K, Siboni S, Vercruysse GA, Ibrahim-Zada I, Sperry JL, et al. A multi-institutional analysis of prehospital tourniquet use. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2015;79(1):10–14; discussion 4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry R, Matsushima K, Ghafil C, Henry RN, Theeuwen H, Golden AC, Abramson TM, Inaba K. Increased use of prehospital tourniquet and patient survival: Los Angeles countywide study. J Am Coll Surg. 2021;233(2):233–9.e2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montgomery HR, Hammesfahr R, Fisher AD, Cain JS, Greydanus DJ, Butler FK Jr, Goolsby C, Eastman AL. 2019 recommended limb tourniquets in tactical combat casualty care. J Spec Oper Med. 2019;19(4):27–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsnelson S, Oppenheimer J, Gerrasi R, Furer A, Wagnert-Avraham L, Eisenkraft A, Nachman D. Assessing the current generation of tourniquets. Mil Med. 2020;185(3–4):e377–e382.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dennis A, Bajani F, Schlanser V, Tatebe LC, Impens A, Ivkovic K, Li A, Pickett T, Butler C, Kaminsky M, et al. Missing expectations: windlass tourniquet use without formal training yields poor results. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2019;87(5):1096–1103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlanser VL, Tatebe LC, Karalius VP, Liesen E, Pekarek S, Impens A, Ivkovic K, Bajani F, Khalifa A, Dennis AJ. The windlass tourniquet: is it taking the wind out of the “stop the bleed” sails?J Surg Res. 2021;271:91–97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cremonini C, Nee N, Demarest M, Piccinini A, Minneti M, Canamar CP, Benjami ER, Demetriades D, Inaba K. Evaluation of the efficacy of commercial and noncommercial tourniquets for extremity hemorrhage control in a perfused cadaver model. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2021;90(3):522–526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarty JC, Caterson EJ, Chaudhary MA, Herrera-Escobar JP, Hashmi ZG, Goldberg SA, Goolsby C, Lipsitz S, Haider AH, Goralnick E. Can they stop the bleed? Evaluation of tourniquet application by individuals with varying levels of prior self-reported training. Injury. 2019;50(1):10–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duignan KM, Lamb LC, DiFiori MM, Quinlavin J, Feeney JM. Tourniquet use in the prehospital setting: are they being used appropriately?Am J Disaster Med. 2018;13(1):37–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothschild HR, Mathieson K. Effects of tactical emergency casualty care training for law enforcement officers. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2018;33(5):495–500.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jerome JE, Pons PT, Haukoos JS, Manson J, Gravitz S. Tourniquet application by urban police officers: the Aurora, Colorado experience. J Spec Oper Med. 2021;21(1):71–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baruch EN, Kragh JF Jr, Berg AL, Aden JK Rd, Benov A, Shina A, Shlaifer A, Ahimor A, Glassberg E, Yitzhak A. Confidence-competence mismatch and reasons for failure of non-medical tourniquet users. Prehosp Emerg Care. 2017;21(1):39–45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)—a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009;42(2):377–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beekley AC, Sebesta JA, Blackbourne LH, Herbert GS, Kauvar DS, Baer DG, Walters TJ, Mullenix PS, Holcomb JB; 31st Combat Support Hospital Research Group. Prehospital tourniquet use in Operation Iraqi Freedom: effect on hemorrhage control and outcomes. J Trauma. 2008;64(Suppl 2):S28–S37; discussion S.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teixeira PGR, Brown CVR, Emigh B, Long M, Foreman M, Eastridge B, Gale S, Truitt MS, Dissanaike S, Duane T, et al. Civilian prehospital tourniquet use is associated with improved survival in patients with peripheral vascular injury. J Am Coll Surg. 2018;226(5):769–776.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El Sayed MJ, Tamim H, Mailhac A, Mann NC. Trends and predictors of limb tourniquet use by civilian emergency medical services in the United States. Prehosp Emerg Care. 2017;21(1):54–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doyle GS. Tourniquet First!: Journal of Emergency Medical Services; 2010. Available at: https://www.jems.com/operations/tourniquet-first/. Accessed August 16, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kragh JF Jr., Aden JK 3rd, Dubick MA. Tourniquets last to tourniquets first. J Spec Oper Med. 2020;20(2):20–21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chicago Fire Department. Extremity Trauma/External Hemorrhage Management: Region XI Chicago EMS System Protocol. Available at: https://chicagoems.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Extremity-Trauma_Extremity-Hemorrhage-Management_FINAL.pdf. Accessed August 16, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inaba K, Siboni S, Resnick S, Zhu J, Wong MD, Haltmeier T, Benjamin E, Demetriades D. Tourniquet use for civilian extremity trauma. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2015;79(2):232–237;quiz 332–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kauvar DS, Dubick MA, Walters TJ, Kragh JF Jr. Systematic review of prehospital tourniquet use in civilian limb trauma. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2018;84(5):819–825.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarty JC, Hashmi ZG, Herrera-Escobar JP, de Jager E, Chaudhary MA, Lipsitz SR, Jarman M, Caterson EJ, Goralnick E. Effectiveness of the American College of Surgeons bleeding control basic training among laypeople applying different tourniquet types: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg. 2019;154(10):923–929.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goralnick E, Chaudhary MA, McCarty JC, Caterson EJ, Goldberg SA, Herrera-Escobar JP, McDonald M, Lipsitz S, Haider AH. Effectiveness of instructional interventions for hemorrhage control readiness for laypersons in the Public Access and Tourniquet Training Study (PATTS): a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Surg. 2018;153(9):791–799.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pasley AM, Parker BM, Levy MJ, Christiani A, Dubose J, Brenner ML, Scalea T, Pasley JD. Stop the bleed: does the training work one month out?Am Surg. 2018;84(10):1635–1638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinman S. Retention of tourniquet application skills following participation in a bleeding control course. J Emerg Nurs. 2020;46(2):154–162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis J, Morrow MM, Belau A, Sztajnkrycer LS, Wood JN, Kummer T, Sztajnkrycer MD. The efficacy of novel commercial tourniquet designs for extremity hemorrhage control: implications for spontaneous responder every day carry. Prehosp Disaster Med. 2020;35(3):276–280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee C, Porter KM, Hodgetts TJ. Tourniquet use in the civilian prehospital setting. Emerg Med J. 2007;24(8):584–587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taghavi S, Maher Z, Goldberg AJ, Chang G, Mendiola M, Anderson C, Ninokawa S, Tatebe LC, Maluso P, Raza S, et al. An Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma multicenter trial examining prehospital procedures in penetrating trauma patients. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2021;91(1):130–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramly E, Runyan G, King DR. The state of the union: nationwide absence of uniform guidelines for the prehospital use of tourniquets to control extremity exsanguination. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2016;80(5):787–791.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
