<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34888828</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2021</Year>
        <Month>12</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2190-5215</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>26</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Advances in neurobiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Adv Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neuroglia in Psychiatric Disorders.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>3</StartPage>
          <EndPage>19</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>3-19</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/978-3-030-77375-5_1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>In the twentieth century, neuropsychiatric disorders have been perceived solely from a neurone-centric point of view, which considers neurones as the key cellular elements of pathological processes. This dogma has been challenged thanks to the better comprehension of the brain functioning, which, even if far from being complete, has revealed the complexity of interactions that exist between neurones and neuroglia. Glial cells represent a highly heterogeneous population of cells of neural (astroglia and oligodendroglia) and non-neural (microglia) origin populating the central nervous system. The variety of glia reflects the innumerable functions that glial cells perform to support functions of the nervous system. Aberrant execution of glial functions contributes to the development of neuropsychiatric pathologies. Arguably, all types of glial cells are implicated in the neuropathology; however, astrocytes have received particular attention in recent years because of their pleiotropic functions that make them decisive in maintaining cerebral homeostasis. This chapter describes the multiple roles of astrocytes in the healthy central nervous system and discusses the diversity of astroglial responses in neuropsychiatric disorders suggesting that targeting astrocytes may represent an effective therapeutic strategy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive license to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Scuderi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Caterina</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Pharmacology "Vittorio Erspamer", SAPIENZA University of Rome, Rome, Italy. caterina.scuderi@uniroma1.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Verkhratsky</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexei</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Biology, Medicine and Health, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Achucarro Center for Neuroscience, IKERBASQUE, Basque Foundation for Science, Bilbao, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Parpura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vladimir</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurobiology, The University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, AL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Baoman</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Forensic Analytical Toxicology, School of Forensic Medicine, China Medical University, Shenyang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 GM123971</GrantID>
            <Acronym>GM</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Adv Neurobiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101571545</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001253" MajorTopicYN="N">Astrocytes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Disorders</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017628" MajorTopicYN="N">Microglia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009457" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuroglia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Astrocyte</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Astrogliopathy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Homeostatic functions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NG-2 glia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychiatric disorders</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oligodendrocytes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>59</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34888828</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1794177</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9063382</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-77375-5_1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbott NJ, Patabendige AA, Dolman DE, Yusof SR, Begley DJ (2010) Structure and function of the blood-brain barrier. Neurobiol Dis
37:13–25</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19664713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aida T, Yoshida J, Nomura M, Tanimura A, Iino Y, Soma M, Bai N, Ito Y, Cui W, Aizawa H, Yanagisawa M, Nagai T, Takata N, Tanaka KF, Takayanagi R, Kano M, Götz M, Hirase H, Tanaka K (2015) Astroglial glutamate transporter deficiency increases synaptic excitability and leads to pathological repetitive behaviors in mice. Neuropsychopharmacology
2015(40):1569–7159</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexandra IM, Constanze D, Klaus-Armin N (2018) An emerging role of dysfunctional axonoligodendrocyte coupling in neurodegenerative diseases. Dialogues Clin Neurosci
20:283–292</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6436955</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30936768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almeida RG, Lyons DA (2017) On myelinated axon plasticity and neuronal circuit formation and function. J Neurosci
37:10023–10034</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6596541</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29046438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attwell D, Buchan AM, Charpak S, Lauritzen M, Macvicar BA, Newman EA (2010) Glial and neuronal control of brain blood flow. Nature
468:232–243</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3206737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21068832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayata P, Badimon A, Strasburger HJ
et al. (2018) Epigenetic regulation of brain region-specific microglia clearance activity. Nat Neurosci
21:1049–1060. 10.1038/s41593-018-0192-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-018-0192-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30038282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azim K, Angonin D, Marcy G, Pieropan F, Rivera A, Donega V, Cantu C, Williams G, Berninger B, Butt AM, Raineteau O (2017) Pharmacogenomic identification of small molecules for lineage specific manipulation of subventricular zone germinal activity. PLoS Biol
15:e2000698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5370089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28350803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bear MF, Connors BW, Paradiso MA (2007) Exploring the brain. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Philadelphia</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedner P, Dupper A, Huttmann K, Muller J, Herde MK, Dublin P, Deshpande T, Schramm J, Haussler U, Haas CA, Henneberger C, Theis M, Steinhauser C (2015) Astrocyte uncoupling as a cause of human temporal lobe epilepsy. Brain
138:1208–1222</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5963418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25765328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergles DE, Roberts JD, Somogyi P, Jahr CE (2000) Glutamatergic synapses on oligodendrocyte precursor cells in the hippocampus. Nature
405:187–191</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10821275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergles DE, Richardson WD (2015) Oligodendrocyte development and plasticity. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol
8(2):a020453. 10.1101/cshperspect.a020453</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a020453</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4743079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26492571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronzuoli MR, Facchinetti R, Ingrassia D, Sarvadio M, Schiavi S, Steardo L, Verkhratsky A, Trezza V, Scuderi C (2018a) Neuroglia in the autistic brain: evidence from a preclinical model. Mol Autism
9:66. 10.1186/s13229-018-0254-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13229-018-0254-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6307226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30603062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronzuoli MR, Facchinetti R, Steardo L Jr, Romano A, Stecca C, Passarella S, Steardo L, Cassano T, Scuderi C (2018b) Palmitoylethanolamide dampens reactive astrogliosis and improves neuronal trophic support in a triple transgenic model of Alzheimer’s disease: in vitro and in vivo evidence. Oxid Med Cell Longev
16:4720532. 10.1155/2018/4720532</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/4720532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butt AM, Ransom BR (1989) Visualization of oligodendrocytes and astrocytes in the intact rat optic nerve by intracellular injection of lucifer yellow and horseradish peroxidase. Glia
2:470–475</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2531727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butt AM, Papanikolaou M, Rivera A (2019) Physiology of oligodendroglia. In: Verkhratsky A, Ho M, Zorec R, Parpura V (eds) Neuroglia in neurodegenerative diseases. Advances in experimental medicine and biology, vol 1175. Springer, Singapore. 10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cartier N, Lewis C-A, Zhang R, Rossi FMV (2014) The role of microglia in human disease: therapeutic tool or target?
Acta Neuropathol
128:363–380. 10.1007/s00401-014-1330-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-014-1330-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4131134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25107477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colombo JA (2018) Interlaminar glia and other glial themes revisited: pending answers following three decades of glial research. Neuroglia
1:7–20</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham CL, Martínez-Cerdeño V, Noctor SC (2013) Microglia regulate the number of neural precursor cells in the developing cerebral cortex. J Neurosci
33:4216–4233. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3441-12.2013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3441-12.2013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3711552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23467340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czeh B, Nagy SA (2018) Clinical findings documenting cellular and molecular abnormalities of glia in depressive disorders. Front Mol Neurosci
11:56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5835102</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29535607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dare E, Schulte G, Karovic O, Hammarberg C, Fredholm BB (2007) Modulation of glial cell functions by adenosine receptors. Physiol Behav
92:15–20</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17574632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>das Neves SP, Sousa JC, Sousa N, Cerqueira JJ, Marques F (2020) Altered astrocytic function in experimental neuroinflammation and multiple sclerosis. Glia
69(6):1341–1368. 10.1002/glia.23940</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.23940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33247866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies DL, Cox WE (1991) Delayed growth and maturation of astrocytic cultures following exposure to ethanol: electron microscopic observations. Brain Res
547:53–61</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1860071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deitmer JW, Rose CR (1996) pH regulation and proton signalling by glial cells. Prog Neurobiol
48:73–103</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8737439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elbaz B, Popko B (2019) Molecular control of oligodendrocyte development. Trends Neurosci
42:263–277</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7397568</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30770136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escartin C, Galea E, Lakatos A, O’Callaghan JP, Petzold GC, Serrano-Pozo A, Steinhauser C, Volterra A, Carmignoto G, Agarwal A, Allen NJ, Araque A, Luis Barbeito L, Barzilai A, Bergles DE, Bonvento G, Butt AM, Chen W-T, Cohen-Salmon M, Cunningham C, Deneen B, De Strooper B, Díaz-Castro B, Farina C, Freeman M, Gallo V, Goldman JE, Goldman SA, Götz M, Gutiérrez A, Haydon PG, Heiland DH, Hol EM, Holt MG, Iino M, Kastanenka KV, Kettenmann H, Khakh BS, Koizumi S, Lee CJ, Liddelow SA, MacVicar BA, Magistretti P, Messing A, Mishra A, Molofsky AV, Murai K, Norris CM, Okada S, SHR O, Oliveira JF, Panatier A, Parpura V, Pekna M, Pekny M, Pellerin L, Perea G, Pérez-Nievas BG, Pfrieger FW, Poskanzer KE, Quintana FJ, Ransohoff RM, Riquelme-Perez M, Robel S, Rose CR, Rothstein J, Rouach N, Rowitch DH, Semyanov A, Sirko S, Sontheimer H, Swanson RA, Vitorica J, Wanner I-B, Wood LB, Wu J, Zheng B, Zimmer ER, Zorec R, Sofroniew MV, Verkhratsky A (2021) Working consensus on reactive astrocyte nomenclature, definitions and future directions. Nat Neurosci
24(3):312–325. 10.1038/s41593-020-00783-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41593-020-00783-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8007081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33589835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrer I (2018) Astrogliopathy in tauopathies. Neuroglia
1:126–150</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franke H, Grosche J, Schadlich H, Krugel U, Allgaier C, Illes P (2001) P2X receptor expression on astrocytes in the nucleus accumbens of rats. Neuroscience
108:421–429</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fumagalli M, Brambilla R, D’Ambrosi N, Volonte C, Matteoli M, Verderio C, Abbracchio MP (2003) Nucleotide-mediated calcium signaling in rat cortical astrocytes: role of P2X and P2Y receptors. Glia
43:218–230</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12898701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Funfschilling U, Supplie LM, Mahad D, Boretius S, Saab AS, Edgar J, Brinkmann BG, Kassmann CM, Tzvetanova ID, Mobius W, Diaz F, Meijer D, Suter U, Hamprecht B, Sereda MW, Moraes CT, Frahm J, Goebbels S, Nave KA (2012) Glycolytic oligodendrocytes maintain myelin and long-term axonal integrity. Nature
485:517–521</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3613737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22622581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giaume C, Koulakoff A, Roux L, Holcman D, Rouach N (2010) Astroglial networks: a step further in neuroglial and gliovascular interactions. Nat Rev Neurosci
11:87–99</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20087359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginhoux F, Greter M, Leboeuf M
et al. (2010) Fate mapping analysis reveals that adult microglia derive from primitive macrophages. Science
330:841–845. 10.1126/science.1194637</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1194637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3719181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20966214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham AJ, Ray MA, Perry EK, Jaros E, Perry RH, Volsen SG, Bose S, Evans N, Lindstrom J, Court JA (2003) Differential nicotinic acetylcholine receptor subunit expression in the human hippocampus. J Chem Neuroanat
25:97–113</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12663058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griemsmann S, Hoft SP, Bedner P, Zhang J, von Staden E, Beinhauer A, Degen J, Dublin P, Cope DW, Richter N, Crunelli V, Jabs R, Willecke K, Theis M, Seifert G, Kettenmann H, Steinhauser C (2015) Characterization of panglial gap junction networks in the thalamus, neocortex, and hippocampus reveals a unique population of glial cells. Cereb Cortex
25:3420–3433</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4585496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25037920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grubisic V, Verkhratsky A, Zorec R, Parpura V (2018) Enteric glia regulate gut motility in health and disease. Brain Res Bull
136:109–117</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5620110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28363846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerri C, Renau-Piqueras J (1997) Alcohol, astroglia, and brain development. Mol Neurobiol
15:65–81</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9396005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habermacher C, Angulo MC, Benamer N (2019) Glutamate versus GABA in neuron-oligodendroglia communication. Glia
67(11):2092–2106. 10.1002/glia.23618</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.23618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30957306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halestrap AP (2012) The monocarboxylate transporter family—structure and functional characterization. IUBMB Life
64:1–9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22131303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanani M, Verkhratsky A (2021) Satellite glial cells and astrocytes, a comparative review. Neurochem Res:1–13. 10.1007/s11064-021-03255-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11064-021-03255-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heneka MT, Rodriguez JJ, Verkhratsky A (2010) Neuroglia in neurodegeneration. Brain Res Rev
63:189–211</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19944719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hertz L, Dringen R, Schousboe A, Robinson SR (1999) Astrocytes: glutamate producers for neurons. J Neurosci Res
57:417–428</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10440891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hertz L, Lovatt D, Goldman SA, Nedergaard M (2010) Adrenoceptors in brain: cellular gene expression and effects on astrocytic metabolism and [Ca2+]i. Neurochem Int
57:411–420</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2934885</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20380860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hertz L, Song D, Xu J, Peng L, Gibbs ME (2015) Role of the astrocytic Na+, K+-ATPase in K+ homeostasis in brain: K+ uptake, signaling pathways and substrate utilization. Neurochem Res
40:2505–2516</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilgetag CC, Barbas H (2009) Are there ten times more glia than neurons in the brain?
Brain Struct Funct
213:365–366</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19198876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hol EM, Pekny M (2015) Glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) and the astrocyte intermediate filament system in diseases of the central nervous system. Curr Opin Cell Biol
32:121–130</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25726916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houades V, Koulakoff A, Ezan P, Seif I, Giaume C (2008) Gap junction-mediated astrocytic networks in the mouse barrel cortex. J Neurosci
28:5207–5217</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6670639</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18480277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kandel ER, Schwartz JH, Jessell TM (2000) Principles of neural science. McGrawhill, New York</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kane CJ, Berry A, Boop FA, Davies DL (1996) Proliferation of astroglia from the adult human cerebrum is inhibited by ethanol in vitro. Brain Res
731:39–44</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8883852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kettenmann H, Hanisch UK, Noda M, Verkhratsky A (2011) Physiology of microglia. Physiol Rev
91:461–553</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21527731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kettenmann H, Kirchhoff F, Verkhratsky A (2013) Microglia: new roles for the synaptic stripper. Neuron
77:10–18</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23312512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kettenmann H, Zorec R (2013) Release of gliotransmitters and transmitter receptors in astrocytes. In: Kettenmann H, Ransom BR (eds) Neuroglia. Oxford University Press, New York, pp 197–211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kidd GJ, Ohno N, Trapp BD (2013) Biology of Schwann cells. Handb Clin Neurol
115:55–79</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23931775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiray H, Lindsay SL, Hosseinzadeh S, Barnett SC (2016) The multifaceted role of astrocytes in regulating myelination. Exp Neurol
283:541–549</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5019113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26988764</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirchhoff F, Mulhardt C, Pastor A, Becker CM, Kettenmann H (1996) Expression of glycine receptor subunits in glial cells of the rat spinal cord. J Neurochem
66:1383–1390</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8627289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirischuk S, Kettenmann H, Verkhratsky A (2007) Membrane currents and cytoplasmic sodium transients generated by glutamate transport in Bergmann glial cells. Pflugers Arch
454:245–252</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17273865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kofuji P, Newman EA (2004) Potassium buffering in the central nervous system. Neuroscience
129:1045–1056</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2322935</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15561419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korbo L (1999) Glial cell loss in the hippocampus of alcoholics. Alcohol Clin Exp Res
23:164–168</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10029219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn S, Gritti L, Crooks D, Dombrowski Y (2019) Oligodendrocytes in development, myelin generation and beyond. Cells
8(11):1424</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lalo U, Pankratov Y, Kirchhoff F, North RA, Verkhratsky A (2006) NMDA receptors mediate neuron-to-glia signaling in mouse cortical astrocytes. J Neurosci
26:2673–2683</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6675155</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16525046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanciotti A, Brignone MS, Bertini E, Petrucci TC, Aloisi F, Ambrosini E (2013) Astrocytes: emerging stars in leukodystrophy pathogenesis. Transl Neurosci
4(2):144–164</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larson VA, Zhang Y, Bergles DE (2016) Electrophysiological properties of NG2 + cells: matching physiological studies with gene expression profiles. Brain Res
1638:138–160</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26385417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee Y, Morrison BM, Li Y, Lengacher S, Farah MH, Hoffman PN, Liu Y, Tsingalia A, Jin L, Zhang PW, Pellerin L, Magistretti PJ, Rothstein JD (2012) Oligodendroglia metabolically support axons and contribute to neurodegeneration. Nature
487:443–448</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3408792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22801498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Lundkvist A, Andersson D, Wilhelmsson U, Nagai N, Pardo AC, Nodin C, Stahlberg A, Aprico K, Larsson K, Yabe T, Moons L, Fotheringham A, Davies I, Carmeliet P, Schwartz JP, Pekna M, Kubista M, Blomstrand F, Maragakis N, Nilsson M, Pekny M (2008) Protective role of reactive astrocytes in brain ischemia. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab
28:468–481</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17726492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacVicar BA, Tse FW, Crichton SA, Kettenmann H (1989) GABA-activated Cl− channels in astrocytes of hippocampal slices. J Neurosci
9:3577–3583</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6569885</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2477511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKenzie IA, Ohayon D, Li H, de Faria JP, Emery B, Tohyama K, Richardson WD (2014) Motor skill learning requires active central myelination. Science
346:318–322</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25324381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Messing A, Brenner M, Feany MB, Nedergaard M, Goldman JE (2012) Alexander disease. J Neurosci
32:5017–5023</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3336214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22496548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyer N, Richter N, Fan Z, Siemonsmeier G, Pivneva T, Jordan P, Steinhauser C, Semtner M, Nolte C, Kettenmann H (2018) Oligodendrocytes in the mouse corpus callosum maintain axonal function by delivery of glucose. Cell Rep
22:2383–2394</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29490274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Micu I, Plemel JR, Caprariello AV, Nave KA, Stys PK (2018) Axo-myelinic neurotransmission: a novel mode of cell signalling in the central nervous system. Nat Rev Neurosci
19:49–58</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29118449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miguel-Hidalgo JJ (2009) The role of glial cells in drug abuse. Curr Drug Abuse Rev
2:76–82</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2709875</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19606280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miguel-Hidalgo JJ, Rajkowska G (2003) Comparison of prefrontal cell pathology between depression and alcohol dependence. J Psychiatr Res
37:411–420</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12849933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyazaki I, Asanuma M, Diaz-Corrales FJ, Miyoshi K, Ogawa N (2004) Direct evidence for expression of dopamine receptors in astrocytes from basal ganglia. Brain Res
1029:120–123</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15533323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monier A, Adle-Biassette H, Delezoide A-L
et al. (2007) Entry and distribution of microglial cells in human embryonic and fetal cerebral cortex. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol
66:372–382. 10.1097/nen.0b013e3180517b46</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/nen.0b013e3180517b46</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17483694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller C, Bauer NM, Schafer I, White R (2013) Making myelin basic protein -from mRNA transport to localized translation. Front Cell Neurosci
7:169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3784684</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24098271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarrete M, Araque A (2008) Endocannabinoids mediate neuron-astrocyte communication. Neuron
57:883–893</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18367089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarrete M, Araque A (2010) Endocannabinoids potentiate synaptic transmission through stimulation of astrocytes. Neuron
68:113–126</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20920795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nayak D, Roth TL, McGavern DB (2014) Microglia development and function. Annu Rev Immunol
32:367–402. 10.1146/annurev-immunol-032713-120240</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-immunol-032713-120240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5001846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24471431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nilsson M, Eriksson PS, Ronnback L, Hansson E (1993) GABA induces Ca2+ transients in astrocytes. Neuroscience
54:605–614</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8332251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okada S, Nakamura M, Katoh H, Miyao T, Shimazaki T, Ishii K, Yamane J, Yoshimura A, Iwamoto Y, Toyama Y, Okano H (2006) Conditional ablation of Stat3 or Socs3 discloses a dual role for reactive astrocytes after spinal cord injury. Nat Med
12:829–834</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16783372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortiz FC, Habermacher C, Graciarena M, Houry PY, Nishiyama A, Oumesmar BN, Angulo MC (2019) Neuronal activity in vivo enhances functional myelin repair. JCI Insight
5(9):e123434. 10.1172/jci.insight.123434</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/jci.insight.123434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parpura V, Verkhratsky A (2012) Neuroglia at the crossroads of homoeostasis, metabolism and signalling: evolution of the concept. ASN Neuro
4:201–205. 10.1042/AN20120019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/AN20120019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3342593</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22455879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pastor A, Chvatal A, Sykova E, Kettenmann H (1995) Glycine- and GABA-activated currents in identified glial cells of the developing rat spinal cord slice. Eur J Neurosci
7:1188–1198</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7582092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pastor A, Kremer M, Moller T, Kettenmann H, Dermietzel R (1998) Dye coupling between spinal cord oligodendrocytes: differences in coupling efficiency between gray and white matter. Glia
24:108–120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9700494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel JR, Klein RS (2011) Mediators of oligodendrocyte differentiation during remyelination. FEBS Lett
585:3730–3737</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3158966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21539842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pekny M, Johansson CB, Eliasson C, Stakeberg J, Wallen A, Perlmann T, Lendahl U, Betsholtz C, Berthold CH, Frisen J (1999) Abnormal reaction to central nervous system injury in mice lacking glial fibrillary acidic protein and vimentin. J Cell Biol
145:503–514</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2185074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10225952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pekny M, Wilhelmsson U, Pekna M (2014) The dual role of astrocyte activation and reactive gliosis. Neurosci Lett
565:30–38</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24406153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pekny M, Pekna M, Messing A, Steinhauser C, Lee JM, Parpura V, Hol EM, Sofroniew MV, Verkhratsky A (2016) Astrocytes: a central element in neurological diseases. Acta Neuropathol
131:323–345</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26671410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfrieger FW (2010) Role of glial cells in the formation and maintenance of synapses. Brain Res Rev
63:39–46</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19931561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pilitsis JG, Kimelberg HK (1998) Adenosine receptor mediated stimulation of intracellular calcium in acutely isolated astrocytes. Brain Res
798:294–303</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9666151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prinz M, Priller J, Sisodia SS, Ransohoff RM (2011) Heterogeneity of CNS myeloid cells and their roles in neurodegeneration. Nat Neurosci
14:1227–1235. 10.1038/nn.2923</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.2923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21952260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prinz M, Priller J (2014) Microglia and brain macrophages in the molecular age: from origin to neuropsychiatric disease. Nat Rev Neurosci
15:300–312. 10.1038/nrn3722</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrn3722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24713688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajkowska G, Miguel-Hidalgo JJ, Makkos Z, Meltzer H, Overholser J, Stockmeier C (2002) Layer-specific reductions in GFAP-reactive astroglia in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res
57:127–138</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12223243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajkowska G, Stockmeier CA (2013) Astrocyte pathology in major depressive disorder: insights from human postmortem brain tissue. Curr Drug Targets
14:1225–1236</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799810</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23469922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribak CE, Tong WM, Brecha NC (1996) GABA plasma membrane transporters, GAT-1 and GAT-3, display different distributions in the rat hippocampus. J Comp Neurol
367:595–606</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8731228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roux L, Benchenane K, Rothstein JD, Bonvento G, Giaume C (2011) Plasticity of astroglial networks in olfactory glomeruli. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
108:18442–18446</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3214998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21997206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruitenberg MJ, Vukovic J, Sarich J, Busfield SJ, Plant GW (2006) Olfactory ensheathing cells: characteristics, genetic engineering, and therapeutic potential. J Neurotrauma
23:468–478</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16629630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saab AS, Tzvetavona ID, Trevisiol A, Baltan S, Dibaj P, Kusch K, Mobius W, Goetze B, Jahn HM, Huang W, Steffens H, Schomburg ED, Perez-Samartin A, Perez-Cerda F, Bakhtiari D, Matute C, Lowel S, Griesinger C, Hirrlinger J, Kirchhoff F, Nave KA (2016) Oligodendroglial NMDA receptors regulate glucose import and axonal energy metabolism. Neuron
91:119–132</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27292539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saher G, Stumpf SK (2015) Cholesterol in myelin biogenesis and hypomyelinating disorders. Biochim Biophys Acta
1851:1083–1094</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25724171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scalise M, Pochini L, Galluccio M, Indiveri C (2016) Glutamine transport. From energy supply to sensing and beyond. Biochim Biophys Acta
1857(8):1147–1157</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26951943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlegelmilch T, Henke K, Peri F (2011) Microglia in the developing brain: from immunity to behaviour. Curr Opin Neurobiol
21:5–10. 10.1016/j.conb.2010.08.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.conb.2010.08.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20817438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scuderi C, Bronzuoli MR, Facchinetti R, Pace L, Ferraro L, Broad KD, Serviddio G, Bellanti F, Palombelli G, Carpinelli G, Canese R, Gaetani S, Steardo L Jr, Steardo L, Cassano T (2018) Ultramicronized palmitoylethanolamide rescues learning and memory impairments in a triple transgenic mouse model of Alzheimer’s disease by exerting anti-inflammatory and neuroprotective effects. Transl Psychiatry
8(1):32. 10.1038/s41398-017-0076-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-017-0076-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5802581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scuderi C, Verkhratsky A (2020) The role of neuroglia in autism spectrum disorders. Prog Mol Biol Transl Sci
173:301–330. 10.1016/bs.pmbts.2020.04.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.pmbts.2020.04.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sellner S, Paricio-Montesinos R, Spieß A
et al. (2016) Microglial CX3CR128 promotes adult neurogenesis by inhibiting Sirt 1/p65 signaling independent of CX3CL1. Acta Neuropathol Commun
4:102. 10.1186/s40478-016-0374-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-016-0374-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5027111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27639555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma G, Vijayaraghavan S (2001) Nicotinic cholinergic signaling in hippocampal astrocytes involves calcium-induced calcium release from intracellular stores. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
98:4148–4153</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC31194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11259680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shelton MK, McCarthy KD (2000) Hippocampal astrocytes exhibit Ca2+-elevating muscarinic cholinergic and histaminergic receptors in situ. J Neurochem
74:555–563</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10646506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shigemoto-Mogami Y, Hoshikawa K, Goldman JE
et al. (2014) Microglia enhance neurogenesis and oligodendrogenesis in the early postnatal subventricular zone. J Neurosci
34:2231–2243. 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1619-13.2014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1619-13.2014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3913870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24501362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sierra A, Encinas JM, Deudero JJP
et al. (2010) Microglia shape adult hippocampal neurogenesis through apoptosis-coupled phagocytosis. Cell Stem Cell
7:483–495. 10.1016/j.stem.2010.08.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stem.2010.08.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4008496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20887954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sofroniew MV (2009) Molecular dissection of reactive astrogliosis and glial scar formation. Trends Neurosci
32:638–647</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2787735</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sofroniew MV (2014) Astrogliosis. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol
7:a020420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25380660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun W, McConnell E, Pare JF, Xu Q, Chen M, Peng W, Lovatt D, Han X, Smith Y, Nedergaard M (2013) Glutamate-dependent neuroglial calcium signaling differs between young and adult brain. Science
339:197–200</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3569008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23307741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swinnen N, Smolders S, Avila A
et al. (2013) Complex invasion pattern of the cerebral cortex by microglial cells during development of the mouse embryo. Glia
61:150–163. 10.1002/glia.22421</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.22421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23001583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang G, Xu Z, Goldman JE (2006) Synergistic effects of the SAPK/JNK and the proteasome pathway on glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) accumulation in Alexander disease. J Biol Chem
281:38634–38643</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17038307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tay TL, Savage JC, Hui CW
et al. (2017) Microglia across the lifespan: from origin to function in brain development, plasticity and cognition. J Physiol (Lond)
595:1929–1945. 10.1113/JP272134</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP272134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5350449</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27104646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tay TL, Béchade C, D’Andrea I
et al. (2018) Microglia gone rogue: impacts on psychiatric disorders across the lifespan. Front Mol Neurosci
10:421. 10.3389/fnmol.2017.00421</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnmol.2017.00421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5758507</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29354029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tay TL, Carrier M, Tremblay MÈ (2019) Physiology of microglia. In: Verkhratsky A, Ho M, Zorec R, Parpura V (eds) Neuroglia in neurodegenerative diseases. Advances in experimental medicine and biology, vol 1175. Springer, Singapore. 10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-13-9913-8_6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueno M, Fujita Y, Tanaka T
et al. (2013) Layer V cortical neurons require microglial support for survival during postnatal development. Nat Neurosci
16:543–551. 10.1038/nn.3358</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nn.3358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23525041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vejar S, Oyarzun JE, Retamal MA, Ortiz FC, Orellana JA (2019) Connexin and pannexin-based channels in oligodendrocytes: implications in brain health and disease. Front Cell Neurosci
13:3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30760982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A (2010) Physiology of neuronal-glial networking. Neurochem Int
57:332–343</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20144673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Butt AM (2013) Glial physiology and pathophysiology. Wiley-Blackwell, Chichester, p 560</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Chvatal A (2020) NMDA receptors in astrocytes. Neurochem Res
45:122–133</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30767094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Krishtal OA, Burnstock G (2009) Purinoceptors on neuroglia. Mol Neurobiol
39:190–208</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19283516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Rodriguez JJ, Steardo L (2014) Astrogliopathology: a central element of neuropsychiatric diseases? Neuroscientist
20:576–588</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24301046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Parpura V (2015) Physiology of astroglia: channels, receptors, transporters, ion signaling and gliotransmission. Morgan &amp; Claypool Publishers, p 172</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Matteoli M, Parpura V, Mothet JP, Zorec R (2016) Astrocytes as secretory cells of the central nervous system: idiosyncrasies of vesicular secretion. EMBO J
35(3):239–257. 10.15252/embj.201592705</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embj.201592705</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4741299</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26758544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Zorec R, Parpura V (2017a) Stratification of astrocytes in healthy and diseased brain. Brain Pathol
27:629–644</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28805002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Zorec R, Rodriguez JJ, Parpura V (2017b) Neuroglia: functional paralysis and reactivity in Alzheimer’s disease and other neurodegenerative pathologies. Adv Neurobiol
15:427–449</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28674992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Nedergaard M (2018) Physiology of astroglia. Physiol Rev
98:239–389</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6050349</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Rose CR (2020) Na+-dependent transporters: the backbone of astroglial homeostatic function. Cell Calcium
85:102136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31835178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Oberheim Bush NA, Nedergaard M, Butt AM (2018) The special case of human astrocytes. Neuroglia
1:21–29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Ho MS, Zorec R, Parpura V (2019) The concept of neuroglia. In: Verkhratsky A, Ho M, Zorec R, Parpura V (eds) Neuroglia in neurodegenerative diseases. Advances in experimental medicine and biology, vol 1175. Springer, Singapore</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verney C, Monier A, Fallet-Bianco C, Gressens P (2010) Early microglial colonization of the human forebrain and possible involvement in periventricular white-matter injury of preterm infants. J Anat
217:436–448. 10.1111/j.1469-7580.2010.01245.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-7580.2010.01245.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2992419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20557401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virchow R (1860) Cellular pathology. Robert M de Witt, New York</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Bartheld CS, Bahney J, Herculano-Houzel S (2016) The search for true numbers of neurons and glial cells in the human brain: a review of 150 years of cell counting. J Comp Neurol
524:3865–3895</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5063692</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27187682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voskuhl RR, Itoh N, Tassoni A, Matsukawa MA, Ren E, Tse V, Jang E, Suen TT, Itoh Y (2019) Gene expression in oligodendrocytes during remyelination reveals cholesterol homeostasis as a therapeutic target in multiple sclerosis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A
116:10130–10139</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6525478</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31040210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinhard L, d’Errico P, Tay TL (2018) Headmasters: microglial regulation of learning and memory in health and disease. Molecular
5:63–89. 10.3934/molsci.2018.1.63</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3934/molsci.2018.1.63</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao L, Ohayon D, McKenzie IA, Sinclair-Wilson A, Wright JL, Fudge AD, Emery B, Li H, Richardson WD (2016) Rapid production of new oligodendrocytes is required in the earliest stages of motor-skill learning. Nat Neurosci
19:1210–1217</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5008443</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27455109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zafra F, Aragon C, Olivares L, Danbolt NC, Gimenez C, Storm-Mathisen J (1995) Glycine transporters are differentially expressed among CNS cells. J Neurosci
15:3952–3969</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6578198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7751957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeidan-Chulia F, Salmina AB, Malinovskaya NA, Noda M, Verkhratsky A, Moreira JC (2014) The glial perspective of autism spectrum disorders. Neurosci Biobehav Rev
38:160–172</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24300694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
