<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34905941</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2633-1462</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2</Volume>
            <Issue>12</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bone &amp; joint open</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bone Jt Open</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Closed incision negative pressure wound therapy versus conventional dressings following soft-tissue sarcoma excision: a prospective, randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1049</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1056</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1049-1056</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1302/2633-1462.212.BJO-2021-0103.R1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The primary objective of this study was to compare the postoperative infection rate between negative pressure wound therapy (NPWT) and conventional dressings for closed incisions following soft-tissue sarcoma (STS) surgery. Secondary objectives were to compare rates of adverse wound events and functional scores.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this prospective, single-centre, randomized controlled trial (RCT), patients were randomized to either NPWT or conventional sterile occlusive dressings. A total of 17 patients, with a mean age of 54 years (21 to 81), were successfully recruited and none were lost to follow-up. Wound reviews were undertaken to identify any surgical site infection (SSI) or adverse wound events within 30 days. The Toronto Extremity Salvage Score (TESS) and Musculoskeletal Tumor Society (MSTS) score were recorded as patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There were two out of seven patients in the control group (28.6%), and two out of ten patients in the intervention group (20%) who were diagnosed with a SSI (p &gt; 0.999), while one additional adverse wound event was identified in the control group (p = 0.593). No significant differences in PROMs were identified between the groups at either 30 days (TESS, p = 0.987; MSTS, p = 0.951) or six-month (TESS, p = 0.400) follow-up. However, neoadjuvant radiotherapy was significantly associated with a SSI within 30 days of surgery, across all patients (p = 0.029). The mean preoperative modified Glasgow Prognostic Score (mGPS) was also significantly higher among patients who developed a postoperative adverse wound event (p = 0.028), including a SSI (p = 0.008), across both groups.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first RCT comparing NPWT with conventional dressings following musculoskeletal tumour surgery. Postoperative wound complications are common in this group of patients and we observed an overall SSI rate of 23.5%. We propose proceeding to a multicentre trial, which will help more clearly define the role of closed incision NPWT in STS surgery. Cite this article: <i>Bone Jt Open</i> 2021;2(12):1049-1056.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shields</LastName>
            <ForeName>David W</ForeName>
            <Initials>DW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Glasgow Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Razii</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nima</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Glasgow Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Doonan</LastName>
            <ForeName>James</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Trauma and Orthopaedics, Glasgow Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mahendra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ashish</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Musculoskeletal Oncology, Glasgow Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gupta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Musculoskeletal Oncology, Glasgow Royal Infirmary, Glasgow, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bone Jt Open</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101770336</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2633-1462</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dressings</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal Tumor Society (MSTS) score</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal tumour surgery</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Negative Pressure Wound Therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Negative pressure wound therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Soft tissue sarcoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Surgical site infection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Toronto Extremity Salvage Score (TESS)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wound complications</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal tumour surgery</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">postoperative infections</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">radiotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trial</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">soft tissue sarcomas</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical site infections (SSIs)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wounds</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34905941</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8711667</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2633-1462.212.BJO-2021-0103.R1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Crago AM, Lee AY. Multimodality management of soft tissue tumors in the extremity. Surg Clin North Am. 2016;96(5):977–992. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4996368</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27542637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Clark MA, Fisher C, Judson I, Thomas JM. Soft-tissue sarcomas in adults. N Engl J Med. 2005;353(7):701–711. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16107623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Clark MA, Thomas JM. Amputation for soft-tissue sarcoma. Lancet Oncol. 2003;4(6):335–342. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12788405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Peat BG, Bell RS, Davis A, et al. . 
Wound-healing complications after soft-tissue sarcoma surgery. Plast Reconstr Surg. 1994;93(5):980–987. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8134491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Geller DS, Hornicek FJ, Mankin HJ, Raskin KA. Soft tissue sarcoma resection volume associated with wound-healing complications. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2007;459:182–185. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17452922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Baldini EH, Lapidus MR, Wang Q, et al. . 
Predictors for major wound complications following preoperative radiotherapy and surgery for soft-tissue sarcoma of the extremities and trunk: Importance of tumor proximity to skin surface. Ann Surg Oncol. 2013;20(5):1494–1499. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23242820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schwartz A, Rebecca A, Smith A, et al. . 
Risk factors for significant wound complications following wide resection of extremity soft tissue sarcomas. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2013;471(11):3612–3617. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3792250</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23813183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Moore J, Isler M, Barry J, Mottard S. Major wound complication risk factors following soft tissue sarcoma resection. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2014;40(12):1671–1676. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25456440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Argenta LC, Morykwas MJ. Vacuum-assisted closure: A new method for wound control and treatment: Clinical experience. Ann Plast Surg. 1997;38(6):563–576.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9188971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Morykwas MJ, Argenta LC, Shelton-Brown EI, McGuirt W. Vacuum-assisted closure: A new method for wound control and treatment: Animal studies and basic foundation. Ann Plast Surg. 1997;38(6):553–562. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9188970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Putnis S, Khan WS, Wong JM-L. Negative pressure wound therapy - a review of its uses in orthopaedic trauma. Open Orthop J. 2014;8:142–147. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4110389</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25067967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Masters J, Cook J, Achten J, Costa ML, WHISH Study Group . A feasibility study of standard dressings versus negative-pressure wound therapy in the treatment of adult patients having surgical incisions for hip fractures: The WHISH randomized controlled trial. Bone Joint J. 2021;103-B(4):755–761. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33789474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Langstein HN, Robb GL. Reconstructive approaches in soft tissue sarcoma. Semin Surg Oncol. 1999;17(1):52–65. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10402638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Willy C, Agarwal A, Andersen CA, et al. . 
Closed Incision negative pressure therapy: International multidisciplinary consensus recommendations. Int Wound J. 2017;14(2):385–398. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7949983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27170231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kong R, Shields D, Bailey O, Gupta S, Mahendra A. Negative pressure wound therapy for closed surgical wounds in musculoskeletal oncology patients - a case-control trial. Open Orthop J. 2017;11:502–507. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5481620</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28694889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bailey O, Shields DW, Donnelly I, et al. . 
SUNstudy study protocol: Sarcoma usual versus negative pressure dressing study protocol. J Clin Exp Orthop. 2017;3:1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
World Medical Association . World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191–2194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Krishnan R, MacNeil SD, Malvankar-Mehta MS. Comparing sutures versus staples for skin closure after orthopaedic surgery: Systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2016;6(1):e009257. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4735308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tsujinaka T, Yamamoto K, Fujita J, et al. . 
Subcuticular sutures versus staples for skin closure after open gastrointestinal surgery: A phase 3, multicentre, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2013;382(9898):1105–1112. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24075050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Davis AM, Wright JG, Williams JI, Bombardier C, Griffin A, Bell RS. Development of a measure of physical function for patients with bone and soft tissue sarcoma. Qual Life Res. 1996;5(5):508–516. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8973131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Enneking WF, Dunham W, Gebhardt MC, Malawar M, Pritchard DJ. A system for the functional evaluation of reconstructive procedures after surgical treatment of tumors of the musculoskeletal system. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1993;286:241–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8425352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Proctor MJ, Morrison DS, Talwar D, et al. . 
An inflammation-based prognostic score (mGPS) predicts cancer survival independent of tumour site: a Glasgow Inflammation Outcome Study. Br J Cancer. 2011;104(4):726–734. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3049591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Norman G, Goh EL, Dumville JC, et al. . 
Negative pressure wound therapy for surgical wounds healing by primary closure. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;6(6):CD009261. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7389520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32542647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Semsarzadeh NN, Tadisina KK, Maddox J, Chopra K, Singh DP. Closed incision negative-pressure therapy is associated with decreased surgical-site infections: A meta-analysis. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2015;136(3):592–602. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26313829</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
De Vries FEE, Wallert ED, Solomkin JS, et al. . 
A systematic review and meta-analysis including grade qualification of the risk of surgical site infections after prophylactic negative pressure wound therapy compared with conventional dressings in clean and contaminated surgery. Medicine (Baltimore). 2016;95(36):e4673. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5023882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27603360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Png ME, Madan JJ, Dritsaki M, et al. . 
Cost-utility analysis of standard dressing compared with incisional negative-pressure wound therapy among patients with closed surgical wounds following major trauma to the lower limb. Bone Joint J. 2020;102-B(8):1072–1081. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32731829</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
De Magistris L, Paquette B, Orry D, et al. . 
Preoperative inflammation increases the risk of infection after elective colorectal surgery: Results from a prospective cohort. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2016;31(9):1611–1617. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5517619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27357511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dormand E-L, Banwell PE, Goodacre TEE. Radiotherapy and wound healing. Int Wound J. 2005;2(2):112–127. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7951225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16722862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
O’Sullivan B, Davis AM, Turcotte R, et al. . 
Preoperative versus postoperative radiotherapy in soft-tissue sarcoma of the limbs: A randomised trial. Lancet. 2002;359(9325):2235–2241. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12103287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tseng JF, Ballo MT, Langstein HN, et al. . 
The effect of preoperative radiotherapy and reconstructive surgery on wound complications after resection of extremity soft-tissue sarcomas. Ann Surg Oncol. 2006;13(9):1209–1215. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16952046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bedi M, King DM, DeVries J, Hackbarth DA, Neilson JC. Does vacuum-assisted closure reduce the risk of wound complications in patients with lower extremity sarcomas treated with preoperative radiation?
Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2019;477(4):768–774. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sakellariou VI, Mavrogenis AF, Papagelopoulos PJ. Negative-pressure wound therapy for musculoskeletal tumor surgery. Adv Skin Wound Care. 2011;24(1):25–30. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21173588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chen YU, Xu S-F, Xu M, Yu X-C. Use of negative pressure wound therapy as an adjunct to the treatment of extremity soft-tissue sarcoma with ulceration or impending ulceration. Oncol Lett. 2016;12(1):757–763. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4907320</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tukiainen E, Böhling T, Huuhtanen R. Soft tissue sarcoma of the trunk and extremities. Scand J Surg. 2003;92(4):257–263. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14758914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dennis N, Francis M, Lawrence G. Soft Tissue Sarcoma Incidence and Survival: Tumours Diagnosed in England between 1985 and 2009. R12/06, National Cancer Intelligence Network, 2012. http://www.ncin.org.uk/view?rid=2062
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Francis M, Dennis N, Charman J, Lawrence G, Grimer R. Bone and Soft Tissue Sarcomas UK Incidence and Survival: 1996 to 2010. November
2013. http://www.ncin.org.uk/view?rid=2353 (date last accessed
9 November 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tahir M, Chaudhry EA, Zimri FK. Negative pressure wound therapy versus conventional dressing for open fractures in lower extremity trauma. Bone Joint J. 2020;102-B(7):912–917. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aljuhani W, Almutlaq M, Alomar A, Alanazi K, Al-Thani AS, Alqahtani T. Incidence and predictors of 30-day postoperative complications following musculoskeletal tumor surgery. J Musculoskelet Surg Res. 2020;4(3):141–145. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Irwin TJ, Orgill D. Closed incision negative pressure wound therapy after resection of large, radiated, soft tissue sarcomas. Cureus. 2020;12(5):e8055. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286594</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32537273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wong S, Ver Halen JP. Closed incision negative-pressure therapy is associated with decreased surgical-site infections: a meta-analysis. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2016;138(1):156e–157e.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27002559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
