<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34902110</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1888</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>American journal of clinical dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Efinaconazole in Onychomycosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>207</StartPage>
          <EndPage>218</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>207-218</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40257-021-00660-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Onychomycosis is a fungal nail infection that causes nail discoloration, nail plate thickening, and onycholysis. Efinaconazole 10% topical solution is an FDA-approved treatment for onychomycosis patients aged 6 years and above. The drug functions as an antifungal by disrupting ergosterol synthesis in the fungal cell membrane. It exhibits higher in vitro activity against dermatophytes than other available antifungals such as ciclopirox and itraconazole, and the activity is comparable to amorolfine and terbinafine. Efinaconazole also provides enhanced nail penetration compared with other topical antifungals due to low surface tension, poor water solubility, and low keratin affinity. The pharmacokinetic studies suggest that the efinaconazole topical delivery to the nail bed is not markedly affected by the presence of disease. There is a subset of onychomycosis patients who are more likely to respond to efinaconazole 10% solution: female patients, those with lower BMI, mild onychomycosis, a short disease duration, no infected non-target toenails (large toenail disease only), and when concomitant tinea pedis is treated. Experts recommend efinaconazole 10% topical solution as the first line for mild-to-moderate onychomycosis, pediatric onychomycosis, those with liver or kidney disease, and as maintenance therapy to prevent relapse. The side effects of topical efinaconazole are minimal: most commonly ingrown toenails, dermatitis, vesicles, and pain at the application site. Altogether, phase I and phase III clinical trials, and post-hoc analyses indicate that efinaconazole 10% topical solution is a safe and effective treatment for adult and pediatric onychomycosis, with a satisfactory mycological and clinical cure.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gupta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aditya K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8664-7723</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., 645 Windermere Road, London, ON, N5X 2P1, Canada. agupta@mediproberesearch.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada. agupta@mediproberesearch.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Talukder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mesbah</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., 645 Windermere Road, London, ON, N5X 2P1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>New Zealand</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Clin Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100895290</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1175-0561</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014230">Triazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>J82SB7FXWB</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C431707">efinaconazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000287" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Topical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014009" MajorTopicYN="Y">Onychomycosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014230" MajorTopicYN="N">Triazoles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>27</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902110</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-021-00660-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40257-021-00660-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlahovic TC, Gupta AK. Efinaconazole topical solution (10%) for the treatment of onychomycosis in adult and pediatric patients. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2021;30:1–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westerberg DP, Voyack MJ. Onychomycosis: current trends in diagnosis and treatment. Am Fam Physician. 2013;88(11):762–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24364524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Penlac<sup>®</sup> Nail Lacquer (ciclopirox) Topical Solution, 8%. 2004. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2004/21022s004lbl.pdf . Accessed 06 Aug 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Penlac<sup>®</sup> (ciclopirox topical 8% w/w solution) product monograph. 2021. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2004/21022s004lbl.pdf . Accessed 16 Sep 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohn M, Kraemer KT. Dermatopharmacology of ciclopirox nail lacquer topical solution 8% in the treatment of onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2000;43(4):S57–69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mjd.2000.109072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eichenfield LF, Elewski B, Sugarman JL, Rosen T, Vlahovic TC, Gupta AK, et al. Efinaconazole 10% topical solution for the treatment of onychomycosis in pediatric patients: open-label phase 4 study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;84(4):1140–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.06.1004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Aly R, Baldwin SL, Soto RFG, Rich P, Weisfeld M, et al. Efficacy and safety of tavaborole topical solution, 5%, a novel boron-based antifungal agent, for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis: results from 2 randomized phase-III studies. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2015;73(1):62–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2015.04.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Pollak RA, Pillai R, Olin JT. Access of efinaconazole topical solution, 10%, to the infection site by spreading through the subungual space. J Drugs Dermatol. 2014;13(11):1394–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25607708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Rich P, Pollak R, Pariser DM, Watanabe S, Senda H, et al. Efinaconazole 10% solution in the treatment of toenail onychomycosis: two phase III multicenter, randomized, double-blind studies. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2013;68(4):600–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2012.10.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Elewski BE, Sugarman JL, Ieda C, Kawabata H, Kang R, et al. The efficacy and safety of efinaconazole 10% solution for treatment of mild to moderate onychomycosis: a pooled analysis of two phase 3 randomized trials. J Drugs Dermatol. 2014;13(7):815–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25007364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Fleckman P, Baran R. Ciclopirox nail lacquer topical solution 8% in the treatment of toenail onychomycosis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2000;43(4):S70–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mjd.2000.109071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haria M, Bryson HM. Amorolfine. A review of its pharmacological properties and therapeutic potential in the treatment of onychomycosis and other superficial fungal infections. Drugs. 1995;49(1):103–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00003495-199549010-00008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hold K, Bullington R, Jones T, Beutner K. In vivo nail residence time of AN2690, a novel broad-spectrum antifungal agent in development for the topical treatment of onychomycosis: P1816. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2007;56(2).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauharanta J. Comparative efficacy and safety of amorolfine nail lacquer 2% versus 5% once weekly. Clin Exp Dermatol. 1992;17:41–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.1992.tb00277.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monti D, Herranz U, Dal Bo L, Subissi A. Nail penetration and predicted mycological efficacy of an innovative hydrosoluble ciclopirox nail lacquer vs. a standard amorolfine lacquer in healthy subjects. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2013;27(2):e153–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2012.04529.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto M, Sugimoto N, Kawabata H, Yamakawa E, Kodera N, Pillai R, et al. Transungual delivery of efinaconazole: its deposition in the nail of onychomycosis patients and in vitro fungicidal activity in human nails. J Drugs Dermatol. 2014;13(11):1388–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25607707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugiura K, Sugimoto N, Hosaka S, Katafuchi-Nagashima M, Arakawa Y, Tatsumi Y, et al. The low keratin affinity of efinaconazole contributes to its nail penetration and fungicidal activity in topical onychomycosis treatment. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2014;58(7):3837–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.00111-14</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gasser J, Pagani E, Vittadello F, Nobile C, Zampieri P, Eisendle K. Frequency, type and treatment of fungal pathogens in toenail onychomycosis in the central Alpine region of South Tyrol, northern Italy—a 10-year retrospective study from 2004 to 2013. Mycoses. 2016;59(12):760–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/myc.12528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Product monograph of JUBLIA<sup>®</sup> (efinaconazole), topical solution, 10% w/w (Bausch Health, Canada Inc.). 2020. https://pdf.hres.ca/dpd_pm/00054721.PDF . Accessed 01 Sep 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Highlights of prescribing information, JUBLIA<sup>®</sup> (efinaconazole) topical solution (FDA label). 2020. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2020/203567s009lbl.pdf . Accessed 01 Sep 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jo Siu WJ, Tatsumi Y, Senda H, Pillai R, Nakamura T, Sone D, et al. Comparison of in vitro antifungal activities of efinaconazole and currently available antifungal agents against a variety of pathogenic fungi associated with onychomycosis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2013;57(4):1610–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AAC.02056-12</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tupaki-Sreepurna A, Jishnu BT, Thanneru V, Sharma S, Gopi A, Sundaram M, et al. An assessment of in vitro antifungal activities of efinaconazole and itraconazole against common non-dermatophyte fungi causing onychomycosis. J Fungi (Basel). 2017;3(2):20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jof3020020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nachrichtendienst V. Almirall and Kaken Pharmaceutical enter into a license and distribution agreement for European rights to the topical formulation of efinaconazole. 2021. https://www.prnewswire.com/de/pressemitteilungen/almirall-and-kaken-pharmaceutical-enter-into-a-license-and-distribution-agreement-for-european-rights-to-the-topical-formulation-of-efinaconazole-850637563.html . Accessed 22 Sep 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kircik LH. Enhancing transungual delivery and spreading of efinaconazole under the nail plate through a unique formulation approach. J Drugs Dermatol. 2014;13(12):1457–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25607788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Pillai R. The presence of an air gap between the nail plate and nail bed in onychomycosis patients: treatment implications for topical therapy. J Drugs Dermatol. 2015;14(8):859–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26267730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del Rosso JQ, Reece B, Smith K, Miller T. Efinaconazole 10% solution: a new topical treatment for onychomycosis: contact sensitization and skin irritation potential. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2013;6(3):20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24307921</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3848648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iozumi K, Abe M, Ito Y, Uesugi T, Onoduka T, Kato I, et al. Efficacy of long-term treatment with efinaconazole 10% solution in patients with onychomycosis, including severe cases: a multicenter, single-arm study. J Dermatol. 2019;46(8):641–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1346-8138.14935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA. Long-term efficacy and safety of once-daily Efinaconazole 10% topical solution (Jublia) for dermatophyte toenail onychomycosis: an interim analysis. Skin Ther Lett. 2021;26(1):5–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rich P. Efinaconazole topical solution, 10%: the benefits of treating onychomycosis early. J Drugs Dermatol. 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosen T. Evaluation of gender as a clinically relevant outcome variable in the treatment of onychomycosis with efinaconazole topical solution 10%. Cutis. 2015;96(3):197–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Venkataraman M, Anbalagan N, Guenin EP. One size does not fit all: the need for individualized treatment based on factors that may affect the therapeutic outcome of efinaconazole 10% solution for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis. Int J Dermatol. 2021;60:1296–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.15739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vlahovic TC, Joseph WS. Efinaconazole topical, 10% for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis in patients with diabetes. J Drugs Dermatol. 2014;13(10):1186–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25607552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE, Tosti A. Risk factors and comorbidities for onychomycosis: implications for treatment with topical therapy. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2015;8(11):38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26705439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4689496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez DA. Efinaconazole topical solution, 10%, for the treatment of mild and moderate toenail onychomycosis. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2015;8(6):24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26155324</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4479366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Korotzer A. Topical treatment of onychomycosis and clinically meaningful outcomes. J Drugs Dermatol. 2016;15(10):1260–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27741345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del Rosso JQ. Onychomycosis of toenails and post-hoc analyses with Efinaconazole 10% solution once-daily treatment: impact of disease severity and other concomitant associated factors on selection of therapy and therapeutic outcomes. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2016;9(2):42–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27354888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4896821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Elewski BE. Treatment of onychomycosis with efinaconazole 10% topical solution and quality of life. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2014;7(11):25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25489379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4255695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Venkataraman M, Quinlan EM, Gupta MA, Anbalagan N, Lyons R. More than nail deep: the effect of efinaconazole 10% treatment on the quality of life in patients with onychomycosis: a post hoc study. Skin Appendage Disord. 2021;7(4):272–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000514361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foley K, Gupta AK, Versteeg S, Mays R, Villanueva E, John D. Topical and device‐based treatments for fungal infections of the toenails. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;(1).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Totri CR, Feldstein S, Admani S, Friedlander SF, Eichenfield LF. Epidemiologic analysis of onychomycosis in the San Diego pediatric population. Pediatr Dermatol. 2017;34(1):46–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pde.12986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Venkataraman M, Shear NH, Piguet V. Onychomycosis in children—review on treatment and management strategies. J Dermatolog Treat. 2020;26:1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09546634.2020.1810607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Joseph WS, Vlahovic TC, Scher RK, Rich P, Ghannoum M, et al. Therapeutic recommendations for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis in the US. J Drugs Dermatol. 2021;20(10):1076–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34636509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe S, Iozumi K, Abe M, Ito Y, Uesugi T, Onoduka T, et al. Clinical effectiveness of efinaconazole 10% solution for treatment of onychomycosis with longitudinal spikes. J Dermatol. 2021;48(10):1474–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1346-8138.16035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA Adverse Event Reporting System (FAERS) Public Dashboard. 2020. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/questions-and-answers-fdas-adverse-event-reporting-system-faers/fda-adverse-event-reporting-system-faers-public-dashboard . Accessed 17 Dec 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cernea M. How effective is efinaconazole in the management of onychomycosis? Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2016;17(4):611–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/14656566.2016.1146687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glynn M, Jo W, Minowa K, Sanada H, Nejishima H, Matsuuchi H, et al. Efinaconazole: developmental and reproductive toxicity potential of a novel antifungal azole. Reprod Toxicol. 2015;52:18–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reprotox.2014.12.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
