<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34900583</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2213-6258</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2021</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Case studies on transport policy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Case Stud Transp Policy</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The evolving impact of coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic on public transportation in Ghana.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1607</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1614</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1607-1614</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cstp.2021.08.010</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">People's mobility improves as a result of transportation, allowing for greater accessibility. However, the COVID-19 pandemic, which began in December 2019 in Wuhan, China, has had a significant effect on mobility and accessibility to public transport.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Looking at the nature of public transports in Ghana with passengers sitting close to each other coupled with the restrictions on mobility, this paper sought to investigate the effect of the pandemic on public transportation in Ghana.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study attempts to use an online and paper-based questionnaire that included questions on usual mode of transportation, usual mode of public transportation prior to and throughout the time of COVID-19, factors influencing public transport mode option prior to and throughout the time of COVID-19 from 1005 commuters. Statistical analysis included descriptive analysis and in addition quantitative comparative analysis. Non-parametric tests were used for inferential statistical analysis. To understand whether usual mode of transportation has evolved due to COVID-19, Wilcoxon signed-ranked test was used to contrast factors influencing mode option prior to and throughout the time of COVID-19.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Results explained that the major impact of COVID-19 on public transportation were social distancing and increase in the cost of transportation. There was a sharp decline in the use of para transit services with high occupancy such as "trotro" to the use of taxis. Commuters considered physical distancing, occupants wearing face masks, cleanliness of vehicle and safety from traffic accidents as essential factors influencing public transport mode choice during COVID-19. The results of the cross-tabulation analysis, which looked at the relationship between the effect of COVID-19 on transportation and the effect of COVID-19 on social, economic and religious activities showed these variables were insignificant, X<sup>2</sup> (2, N = 1005) = 3.057, <i>p</i> = .217.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">On the basis of the study findings, some recommendations were made for policymakers and stakeholders in the transport industry in order to make it much safer and conducive to travel on public transport in a pandemic in the country.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 World Conference on Transport Research Society. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sogbe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eugene</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>DESK-Air Engineering Consults, P.O. Box HP 1332, Ho, Ghana.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Case Stud Transp Policy</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101766458</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2213-624X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>6</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34900583</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8648554</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cstp.2021.08.010</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2213-624X(21)00144-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abane A. Mode choice for the journey to work among formal sector employees in Accra, Ghana. J. Transp. Geogr. 1993;1(4):219–229. doi: 10.1016/0966-6923(93)90046-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0966-6923(93)90046-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abane A.M. Travel behaviour in Ghana: empirical observations from four metropolitan areas. J. Transp. Geogr. 2011;19(2):313–322. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2010.03.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2010.03.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdullah M., Dias C., Muley D., Shahin M. Exploring the impacts of COVID-19 on travel behaviour and mode preferences. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;8 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100255</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Addo, S. T., 2002. Provision of Urban Transport Services in Accra Provision of Urban Transport Services in Accra. https://www.ssatp.org/sites/ssatp/files/publications/Presentations/UrbanTransportServices-Accra.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Affran, H., Addo-Lartey, B., Aheto, A., Ganleid, M.K., Sarfo, J.K., Aryeetey, B.R., 2020. Limiting spread of COVID-19 in Ghana: Compliance audit of selected transportation stations in the Greater Accra region of Ghana. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0238971.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7485755</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32915888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agyeman S., Cheng L. Analysis of barriers to perceived service quality in Ghana: students’ perspectives on bus mobility attributes. Transport Policy. 2020;99:63–85. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2020.08.015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2020.08.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agyemang W.  32nd Southern African Transport Conference. 2013. Measurement of Service Quality of “Trotro” As Public Transportation in Ghana: a Case Study of the City of Kumasi.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akple M.S., Sogbe E., Atombo C. Evaluation of road traffic signs, markings and traffic rules compliance among drivers’ in Ghana. Case Stud. Transp. Policy. 2020;8(4):1295–1306. doi: 10.1016/j.cstp.2020.09.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cstp.2020.09.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almlöf E., Rubensson I., Cebecauer M., Jenelius E. Who continued traveling by public transport during COVID-19? Socioeconomic factors explaining travel behaviour in Stockholm 2020 based on smart card data. SSRN Electron. J. 2021 doi: 10.2139/SSRN.3689091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/SSRN.3689091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aloi A., Alonso B., Benavente J., Cordera R., Echániz E., González F., Ladisa C., Lezama-Romanelli R., López-Parra Á., Mazzei V., Perrucci L., Prieto-Quintana D., Rodríguez A., Sañudo R. Effects of the COVID-19 lockdown on urban mobility: empirical evidence from the city of Santander (Spain) Sustainability (Switzerland) 2020;12(9):3870. doi: 10.3390/su12093870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12093870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amoh-Gyimah R., Aidoo E.N. Mode of transport to work by government employees in the Kumasi metropolis, Ghana. J. Transp. Geogr. 2013;31:35–43. doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2013.05.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2013.05.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ansah, M., 2020. Commercial vehicles ordered to carry fewer passengers to curb spread of COVID-19. Retrieved December 16, 2020, from https://citinewsroom.com/2020/03/commercial-vehicles-ordered-to-carry-fewer-passengers-to-curb-spread-of-covid-19/.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arellana, J., Márquez, L., Cantillo, V., 2020. COVID-19 Outbreak in Colombia: An Analysis of Its Impacts on Transport Systems. doi:10.1155/2020/8867316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asante L.A., Mills R.O. Exploring the Socio-Economic Impact of COVID-19 Pandemic in Marketplaces in Urban Ghana. Africa Spectrum. 2020;55(2):170–181. doi: 10.1177/0002039720943612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0002039720943612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bucsky P. Modal share changes due to COVID-19: the case of Budapest. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;8:100141. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100141</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290209</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campisi, T., Basbas, S., Skoufas, A., Akgün, N., Ticali, D., &amp; Tesoriere, G., 2020. The Impact of COVID-19 Pandemic on the Resilience of Sustainable Mobility in Sicily. doi:10.3390/su12218829.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Haas M., Faber R., Hamersma M. How COVID-19 and the Dutch ‘intelligent lockdown’ change activities, work and travel behaviour: evidence from longitudinal data in the Netherlands. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;6:100150. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vos J. The effect of COVID-19 and subsequent social distancing on travel behaviour. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;5 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100121</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7180344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dzisi E.K.J., Dei O.A. Adherence to social distancing and wearing of masks within public transportation during the COVID 19 pandemic. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;7:100191. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396893</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eboli L., Mazzulla G. A stated preference experiment for measuring service quality in public transport. Transp. Planning Technol. 2008;31(5):509–523. doi: 10.1080/03081060802364471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03081060802364471</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatmi M.R. COVID-19 impact on urban mobility. J. Urban Manage. 2020;9(3):270–275. doi: 10.1016/J.JUM.2020.08.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JUM.2020.08.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fenichel E.P., Kuminoff N.V., Chowell G., Boni M.F. Skip the trip: air travelers’ behavioral responses to pandemic influenza. PLoS ONE. 2013;8(3):e58249. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0058249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0058249</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3604007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23526970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goscé, L., and Johansson, A., 2018. R ES EA R CH Open Access Analysing the link between public transport use and airborne transmission: mobility and contagion in the London underground. doi:10.1186/s12940-018-0427-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30514301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haleem A., Javaid M., Vaishya R. Effects of COVID-19 pandemic in daily life. Curr. Med. Res. Pract. 2020;10(2):78–79. doi: 10.1016/j.cmrp.2020.03.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmrp.2020.03.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7147210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hotor, D. E., 2016. (PDF) THE USE OF PUBLIC TRANSPORT SERVICES BY RESIDENTS IN THE ACCRA METROPOLITAN AREA | Hotor Dominic-Edem - Academia.edu. Retrieved December 18, 2020, from https://www.academia.edu/38608198/THE_USE_OF_PUBLIC_TRANSPORT_SERVICES_BY_RESIDENTS_IN_THE_ACCRA_METROPOLITAN_AREA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenelius E., Cebecauer M. Impacts of COVID-19 on public transport ridership in Sweden: analysis of ticket validations, sales and passenger counts. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;8:100242. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7575262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiao, J., &amp; Azimian, A., 2021. Exploring the factors affecting travel behaviors during the second phase of the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States. doi:10.1080/19427867.2021.1904736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joewono T.B., Kubota H. Safety and security improvement in public transportation based on public perception in developing countries. IATSS Res. 2006;30(1):86–100. doi: 10.1016/s0386-1112(14)60159-.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0386-1112(14)60159-</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim C., Cheon H., Choi K., Joh C.-H., Lee H.-J. Exposure to fear: changes in travel behavior during MERS outbreak in Seoul. KSCE J. Civ. Eng. 2017;21(7):2888–2895. doi: 10.1007/s12205-017-0821-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12205-017-0821-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, M. I., Zhao, J., Sun, Q. I., Pan, Y. I., Zhou, W., Xiong, C., Zhang, L., 2020. Human mobility trends during the early stage of the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0241468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7652287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33166301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipsitch M., Swerdlow D.L., Finelli L. Defining the epidemiology of Covid-19 — studies needed. New England J. Med. 2020;382(13):1194–1196. doi: 10.1056/nejmp2002125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmp2002125</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32074416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mbara, T. C., 2002. TRANSPORT: HOW HAVE AFRICAN CITIES MANAGED THE SECTOR? WHAT ARE THE POSSIBLE OPTIONS?</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health, 2020. Press Releases | COVID-19 | Ghana. Retrieved December 17, 2020, from https://www.ghanahealthservice.org/covid19/press-releases.php.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mogaji E. Impact of COVID-19 on transportation in Lagos, Nigeria. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;6 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100154AZ.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100154AZ</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7290214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34171020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nyarku, K., Kusi, L., Agyeman, D., 2017. View of Service Quality and Customer Acceptability at the Cape Coast Branch of Metro Mass Transit Limited. Retrieved December 19, 2020, from https://journal.ucc.edu.gh/index.php/jobed/article/view/130/32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ojo, T. K., and Suleman, D., 2014. Service Quality and Customer Satisfaction of Public Transport on Cape Coast-Accra Route, Ghana Establishing a foundation for Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) at African Mines: The Case of Ghana View project Geolournal View project. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/266385664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oluwaseyi A., Olawunmi F. Assessment of bus rapid transit in efficient of movement of commuters in Lagos State. European J. Hum. Social Sci. 2016;35(November):15. Https://Www.Researchgate.Net/Publication/306344953 Available at.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orro A., Novales M., Monteagudo Á., Pérez-López J.B., Bugarín M.R. Impact on city bus transit services of the COVID-19 lockdown and return to the new normal: The case of A Coruña (Spain) Sustainability (Switzerland) 2020;12(17):7206. doi: 10.3390/su12177206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12177206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parady G., Taniguchi A., Takami K. Travel behavior changes during the COVID-19 pandemic in Japan: analyzing the effects of risk perception and social influence on going-out self-restriction. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;7:100181. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pawar D.S., Yadav A.K., Akolekar N., Velaga N.R. Impact of physical distancing due to novel coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) on daily travel for work during transition to lockdown. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;7:100203. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poku-Boansi M. Path dependency in transport: a historical analysis of transport service delivery in Ghana. Case Stud. Transp. Policy. 2020;8(4):1137–1147. doi: 10.1016/j.cstp.2020.07.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cstp.2020.07.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poku-Boansi M., Adarkwa K. The determinants of demand for public transport services in Kumasi, Ghana. J. Sci. Technol. (Ghana) 2014;33(3):60. doi: 10.4314/just.v33i3.7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4314/just.v33i3.7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poku-Boansi, M, and Adarkwa, K., 2011. AN ANALYSIS OF THE SUPPLY OF URBAN PUBLIC TRANSPORT SERVICES IN KUMASI, GHANA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramelli S., Wagner A.F. Feverish Stock Price Reactions to COVID-19*. Rev. Corporate Finance Stud. 2020;9(3):622–655. doi: 10.1093/rcfs/cfaa012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rcfs/cfaa012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sam E.F., Hamidu O., Daniels S. SERVQUAL analysis of public bus transport services in Kumasi metropolis, Ghana: core user perspectives. Case Stud. Transport Policy. 2018;6(1):25–31. doi: 10.1016/j.cstp.2017.12.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cstp.2017.12.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scheff S.W.  Fundamental Statistical Principles for the Neurobiologist. Elsevier; 2016. Nonparametric statistics; pp. 157–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/B978-0-12-804753-8.00008-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlosser F., Maier B.F., Jack O., Hinrichs D., Zachariae A., Brockmann D. COVID-19 lockdown induces disease-mitigating structural changes in mobility networks. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. 2020 doi: 10.1073/pnas.2012326117. 202012326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2012326117</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7776901</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33273120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shakibaei S., de Jong G.C., Alpkökin P., Rashidi T.H. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on travel behavior in Istanbul: a panel data analysis. Sustain. Cities Society. 2020;65:102619. doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2020.102619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2020.102619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7682431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33251093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shamshiripour A., Rahimi E., Shabanpour R., Mohammadian A., (Kouros) How is COVID-19 reshaping activity-travel behavior? Evidence from a comprehensive survey in Chicago. Transp. Res. Interdiscip. Perspect. 2020;7 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100216</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474875</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilbur M., Ayman A., Ouyang A., Poon V., Kabir R., Vadali A., Pugliese P., Freudberg D., Laszka A., Dubey A. Impact of COVID-19 on Public Transit Accessibility and Ridership. ArXiv Preprint. 2020 ArXiv:2008.02413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization, WHO (2020a). Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) Global epidemiological situation. https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20200928-weekly-epi-update.pdf?sfvrsn=9e354665_6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization, W. H. O. (2020b). Advice for the public. Retrieved December 16, 2020, from https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xia, Y. (2020). Correlation and association analyses in microbiome study integrating multiomics in health and disease. in: Progress in Molecular Biology and Translational Science (Vol. 171, pp. 309–491). doi:10.1016/bs.pmbts.2020.04.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32475527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yıldırım, M., Geçer, E., &amp; Akgül, Ö., 2020. The impacts of vulnerability, perceived risk, and fear on preventive behaviours against COVID-19. doi:10.1080/13548506.2020.1776891.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32490689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yobo E., Kamu U., Gana M. State Intervention in Public Transportation in Ghana Toplu Taşımada Kamu Müdahalesi: Gana Örneği. JTL J. Transp. Logistics. 2018;3(1) doi: 10.26650/JTL.2018.03.01.04.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26650/JTL.2018.03.01.04</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
