<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34905301</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2326-5205</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>74</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Arthritis &amp; rheumatology (Hoboken, N.J.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Arthritis Rheumatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Identification of Similarities Between Skin Lesions in Patients With Antisynthetase Syndrome and Skin Lesions in Patients With Dermatomyositis by Highly Multiplexed Imaging Mass Cytometry.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>882</StartPage>
          <EndPage>891</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>882-891</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/art.42050</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Antisynthetase syndrome (ASyS) and dermatomyositis (DM) are autoimmune disorders that overlap clinically. Given the presence of DM-like skin lesions in ASyS patients, there is debate about whether ASyS is a distinct disease or a subclassification of DM. Recent studies identified differences in type I interferon (IFN) expression between ASyS and DM muscle and finger eruptions. This study was undertaken to elucidate similarities and differences in the pathogenesis of cutaneous disease in ASyS and DM at the single-cell level.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Five ASyS patients and 7 DM patients were recruited from a prospectively collected database of well-characterized DM patients. ASyS patients were clinically confirmed as having ASyS according to the Connors et al criteria and the Solomon et al criteria and the presence of aminoacyl-transfer RNA synthetase antibodies. Immunophenotyping was conducted using immunofluorescence (IF) and imaging mass cytometry (IMC).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">IF staining for MxA and IFNβ expression revealed up-regulation of type I IFN in ASyS and DM samples compared to healthy control samples (P &lt; 0.05). IMC showed similar numbers of macrophages, T cells, B cells, and dendritic cells in ASyS and DM samples, with no differences in counts (P &gt; 0.05), but an increase in myeloid dendritic cell percentage in DM samples (P &lt; 0.05). Key type I IFN, cytokine, and JAK/STAT pathways were similarly expressed in both ASyS and DM (P &gt; 0.05). At the single-cell level, macrophages positive for phosphorylated stimulator of IFN genes in ASyS samples expressed increased levels of tumor necrosis factor, interluekin-17 (IL-17), and IFNβ (P &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">IMC is a powerful tool that identifies a role for the type I IFN system in DM-like skin lesions in ASyS and DM with some differences at the cellular level, but overall significant overlap, supporting similar therapeutic decision making.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 American College of Rheumatology. This article has been contributed to by US Government employees and their work is in the public domain in the USA.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Patel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jay</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4737-8740</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Affairs Medical Center and University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ravishankar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adarsh</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5541-1427</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Affairs Medical Center and University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maddukuri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Spandana</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8219-4202</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Affairs Medical Center and University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vazquez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1721-5617</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Affairs Medical Center and University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Grinnell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Madison</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3183-5185</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Affairs Medical Center and University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Werth</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victoria P</ForeName>
            <Initials>VP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3030-5369</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Affairs Medical Center and University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AR076766</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Arthritis Rheumatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101623795</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2326-5191</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007370">Interferon Type I</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>77238-31-4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016899">Interferon-beta</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C537778">Antisynthetase syndrome</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatomyositis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019044" MajorTopicYN="N">Image Cytometry</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Interferon Type I</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016899" MajorTopicYN="N">Interferon-beta</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myositis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34905301</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.42050</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witt LJ, Curran JJ, Strek ME. The diagnosis and treatment of antisynthetase syndrome. Clin Pulm Med 2016;23:218-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Love LA, Leff RL, Fraser DD, Targoff IN, Dalakas M, Plotz PH, et al. A new approach to the classification of idiopathic inflammatory myopathy: myositis-specific autoantibodies define useful homogeneous patient groups. Medicine (Baltimore) 1991;70:360-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukamatsu H, Hirai Y, Miyake T, Kaji T, Morizane S, Yokoyama E, et al. Clinical manifestations of skin, lung and muscle diseases in dermatomyositis positive for anti-aminoacyl tRNA synthetase antibodies. J Dermatol 2019;46:886-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connors GR, Christopher-Stine L, Oddis CV, Danoff SK. Interstitial lung disease associated with the idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: what progress has been made in the past 35 years? Chest 2010;138:1464-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solomon J, Swigris JJ, Brown KK. Myositis-related interstitial lung disease and antisynthetase syndrome. J Bras Pneumol 2011;37:100-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krathen M, Fiorentino D, Werth V. Dermatomyositis. Curr Dir Autoimmun 2008;10:313-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundberg IE, Tjärnlund A, Bottai M, Werth VP, Pilkington C, de Visser M, et al. 2017 European League Against Rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for adult and juvenile idiopathic inflammatory myopathies and their major subgroups. Arthritis Rheumatol 2017;69:2271-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamaguchi Y, Fujimoto M, Matsushita T, Kaji K, Komura K, Hasegawa M, et al. Common and distinct clinical features in adult patients with anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase antibodies: heterogeneity within the syndrome. PLoS One 2013;8:60442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsushita T, Hasegawa M, Fujimoto M, Hamaguchi Y, Komura K, Hirano T, et al. Clinical evaluation of anti-aminoacyl tRNA synthetase antibodies in Japanese patients with dermatomyositis. J Rheumatol 2007;34:1012-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castañeda S, Cavagna L, González-Gay MA. New criteria needed for antisynthetase syndrome. JAMA Neurol 2018;75:258-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baechler EC, Bilgic H, Reed AM. Type I interferon pathway in adult and juvenile dermatomyositis. Arthritis Res Ther 2011;13:249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao AP, Salajegheh M, Nazareno R, Kagan JC, Jubin RG, Greenberg SA. Interferon β is associated with type 1 interferon-inducible gene expression in dermatomyositis. Ann Rheum Dis 2011;70:831-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong D, Kea B, Pesich R, Higgs BW, Zhu W, Brown P, et al. Interferon and biologic signatures in dermatomyositis skin: specificity and heterogeneity across diseases. PLoS One 2012;7:e29161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uruha A, Allenbach Y, Charuel JL, Musset L, Aussy A, Boyer O, et al. Diagnostic potential of sarcoplasmic myxovirus resistance protein A expression in subsets of dermatomyositis. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol 2019;45:513-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okiyama N, Yamaguchi Y, Kodera M, Hamaguchi Y, Yokozeki H, Ishiguro N, et al. Distinct histopathologic patterns of finger eruptions in dermatomyositis based on myositis-specific autoantibody profiles. JAMA Dermatology 2019;155:1080-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeidi M, Chen KL, Patel B, Ravishankar A, Lim R, Werth VP. Increased MxA protein expression and dendritic cells in spongiotic dermatitis differentiates dermatomyositis from eczema in a single-center case-control study. J Cutan Pathol 2020;48:364-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aouizerate J, Amer YB, Bazzez G, Gherardi R, Rigoloet M, Authier F. Myofiber HLA-DR expression is a distinctive biomarker for overlap myositis and inclusion body myositis. Neuromuscul Disord 2015;2:154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Bleecker JL, De Paepe B, Aronica E, de Visser M, Amato A, Benveniste O, et al. 205th ENMC International Workshop: pathology diagnosis of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies part II 28-30 March 2014, Naarden, The Netherlands. Neuromuscul Disord 2015;25:268-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anyanwu CO, Fiorentino DF, Chung L, Dzuong C, Wang Y, Okawa J, et al. Validation of the Cutaneous Dermatomyositis Disease Area and Severity Index (CDASI): characterizing disease severity and assessing responsiveness to clinical change. Br J Dermatol 2015;173:969-974.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel J, Maddukuri S, Li Y, Bax C, Werth VP. Highly multiplexed mass cytometry identifies the immunophenotype in the skin of dermatomyositis. J Invest Dermatol 2021;141:2151-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baka Z, Senolt L, Vencovsky J, Mann H, Simon PS, Kittel Á, et al. Increased serum concentration of immune cell derived microparticles in polymyositis/dermatomyositis. Immunol Lett 2010;128:124-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang T, Huang Y, Liu H, Xu Q, Gong Y, Chen Y, et al. Reduced miR-146a promotes REG3A expression and macrophage migration in polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Front Immunol 2020;11:37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malmström V, Venalis P, Albrecht I. T cells in myositis. Arthritis Res Ther 2012;14:230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fasth AE, Dastmalchi M, Rahbar A, Salomonsson S, Pandya JM, Lindroos E, et al. T cell infiltrates in the muscles of patients with dermatomyositis and polymyositis are dominated by CD28 null T cells. J Immunol 2009;183:4792-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antiga E, Kretz CC, Klembt R, Massi D, Ruland V, Stumpf C, et al. Characterization of regulatory T cells in patients with dermatomyositis. J Autoimmun 2010;35:342-50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen KL, Patel J, Zeidi M, Wysocka M, Bashir MM, Patel B, et al. Myeloid dendritic cells are major producers of IFN-β in dermatomyositis and may contribute to hydroxychloroquine refractoriness. J Invest Dermatol 2021;141:1906-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou R, Xie X, Li X, Qin Z, Wei C, Liu J, et al. The triggers of the cGAS-STING pathway and the connection with inflammatory and autoimmune diseases. Infect Genet Evol 2020;77:104094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gitiaux C, Bondet V, Bekaddour N, Nusbaum P, Hubas A, Melki I, et al. Inhibition of IFNα secretion in cells from patients with juvenile dermatomyositis under TBK1 inhibitor treatment revealed by single-molecular assay technology. Rheumatology 2020;59:1171-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Wang D, Wang L, Wang S, Roden AC, Zhao H, et al. Profibrotic effect of IL-17A and elevated IL-17RA in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and rheumatoid arthritis-associated lung disease support a direct role for IL-17A/IL-17RA in human fibrotic interstitial lung disease. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol 2019;316:L487-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cantaert T, Baeten D, Tak PP, van Baarsen LG. Type I IFN and TNFα cross-regulation in immune-mediated inflammatory disease: basic concepts and clinical relevance. Arthritis Res Ther 2010;12:219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
