<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34919300</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-3083</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology : JEADV</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Eyelash trichomegaly: a systematic review of acquired and congenital aetiologies of lengthened lashes.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>536</StartPage>
          <EndPage>546</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>536-546</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jdv.17877</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Long eyelashes have been popularized and many commercially available products exist to achieve eyelash growth as a desired cosmetic effect. Eyelash trichomegaly may be induced by medications, procedures, or be related to medical conditions; however, the exact mechanisms that govern eyelash growth are not well elucidated. This study aims to identify and summarize aetiologies associated with eyelash trichomegaly. We report a systematic review of 148 clinical trials, prospective and retrospective studies, and case reports describing all evidence-based potential aetiologies of eyelash trichomegaly obtained from the Medline/PubMed and Cochrane Library through January 2021. Inclusion criteria were defined as (i) human studies involving congenital and acquired diseases in which eyelash trichomegaly is a characteristic or (ii) assessment of trichomegaly as an adverse or desired effect of a medication or procedure. Exclusion criteria included: animal studies, articles not available in English, outcomes unrelated to eyelash trichomegaly, and secondary review articles. Pharmacologic agents associated with eyelash trichomegaly included prostaglandin analogues (15-keto fluprostenol isopropyl ester, bimatoprost, latanoprost, and travoprost), epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors (cetuximab, erlotinib, and panitumumab), interferon-alpha, and calcineurin inhibitors (tacrolimus and cyclosporine). Surgical procedures of the eyelid, as well as allergic rhinitis, atopic dermatitis, HIV, ichthyosis vulgaris (IV), uveitis, and vernal keratoconjunctivitis were also associated with increased eyelash growth. Congenital disorders associated with lengthened eyelashes included Cantú syndrome, CHOPS syndrome, Coffin-Siris syndrome, congenital heart disease, Cornelia de Lange syndrome, Costello syndrome, familial trichomegaly, Floating Harbor syndrome, Hermansky-Pudlak syndrome, Kabuki-Makeup syndrome, KBG syndrome, Oliver-McFarlane syndrome, Rubinstein-Taybi syndrome, and Smith-Magenis syndrome. While the most common cause of eyelash trichomegaly is topical bimatoprost use, better understanding of pathways implicated in eyelash trichomegaly may lead to the discovery of additional medications to stimulate eyelash growth and create avenues for future therapeutic interventions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hutchison</LastName>
            <ForeName>D M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0668-0057</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beckman Laser Institute, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Duffens</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yale</LastName>
            <ForeName>K</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Park</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beckman Laser Institute, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cardenas</LastName>
            <ForeName>K</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mesinkovska</LastName>
            <ForeName>N A</ForeName>
            <Initials>NA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2705-7002</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beckman Laser Institute, University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9216037</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0926-9959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000015" MajorTopicYN="Y">Abnormalities, Multiple</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001848" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bone Diseases, Developmental</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019066" MajorTopicYN="N">Facies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008607" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intellectual Disability</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014071" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tooth Abnormalities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34919300</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.17877</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gray H. Trichomegaly or movie lashes. Stanford Med Bull 1944; 2: 157-158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lothian Health Services Archive. Clubbed Fingers, Long Eyelashes, and a Subaverage Condition: Unusual Markers of Tuberculosis in the Royal Victoria Dispensary Case Notes, 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crookshank FG. Some recent theories of tuberculosis and their possible significance. Proc R Soc Med 1913; 6: 68-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patrizi A, Neri I, Trestini D, Landi C, Ricci G, Masi M. Acquired trichomegaly of the eyelashes in a child with human immunodeficiency virus infection. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 1998; 11: 89-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan MH, Sadick NS, Talmor M. Acquired trichomegaly of the eyelashes: a cutaneous marker of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. J Am Acad Dermatol 1991; 25: 801-804.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aumond S, Bitton E. The eyelash follicle features and anomalies: a review. J Optom 2018; 11: 211-222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paus R, Burgoa I, Platt CI, Griffiths T, Poblet E, Izeta A. Biology of the eyelash hair follicle: an enigma in plain sight. Br J Dermatol 2016; 174: 741-752.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart LA, Clarke M, Rovers M et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analyses of individual participant data: the PRISMA-IPD statement. JAMA 2015; 313: 1657-1665.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalal A, Sharma S, Kumar A, Sharma N. Eyelash trichomegaly: a rare presenting feature of systemic lupus erythematosus. Int J Trichology 2017; 9: 79-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jalili IK. Cone-rod congenital amaurosis associated with congenital hypertrichosis: an autosomal recessive condition. J Med Genet 1989; 26: 504-510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhattacharjee H, Bhattacharjee K, Tahiliani P. Congenital polycoria, trichomegaly, and hereditary congenital cataract. J AAPOS 2013; 17: 619-620.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Cruz D, Zafra de la Rosa GF, Sánchez-Corona J et al. SED-brachydactyly and distinctive speech: report of two new cases. Genet Couns 2007; 18: 85-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldstein JH, Hutt AE. Trichomegaly, cataract, and hereditary spherocytosis in two siblings. Am J Ophthalmol 1972; 73: 333-335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathachan SR, Sinha S, Sardana K, Malhotra P. A case of familial trichomegaly with synophrys in association with loose anagen syndrome. Indian Dermatol Online J 2020; 11: 263-265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karaman A, Aydin H, Geçkinli B, Göksu K. The deletion 22q13 syndrome: a new case. Genet Couns 2015; 26: 53-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-Enseñat MA, Vicente A, Poo P et al. Phylloid hypomelanosis and mosaic partial trisomy 13: two cases that provide further evidence of a distinct clinicogenetic entity. Arch Dermatol 2009; 145: 576-578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ziakas NG, Jogiya A, Michaelides M. A case of familial trichomegaly in association with oculocutaneous albinism type 1. Eye (Lond) 2004; 18: 863-864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nazareth MR, Bunimovich O, Rothman IL. Trichomegaly in a 3-year-old girl with alopecia areata. Pediatr Dermatol 2009; 26: 188-193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ning B, Dharmasena A, Inkster C. Regrowth of upper eyelid eyelashes after making a surgical incision on the upper eyelid in a case of severe alopecia areata. Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg 2014; 30: e2-e3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vélez A, Kindelán JM, García-Herola A, García-Lázaro M, Sánchez-Guijo P. Acquired trichomegaly and hypertrichosis in metastatic adenocarcinoma. Clin Exp Dermatol 1995; 20: 237-239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma RC, Mahajan VK, Sharma NL, Sharma A. Trichomegaly of the eyelashes in dermatomyositis. Dermatology 2002; 205: 305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossetto JD, Nascimento H, Muccioli C, Belfort R, Jr. Essential trichomegaly: case report. Arq Bras Oftalmol 2013; 76: 50-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernández-Crehuet P, Ruiz-Villaverde R. Essential trichomegaly of the eyelashes. Int J Trichology 2016; 8: 153-154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honma M, Shimamura T, Komatsu S, Minami-Hori M, Hinooka R, Iizuka H. Eyelash trichomegaly: report of a case following diffuse hair loss associated with transient malnutrition. J Dermatol 2013; 40: 759-760.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta N, D'Souza P. Ciliary hypertrichosis in a child with keratomalacia. Ann Trop Med Parasitol 2010; 104: 609-611.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aghaei S, Dastgheib L. Acquired eyelash trichomegaly and generalized hypertrichosis associated with breast anomaly. Dermatol Online J 2006; 12: 19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muraki K, Katano R, Hiraki Y, Ueda K, Fujita H. A case of an interstitial tandem direct duplication of long arm of chromosome 4: 46, XY, dup (4) (q25q31.3) de novo. Hiroshima J Med Sci 1997; 46: 105-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mégarbané A, Samaras L, Chédid R et al. Developmental delay, dysmorphic features, neonatal spontaneous fractures, wrinkled skin, and hepatic failure: a new metabolic syndrome? Am J Med Genet A 2008; 146a: 3198-3201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joganathan V, Norris JH. Periocular manifestations of afatinib therapy. Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg 2019; 35: e12-e13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang G, Basti S, Jampol LM. Acquired trichomegaly and symptomatic external ocular changes in patients receiving epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors: case reports and a review of literature. Cornea 2007; 26: 858-860.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agrawal CR, Goyal P, Doval DC, Dutta K, Domadia K, Kothiwal S. Eyelashes trichomegaly: an unusual side effect of gefitinib therapy. Int J Trichology 2018; 10: 44-46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bétrian S, Gomez-Roca C, Vigarios E, Delord JP, Sibaud V. Severe onycholysis and eyelash trichomegaly following use of new selective Pan-FGFR inhibitors. JAMA Dermatol 2017; 153: 723-725.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deutsch A, McLellan BN. Severe onycholysis and eyelash trichomegaly in a patient treated with erdafitinib. JAAD Case Rep 2020; 6: 569-571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song J, Song A, Palmares T, Song M, Song H. Ruxolitinib found to cause eyelash growth: a case report. J Med Case Rep 2017; 11: 189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas CL, Mortimer PS, Larkin JM, Basu TN, Gore ME, Fearfield L. A mitogen-activated protein kinase kinase inhibitor induced compound skin toxicity with oedema in metastatic malignant melanoma. Clin Exp Dermatol 2016; 41: 267-271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santmyire-Rosenberger BR, Albert M. Acquired trichomegaly with topiramate. J Am Acad Dermatol 2005; 53: 362-363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith S, Fagien S, Whitcup SM et al. Eyelash growth in subjects treated with bimatoprost: a multicenter, randomized, double-masked, vehicle-controlled, parallel-group study. J Am Acad Dermatol 2012; 66: 801-806.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vetrugno M, Sborgia C, Balestrazzi E et al. Efficacy and safety of bimatoprost in patients with uncontrolled glaucoma as alternative to filtration surgery. Eur J Ophthalmol 2005; 15: 477-481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manni G, Centofanti M, Parravano M, Oddone F, Bucci MG. A 6-month randomized clinical trial of bimatoprost 0.03% versus the association of timolol 0.5% and latanoprost 0.005% in glaucomatous patients. Albrecht Von Graefes Arch Klin Exp Ophthalmol 2004; 242; 767-770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skorin L, Jr, Dailey KH. Clicking eyelids: a new finding of prostaglandin-associated periorbitopathy. Optom vis Sci 2016; 93: 779-781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herane MI, Urbina F. Acquired trichomegaly of the eyelashes and hypertrichosis induced by bimatoprost. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2004; 18: 644-645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitcup SM, Cantor LB, VanDenburgh AM, Chen K. A randomised, double masked, multicentre clinical trial comparing bimatoprost and timolol for the treatment of glaucoma and ocular hypertension. Br J Ophthalmol 2003; 87: 57-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noecker RS, Dirks MS, Choplin NT, Bernstein P, Batoosingh AL, Whitcup SM. A six-month randomized clinical trial comparing the intraocular pressure-lowering efficacy of bimatoprost and latanoprost in patients with ocular hypertension or glaucoma. Am J Ophthalmol 2003; 135: 55-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glaser DA, Hossain P, Perkins W et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of bimatoprost solution 003% application to the eyelid margin for the treatment of idiopathic and chemotherapy-induced eyelash hypotrichosis: a randomized controlled trial. Br J Dermatol 2015; 172: 1384-1394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harii K, Arase S, Tsuboi R, Weng E, Daniels S, VanDenburgh A. Bimatoprost for eyelash growth in Japanese subjects: two multicenter controlled studies. Aesthetic Plast Surg 2014; 38: 451-460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahluwalia GS. Safety and efficacy of bimatoprost solution 0.03% topical application in patients with chemotherapy-induced eyelash loss. J Investig Dermatol Symp Proc 2013; 16: S73-S76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirta D, Baumann L, Bruce S, Ahluwalia G, Weng E, Daniels S. Safety and efficacy of bimatoprost for eyelash growth in postchemotherapy subjects. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol 2015; 8: 11-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris CL, Stinnett S, Woodward J. The role of bimatoprost eyelash gel in chemotherapy-induced madarosis: an analysis of efficacy and safety. Int J Trichology 2011; 3: 84-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwon O, Kim JY, Paik SH et al. Long-term utility and durability of the therapeutic effects of bimatoprost 0.03% for eyelash augmentation in healthy Asian subjects. Dermatology 2014; 229: 222-229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fagien S, Walt JG, Carruthers J et al. Patient-reported outcomes of bimatoprost for eyelash growth: results from a randomized, double-masked, vehicle-controlled, parallel-group study. Aesthetic Surg J 2013; 33: 789-798.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wester ST, Lee WW, Shi W. Eyelash growth from application of bimatoprost in gel suspension to the base of the eyelashes. Ophthalmology 2010; 117: 1024-1031.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodward JA, Haggerty CJ, Stinnett SS, Williams ZY. Bimatoprost 0.03% gel for cosmetic eyelash growth and enhancement. J Cosmet Dermatol 2010; 9: 96-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoelin S, Walt JG, Earl M. Safety, effectiveness, and subjective experience with topical bimatoprost 0.03% for eyelash growth. Dermatol Surg 2010; 36: 638-649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peabody T, Reitz S, Smith J, Teti B. Clinical management of trichotillomania with bimatoprost. Optom Vis Sci 2013; 90: e167-e171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borchert M, Bruce S, Wirta D et al. An evaluation of the safety and efficacy of bimatoprost for eyelash growth in pediatric subjects. Clin Ophthalmol 2016; 10: 419-429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ochoa BE, Sah D, Wang G, Stamper R, Price VH. Instilled bimatoprost ophthalmic solution in patients with eyelash alopecia areata. J Am Acad Dermatol 2009; 61: 530-532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bitton E, Courey C, Giancola P, Diaconu V, Wise J, Wittich W. Effects of LATISSE (bimatoprost 0.03 per cent topical solution) on the ocular surface. Clin Exp Optom 2017; 100: 583-589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nh O, Letulé V, Ruzicka T, Herzinger T, Goldscheider I, von Braunmühl T. Periocular discoloration after using a prostaglandin analog for eyelash enhancement: evaluation with reflectance confocal microscopy. J Cosmet Dermatol 2017; 16: 18-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pucci N, Massai C, Bernardini R et al. Eyelash length in children with vernal keratoconjunctivitis: effect of treatment with cyclosporine eye drops. Int J Immunopathol Pharmacol 2007; 20: 595-599.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ciro C, Luigi P. Effect of fluprostenol isopropyl ester and 15-keto fluprostenol on eyelash growth: a clinical and pharmacologic study. Skinmed 2018; 16: 231-233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabbrocini G, Napolitano A, Masarà A, Cacciapuoti S. 15 keto fluprostenol isopropyl ester (80 µgr/mL) gel for cosmetic eyelash growth and enhancement. J Cosmet Dermatol 2019; 18: 545-549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Digiuni M, Manni G, Vetrugno M et al. An evaluation of therapeutic noninferiority of 0.005% latanoprost ophthalmic solution and xalatan in patients with glaucoma or ocular hypertension. J. Glaucoma 2013; 22: 707-712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alm A. Latanoprost in the treatment of glaucoma. Clin Ophthalmol 2014; 8: 1967-1985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiba T, Kashiwagi K, Ishijima K et al. A prospective study of iridial pigmentation and eyelash changes due to ophthalmic treatment with latanoprost. Jpn J Ophthalmol 2004; 48: 141-147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elgin U, Batman A, Berker N, Ilhan B. The comparison of eyelash lengthening effect of latanoprost therapy in adults and children. Eur J Ophthalmol 2006; 16: 247-250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coronel-Pérez IM, Rodríguez-Rey EM, Camacho-Martínez FM. Latanoprost in the treatment of eyelash alopecia in alopecia areata universalis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2010; 24: 481-485.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faghihi G, Andalib F, Asilian A. The efficacy of latanoprost in the treatment of alopecia areata of eyelashes and eyebrows. Eur J Dermatol 2009; 19: 586-587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dixon ER, Landry T, Venkataraman S et al. A 3-month safety and efficacy study of travoprost 0.004% ophthalmic solution compared with timolol in pediatric patients with glaucoma or ocular hypertension. J AAPOS 2017; 21: 370-374.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bikowski J, Lau EG, Jacob SE. Eyelash growth: a beneficial side effect of prostaglandin analogues. Cutis 2010; 85: 187-188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tran QT, Kennedy LH, Leon Carrion S et al. EGFR regulation of epidermal barrier function. Physiol Genomics 2012; 44: 455-469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matos LV, Pissarra A, Malheiro M, Plácido AN. Trichomegaly of the eyelashes induced by the epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor cetuximab in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer. BMJ Case Rep 2019; 12: e228968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez NA, Ascaso FJ. Trichomegaly and poliosis of the eyelashes during cetuximab treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer. J Clin Oncol 2011; 29: e532-e533.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaccaro M, Pollicino A, Barbuzza O, Guarneri B. Trichomegaly of the eyelashes following treatment with cetuximab. Clin Exp Dermatol 2009; 34: 402-403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vano-Galvan S, Moreno-Martin P, Jaén P. Progressive trichomegaly. Neth J Med 2009; 67: 35-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouché O, Brixi-Benmansour H, Bertin A, Perceau G, Lagarde S. Trichomegaly of the eyelashes following treatment with cetuximab. Ann Oncol 2005; 16: 1711-1712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Štulhofer Buzina D, Martinac I, Ledić Drvar D, Čeović R, Bilić I, Marinović B. Adverse reaction to cetuximab, an epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor. Acta Dermatovenerol Croat 2016; 24: 70-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dueland S, Sauer T, Lund-Johansen F, Ostenstad B, Tveit KM. Epidermal growth factor receptor inhibition induces trichomegaly. Acta Oncol 2003; 42: 345-346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen PR, Escudier SM, Kurzrock R. Cetuximab-associated elongation of the eyelashes: case report and review of eyelash trichomegaly secondary to epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors. Am J Clin Dermatol 2011; 12: 63-67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bambury R, McCaffrey JA. Trichomegaly of the eyelashes after colorectal cancer treatment with the epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor cetuximab. Clin Colorectal Cancer 2009; 8: 235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foerster CG, Cursiefen C, Kruse FE. Persisting corneal erosion under cetuximab (Erbitux) treatment (epidermal growth factor receptor antibody). Cornea 2008; 27: 612-614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koksal UI, Pilanci KN, Ordu C, Okutur K, Saglam S, Demir G. Trichomegaly induced by cetuximab: case series and review the literature. Am J Ther 2016; 23: e1226-e1229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osio A, Mateus C, Soria JC et al. Cutaneous side-effects in patients on long-term treatment with epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors. Br J Dermatol 2009; 161: 515-521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borkar DS, Lacouture ME, Basti S. Spectrum of ocular toxicities from epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors and their intermediate-term follow-up: a five-year review. Support Care Cancer 2013; 21: 1167-1174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabbrocini G, Panariello L, Cacciapuoti S, Bianca D, Ayala F. Trichomegaly of the eyelashes during therapy with epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors: report of 3 cases. Dermatitis 2012; 23: 237-238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goyal S, Uwaydat SH. Epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitor induced trichomegaly and poliosis. Ophthalmology 2018; 125: 294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goyal A, Blaes A. Trichomegaly associated with panitumumab. N Engl J Med 2020; 383: e94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santiago F, Gonçalo M, Reis JP, Figueiredo A. Adverse cutaneous reactions to epidermal growth factor receptor inhibitors: a study of 14 patients. An Bras Dermatol 2011; 86: 483-490.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harshuk-Shabso S, Dressler H, Niehrs C, Aamar E, Enshell-Seijffers D. Fgf and Wnt signaling interaction in the mesenchymal niche regulates the murine hair cycle clock. Nat Commun 2020; 11: 5114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bichsel KJ, Gogia N, Malouff T et al. Role for the epidermal growth factor receptor in chemotherapy-induced alopecia. PLoS One 2013; 8: e69368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howaizi M. Pegylated interferon-induced eyelid and eyebrow trichomegaly during chronic hepatitis C. J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2005; 20: 1945-1946.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goksugur N, Karabay O. Eyelash and eyebrow trichomegaly induced by interferon-alfa 2a. Clin Exp Dermatol 2007; 32: 583-584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misery L. Diffuse hypertrichosis in the course of hepatitis C treatment by IFN-alpha and ribavirin. J Interferon Cytokine Res 2002; 22: 881-882.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández-Núñez A, Fernández-Herrera J, Buceta LR, García-Díez A. Trichomegaly following treatment with interferon alpha-2b. Lancet 2002; 359: 1107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foon KA, Dougher G. Increased growth of eyelashes in a patient given leukocyte A interferon. N Engl J Med 1984; 311: 1259.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ward KM, Barnett C, Fox LP, Grossman ME. Eyelash trichomegaly associated with systemic tacrolimus. Arch Dermatol 2006; 142: 248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horsley V, Aliprantis AO, Polak L, Glimcher LH, Fuchs E. NFATc1 balances quiescence and proliferation of skin stem cells. Cell 2008; 132: 299-310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayamanne DG, Dayan MR, Porter R. Cyclosporin-induced trichomegaly of accessory lashes as a cause of ocular irritation. Nephrol Dial Transplant 1996; 11: 1159-1161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weaver DT, Bartley GB. Cyclosporine-induced trichomegaly. Am J Ophthalmol 1990; 109: 239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molés-Poveda P, Cowen EW. Trichomegaly induced by topical tacrolimus for the treatment of periorbital vitiligo: a brief report of a new adverse effect. Pediatr Dermatol 2019; 36: e95-e96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams ZY, Richard M, Stinnett SS, Woodward JA. Eyelash growth after enucleation and evisceration surgery. Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg 2010; 26: 50-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh M, Pawar M. Eyelash length for the diagnosis of atopic dermatitis and ichthyosis vulgaris in children-a case control study. Eur J Pediatr 2018; 177: 955-960.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alpsoy E. Hypotrichosis, long eyelashes and atopic dermatitis: a new syndrome? J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2004; 18: 374-375.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy Y, Segal N, Ben-Amitai D, Danon YL. Eyelash length in children and adolescents with allergic diseases. Pediatr Dermatol 2004; 21: 534-537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolognia J, Cerroni L &amp; Schaffer JV Dermatology, 2018. Saunders/Elsevier. ISBN 9780702062759 0702062758.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayer A, Bagkesen H, Sobaci G. Acquired trichomegaly in uveitis. Can J Ophthalmol 2007; 42: 101-106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pucci N, Novembre E, Lombardi E et al. Long eyelashes in a case series of 93 children with vernal keratoconjunctivitis. Pediatrics 2005; 115: e86-e91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almagro M, del Pozo J, García-Silva J, Martínez W, Castro A, Fonseca E. Eyelash length in HIV-infected patients. Aids 2003; 17: 1695-1696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondoh T, Amamoto N, Hirota T et al. Very long eyelashes, long eyebrows, sparse hair, and mental retardation in two unrelated boys: an atypical form of Oliver-McFarlane syndrome without retinal degeneration, or a new clinical entity? Am J Med Genet A 2003; 120a: 437-438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haimi M, Gershoni-Baruch R. Autosomal recessive Oliver-McFarlane syndrome: retinitis pigmentosa, short stature (GH deficiency), trichomegaly, and hair anomalies or CPD syndrome (chorioretinopathy-pituitary dysfunction). Am J Med Genet A 2005; 138a: 268-271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedroso JL, Rivero RL, de Miranda VA et al. Neuroimaging features in congenital trichomegaly: the Oliver-McFarlane syndrome. J Neuroimaging 2014; 24: 418-420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheng X, Zhang S, Peter Boergen K, Li H, Liu Y. Oliver-McFarlane syndrome in a chinese boy: retinitis pigmentosa, trichomegaly, hair anomalies and mental retardation. Ophthalmic Genet 2015; 36: 70-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patsi O, De Beaufort C, Kerschen P et al. A new PNPLA6 mutation presenting as Oliver McFarlane syndrome. J Neurol Sci 2018; 392: 1-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haritoglou C, Rudolph G, Kalpadakis P, Boergen KP. Congenital trichomegaly (Oliver-McFarlane syndrome): a case report with 9 years' follow up. Br J Ophthalmol 2003; 87: 119-120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patton MA, Harding AE, Baraitser M. Congenital trichomegaly, pigmentary retinal degeneration, and short stature. Am J Ophthalmol 1986; 101: 490-491.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corby DG, Lowe RS, Jr, Haskins RC, Hebertson LM. Trichomegaly, pigmentary degeneration of the retina, and growth retardation. A new syndrome originating in utero. Am J Dis Child 1971; 121: 344-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NIH National Library of Medicine. Floating-Harbor Syndrome: Medlineplus Genetics. MedlinePlus, U.S. National Library of Medicine. https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/floating-harbor-syndrome/ (last accessed: 13 December 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cannavò S, Bartolone L, Lapa D et al. Abnormalities of GH secretion in a young girl with Floating-Harbor syndrome. J Endocrinol Invest 2002; 25: 58-64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majewski F, Lenard HG. The Floating-Harbor syndrome. Eur J Pediatr 1991; 150: 250-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodman RH, Smolik S. CBP/p300 in cell growth, transformation, and development. Genes Dev 2000; 14: 1553-1577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zwierzchowski TJ, Przedborska A, Wilmańska I, Raczkowski JW. Rubinstein-Taybi syndrome in a 19-years old boy. Neuro Endocrinol Lett 2015; 36: 417-420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones KL, Jones MC, Campo M. Smith's Recognizable Patterns of Human Malformation E-Book. Philadelphia, PA: Saunders, 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gnazzo M, Lepri FR, Dentici ML et al. KBG syndrome: common and uncommon clinical features based on 31 new patients. Am J Med Genet A 2020; 182: 1073-1083.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang A, Yeung PL, Li CW et al. Identification of a novel family of ankyrin repeats containing cofactors for p160 nuclear receptor coactivators. J Biol Chem 2004; 279: 33799-33805.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blauer M, Vaalasti A, Pauli SL, Ylikomi T, Joensuu T, Tuohimaa P. Location of androgen receptor in human skin. J Invest Dermatol 1991; 97: 264-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Randall VA, Hibberts NA, Thornton MJ et al. The hair follicle: a paradoxical androgen target organ. Horm Res 2000; 54: 243-250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NIH National Library of Medicine . PNPLA6 Gene: Medlineplus Genetics. MedlinePlus, U.S. National Library of Medicine. https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/gene/pnpla6/ (last accessed: 20 November 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barakat MR, Traboulsi EI, Sears JE. Coats' disease, megalopapilla and Cornelia de Lange syndrome. Ophthalmic Genet 2009; 30: 106-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson L, Kline AD, Barr MA, Koch S. de Lange syndrome: a clinical review of 310 individuals. Am J Med Genet 1993; 47: 940-946.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park KH, Lee ST, Ki CS, Byun SY. Cornelia de Lange Syndrome with NIPBL gene mutation: a case report. J Korean Med Sci 2010; 25: 1821-1823.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson R. The de Lange syndrome: report of three cases. Can Med Assoc J 1964; 91: 643-646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sciorra LJ, Bahng K, Lee ML. Trisomy in the distal end of the long arm of chromosome 3. A condition clinically similar to the Cornelia de Lange syndrome. Am J Dis Child 1979; 133: 727-730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levin AV, Seidman DJ, Nelson LB, Jackson LG. Ophthalmologic findings in the Cornelia de Lange syndrome. J Pediatr Ophthalmol Strabismus 1990; 27: 94-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luna-Peláez N, March-Díaz R, Ceballos-Chávez M et al. The Cornelia de Lange syndrome-associated factor NIPBL interacts with BRD4 ET domain for transcription control of a common set of genes. Cell Death Dis 2019; 10: 548.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raible SE, Mehta D, Bettale C et al. Clinical and molecular spectrum of CHOPS syndrome. Am J Med Genet A 2019; 179: 1126-1138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosho T, Okamoto N. Genotype-phenotype correlation of Coffin-Siris syndrome caused by mutations in SMARCB1, SMARCA4, SMARCE1, and ARID1A. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet 2014; 166c: 262-275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Sluijs PJ, Jansen S, Vergano SA et al. The ARID1B spectrum in 143 patients: from nonsyndromic intellectual disability to Coffin-Siris syndrome. Genet Med 2019; 21: 1295-1307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carey JC, Hall BD. The Coffin-Siris syndrome: five new cases including two siblings. Am J Dis Child 1978; 132: 667-671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrier SA, Bodurtha JN, Burton B et al. The Coffin-Siris syndrome: a proposed diagnostic approach and assessment of 15 overlapping cases. Am J Med Genet A 2012; 158a: 1865-1876.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NORD National Organization for Rare Disorders Coffin Siris Syndrome. https://rarediseases.org/rare-diseases/coffin-siris-syndrome/ (last accessed: 13 December 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rocha CT, Peixoto IT, Fernandes PM, Torres CP, de Queiroz AM. Dental findings in Kabuki make-up syndrome: a case report. Spec Care Dentist 2008; 28: 53-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niikawa N, Matsuura N, Fukushima Y, Ohsawa T, Kajii T. Kabuki make-up syndrome: a syndrome of mental retardation, unusual facies, large and protruding ears, and postnatal growth deficiency. J Pediatr 1981; 99: 565-569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuroki Y, Suzuki Y, Chyo H, Hata A, Matsui I. A new malformation syndrome of long palpebral fissures, large ears, depressed nasal tip, and skeletal anomalies associated with postnatal dwarfism and mental retardation. J Pediatr 1981; 99: 570-573.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sobreira N, Brucato M, Zhang L et al. Patients with a Kabuki syndrome phenotype demonstrate DNA methylation abnormalities. Eur J Hum Genet 2017; 25: 1335-1344.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guérin-Moreau M, Colin E, Nguyen S et al. Dermatologic features of Smith-Magenis syndrome. Pediatr Dermatol 2015; 32: 337-341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NIH National Library of Medicine. Smith-Magenis Syndrome: Medlineplus Genetics. MedlinePlus, U.S. National Library of Medicine. https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/smith-magenis-syndrome (last accessed: 7 November 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okano J, Levy C, Lichti U et al. Cutaneous retinoic acid levels determine hair follicle development and downgrowth. J Biol Chem 2012; 287: 39304-39315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toro J, Turner M, Gahl WA. Dermatologic manifestations of Hermansky-Pudlak syndrome in patients with and without a 16-base pair duplication in the HPS1 gene. Arch Dermatol 1999; 135: 774-780.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NIH National Library of Medicine. Hermansky-Pudlak Syndrome: Medlineplus Genetics. MedlinePlus, U.S. National Library of Medicine. https://medlineplus.gov/genetics/condition/hermansky-pudlak-syndrome/ (last accessed: 7 November 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mansour AM, Bitar FF, Traboulsi EI et al. Ocular pathology in congenital heart disease. Eye (Lond) 2005; 19: 29-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verloes A, Massin M, Fransolet AC, Misson JP. Hypertrichosis, fallot tetralogy, growth and developmental delay. Clin Dysmorphol 2004; 13: 247-250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urban J, Qi L, Zhao H, Rybak I, Rauen KA, Kiuru M. Comparison of hair manifestations in cardio-facio-cutaneous and Costello syndromes highlights the influence of the RAS pathway on hair growth. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2020; 34: 601-607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gripp KW, Hopkins E, Sol-Church K et al. Phenotypic analysis of individuals with Costello syndrome due to HRAS p. G13C. Am J Med Genet A 2011; 155a: 706-716.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rishikaysh P, Dev K, Diaz D, Qureshi WM, Filip S, Mokry J. Signaling involved in hair follicle morphogenesis and development. Int J Mol Sci 2014; 15: 1647-1670.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scurr I, Wilson L, Lees M et al. Cantu syndrome: report of nine new cases and expansion of the clinical phenotype. Am J Med Genet A 2011; 155A: 508-518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamer F, Yuksel ME. Familial eyelash trichomegaly: the case of a sister and a brother. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol 2016; 82: 700-702.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osovsky M, Merlob P. Trichomegaly in two sisters with synophrys in the older sibling. Am J Med Genet A 2005; 136a: 398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harrison DA, Mullaney PB. Familial trichomegaly. Arch Ophthalmol 1997; 115: 1602-1603.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins CA, Petukhova L, Harel S et al. FGF5 is a crucial regulator of hair length in humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2014; 111: 10648-10653.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
