<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34916419</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Is activation of GDNF/RET signaling the answer for successful treatment of Parkinson's disease? A discussion of data from the culture dish to the clinic.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1462</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1467</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1462-1467</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.327330</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The neurotrophic signaling of glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor (GDNF) with its canonical receptor, the receptor tyrosine kinase RET, coupled together with the GDNF family receptor alpha 1 is important for dopaminergic neuron survival and physiology in cell culture experiments and animal models. This prompted the idea to try GDNF/RET signaling as a therapeutic approach to treat Parkinson's disease with the hallmark of dopaminergic cell death in the substantia nigra of the midbrain. Despite several clinical trials with GDNF in Parkinson's disease patients, which mainly focused on optimizing the GDNF delivery technique, benefits were only seen in a few patients. In general, the endpoints did not show significant improvements. This suggests that it will be helpful to learn more about the basic biology of this fascinating but complicated GDNF/RET signaling system in the dopaminergic midbrain and about recent developments in the field to facilitate its use in the clinic. Here we will refer to the latest publications and point out important open questions in the field.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Conway</LastName>
            <ForeName>James A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Translational and Stratified Medicine, Peninsula Medical School, Faculty of Health, University of Plymouth, Devon, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kramer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Edgar R</ForeName>
            <Initials>ER</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Translational and Stratified Medicine, Peninsula Medical School, Faculty of Health, University of Plymouth, Devon, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GFRα1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nedd4</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson’s disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RET</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical trials</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dopaminergic neurons</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut-brain axis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">α-synuclein</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34916419</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8771118</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.327330</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_7_1462_327330</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albert K, Voutilainen MH, Domanskyi A, Airavaara M. AAV vector-mediated gene delivery to substantia nigra dopamine neurons: implications for gene therapy and disease models. Genes (Basel) 2017;8:63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5333052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28208742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axelsen TM, Woldbye DPD. Gene therapy for Parkinson's disease, an update. J Parkinsons Dis. 2018;8:195–215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6027861</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29710735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Backman CM, Shan L, Zhang YJ, Hoffer BJ, Leonard S, Troncoso JC, Vonsatel P, Tomac AC. Gene expression patterns for GDNF and its receptors in the human putamen affected by Parkinson's disease: a real-time PCR study. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2006;252:160–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16644101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barker RA, Björklund A, Gash DM, Whone A, Van Laar A, Kordower JH, Bankiewicz K, Kieburtz K, Saarma M, Booms S, Huttunen HJ, Kells AP, Fiandaca MS, Stoessl AJ, Eidelberg D, Federoff H, Voutilainen MH, Dexter DT, Eberling J, Brundin P, et al.  GDNF and Parkinson's disease: where next? a summary from a recent workshop. J Parkinsons Dis. 2020;10:875–891.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7458523</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barlow A, de Graaff E, Pachnis V. Enteric nervous system progenitors are coordinately controlled by the G protein-coupled receptor EDNRB and the receptor tyrosine kinase RET. Neuron. 2003;40:905–916.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14659090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartus RT, Kordower JH, Johnson EM, Jr, Brown L, Kruegel BR, Chu Y, Baumann TL, Lang AE, Olanow CW, Herzog CD. Post-mortem assessment of the short and long-term effects of the trophic factor neurturin in patients with alpha-synucleinopathies. Neurobiol Dis. 2015;78:162–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25841760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bespalov MM, Saarma M. GDNF family receptor complexes are emerging drug targets. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2007;28:68–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17218019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boger HA, Middaugh LD, Zaman V, Hoffer B, Granholm AC. Differential effects of the dopamine neurotoxin MPTP in animals with a partial deletion of the GDNF receptor, GFR alpha1, gene. Brain Res. 2008;1241:18–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2642614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18822276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braak H, Del Tredici K. Neuropathological staging of brain pathology in sporadic Parkinson's disease: separating the wheat from the chaff. J Parkinsons Dis. 2017;7(s1):S71–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5345633</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28282810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braak H, de Vos RA, Bohl J, Del Tredici K. Gastric alpha-synuclein immunoreactive inclusions in Meissner's and Auerbach's plexuses in cases staged for Parkinson's disease-related brain pathology. Neurosci Lett. 2006;396:67–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen W, Hu Y, Ju D. Gene therapy for neurodegenerative disorders: advances, insights and prospects. Acta Pharm Sin B. 2020;10:1347–1359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7488363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32963936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chmielarz P, Er S, Konovalova J, Bandres L, Hlushchuk I, Albert K, Panhelainen A, Luk K, Airavaara M, Domanskyi A. GDNF/RET signaling pathway activation eliminates lewy body pathology in midbrain dopamine neurons. Mov Disord. 2020;35:2279–2289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32964492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chtarto A, Humbert-Claude M, Bockstael O, Das AT, Boutry S, Breger LS, Klaver B, Melas C, Barroso-Chinea P, Gonzalez-Hernandez T, Muller RN, DeWitte O, Levivier M, Lundberg C, Berkhout B, Tenenbaum L. A regulatable AAV vector mediating GDNF biological effects at clinically-approved sub-antimicrobial doxycycline doses. Mol Ther Methods Clin Dev. 2016;5:16027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4813607</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27069954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conway JA, Ince S, Black S, Kramer ER. GDNF/RET signaling in dopamine neurons in vivo. Cell Tissue Res. 2020;382:135–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32870383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decressac M, Kadkhodaei B, Mattsson B, Laguna A, Perlmann T, Bjorklund A. alpha-Synuclein-induced down-regulation of Nurr1 disrupts GDNF signaling in nigral dopamine neurons. Sci Transl Med. 2012 doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.3004676.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decressac M, Ulusoy A, Mattsson B, Georgievska B, Romero-Ramos M, Kirik D, Bjorklund A. GDNF fails to exert neuroprotection in a rat alpha-synuclein model of Parkinson's disease. Brain. 2011;134:2302–2311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drinkut A, Tillack K, Meka DP, Schulz JB, Kuegler S, Kramer ER. RET is essential to mediate GDNF's neuroprotective and neuroregenerative effect in a Parkinson disease mouse model. Cell Death Dis. 2016;7:e2359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5059866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27607574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duffy MF, Collier TJ, Patterson JR, Kemp CJ, Fischer DL, Stoll AC, Sortwell CE. Quality over quantity: advantages of using alpha-synuclein preformed fibril triggered synucleinopathy to model idiopathic Parkinson's disease. Front Neurosci. 2018;12:621.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6132025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30233303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enterria-Morales D, Lopez-Lopez I, Lopez-Barneo J, d’Anglemont de Tassigny X. Role of glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor in the maintenance of adult mesencephalic catecholaminergic neurons. Mov Disord. 2020;35:565–576.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31930748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuqua JL, Littrell OM, Lundblad M, Turchan-Cholewo J, Abdelmoti LG, Galperin E, Bradley LH, Cass WA, Gash DM, Gerhardt GA. Dynamic changes in dopamine neuron function after DNSP-11 treatment: effects in vivo and increased ERK 1/2 phosphorylation in vitro. Peptides. 2014;54:1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989369</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24406899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gash DM, Gerhardt GA, Bradley LH, Wagner R, Slevin JT. GDNF clinical trials for Parkinson's disease: a critical human dimension. Cell Tissue Res. 2020;382:65–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32830288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgievska B, Kirik D, Bjorklund A. Overexpression of glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor using a lentiviral vector induces time- and dose-dependent downregulation of tyrosine hydroxylase in the intact nigrostriatal dopamine system. J Neurosci. 2004;24:6437–6445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729873</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15269253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gill SS, Patel NK, Hotton GR, O’Sullivan K, McCarter R, Bunnage M, Brooks DJ, Svendsen CN, Heywood P. Direct brain infusion of glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor in Parkinson disease. Nat Med. 2003;9:589–595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12669033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greene JG. Causes and consequences of degeneration of the dorsal motor nucleus of the vagus nerve in Parkinson's disease. Antioxid Redox Signal. 2014;21:649–667.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24597973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grondin R, Littrell OM, Zhang Z, Ai Y, Huettl P, Pomerleau F, Quintero JE, Andersen AH, Stenslik MJ, Bradley LH, Lemmon J, O’Neill MJ, Gash DM, Gerhardt GA. GDNF revisited: a novel mammalian cell-derived variant form of GDNF increases dopamine turnover and improves brain biodistribution. Neuropharmacology. 2019;147:28–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29857941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedstrom KL, Murtie JC, Albers K, Calcutt NA, Corfas G. Treating small fiber neuropathy by topical application of a small molecule modulator of ligand-induced GFRalpha/RET receptor signaling. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:2325–2330.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3926041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24449858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heiss JD, Lungu C, Hammoud DA, Herscovitch P, Ehrlich DJ, Argersinger DP, Sinharay S, Scott G, Wu T, Federoff HJ, Zaghloul KA, Hallett M, Lonser RR, Bankiewicz KS. Trial of magnetic resonance-guided putaminal gene therapy for advanced Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2019;34:1073–1078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6642028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31145831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernando S, Herran E, Figueiro-Silva J, Pedraz JL, Igartua M, Carro E, Hernandez RM. Intranasal administration of TAT-conjugated lipid nanocarriers loading GDNF for Parkinson's disease. Mol Neurobiol. 2018;55:145–155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28866799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyndman BD, Crupi MJF, Peng S, Bone LN, Rekab AN, Lian EY, Wagner SM, Antonescu CN, Mulligan LM. Differential recruitment of E3 ubiquitin ligase complexes regulates RET isoform internalization. J Cell Sci. 2017;130:3282–3296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishiguro Y, Iwashita T, Murakami H, Asai N, Iida K, Goto H, Hayakawa T, Takahashi M. The role of amino acids surrounding tyrosine 1062 in RET in specific binding of the shc phosphotyrosine-binding domain. Endocrinology. 1999;140:3992–3998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10465268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ivanova L, Tammiku-Taul J, Sidorova Y, Saarma M, Karelson M. Small-molecule ligands as potential GDNF family receptor agonists. ACS Omega. 2018;3:1022–1030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6045390</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30023796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jmaeff S, Sidorova Y, Lippiatt H, Barcelona PF, Nedev H, Saragovi LM, Hancock MA, Saarma M, Saragovi HU. Small-molecule ligands that bind the RET receptor activate neuroprotective signals independent of but modulated by coreceptor GFRalpha1. Mol Pharmacol. 2020a;98:1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jmaeff S, Sidorova Y, Nedev H, Saarma M, Saragovi HU. Small-molecule agonists of the RET receptor tyrosine kinase activate biased trophic signals that are influenced by the presence of GFRa1 co-receptors. J Biol Chem. 2020b;295:6532–6542.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32245892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kingsbury AE, Daniel SE, Sangha H, Eisen S, Lees AJ, Foster OJ. Alteration in alpha-synuclein mRNA expression in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2004;19:162–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14978671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkeby A, Barker RA. Parkinson disease and growth factors -is GDNF good enough? Nat Rev Neurol. 2019;15:312–314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30948845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopra JJ, Panhelainen A, Af Bjerken S, Porokuokka LL, Varendi K, Olfat S, Montonen H, Piepponen TP, Saarma M, Andressoo JO. Dampened amphetamine-stimulated behavior and altered dopamine transporter function in the absence of brain GDNF. J Neurosci. 2017;37:1581–1590.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6705679</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28096470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopra J, Vilenius C, Grealish S, Harma MA, Varendi K, Lindholm J, Castren E, Voikar V, Bjorklund A, Piepponen TP, Saarma M, Andressoo JO. GDNF is not required for catecholaminergic neuron survival in vivo. Nat Neurosci. 2015;18:319–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4878654</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25710828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kordower JH. AAV2-Neurturin for Parkinson's disease: what lessons have we learned? Methods Mol Biol. 2016;1382:485–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26611606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kramer ER, Aron L, Ramakers GMJ, Seitz S, Zhuang X, Beyer K, Smidt MP, Klein R. Absence of RET signaling in mice causes progressive and late degeneration of the nigrostriatal system. PLoS Biol. 2007;5:616–628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1808500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17298183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kramer ER, Liss B. GDNF-RET signaling in midbrain dopaminergic neurons and its implication for Parkinson disease. FEBS Lett. 2015;589:3760–3772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26555190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A, Kopra J, Varendi K, Porokuokka LL, Panhelainen A, Kuure S, Marshall P, Karalija N, Härma MA, Vilenius C, Lilleväli K, Tekko T, Mijatovic J, Pulkkinen N, Jakobson M, Jakobson M, Ola R, Palm E, Lindahl M, Strömberg I, et al.  GDNF overexpression from the native locus reveals its role in the nigrostriatal dopaminergic system function. PLoS Genet. 2015;11:e1005710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4682981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26681446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lake D, Correa SA, Muller J. Negative feedback regulation of the ERK1/2 MAPK pathway. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2016;73:4397–4413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5075022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27342992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lang AE, Gill S, Patel NK, Lozano A, Nutt JG, Penn R, Brooks DJ, Hotton G, Moro E, Heywood P, Brodsky MA, Burchiel K, Kelly P, Dalvi A, Scott B, Stacy M, Turner D, Wooten VG, Elias WJ, Laws ER, et al.  Randomized controlled trial of intraputamenal glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor infusion in Parkinson disease. Ann Neurol. 2006;59:459–466.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16429411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li K, Zhang K, Xu S, Wang X, Zhou Y, Zhou Y, Gao P, Lin J, Ding G, Guo G. EMP-induced BBB-disruption enhances drug delivery to glioma and increases treatment efficacy in rats. Bioelectromagnetics. 2018;39:60–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29105885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo Bianco C, Deglon N, Pralong W, Aebischer P. Lentiviral nigral delivery of GDNF does not prevent neurodegeneration in a genetic rat model of Parkinson's disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2004;17:283–289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15474365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahato AK, Kopra J, Renko JM, Visnapuu T, Korhonen I, Pulkkinen N, Bespalov MM, Domanskyi A, Ronken E, Piepponen TP, Voutilainen MH, Tuominen RK, Karelson M, Sidorova YA, Saarma M. Glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor receptor Rearranged during transfection agonist supports dopamine neurons in vitro and enhances dopamine release in vivo. Mov Disord. 2020;35:245–255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7496767</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840869</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahato AK, Sidorova YA. Glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factors (GFLs) and small molecules targeting RET receptor for the treatment of pain and Parkinson's disease. Cell Tissue Res. 2020;382:147–160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529621</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manfredsson FP, Polinski NK, Subramanian T, Boulis N, Wakeman DR, Mandel RJ. The future of GDNF in Parkinson's disease. Front Aging Neurosci. 2020;12:593572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7750181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33364933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meka DP, Mueller-Rischart AK, Nidadavolu P, Mohammadi B, Motori E, Ponna SK, Aboutalebi H, Bassal M, Annamneedi A, Finckh B, Miesbauer M, Rotermund N, Lohr C, Tatzelt J, Winklhofer KF, Kramer ER. Parkin cooperates with GDNF/RET signaling to prevent dopaminergic neuron degeneration. J Clin Invest. 2015;125:1873–1885.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4611569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25822020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mijatovic J, Airavaara M, Planken A, Auvinen P, Raasmaja A, Piepponen TP, Costantini F, Ahtee L, Saarma M. Constitutive RET activity in knock-in multiple endocrine neoplasia type B mice induces profound elevation of brain dopamine concentration via enhanced synthesis and increases the number of TH-positive cells in the substantia nigra. J Neurosci. 2007;27:4799–4809.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17475787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nosrat CA, Tomac A, Hoffer BJ, Olson L. Cellular and developmental patterns of expression of RET and glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor receptor alpha mRNAs. Exp Brain Res. 1997;115:410–422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9262196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nutt JG, Burchiel KJ, Comella CL, Jankovic J, Lang AE, Laws ER, Jr, Lozano AM, Penn RD, Simpson RK, Jr, Stacy M, Wooten GF factor IGSGIiGcl-dn. Randomized, double-blind trial of glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor (GDNF) in PD. Neurology. 2003;60:69–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olgiati S, Thomas A, Quadri M, Breedveld GJ, Graafland J, Eussen H, Douben H, de Klein A, Onofrj M, Bonifati V. Early-onset parkinsonism caused by alpha-synuclein gene triplication: clinical and genetic findings in a novel family. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2015;21:981–986.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26077166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedrosa Carrasco AJ, Timmermann L, Pedrosa DJ. Management of constipation in patients with Parkinson's disease. NPJ Parkinsons Dis. 2018;4:6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5856748</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29560414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polinski NK, Volpicelli-Daley LA, Sortwell CE, Luk KC, Cremades N, Gottler LM, Froula J, Duffy MF, Lee VMY, Martinez TN, Dave KD. Best practices for generating and using alpha-synuclein pre-formed fibrils to model Parkinson's disease in rodents. J Parkinsons Dis. 2018;8:303–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6004926</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29400668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quintino L, Avallone M, Brannstrom E, Kavanagh P, Lockowandt M, Garcia Jareno P, Breger LS, Lundberg C. GDNF-mediated rescue of the nigrostriatal system depends on the degree of degeneration. Gene Ther. 2019;26:57–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6514883</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30531868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renko JM, Mahato AK, Visnapuu T, Valkonen K, Karelson M, Voutilainen MH, Saarma M, Tuominen RK, Sidorova YA. Neuroprotective potential of a small molecule RET Agonist in cultured dopamine neurons and hemiparkinsonian rats. J Parkinsons Dis. 2021 doi: 10.3233/JPD-202400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8461720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34024778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Runeberg-Roos P, Penn RD. Improving therapeutic potential of GDNF family ligands. Cell Tissue Res. 2020;382:173–183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7529618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32725425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Runeberg-Roos P, Piccinini E, Penttinen AM, Matlik K, Heikkinen H, Kuure S, Bespalov MM, Peranen J, Garea-Rodriguez E, Fuchs E, Airavaara M, Kalkkinen N, Penn R, Saarma M. Developing therapeutically more efficient Neurturin variants for treatment of Parkinson's disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;96:335–345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27425888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schaeffer E, Kluge A, Bottner M, Zunke F, Cossais F, Berg D, Arnold P. Alpha synuclein connects the gut-brain axis in Parkinson's disease patients - a view on clinical aspects, cellular pathology and analytical methodology. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8:573696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7509446</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlee S, Carmillo P, Whitty A. Quantitative analysis of the activation mechanism of the multicomponent growth-factor receptor RET. Nat Chem Biol. 2006;2:636–644.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17013378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siddiqui MF, Rast S, Lynn MJ, Auchus AP, Pfeiffer RF. Autonomic dysfunction in Parkinson's disease: a comprehensive symptom survey. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2002;8:277–284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12039423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidorova YA, Bespalov MM, Wong AW, Kambur O, Jokinen V, Lilius TO, Suleymanova I, Karelson G, Rauhala PV, Karelson M, Osborne PB, Keast JR, Kalso EA, Saarma M. A novel small molecule gdnf receptor RET agonist, BT13, promotes neurite growth from sensory neurons in vitro and attenuates experimental neuropathy in the rat. Front Pharmacol. 2017;8:365.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5478727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28680400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidorova YA, Saarma M. Can growth factors cure Parkinson's disease? Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2020;41:909–922.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33198924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slevin JT, Gash DM, Smith CD, Gerhardt GA, Kryscio R, Chebrolu H, Walton A, Wagner R, Young AB. Unilateral intraputamenal glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor in patients with Parkinson disease: response to 1 year of treatment and 1 year of withdrawal. J Neurosurg. 2007;106:614–620.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17432712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slevin JT, Gerhardt GA, Smith CD, Gash DM, Kryscio R, Young B. Improvement of bilateral motor functions in patients with Parkinson disease through the unilateral intraputaminal infusion of glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor. J Neurosurg. 2005;102:216–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15739547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith RC, O’Bryan LM, Mitchell PJ, Leung D, Ghanem M, Wilson JM, Hanson JC, Sossick S, Cooper J, Huang L, Merchant KM, Lu J, O’Neill MJ. Increased brain bio-distribution and chemical stability and decreased immunogenicity of an engineered variant of GDNF. Exp Neurol. 2015;267:165–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stenslik MJ, Potts LF, Sonne JW, Cass WA, Turchan-Cholewo J, Pomerleau F, Huettl P, Ai Y, Gash DM, Gerhardt GA, Bradley LH. Methodology and effects of repeated intranasal delivery of DNSP-11 in a rat model of Parkinson's disease. J Neurosci Methods. 2015;251:120–129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500736</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25999268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su X, Fischer DL, Li X, Bankiewicz K, Sortwell CE, Federoff HJ. Alpha-Synuclein mRNA is not increased in sporadic PD and alpha-synuclein accumulation does not block GDNF signaling in Parkinson's disease and disease models. Mol Ther. 2017;25:2231–2235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5628770</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28522034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taraviras S, Marcos-Gutierrez CV, Durbec P, Jani H, Grigoriou M, Sukumaran M, Wang LC, Hynes M, Raisman G, Pachnis V. Signalling by the RET receptor tyrosine kinase and its role in the development of the mammalian enteric nervous system. Development. 1999;126:2785–2797.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10331988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tofaris GK, Kim HT, Hourez R, Jung JW, Kim KP, Goldberg AL. Ubiquitin ligase Nedd4 promotes alpha-synuclein degradation by the endosomal-lysosomal pathway. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2011;108:17004–17009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3193191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21953697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tokugawa K, Yamamoto K, Nishiguchi M, Sekine T, Sakai M, Ueki T, Chaki S, Okuyama S. XIB4035, a novel nonpeptidyl small molecule agonist for GFRalpha-1. Neurochem Int. 2003;42:81–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12441171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turconi G, Kopra J, Voikar V, Kulesskaya N, Vilenius C, Piepponen TP, Andressoo JO. Chronic 2-fold elevation of endogenous GDNF levels is safe and enhances motor and dopaminergic function in aged mice. Mol Ther Methods Clin Dev. 2020;17:831–842.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7191127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32368564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uesaka T, Jain S, Yonemura S, Uchiyama Y, Milbrandt J, Enomoto H. Conditional ablation of GFRalpha1 in postmigratory enteric neurons triggers unconventional neuronal death in the colon and causes a Hirschsprung's disease phenotype. Development. 2007;134:2171–2181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17507417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viisanen H, Nuotio U, Kambur O, Mahato AK, Jokinen V, Lilius T, Li W, Santos HA, Karelson M, Rauhala P, Kalso E, Sidorova YA. Novel RET agonist for the treatment of experimental neuropathies. Mol Pain. 2020;16:1744806920950866.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7440726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volinsky N, Kholodenko BN. Complexity of receptor tyrosine kinase signal processing. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2013;5:a009043.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721286</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23906711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallen AA, Castro DS, Zetterstrom RH, Karlen M, Olson L, Ericson J, Perlmann T. Orphan nuclear receptor Nurr1 is essential for RET expression in midbrain dopamine neurons and in the brain stem. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2001;18:649–663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11749040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whone AL, Boca M, Luz M, Woolley M, Mooney L, Dharia S, Broadfoot J, Cronin D, Schroers C, Barua NU, Longpre L, Barclay CL, Boiko C, Johnson GA, Fibiger HC, Harrison R, Lewis O, Pritchard G, Howell M, Irving C, et al.  Extended treatment with glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor in Parkinson's disease. J Parkinsons Dis. 2019a;9:301–313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6597995</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30829619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whone A, Luz M, Boca M, Woolley M, Mooney L, Dharia S, Broadfoot J, Cronin D, Schroers C, Barua NU, Longpre L, Barclay CL, Boiko C, Johnson GA, Fibiger HC, Harrison R, Lewis O, Pritchard G, Howell M, Irving C, et al.  Randomized trial of intermittent intraputamenal glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor in Parkinson's disease. Brain. 2019b;142:512–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6391602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin D, Valles FE, Fiandaca MS, Forsayeth J, Larson P, Starr P, Bankiewicz KS. Striatal volume differences between non-human and human primates. J Neurosci Methods. 2009;176:200–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2662364</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18809434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshii SR, Kishi C, Ishihara N, Mizushima N. Parkin mediates proteasome-dependent protein degradation and rupture of the outer mitochondrial membrane. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:19630–19640.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3103342</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21454557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaman V, Boger HA, Granholm AC, Rohrer B, Moore A, Buhusi M, Gerhardt GA, Hoffer BJ, Middaugh LD. The nigrostriatal dopamine system of aging GFRalpha-1 heterozygous mice: neurochemistry, morphology and behavior. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;28:1557–1568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2704551</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18973577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
