<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34913178</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2125</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>88</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>British journal of clinical pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Br J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Choice of oral anticoagulant prescribed by general practices in Wales: Application of Dirichlet regression and linked data.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2782</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2792</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2782-2792</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bcp.15183</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">There has been sustained growth in the prescribing of direct oral anticoagulants (OACs) in primary care in the UK. Given the different indications, properties and prices of OACs, variation between prescribers is expected; however, a high level of variation may be evidence of inappropriate or suboptimal prescribing. This study examined the variation in the relative use of OACs in primary care in Wales.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data on total defined daily doses of all community-dispensed OACs in 2019 were linked at the GP practice level with disease registers, patient demographic data and GP and patient numbers. The relative use of each OAC, as a fraction of all OACs prescribed, was analysed using Dirichlet regression to quantify the association between prescribing patterns and practice and area-level characteristics.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Across 417 GP practices, the mean (range) in the relative prescribing of warfarin was 37% (6%-64%), apixaban was 32% (2%-65%), rivaroxaban 23% (0%-66%), dabigatran 3% (0%-23%) and edoxaban 6% (0%-59%). Statistical modelling provided strong evidence that prescribing patterns are associated with a GP practice's health board and also their nearest major hospital. Compared to the null model, a model including health board resulted in a 15% fall in Akaike information criterion, increasing to 20% with the addition of nearest major hospital and 27% including further covariates.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Systematic variation in OAC prescribing, by health board and based on nearest hospital, indicates that factors other than patient clinical characteristics and preferences may be influencing prescribing decisions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hill-McManus</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1936-3907</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Health Economics and Medicines Evaluation, Bangor University, Bangor, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hughes</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dyfrig A</ForeName>
            <Initials>DA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8247-7459</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Health Economics and Medicines Evaluation, Bangor University, Bangor, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Br J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7503323</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0306-5251</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011728">Pyridones</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>9NDF7JZ4M3</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000069552">Rivaroxaban</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>I0VM4M70GC</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000069604">Dabigatran</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001281" MajorTopicYN="Y">Atrial Fibrillation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069604" MajorTopicYN="N">Dabigatran</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011728" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyridones</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069552" MajorTopicYN="N">Rivaroxaban</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000075403" MajorTopicYN="N">Semantic Web</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014852" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Wales</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dirichlet regression</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral anticoagulants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacoepidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescribing variation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>44</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34913178</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15183</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loo SY, Dell'Aniello S, Huiart L, Renoux C. Trends in the prescription of novel oral anticoagulants in UK primary care. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2017;83(9):2096-2106. doi: 10.1111/bcp.13299</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ho KH, Van Hove M, Leng G. Trends in anticoagulant prescribing: a review of local policies in English primary care. BMC Health Serv Res. 2020;20(1):1-8. doi: 10.1186/s12913-020-5058-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vinogradova Y, Coupland C, Hill T, Hippisley-Cox J. Risks and benefits of direct oral anticoagulants versus warfarin in a real world setting: cohort study in primary care. BMJ. 2018;362:k2505. doi: 10.1136/bmj.k2505</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zirlik A, Bode C. Vitamin K antagonists: relative strengths and weaknesses vs. direct oral anticoagulants for stroke prevention in patients with atrial fibrillation. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2017;43(3):365-379. doi: 10.1007/s11239-016-1446-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burn J, Pirmohamed M. Direct oral anticoagulants versus warfarin: is new always better than the old? Open Hear. 2018;5(1):e000712. doi: 10.1136/openhrt-2017-000712</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pink J, Pirmohamed M, Hughes DA. Comparative effectiveness of dabigatran, rivaroxaban, apixaban, and warfarin in the management of patients with nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2013;94(2):269-276. doi: 10.1038/clpt.2013.83</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Atrial fibrillation: management. Clinical Guideline 180. 2014. Accessed December 18, 2021. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg180. Published June 18, 20114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>All Wales Medicines Strategy Group. All Wales Advice on Oral Anticoagulation for Non-Valvular Atrial Fibrillation. 2020. Accessed December 18, 2021. https://awmsg.nhs.wales/files/guidelines-and-pils/all-wales-advice-on-oral-anticoagulation-for-non-valvular-atrial-fibrillation-pdf/. Published March 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aneurin Bevan University Health Board. Pointers to DOAC Treatment Choices in Non-valvular AF. 2019. http://www.wales.nhs.uk/sites3/Documents/814/WhichNOACforWhichPatientFINAL.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The Association of the British Pharmaceutical Industry. One year on: why are patients still having unnecessary AF-related strokes? 2016. Accessed December 18, 2021. https://www.heartrhythmalliance.org/files/files/afa/for-clinicians/SAFI%20report.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang ZX, van de Garde EMW, Söhne M, Harmsze AM, van den Broek MPH. Quality of clinical direct oral anticoagulant prescribing and identification of risk factors for inappropriate prescriptions. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2020;86(8):1567-1574. doi: 10.1111/bcp.14264</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pharithi RB, Ranganathan D, O'Brien J, et al. Is the prescription right? A review of non-vitamin K antagonist anticoagulant (NOAC) prescriptions in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation. Safe prescribing in atrial fibrillation and evaluation of non-vitamin K oral anticoagulants in stroke prevention (SAFE-NOACS) group. Ir J Med Sci. 2019;188(1):101-108. doi: 10.1007/s11845-018-1837-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schaefer JK, Sood SL, Haymart B, et al. Sociodemographic factors in patients continuing warfarin vs those transitioning to direct oral anticoagulants. Blood Adv. 2017;1(26):2536-2540. doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2017012377</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nathan AS, Geng Z, Dayoub EJ, et al. Racial, ethnic, and socioeconomic inequities in the prescription of direct oral anticoagulants in patients with venous thromboembolism in the United States. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2019;12(4):1-7. doi: 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.119.005600</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Essien UR, Magnani JW, Chen N, Gellad WF, Fine MJ, Hernandez I. Race/ethnicity and sex-related differences in direct oral anticoagulant initiation in newly diagnosed atrial fibrillation: a retrospective study of Medicare data. J Natl Med Assoc. 2020;112(1):103-108. doi: 10.1016/j.jnma.2019.10.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gurusamy VK, Brobert G, Vora P, Friberg L. Sociodemographic factors and choice of oral anticoagulant in patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation in Sweden: a population-based cross-sectional study using data from national registers. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2019;19(1):1-6. doi: 10.1186/s12872-019-1029-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu J, Alexander GC, Nazarian S, Segal JB, Wu AW. Trends and variation in oral anticoagulant choice in patients with atrial fibrillation, 2010-2017. Pharmacotherapy. 2018;38(9):907-920.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medlinskiene K, Fay M, Petty D. Uptake of oral anticoagulants for stroke prevention in patients with atrial fibrillation in a single clinical commissioning group in England without restrictions to their use. Clin Drug Investig. 2019;39(4):401-405. doi: 10.1007/s40261-019-00763-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NHS Wales Shared Services Partnership (SSP). GP Practice Analysis (2013-2020) [Data File]. GP Practice Analysis. Accessed April 20, 2020. http://www.primarycareservices.wales.nhs.uk/gp-practice-analysis. Published 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NHS Wales Shared Services Partnership (SSP). GP Prescribing Data Extract 2012-2020 [Data Files]. General Practice Prescribing Data Extract. Accessed January 1, 2020. http://www.primarycareservices.wales.nhs.uk/general-practice-prescribing-data-extrac. Published 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsh Government. General Medical Services Contract: Quality and Outcomes Framework Statistics for Wales, 2018-19. Vol SFR 87/201. 2019. Accessed December 18, 2021. https://gov.wales/sites/default/files/statistics-and-research/2019-09/general-medical-services-contract-quality-and-outcomes-framework-april-2018-march-20199-599.pdf. Published September 25, 2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics for Wales. Welsh Index of Multiple Deprivation (WIMD) 2019 Results Report; 2019. Accessed December 18, 2021. https://gov.wales/sites/default/files/statistics-and-research/2020-02/welsh-index-multiple-deprivation-2019-results-report.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsh Government. General medical practitioners: as at 30 September 2018. Statistics and research. 2018. Accessed January 1, 2020. https://gov.wales/general-medical-practitioners-30-september-2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Public Health Wales Observatory. General Practice Population Profiles 2015 Analysis. General Practice Population Profiles. 2015. Accessed January 1, 2020. http://www.publichealthwalesobservatory.wales.nhs.uk/analysis-gp-population-profiles</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maier MJ. DirichletReg: Dirichlet regression for compositional data in R. Institute for Statistics and Mathematics, Vienna University of Economics and Business, Report 125. 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsagris M, Stewart C. A Dirichlet regression model for compositional data with zeros. Lobachevskii J Math. 2018;39(3):398-412. doi: 10.1134/S1995080218030198</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin I, Uh HW, Supali T, Mitreva M, Houwing-Duistermaat JJ. The mixed model for the analysis of a repeated-measurement multivariate count data. Stat Med. 2019;38(12):2248-2268. doi: 10.1002/sim.8101</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gueoruieva R, Rosenheck R, Zelterman D. Dirichlet component regression and its applications to psychiatric data. Comput Stat Data Anal. 2008;52(12):5344-5355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paradis E. ape v5.4-1. 2020. Accessed December 18, 2021. https://www.rdocumentation.org/packages/ape. Published August 13, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Douma JC, Weedon JT. Analysing continuous proportions in ecology and evolution: a practical introduction to beta and Dirichlet regression. Methods Ecol Evol. 2019;10(9):1412-1430. doi: 10.1111/2041-210X.13234</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aitchison J. The Statistical Analysis of Compositional Data. London: Chapman and Hall; 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldacre B, Reynolds C, Powell-Smith A, et al. Do doctors in dispensing practices with a financial conflict of interest prescribe more expensive drugs? A cross-sectional analysis of English primary care prescribing data. BMJ Open. 2019;9(2):1-8. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026886</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sedgwick P. Understanding the ecological fallacy. BMJ. 2015;351:h4773. doi: 10.1136/bmj.h4773</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
