<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34935179</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>48</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The blood-CSF-brain route of neurological disease: The indirect pathway into the brain.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e12789</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e12789</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12789</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The brain is protected by the endothelial blood-brain barrier (BBB) that limits the access of micro-organisms, tumour cells, immune cells and autoantibodies to the parenchyma. However, the classic model of disease spread across a disrupted BBB does not explain the focal distribution of lesions seen in a variety of neurological diseases and why lesions are frequently adjacent to the cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) spaces. We have critically reviewed the possible role of a blood-CSF-brain route as a disease entry pathway into the brain parenchyma. The initial step of this pathway is the transfer of pathogens or immune components from the blood into the CSF at the choroid plexuses, where the blood-CSF barrier (BCSFB) is located. The flow of CSF results in disease dissemination throughout the CSF spaces. Access to the brain parenchyma from the CSF can then occur across the ependymal layer at the ventricular surface or across the pial-glial barrier of the subarachnoid space and the Virchow-Robin spaces. We have reviewed the anatomy and physiology of the blood-CSF-brain pathway and the brain barriers controlling this process. We then summarised the evidence supporting this brain entry route in a cross-section of neurological diseases including neuromyelitis optica, multiple sclerosis, neurosarcoidosis, neuropsychiatric lupus, cryptococcal infection and both solid and haematological tumours. This summary highlights the conditions that share the blood-CSF-brain pathway as a pathogenetic mechanism. These include the characteristic proximity of lesions to CSF, evidence of disruption of the brain barriers and the identification of significant pathology within the CSF. An improved understanding of pathological transfer through the CSF and across all brain barriers will inform on more effective and targeted treatments of primary and secondary diseases of the central nervous system.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cousins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Oliver</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8758-3760</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroimaging, IoPPN, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hodges</LastName>
            <ForeName>Angela</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Old Age Psychiatry, IoPPN, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schubert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julia</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroimaging, IoPPN, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Veronese</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mattia</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroimaging, IoPPN, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Turkheimer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Federico</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroimaging, IoPPN, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miyan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jaleel</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Neuroscience and Experimental Psychology, School of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Biology, Medicine and Health, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Engelhardt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Britta</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Theodor Kocher Institute, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roncaroli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Federico</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3650-5572</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Neuroscience and Experimental Psychology, School of Biological Sciences, Faculty of Biology, Medicine and Health, The University of Manchester, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Geoffrey Jefferson Brain Research Centre, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001692" MajorTopicYN="N">Biological Transport</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001812" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood-Brain Barrier</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002490" MajorTopicYN="N">Central Nervous System</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002831" MajorTopicYN="N">Choroid Plexus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virchow-Robin spaces</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood-CSF barrier</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood-brain barrier</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">choroid plexus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34935179</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12789</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright BL, Lai JT, Sinclair AJ. Cerebrospinal fluid and lumbar puncture: A practical review. J Neurol. 2012;259:1530-1545.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyan J, Cains S, Larcombe S, et al. Subarachnoid cerebrospinal fluid is essential for normal development of the cerebral cortex. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2020;102:28-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spector R, Robert Snodgrass S, Johanson CE. A balanced view of the cerebrospinal fluid composition and functions: Focus on adult humans. Exp Neurol. 2015;273:57-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johanson CE, Duncan JA 3rd, Klinge PM, Brinker T, Stopa EG, Silverberg GD. Multiplicity of cerebrospinal fluid functions: New challenges in health and disease. Cerebrospinal Fluid Res. 2008;5(1):10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradbury M. Lymphatics and the central nervous system. Trends Neurosci. 1981;4:100-101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iliff JJ, Wang M, Liao Y, et al. A paravascular pathway facilitates CSF flow through the brain parenchyma and the clearance of interstitial solutes, including amyloid β. Sci Transl Med. 2012;4:147ra11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Louveau A, Smirnov I, Keyes TJ, et al. Structural and functional features of central nervous system lymphatic vessels. Nature. 2015;523(7560):337-341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aspelund A, Antila S, Proulx ST, et al. A dural lymphatic vascular system that drains brain interstitial fluid and macromolecules. J Exp Med. 2015;212:991-999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbott NJ, Pizzo ME, Preston JE, Janigro D, Thorne RG. The role of brain barriers in fluid movement in the CNS: Is there a 'glymphatic' system? Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135(3):387-407.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AJ, Yao X, Dix JA, Jin BJ, Verkman AS. Test of the ‘glymphatic’ hypothesis demonstrates diffusive and aquaporin-4-independent solute transport in rodent brain parenchyma. Elife. 2017;6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szentistványi I, Patlak CS, Ellis RA, Cserr HF. Drainage of interstitial fluid from different regions of rat brain. Am J Physiol. 1984;246(6 Pt 2):F835-F844.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eide PK, Ringstad G. Delayed clearance of cerebrospinal fluid tracer from entorhinal cortex in idiopathic normal pressure hydrocephalus: A glymphatic magnetic resonance imaging study. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2018. 271678X18760974</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carare RO, Bernardes-Silva M, Newman TA, et al. Solutes, but not cells, drain from the brain parenchyma along basement membranes of capillaries and arteries: Significance for cerebral amyloid angiopathy and neuroimmunology. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2008;34(2):131-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albargothy NJ, Johnston DA, MacGregor-Sharp M, et al. Convective influx/glymphatic system: Tracers injected into the CSF enter and leave the brain along separate periarterial basement membrane pathways. Acta Neuropathol. 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engelhardt B, Carare RO, Bechmann I, Flügel A, Laman JD, Weller RO. Vascular, glial, and lymphatic immune gateways of the central nervous system. Acta Neuropathol. 2016;132:317-338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Q, Decker Y, Müller A, Ineichen BV, Proulx ST. Clearance of cerebrospinal fluid from the sacral spine through lymphatic vessels. J Exp Med. 2019;216(11):2492-2502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L, Zhang Y, Zhao Y, Marshall C, Wu T, Xiao M. Deep cervical lymph node ligation aggravates AD-like pathology of APP/PS1 mice. Brain Pathol. 2019;29:176-192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laman JD, Weller RO. Drainage of cells and soluble antigen from the CNS to regional lymph nodes. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2013;8(4):840-856.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engelhardt B, Vajkoczy P, Weller RO. The movers and shapers in immune privilege of the CNS. Nat Immunol. 2017;18:123-131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spector R. Nutrient transport systems in brain: 40 years of progress. J Neurochem. 2009;111(2):315-320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hladky SB, Barrand MA. Elimination of substances from the brain parenchyma: Efflux via perivascular pathways and via the blood-brain barrier. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2018;15:30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wardlaw JM, Benveniste H, Nedergaard M, et al. Disease cftFLTNoEotRotPSiCSV. Perivascular spaces in the brain: Anatomy, physiology and pathology. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;16(3):137-153.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhattacharya A, Kaushik DK, Lozinski BM, Yong VW. Beyond barrier functions: Roles of pericytes in homeostasis and regulation of neuroinflammation. J Neurosci Res. 2020;98:2390-2405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Z, Chopp M, Chen J. Multifaceted roles of pericytes in central nervous system homeostasis and disease. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2020;40(7):1381-1401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbott NJ, Patabendige AA, Dolman DE, Yusof SR, Begley DJ. Structure and function of the blood-brain barrier. Neurobiol Dis. 2010;37:13-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horng S, Therattil A, Moyon S, et al. Astrocytic tight junctions control inflammatory CNS lesion pathogenesis. In J Clin Invest. 3136-3151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obermeier B, Daneman R, Ransohoff RM. Development, maintenance and disruption of the blood-brain barrier. Nat Med. 2013;19:1584-1596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cserr HF. Physiology of the choroid plexus. Physiol Rev. 1971;51(2):273-311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pollay M. The function and structure of the cerebrospinal fluid outflow system. Cerebrospinal Fluid Res. 2010;7:9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proulx ST. Cerebrospinal fluid outflow: A review of the historical and contemporary evidence for arachnoid villi, perineural routes, and dural lymphatics. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2021;78:2429-2457.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang ET, Inman CB, Weller RO. Interrelationships of the pia mater and the perivascular (Virchow-Robin) spaces in the human cerebrum. J Anat. 1990;170:111-123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakker ENTP, Naessens DMP, VanBavel E. Paravascular spaces: Entry to or exit from the brain? Exp Physiol. 2019;104:1013-1017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weller RO, Sharp MM, Christodoulides M, Carare RO, Møllgård K. The meninges as barriers and facilitators for the movement of fluid, cells and pathogens related to the rodent and human CNS. Acta Neuropathol. 2018;135:363-385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Achiron A, Faibel M. Sandlike appearance of Virchow-Robin spaces in early multiple sclerosis: A novel neuroradiologic marker. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2002;23:376-380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heier LA, Bauer CJ, Schwartz L, Zimmerman RD, Morgello S, Deck MD. Large Virchow-Robin spaces: MR-clinical correlation. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 1989;10(5):929-936.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman RE, Rutland JW, Fields MC, et al. Quantification of perivascular spaces at 7T: A potential MRI biomarker for epilepsy. Seizure. 2018;54:11-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouvy WH, Biessels GJ, Kuijf HJ, Kappelle LJ, Luijten PR, Zwanenburg JJ. Visualization of perivascular spaces and perforating arteries with 7 T magnetic resonance imaging. Invest Radiol. 2014;49:307-313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francis F, Ballerini L, Wardlaw JM. Perivascular spaces and their associations with risk factors, clinical disorders and neuroimaging features: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Stroke. 2019;14(4):359-371.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wuerfel J, Haertle M, Waiczies H, et al. Perivascular spaces-MRI marker of inflammatory activity in the brain? Brain. 2008;131:2332-2340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen D, Rijnink EC, Nabuurs RJ, et al. Brain histopathology in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: Identification of lesions associated with clinical neuropsychiatric lupus syndromes and the role of complement. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2017;56:77-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarnat HB. Ependymal reactions to injury. A review. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 1995;54:1-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dooling EC, Chi JG, Gilles FH. Ependymal changes in the human fetal brain. Ann Neurol. 1977;1:535-541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felten DL, Harrigan P, Burnett BT, Cummings JP. Fourth ventricular tanycytes: A possible relationship with monoaminergic nuclei. Brain Res Bull. 1981;6:427-436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gould SJ, Howard S, Papadaki L. The development of ependyma in the human fetal brain: An immunohistological and electron microscopic study. Brain Res Dev Brain Res. 1990;55(2):255-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vígh B, Manzano e Silva MJ, Frank CL, Vincze C, Czirok SJ, Szabó A, Lukáts A, Szél A. The system of cerebrospinal fluid-contacting neurons. Its supposed role in the nonsynaptic signal transmission of the brain. Histol Histopathol. 2004;19:607-628.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duvernoy HM, Risold PY. The circumventricular organs: An atlas of comparative anatomy and vascularization. Brain Res Rev. 2007;56(1):119-147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiménez AJ, Domínguez-Pinos MD, Guerra MM, Fernández-Llebrez P, Pérez-Fígares JM. Structure and function of the ependymal barrier and diseases associated with ependyma disruption. In Tissue Barriers. 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Del Bigio MR. The ependyma: A protective barrier between brain and cerebrospinal fluid. Glia. 1995;14(1):1-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore GR, Laule C, Leung E, Pavlova V, Morgan BP, Esiri MM. Complement and humoral adaptive immunity in the human choroid plexus: Roles for stromal concretions, basement membranes, and epithelium. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2016;75(5):415-428.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hladky SB, Barrand MA. Fluid and ion transfer across the blood-brain and blood-cerebrospinal fluid barriers: A comparative account of mechanisms and roles. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2016;13:19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deike-Hofmann K, Reuter J, Haase R, et al. Glymphatic pathway of gadolinium-based contrast agents through the brain: Overlooked and misinterpreted. Invest Radiol. 2019;54:229-237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vladic A, Klarica M, Bulat M. Dynamics of distribution of 3H-inulin between the cerebrospinal fluid compartments. Brain Res. 2009;1248:127-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felgenhauer K. Protein size and cerebrospinal fluid composition. Klin Wochenschr. 1974;52(24):1158-1164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engelhardt B, Ransohoff RM. The ins and outs of T-lymphocyte trafficking to the CNS: Anatomical sites and molecular mechanisms. Trends Immunol. 2005;26:485-495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petito CK, Adkins B. Choroid plexus selectively accumulates T-lymphocytes in normal controls and after peripheral immune activation. J Neuroimmunol. 2005;162:19-27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reboldi A, Coisne C, Baumjohann D, et al. C-C chemokine receptor 6-regulated entry of TH-17 cells into the CNS through the choroid plexus is required for the initiation of EAE. Nat Immunol. 2009;10(5):514-523.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strazielle N, Creidy R, Malcus C, Boucraut J, Ghersi-Egea JF. T-lymphocytes traffic into the brain across the blood-CSF barrier: Evidence using a reconstituted choroid plexus epithelium. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0150945.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mezey É, Szalayova I, Hogden CT, et al. An immunohistochemical study of lymphatic elements in the human brain. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021;118(3):e2002574118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magdoom KN, Brown A, Rey J, Mareci TH, King MA, Sarntinoranont M. MRI of whole rat brain perivascular network reveals role for ventricles in brain waste clearance. Sci Rep. 2019;9:11480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pizzo ME, Wolak DJ, Kumar NN, et al. Intrathecal antibody distribution in the rat brain: Surface diffusion, perivascular transport and osmotic enhancement of delivery. J Physiol. 2018;596:445-475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gardner C, Magliozzi R, Durrenberger PF, Howell OW, Rundle J, Reynolds R. Cortical grey matter demyelination can be induced by elevated pro-inflammatory cytokines in the subarachnoid space of MOG-immunized rats. Brain. 2013;136(12):3596-3608.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magliozzi R, Howell OW, Durrenberger P, et al. Meningeal inflammation changes the balance of TNF signalling in cortical grey matter in multiple sclerosis. J Neuroinflammation. 2019;16(1):259.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson M, Alvarez-Cermeno J, Bernardi G, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid in the diagnosis of multiple sclerosis: A consensus report. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1994;57:897-902.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reiber H. Flow rate of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)-A concept common to normal blood-CSF barrier function and to dysfunction in neurological diseases. J Neurol Sci. 1994;122:189-203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayringer I, Timeltaler B, Deisenhammer F. Correlation between the IgG index, oligoclonal bands in CSF, and the diagnosis of demyelinating diseases. Eur J Neurol. 2005;12(7):527-530.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Runge VM, Schoerner W, Niendorf HP, et al. Initial clinical evaluation of gadolinium DTPA for contrast-enhanced magnetic resonance imaging. Magn Reson Imaging. 1985;3(1):27-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rudie JD, Rauschecker AM, Nabavizadeh SA, Mohan S. Neuroimaging of dilated perivascular spaces: From benign and pathologic causes to mimics. J Neuroimaging. 2018;28:139-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smirniotopoulos JG, Murphy FM, Rushing EJ, Rees JH, Schroeder JW. Patterns of contrast enhancement in the brain and meninges. Radiographics. 2007;27:525-551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asgari N, Flanagan EP, Fujihara K, et al. Disruption of the leptomeningeal blood barrier in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. In Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lisanti CJ, Asbach P, Bradley WG Jr. The ependymal “Dot-Dash” sign: An MR imaging finding of early multiple sclerosis. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2005;26:2033-2036.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishihara H, Soldati S, Mossu A, et al. Human CD4(+) T cell subsets differ in their abilities to cross endothelial and epithelial brain barriers in vitro. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2020;17(1):3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwerk C, Tenenbaum T, Kim KS, Schroten H. The choroid plexus-A multi-role player during infectious diseases of the CNS. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;9:80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingerchuk DM, Banwell B, Bennett JL, et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Neurology. 2015;85:177-189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HJ, Paul F, Lana-Peixoto MA, et al. MRI characteristics of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: An international update. Neurology. 2015;84:1165-1173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock SJ, Weinshenker BG, Lucchinetti CF, Wingerchuk DM, Corboy JR, Lennon VA. Neuromyelitis optica brain lesions localized at sites of high aquaporin 4 expression. Arch Neurol. 2006;63:964-968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo Y, Weigand SD, Popescu BF, et al. Pathogenic implications of cerebrospinal fluid barrier pathology in neuromyelitis optica. Acta Neuropathol. 2017;133(4):597-612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnett Y, Sutton IJ, Ghadiri M, Masters L, Zivadinov R, Barnett MH. Conventional and advanced imaging in neuromyelitis optica. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2014;35:1458-1466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Paul F, Franciotta D, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid findings in aquaporin-4 antibody positive neuromyelitis optica: Results from 211 lumbar punctures. J Neurol Sci. 2011;306(1-2):82-90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dujmovic I, Mader S, Schanda K, et al. Temporal dynamics of cerebrospinal fluid anti-aquaporin-4 antibodies in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. J Neuroimmunol. 2011;234(1-2):124-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SM, Waters P, Vincent A, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid/serum gradient of IgG is associated with disability at acute attacks of neuromyelitis optica. J Neurol. 2011;258(12):2176-2180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marignier R, Ruiz A, Cavagna S, et al. Neuromyelitis optica study model based on chronic infusion of autoantibodies in rat cerebrospinal fluid. J Neuroinflammation. 2016;13(1):111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishiyama S, Ito T, Misu T, et al. A case of NMO seropositive for aquaporin-4 antibody more than 10 years before onset. Neurology. 2009;72:1960-1961.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Franciotta D, Paul F, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid antibodies to aquaporin-4 in neuromyelitis optica and related disorders: Frequency, origin, and diagnostic relevance. J Neuroinflammation. 2010;7:52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klawiter EC, Alvarez E 3rd, Xu J, et al. NMO-IgG detected in CSF in seronegative neuromyelitis optica. Neurology. 2009;72(12):1101-1103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saji E, Arakawa M, Yanagawa K, et al. Cognitive impairment and cortical degeneration in neuromyelitis optica. Ann Neurol. 2013;73:65-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misu T, Takano R, Fujihara K, Takahashi T, Sato S, Itoyama Y. Marked increase in cerebrospinal fluid glial fibrillar acidic protein in neuromyelitis optica: An astrocytic damage marker. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2009;80(5):575-577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takano R, Misu T, Takahashi T, Sato S, Fujihara K, Itoyama Y. Astrocytic damage is far more severe than demyelination in NMO: A clinical CSF biomarker study. Neurology. 2010;75:208-216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juryńczyk M, Jacob A, Fujihara K, Palace J. Myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein (MOG) antibody-associated disease: Practical considerations. 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Ruprecht K, Kleiter I, et al. MOG-IgG in NMO and related disorders: A multicenter study of 50 patients. Part 2: Epidemiology, clinical presentation, radiological and laboratory features, treatment responses, and long-term outcome. J Neuroinflammation. 2016;13:280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Ruprecht K, Kleiter I, et al. MOG-IgG in NMO and related disorders: A multicenter study of 50 patients. Part 1: Frequency, syndrome specificity, influence of disease activity, long-term course, association with AQP4-IgG, and origin. J Neuroinflammation. 2016;13:279.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mariotto S, Gajofatto A, Batzu L, et al. Relevance of antibodies to myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein in CSF of seronegative cases. Neurology. 2019;93(20):e1867-e1872.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang B, McKeon A, Hinson SR, et al. Autoimmune glial fibrillary acidic protein astrocytopathy: A novel meningoencephalomyelitis. JAMA Neurol. 2016;73:1297-1307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan EP, Hinson SR, Lennon VA, et al. Glial fibrillary acidic protein immunoglobulin G as biomarker of autoimmune astrocytopathy: Analysis of 102 patients. Ann Neurol. 2017;81:298-309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long Y, Liang J, Xu H, et al. Autoimmune glial fibrillary acidic protein astrocytopathy in Chinese patients: A retrospective study. Eur J Neurol. 2018;25:477-483.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura A, Takemura M, Yamamoto Y, Hayashi Y, Saito K, Shimohata T. Cytokines and biological markers in autoimmune GFAP astrocytopathy: The potential role for pathogenesis and therapeutic implications. J Neuroimmunol. 2019;334:576999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trip SA, Miller DH. Imaging in multiple sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2005; 76 Suppl 3: iii11-iii8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liebsch R, Kornhuber ME, Dietl D, Grafin von Einsiedel H, Conrad B. Blood-CSF barrier integrity in multiple sclerosis. Acta Neurol Scand. 1996;94(6):404-410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Lorenzo S, Ferreira Francisco DM, Vos R, et al. Altered secretory and neuroprotective function of the choroid plexus in progressive multiple sclerosis. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8(1):35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schubert JJ, Veronese M, Marchitelli L, et al. Dynamic 11C-PiB PET shows cerebrospinal fluid flow alterations in Alzheimer's disease and multiple sclerosis. J Nucl Med. 2019. jnumed. 118.223834</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Konig FB, Metz I, et al. Pattern II and pattern III MS are entities distinct from pattern I MS: Evidence from cerebrospinal fluid analysis. J Neuroinflammation. 2017;14:171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magliozzi R, Howell O, Vora A, et al. Meningeal B-cell follicles in secondary progressive multiple sclerosis associate with early onset of disease and severe cortical pathology. Brain. 2007;130:1089-1104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magliozzi R, Howell OW, Reeves C, et al. A gradient of neuronal loss and meningeal inflammation in multiple sclerosis. Ann Neurol. 2010;68:477-493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howell OW, Reeves CA, Nicholas R, et al. Meningeal inflammation is widespread and linked to cortical pathology in multiple sclerosis. Brain. 2011;134:2755-2771.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howell OW, Schulz-Trieglaff EK, Carassiti D, et al. Extensive grey matter pathology in the cerebellum in multiple sclerosis is linked to inflammation in the subarachnoid space. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2015;41:798-813.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irani SR, Gelfand JM, Al-Diwani A, Vincent A. Cell-surface central nervous system autoantibodies: Clinical relevance and emerging paradigms. Ann Neurol. 2014;76(2):168-184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalmau J. NMDA receptor encephalitis and other antibody-mediated disorders of the synapse: The 2016 Cotzias Lecture. In Neurology. 2016;2471-2482.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gresa-Arribas N, Titulaer MJ, Torrents A, et al. Antibody titres at diagnosis and during follow-up of anti-NMDA receptor encephalitis: A retrospective study. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(2):167-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadoth A, Zekeridou A, Klein CJ, et al. Elevated LGI1-IgG CSF index predicts worse neurological outcome. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5:646-650.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai M, Hughes EG, Peng X, et al. AMPA receptor antibodies in limbic encephalitis alter synaptic receptor location. Ann Neurol. 2009;65(4):424-434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreye J, Wenke NK, Chayka M, et al. Human cerebrospinal fluid monoclonal N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor autoantibodies are sufficient for encephalitis pathogenesis. Brain. 2016;139(10):2641-2652.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abreu MR, Jakosky A, Folgerini M, Brenol JC, Xavier RM, Kapczinsky F. Neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: Correlation of brain MR imaging, CT, and SPECT. Clin Imaging. 2005;29(3):215-221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLean BN, Miller D, Thompson EJ. Oligoclonal banding of IgG in CSF, blood-brain barrier function, and MRI findings in patients with sarcoidosis, systemic lupus erythematosus, and Behcet's disease involving the nervous system. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1995;58(5):548-554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gelb S, Stock AD, Anzi S, Putterman C, Ben-Zvi A. Mechanisms of neuropsychiatric lupus: The relative roles of the blood-cerebrospinal fluid barrier versus blood-brain barrier. J Autoimmun. 2018;91:34-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkins CJ, Kondon JJ, Quismorio FP, Friou GJ. The choroid plexus in systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Intern Med. 1972;76:65-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gershwin ME, Hyman LR, Steinberg AD. The choroid plexus in CNS involvement of systemic lupus erythematosus. J Pediatr. 1975;87(4):588-590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stock AD, Der E, Gelb S, et al. Tertiary lymphoid structures in the choroid plexus in neuropsychiatric lupus. JCI. Insight. 2019;4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeltsch-David H, Muller S. Neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus: Pathogenesis and biomarkers. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10:579-596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herring AB, Urich H. Sarcoidosis of the central nervous system. J Neurol Sci. 1969;9(3):405-422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wengert O, Rothenfusser-Korber E, Vollrath B, et al. Neurosarcoidosis: Correlation of cerebrospinal fluid findings with diffuse leptomeningeal gadolinium enhancement on MRI and clinical disease activity. J Neurol Sci. 2013;335:124-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams DW 3rd, Elster AD, Kramer SI. Neurosarcoidosis: Gadolinium-enhanced MR imaging. J Comput Assist Tomogr. 1990;14(5):704-707.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klock C, Cerski M, Goldani LZ. Histopathological aspects of neurocryptococcosis in HIV-infected patients: Autopsy report of 45 patients. Int J Surg Pathol. 2009;17:444-448.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammoud DA, Mahdi E, Panackal AA, et al. Choroid plexitis and ependymitis by magnetic resonance imaging are biomarkers of neuronal damage and inflammation in HIV-negative cryptococcal meningoencephalitis. In Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):9184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skripuletz T, Schwenkenbecher P, Pars K, et al. Importance of follow-up cerebrospinal fluid analysis in cryptococcal meningoencephalitis. Dis Markers. 2014;2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duarte SBL, Oshima MM, Mesquita J, do Nascimento FBP, de Azevedo PC, Reis F. Magnetic resonance imaging findings in central nervous system cryptococcosis: Comparison between immunocompetent and immunocompromised patients. Radiol Bras. 2017;50:359-365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonig L, Mohn N, Ahlbrecht J, et al. Leptomeningeal metastasis: The role of cerebrospinal fluid diagnostics. Front Neurol. 2019;10:839.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vandenhaute E, Stump-Guthier C, Lasierra Losada M, et al. The choroid plexus may be an underestimated site of tumor invasion to the brain: An in vitro study using neuroblastoma cell lines. Cancer Cell Int. 2015;15:102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iguchi Y, Mano K, Goto Y, et al. Miliary brain metastases from adenocarcinoma of the lung: MR imaging findings with clinical and post-mortem histopathologic correlation. Neuroradiology. 2007;49:35-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlegel U, Schmidt-Wolf IG, Deckert M. Primary CNS lymphoma: Clinical presentation, pathological classification, molecular pathogenesis and treatment. J Neurol Sci. 2000;181(1-2):1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hottenrott T, Schorb E, Fritsch K, et al. The MRZ reaction and a quantitative intrathecal IgG synthesis may be helpful to differentiate between primary central nervous system lymphoma and multiple sclerosis. J Neurol. 2018;265(5):1106-1114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuker W, Nagele T, Korfel A, et al. Primary central nervous system lymphomas (PCNSL): MRI features at presentation in 100 patients. J Neurooncol. 2005;72(2):169-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott BJ, Douglas VC, Tihan T, Rubenstein JL, Josephson SA. A systematic approach to the diagnosis of suspected central nervous system lymphoma. JAMA Neurol. 2013;70(3):311-319.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batchelor T, Loeffler JS. Primary CNS lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2006;24:1281-1288.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koeller KK, Smirniotopoulos JG, Jones RV. Primary central nervous system lymphoma: Radiologic-pathologic correlation. Radiographics. 1997;17(6):1497-1526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetani L, Blennow K, Calabresi P, Di Filippo M, Parnetti L, Zetterberg H. Neurofilament light chain as a biomarker in neurological disorders. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90(8):870-881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leypoldt F, Armangue T, Dalmau J. Autoimmune encephalopathies. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2015;1338:94-114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarbu N, Alobeidi F, Toledano P, et al. Brain abnormalities in newly diagnosed neuropsychiatric lupus: Systematic MRI approach and correlation with clinical and laboratory data in a large multicenter cohort. Autoimmun Rev. 2015;14(2):153-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson JW. The histology of disseminated sclerosis. Edinb Med J. 1916;17:229-241.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asgari N, Berg CT, Mørch MT, Khorooshi R, Owens T. Cerebrospinal fluid aquaporin-4-immunoglobulin G disrupts blood brain barrier. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2015;2:857-863.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirfakhraee M, Crofford MJ, Guinto FC Jr, Nauta HJ, Weedn VW. Virchow-Robin space: A path of spread in neurosarcoidosis. Radiology. 1986;158:715-720.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duvernoy HM, Delon S, Vannson JL. Cortical blood vessels of the human brain. Brain Res Bull. 1981;7(5):519-579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hwang TL, Close TP, Grego JM, Brannon WL, Gonzales F. Predilection of brain metastasis in gray and white matter junction and vascular border zones. Cancer. 1996;77:1551-1555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lassmann H. Pathogenic mechanisms associated with different clinical courses of multiple sclerosis. Front Immunol. 2018;9:3116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumann M, Sahin K, Lechner C, et al. Clinical and neuroradiological differences of paediatric acute disseminating encephalomyelitis with and without antibodies to the myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2015;86(3):265-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schafflick D, Wolbert J, Heming M, et al. Single-cell profiling of CNS border compartment leukocytes reveals that B cells and their progenitors reside in non-diseased meninges. Nat Neurosci. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cugurra A, Mamuladze T, Rustenhoven J, et al. Skull and vertebral bone marrow are myeloid cell reservoirs for the meninges and CNS parenchyma. Science. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broadwell RD, Sofroniew MV. Serum proteins bypass the blood-brain fluid barriers for extracellular entry to the central nervous system. Exp Neurol. 1993;120:245-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tadayon E, Pascual-Leone A, Press D, Santarnecchi E. Choroid plexus volume is associated with levels of CSF proteins: Relevance for Alzheimer's and Parkinson's disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2020;89:108-117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai K, Tain R, Das S, et al. The feasibility of quantitative MRI of perivascular spaces at 7T. J Neurosci Methods. 2015;256:151-156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalmau J, Graus F. Antibody-mediated encephalitis. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(9):840-851.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giovannoni G. Disease-modifying treatments for early and advanced multiple sclerosis: A new treatment paradigm. Curr Opin Neurol. 2018;31:233-243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marz M, Meyer S, Erb U, et al. Pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia-Conquering the CNS across the choroid plexus. Leuk Res. 2018;71:47-54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie H, Luo P, Li Z, Li R, Sun H, Wu D. Continuous intrathecal administration of liposomal amphotericin B for treatment of refractory Cryptococcus neoformans encephalitis: A case report. In Exp Ther Med. 2017;780-784.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saag MS, Graybill RJ, Larsen RA, et al. Practice guidelines for the management of cryptococcal disease. Infectious Diseases Society of America. Clin Infect Dis. 2000;30:710-718.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhargava P, Wicken C, Smith MD, et al. Trial of intrathecal rituximab in progressive multiple sclerosis patients with evidence of leptomeningeal contrast enhancement. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2019;30:136-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bottros MM, Christo PJ. Current perspectives on intrathecal drug delivery. In J Pain Res. 2014;615-626.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
