<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34979112</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6779</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>95</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Gastrointestinal endoscopy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Gastrointest Endosc</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Treatment strategies for reducing early and late recurrence of colonic diverticular bleeding based on stigmata of recent hemorrhage: a large multicenter study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1210</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1222.e12</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1210-1222.e12</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.gie.2021.12.023</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0016-5107(21)01937-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Treatment strategies for colonic diverticular bleeding (CDB) based on stigmata of recent hemorrhage (SRH) remain unstandardized, and no large studies have evaluated their effectiveness. We sought to identify the best strategy among combinations of SRH identification and endoscopic treatment strategies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively analyzed 5823 CDB patients who underwent colonoscopy at 49 hospitals throughout Japan (CODE-BLUE J-Study). Three strategies were compared: find SRH (definitive CDB) and treat endoscopically, find SRH (definitive CDB) and treat conservatively, and without finding SRH (presumptive CDB) treat conservatively. In conducting pairwise comparisons of outcomes in these groups, we used propensity score-matching analysis to balance baseline characteristics between the groups being compared.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both early and late recurrent bleeding rates were significantly lower in patients with definitive CDB treated endoscopically than in those with presumptive CDB treated conservatively (&lt;30 days, 19.6% vs 26.0% [P &lt; .001]; &lt;365 days, 33.7% vs 41.6% [P &lt; .001], respectively). In patients with definitive CDB, the early recurrent bleeding rate was significantly lower in those treated endoscopically than in those treated conservatively (17.4% vs 26.7% [P = .038] for a single test of hypothesis; however, correction for multiple testing of data removed this significance). The late recurrent bleeding rate was also lower, but not significantly, in those treated endoscopically (32.0% vs 36.1%, P = .426). Definitive CDB treated endoscopically showed significantly lower early and late recurrent bleeding rates than when treated conservatively in cases of SRH with active bleeding, nonactive bleeding, and in the right-sided colon but not left-sided colon.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Treating definitive CDB endoscopically was most effective in reducing recurrent bleeding over the short and long term, compared with not treating definitive CDB or presumptive CDB. Physicians should endeavor to find and treat SRH for suspected CDB.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gobinet-Suguro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maya</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nagata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naoyoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan; Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kobayashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katsumasa</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Tokyo Metropolitan Bokutoh Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yamauchi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atsushi</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Kitano Hospital, Tazuke Kofukai Medical Research Institute, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yamada</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atsuo</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Graduate School of Medicine, The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Omori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Nippon Medical School, Graduate School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ikeya</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, St Luke's International University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aoyama</LastName>
            <ForeName>Taiki</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Hiroshima City Asa Citizens Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tominaga</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naoyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Saga Medical Center Koseikan, Saga, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoshinori</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Internal Medicine, St Marianna University School of Medicine, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kishino</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takaaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Center for Digestive and Liver Diseases, Nara City Hospital, Nara, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ishii</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naoki</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Tokyo Shinagawa Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sawada</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tsunaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endoscopy, Nagoya University Hospital, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Murata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, National Hospital Organization Kyoto Medical Center, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Takao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akinari</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Tokyo Metropolitan Cancer and Infectious Diseases Center Komagome Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mizukami</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Oita University, Oita, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kinjo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ken</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Fukuoka University Chikushi Hospital, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fujimori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shunji</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Chiba Hokusoh Hospital, Nippon Medical School, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Uotani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Japanese Red Cross Shizuoka Hospital, Shizuoka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fujita</LastName>
            <ForeName>Minoru</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Endoscopy and Ultrasonography, Department of Clinical Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Kawasaki Medical School General Medical Center, Okayama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Niigata University, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suzuki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sho</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Center for Digestive Disease and Division of Endoscopy, University of Miyazaki Hospital, Miyazaki, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Narasaka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Toshiaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, University of Tsukuba Hospital, Ibaraki, Japan; Division of Endoscopic Center, University of Tsukuba Hospital, Ibaraki, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hayasaka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junnosuke</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Toranomon Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Funabiki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Emergency and Critical Care Center, Saiseikai Yokohamashi Tobu Hospital, Kanagawa, Japan; Department of Emergency Medicine, Fujita Health University Hospital, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kinjo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuzuru</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Naha City Hospital, Okinawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mizuki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akira</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Tokyo Saiseikai Central Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kiyotoki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shu</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Shuto General Hospital, Yamaguchi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mikami</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tatsuya</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Endoscopy, Hirosaki University Hospital, Aomori, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gushima</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ryosuke</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kumamoto University, Kumamoto, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fujii</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, National Hospital Organization Fukuokahigashi Medical Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fuyuno</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuta</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Clinical Science, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gunji</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naohiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Fukushima Medical University, Fukushima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Toya</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yosuke</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Internal Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Iwate, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Narimatsu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, National Defense Medical College, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manabe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Noriaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Endoscopy and Ultrasonography, Department of Clinical Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Kawasaki Medical School, Okayama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nagaike</LastName>
            <ForeName>Koji</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Suita Municipal Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kinjo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tetsu</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Endoscopy, University of the Ryukyus Hospital, Okinawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sumida</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yorinobu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, National Hospital Organization Kyushu Medical Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Funakoshi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sadahiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Fukuoka University Hospital, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kawagishi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kana</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Kitasato University, School of Medicine, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matsuhashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tamotsu</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Neurology, Akita University Graduate School of Medicine, Akita, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Komaki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuga</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Digestive and Lifestyle Diseases, and Hygiene and Health Promotion Medicine, Kagoshima University Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Kagoshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kuniko</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Watanabe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Uemura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naomi</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan; Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, National Center for Global Health and Medicine, Kohnodai Hospital, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Itawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eri</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sugimoto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mitushige</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fukuzawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masakatsu</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kawai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Endoscopy, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaise</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mitsuru</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Nippon Medical School, Graduate School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Itoi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takao</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Gastrointest Endosc</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0010505</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0016-5107</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003106" MajorTopicYN="N">Colon</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003113" MajorTopicYN="N">Colonoscopy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000076385" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diverticular Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004241" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diverticulum, Colon</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006471" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastrointestinal Hemorrhage</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016558" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hemostasis, Endoscopic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012008" MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34979112</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.gie.2021.12.023</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0016-5107(21)01937-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
