<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34979594</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>530</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Regional expression of neuropeptides in the retina of the terrestrial slug Limax valentianus (Gastropoda, Stylommatophora, Limacidae).</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1551</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1568</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1551-1568</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25296</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Gastropods use lens-bearing eyes to detect ambient light. The retina contains photoreceptors that directly project to the brain. Here, we identified the neurotransmitters that the retinal cells use for projection to the brain in the terrestrial slug Limax. We identified 12 genes encoding neuropeptides as well as a novel vesicular glutamate transporter, a marker of glutamatergic neuron, expressed in the retinal cells. Spatial expression profiles of the neuropeptide genes were determined by in situ hybridization. WWamide/MIP1/Pedal peptide2 were coexpressed in the neurons of the accessory retina. In the main retina, prohormone-4 was expressed in the ventrolateral region. Clionin was expressed in the ventromedial region. Pedal peptide was expressed in the anterior region of the main retina and in the accessory retina. Enterin was expressed in many neurons, including the accessory retina, but not in the dorsal region. FxRIamide1 and 2 were coexpressed in the posterior region. Prohormone-4 variant was uniformly expressed in many neurons but scarcely in the accessory retina. MIP2 was widely expressed throughout the dorsoventral axis in the posteriolateral region of the main retina. Myo1 was expressed in many neurons of the main retina but predominantly in the dorsal region. These expression patterns were confirmed by immunohistochemistry with specific antibodies against the neuropeptides. Projections of these peptidergic retinal neurons were confirmed by immunostaining of the optic nerve. Our present study revealed regional differentiation of the retina with respect to the neurotransmitters that the retinal cells use.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matsuo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ryota</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3144-4275</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental Sciences, International College of Arts and Sciences, Fukuoka Women's University, Fukuoka, Fukuoka Prefecture, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matsuo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuko</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental Sciences, International College of Arts and Sciences, Fukuoka Women's University, Fukuoka, Fukuoka Prefecture, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D009479">Neuropeptides</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D049851" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastropoda</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009479" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuropeptides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010786" MajorTopicYN="N">Photoreceptor Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012160" MajorTopicYN="N">Retina</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lehmannia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastropod</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropeptides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurotransmitter</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retina</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34979594</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25296</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn, S. J., Martin, R., Rao, S., &amp; Choi, M. Y. (2017). Neuropeptides predicted from the transcriptome analysis of the gray garden slug Deroceras reticulatum. Peptides, 93, 51-65</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahn, S. J., Mc Donnell, R. J., Cororan, J. A., Martin, R. C., &amp; Choi, M. Y. (2020). Identification and functional characterization of the first molluscan neuromedin U receptor in the slug Deroceras reticulatum. Scientific Reports, 10, 22308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almagro Armenteros, J. J., Tsirigos, K. D., Sønderby, C. K., Petersen, T. N., Winther, O., Brunak, S., von Heijne, G., &amp; Nielsen, H. (2019). SignalP 5.0 improves signal peptide predictions using deep neural networks. Nature Biotechnology, 37(4), 420-423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop, P. O., Kozak, W., Levick, W. R., &amp; Vakkur, G. J. (1963). The determination of the projection of the visual field on to the lateral geniculate nucleus in the cat. Journal of Physiology, 163, 503-539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blackwell, K. T. (2006). Ionic currents underlying difference in light response between type A and type B photoreceptors. Journal of Neurophysiology, 95(5), 3060-3072.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bobkova, M. V., Tartakovskaya, O. S., Borissenko, S. L., Zhukov, V. V., &amp; Meyer-Rochow, V. B. (2004). Restoration of morphological and functional integrity in the regenerating eye of the giant African land snail Achatina fulica. Acta Zoologica, 85(1), 1-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brandenburger, J. L. (1975). Two new kinds of retinal cells in the eye of a snail, Helix aspersa. Journal of Ultrastructure Research, 50(2), 216-230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brockmann, A., Annangudi, S. P., Richmond, T. A., Ament, S. A., Xie, F., Southey, B. R., Rodriguez-Zas, S. R., Robinson, G. E., &amp; Sweedler, J. V. (2009). Quantitative peptidomics reveal brain peptide signatures of behavior. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106(7), 2383-2388.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chase, R., &amp; Tolloczko, B. (1993). Tracing neural pathways in the snail olfaction: From the tip of the tentacles to the brain and beyond. Microscopy Research and Technique, 24(3), 214-230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomczynski, P., &amp; Sacchi, N. (1987). Single-step method of RNA isolation by acid guanidinium thiocyanate-phenol-chloroform extraction. Analytical Biochemistry, 162(1), 156-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colwell, C. S. (1990). Light and serotonin interact in affecting the circadian system of Aplysia. Journal of Comparative Physiology, 167(6), 841-845.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cropper, E. C., Lloyd, P. E., Reed, W., Tenenbaum, R., Kupfermann, I., &amp; Weiss, K. R. (1987). Multiple neuropeptides in cholinergic motor neurons of Aplysia: Evidence for modulation intrinsic to the motor circuit. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 84(10), 3486-3490.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cropper, E. C., Tenenbaum, R., Kolks, M. A., Kupfermann, I., &amp; Weiss, K. R. (1987). Myomodulin: A bioactive neuropeptide present in an identified cholinergic buccal motor neuron of Aplysia. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 84(15), 5483-5486.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crow, T., &amp; Forrester, J. (1991). Light paired with serotonin in vivo produces both short-and long-term enhancement of generator potentials of identified B-photoreceptors in Hermissenda. Journal of Neuroscience, 11(3), 608-617.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crow, T., Heldman, E., Hacopian, V., Enos, R., &amp; Alkon, D. L. (1979). Ultrastructure of photoreceptors in the eye of Hermissenda labelled with intracellular injections of horseradish peroxidase. Journal of Neurocytology, 8(2), 181-195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DiCarlo, J. J., Zoccolan, D., &amp; Rust, N. C. (2012). How does the brain solve visual object recognition? Neuron, 73(3), 415-434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eskin, A., &amp; Maresh, R. D. (1982). Serotonin or electrical optic nerve stimulation increases the photosensitivity of the Aplysia eye. Comparative Biochemistry and Physiology C, 73(1), 27-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felleman, D. J., &amp; Van Essen, D. C. (1991). Distributed hierarchical processing in the primate cerebral cortex. Cerebral Cortex, 1(1), 1-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukunaga, S., Matsuo, R., Hoshino, S., &amp; Kirino, Y. (2006). Novel krüppel-like factor is induced by neuronal activity and sensory input in the central nervous system of the terrestrial slug Limax valentianus. Journal of Neurobiology, 66(2), 169-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenberg, M. J., Payza, K., Nachman, R. J., Holman, G. M., &amp; Price, D. A. (1988). Relationship between the FMRFamide-related peptides and other peptide families. Peptides, 9(1), 125-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henchman, A. P. (1897). The eyes of Limax maximus. Science, 115, 428-429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herman, K. G., &amp; Strumwasser, F. (1984). Regional specializations in the eye of Aplysia, a neuronal circadian oscillator. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 230, 593-613.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirata, T., Kubota, I., Iwasawa, N., Takabatake, I., Ikeda, T., &amp; Muneoka, Y. (1988). Structures and actions of Mytilus inhibitory peptides. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 152(3), 1376-1382.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacklet, J. W. (1969). Circadian rhythm of optic nerve impulses recorded in darkness from isolated eye of Aplysia. Science, 164(3879), 562-563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacklet, J. W. (1991). Photoresponsiveness of Aplysia eye is modulated by the ocular circadian pacemaker and serotonin. Biological Bulletin, 180(2), 284-294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacklet, J. W., Alvarez, R., &amp; Bernstein, R. (1972). Ultrastructure of the eye of Aplysia. Journal of Ultrastructure Research, 38(3), 246-261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacklet, J. W., &amp; Colquhoun, W. (1983). Ultrastructure of photoreceptors and circadian pacemaker neurons in the eye of a gastropod, Bulla. Journal of Neurocytology, 12(4), 673-696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katagiri, N., Katagiri, Y., Shimatani, Y., &amp; Hashimoto, Y. (1995). Cell type and fine structure of the retina of Onchidium stalk-eye. Journal of Electron Microscopy, 44(4), 219-230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katagiri, N., Terakita, A., Shichida, Y., &amp; Katagiri, Y. (2001). Demonstration of a rhodopsin-retinochrome system in the stalk eye of a marine gastropod, Onchidium, by immunohistochemistry. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 433(3), 380-389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kataoka, S. (1975). Fine structure of the retina of a slug, Limax flavus L. Vsion Research, 15, 681-686.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kataoka, S. (1977). Ultrastructure of the cornea and accessory retina in a slug, Limax flavus L. Journal of Ultrastructure Research, 60(3), 296-305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koizumi, O., Hamada, S., Minobe, S., Hamaguchi-Hamada, K., Kurumata-Shigeto, M., Nakamura, M., &amp; Namikawa, H. (2015). The nerve ring in cnidarians: Its presence and structure in hydrozoan medusae. Zoology, 118(2), 79-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Asada, A., Fujitani, K., &amp; Inokuchi, K. (2001). LIRF, a gene induced during long-term potentiation as an immediate-early gene, encodes a novel RING-finger protein. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 289(2), 479-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Fukata, R., Kumagai, M., Kobayashi, S., &amp; Matsuo, Y. (2016a). Distribution of histaminergic neurons and their modulatory effects on oscillatory activity in the olfactory center of the terrestrial slug Limax. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524(18), 3849-3864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Kobayashi, S., Furuta, A., Osugi, T., Takahashi, T., Satake, H., &amp; Matsuo, Y. (2020). Distribution and physiological effects of enterin neuropeptides in the olfactory centers of the terrestrial slug Limax. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 206(3), 401-418.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Kobayashi, S., Watanabe, S., Namiki, S., Iinuma, S., Sakamoto, H., Hirose, K., &amp; Ito, E. (2009). Glutamatergic neurotransmission in the procerebrum (olfactory center) of a terrestrial mollusk. Journal of Neuroscience Research, 87(13), 3011-3023.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Koyanagi, M., Nagata, A., &amp; Matsuo, Y. (2019). Co-expression of opsins in the eye photoreceptor cells of the terrestrial slug Limax valentianus. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 527(18), 3073-3086.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, Y., Nishiyama, H., &amp; Matsuo, R. (2020). Integration of ocular and non-ocular photosensory information in the brain of the terrestrial slug Limax. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 206(6), 907-919.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Tanaka, M., Fukata, R., Kobayashi, S., Aonuma, H., &amp; Matsuo, Y. (2016b). Octopaminergic system in the central nervous system of the terrestrial slug Limax. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 524(1), 119-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, R., Takatori, Y., Hamada, S., Koyanagi, M., &amp; Matsuo, Y. (2017). Expression and light-dependent translocation of β-arrestin in the visual system of the terrestrial slug Limax valentianus. Journal of Experimental Biology, 220(18), 3301-3314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, Y., Uozumi, N., &amp; Matsuo, R. (2014). Photo-tropotaxis based on projection through the cerebral commissure in the terrestrial slug Limax. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 200(12), 1023-1032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuo, Y., Yamanaka, A., &amp; Matsuo, R. (2018). RFamidergic neurons in the olfactory centers of the terrestrial slug Limax. Zoological Letters, 4, 22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michel, S., Schoch, K., &amp; Stevenson, P. A. (2000). Amine and amino acid transmitters in the eye of the mollusc Bulla gouldiana: An immunocytochemical study. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 425(2), 244-256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minakata, H., Ikeda, T., Muneoka, Y., Kobayashi, M., &amp; Nomoto, N. (1993). WWamide-1, 2 and -3: Novel neuromodulatory peptides isolated from ganglia of African giant snail, Achatina fulica. FEBS Letters, 323(1-2), 104-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moroz, L. L., Edwards, J. R., Puthanveettil, S. V., Kohn, A. B., Ha, T., Heyland, A., Knudsen, B., Sahni, A., Yu, F., Liu, L., Jezzini, S., Lovell, P., Iannucculli, W., Chen, M., Nguyen, Y., Sheng, H., Shaw, R., Kalachikov, S., Panchin, Y. V., … Kandel, E. R. (2006). Neuronal transcriptome of Aplysia: Neuronal compartments and circuitry. Cell, 127(7), 1453-1467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozaki, K., Terakita, A., Hara, R., &amp; Hara, T. (1986). Rhodopsin and retinochrome in the retina of a marine gastropod, Conomulex luhuanus. Vision Research, 26(5), 691-705.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson, S. D., Li, Q., Bandyopadhyay, P. K., Gajewiak, J., Yandell, M., Papenfuss, A. T., Purcell, A. W., Norton, R. S., &amp; Safavi-Hemami, H. (2017). Hormone-like peptides in the venoms of marine cone snails. General and Comparative Endocrinology, 244, 11-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakano, H. (2010). Neural map formation in the mouse olfactory system. Neuron, 67(4), 530-542.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi, J. S., Nelson, D. E., &amp; Eskin, A. (1989). Immunocytochemical localization of serotonergic fibers innervating ocular circadian system of Aplysia. Neuroscience, 28(1), 139-147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamamaki, N., &amp; Kawai, K. (1983). Ultrastructure of the accessory eye of the giant snail, Achatina fulica (Gastropoda, Pulmonata). Zoomorphology, 102, 205-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson, J. D., Higgins, D. G., &amp; Gibson, T. J. (1994). CLUSTAL W: Improving the sensitivity of progressive multiple sequence alignment through sequence weighting, position-specific gap penalties and weight matrix choice. Nucleic Acids Research, 22(22), 4673-4680.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuchina, O. P., Zhukov, V. V., &amp; Meyer-Rochow, V. B. (2011). Afferent and efferent pathways in the visual system of the freshwater snail Planorbarius corneus. Zoological Research, 32(4), 403-420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuchina, O. P., Zhukov, V. V., &amp; Meyer-Rochow, V. B. (2012). Distribution of serotonin and FMRF-amide in the brain of Lymnaea stagnalis with respect to the visual system. Zoological Research, 33(E1-2), E1-E12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wässle, H., &amp; Boycott, B. B. (1991). Functional architecture of the mammalian retina. Physiological Reviews, 72(2), 447-480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webber, M. P., Thomson, J. W. S., Buckland-Nicks, J., Croll, R. P., &amp; Wyeth, R. C. (2017). GABA-, histamine-, and FMRFamide-immunoreactivity in the visual, vestibular and central nervous system of Hermissenda crassicornis. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525(16), 3514-3528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamanaka, A., Kobayashi, S., Matsuo, Y., &amp; Matsuo, R. (2021). FxRIamide regulates the oscillatory activity in the olfactory center of the terrestrial slug Limax. Peptides, 141, 170541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhukov, V. V. (2007). On the problem of retinal transmitters of the freshwater mollusc Lymnaea stagnalis. Journal of Evolutionary Biochemistry and Physiology, 43(5), 524-532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zieger, M. V., &amp; Meyer-Rochow, V. B. (2008). Understanding the cephalic eyes of pulmonate gastropods: A review. American Malacological Bulletin, 26, 47-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zieger, M. V., Vakoliuk, I. A., Tuchina, O. P., Zhukov, V. V., &amp; Meyer-Rochow, V. B. (2009). Eyes and vision in Arion rufus and Deroceras agreste (Mollusca; Gastropoda; Pulmonata): What role does photoreception play in the orientation of these terrestrial slugs? Acta Zoologica, 90, 189-204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
