<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34985823</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>530</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neural organization of the third optic neuropil, the lobula, in the highly visual semiterrestrial crab Neohelice granulata.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1533</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1550</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1533-1550</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25295</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The visual neuropils (lamina, medulla, and lobula complex) of malacostracan crustaceans and hexapods have many organizational principles, cell types, and functional properties in common. Information about the cellular elements that compose the crustacean lobula is scarce especially when focusing on small columnar cells. Semiterrestrial crabs possess a highly developed visual system and display conspicuous visually guided behaviors. In particular, Neohelice granulata has been previously used to describe the cellular components of the first two optic neuropils using Golgi impregnation technique. Here, we present a comprehensive description of individual elements composing the third optic neuropil, the lobula, of that same species. We characterized a wide variety of elements (140 types) including input terminals and lobula columnar, centrifugal, and input columnar elements. Results reveal a very dense and complex neuropil. We found a frequently impregnated input element (suggesting a supernumerary cartridge representation) that arborizes in the third layer of the lobula and that presents four variants each with ramifications organized following one of the four cardinal axes suggesting a role in directional processing. We also describe input elements with two neurites branching in the third layer, probably connecting with the medulla and lobula plate. These facts suggest that this layer is involved in the directional motion detection pathway in crabs. We analyze and discuss our findings considering the similarities and differences found between the layered organization and components of this crustacean lobula and the lobula of insects.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lepore</LastName>
            <ForeName>María Grazia</ForeName>
            <Initials>MG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7929-4499</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto de Fisiología, Biología Molecular y Neurociencias (IFIBYNE), UBA-CONICET, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tomsic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2273-5927</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto de Fisiología, Biología Molecular y Neurociencias (IFIBYNE), UBA-CONICET, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departamento de Fisiología, Biología Molecular y Celular "Dr Héctor Maldonado", Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sztarker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julieta</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0683-667X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto de Fisiología, Biología Molecular y Neurociencias (IFIBYNE), UBA-CONICET, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departamento de Fisiología, Biología Molecular y Celular "Dr Héctor Maldonado", Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales, Universidad de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003386" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brachyura</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008526" MajorTopicYN="N">Medulla Oblongata</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019581" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropil</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009899" MajorTopicYN="N">Optic Lobe, Nonmammalian</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014795" MajorTopicYN="N">Visual Pathways</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Golgi impregnation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arthropod</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">crustacean</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lobula columnar neurons</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34985823</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25295</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnett, P. D., Nordström, K., &amp; O'Carroll, D. C. (2007). Retinotopic organization of small-field-target-detecting neurons in the insect visual system. Current Biology, 17(7), 569-578. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2007.02.039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bengochea, M., &amp; Berón de Astrada, M. (2014). Organization of columnar inputs in the third optic ganglion of a highly visual crab. Journal of Physiology, Paris, 108(2-3), 61-70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphysparis.2014.05.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bengochea, M., Berón de Astrada, M., Tomsic, D., &amp; Sztarker, J. (2018). A crustacean lobula plate: Morphology, connections, and retinotopic organization. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 526(1), 109-119. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24322</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berón de Astrada, M., Bengochea, M., Sztarker, J., Delorenzi, A., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2013). Behaviorally related neural plasticity in the arthropod optic lobes. Current Biology: CB, 23(15), 1389-1398. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2013.05.061</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berón de Astrada, M., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2002). Physiology and morphology of visual movement detector neurons in a crab (Decapoda: Brachyura). Journal of Comparative Physiology. A, Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 188(7), 539-551. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-002-0328-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berón de Astrada, M., Tuthill, J. C., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2009). Physiology and morphology of sustaining and dimming neurons of the crab Chasmagnathus granulatus (Brachyura: Grapsidae). Journal of Comparative Physiology. A, Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 195(8), 791-798. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-009-0448-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cannicci, S., Barelli, C., &amp; Vannini, M. (2000). Homing in the swimming crab Thalamita crenata: A mechanism based on underwater landmark memory. Animal Behaviour, 60(2), 203-210. https://doi.org/10.1006/anbe.2000.1458</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Astrada, M. B., Medan, V., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2011). How visual space maps in the optic neuropils of a crab. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 519(9), 1631-1639. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22612</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabian, J. M., &amp; Wiederman, S. D. (2021). Spike bursting in a dragonfly target-detecting neuron. Scientific Reports, 11, 4005. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-83559-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fischbach, P. K.-F., &amp; Dittrich, A. P. M. (1989). The optic lobe of Drosophila melanogaster. I. A Golgi analysis of wild-type structure. Cell and Tissue Research, 258(3), 441-475. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00218858</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S., &amp; Hansson, B. S. (2008). Brain architecture in the terrestrial hermit crab Coenobita clypeatus (Anomura, Coenobitidae), a crustacean with a good aerial sense of smell. BMC Neuroscience, 9, 58. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2202-9-58</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemmi, J. M., &amp; Zeil, J. (2003). Burrow surveillance in fiddler crabs I. Description of behaviour. Journal of Experimental Biology, 206(22), 3935-3950. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.00632</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keleş, M. F., &amp; Frye, M. A. (2017). Object-detecting neurons in drosophila. Current Biology: CB, 27(5), 680-687. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2017.01.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kenning, M., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2013). Brain anatomy of the marine isopod Saduria entomon Linnaeus, 1758 (Valvifera, Isopoda) with special emphasis on the olfactory pathway. Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 7, 32. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2013.00032</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kern, R., Nalbach, H. O., &amp; Varjú, D. (1993). Interactions of local movement detectors enhance the detection of rotation. Optokinetic experiments with the rock crab, Pachygrapsus marmoratus. Visual Neuroscience, 10(4), 643-652.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger, J., Hörnig, M. K., Sandeman, R. E., Sandeman, D. C., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2020). Masters of communication: The brain of the banded cleaner shrimp Stenopus hispidus (Olivier, 1811) with an emphasis on sensory processing areas. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 528(9), 1561-1587. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24831</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lancer, B. H., Evans, B. J. E., Fabian, J. M., O'Carroll, D. C., &amp; Wiederman, S. D. (2019). A target-detecting visual neuron in the dragonfly locks on to selectively attended targets. The Journal of Neuroscience, 39(43), 8497-8509. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1431-19.2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Land, M., &amp; Layne, J. (1995). The visual control of behaviour in fiddler crabs. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 177(1), 91-103. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00243401</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, C., Hoving, H., Cronin, T., &amp; Osborn, K. (2021). Strange eyes, stranger brains: Exceptional diversity of optic lobe organization in midwater crustaceans. Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 288, 20210216. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2021.0216</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medan, V., Berón De Astrada, M., Scarano, F., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2015). A network of visual motion-sensitive neurons for computing object position in an arthropod. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 35(17), 6654-6666. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4667-14.2015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medan, V., Oliva, D., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2007). Characterization of lobula giant neurons responsive to visual stimuli that elicit escape behaviors in the crab Chasmagnathus. Journal of Neurophysiology, 98(4), 2414-2428. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00803.2007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meth, R., Wittfoth, C., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2017). Brain architecture of the Pacific White Shrimp Penaeus vannamei Boone, 1931 (Malacostraca, Dendrobranchiata): Correspondence of brain structure and sensory input? Cell and Tissue Research, 369(2), 255-271. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00441-017-2607-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nordström, K., Barnett, P. D., &amp; O'Carroll, D. C. (2006). Insect Detection of Small Targets Moving in Visual Clutter. PLOS Biology, 4(3), e54. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.0040054</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nordström, K., &amp; O'Carroll, D. C. (2006). Small object detection neurons in female hoverflies. Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 273(1591), 1211-1216. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2005.3424</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okamura, J.-Y., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2007). Visual system of calliphorid flies: Motion- and orientation-sensitive visual interneurons supplying dorsal optic glomeruli. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 500(1), 189-208. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21195</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliva, D., Medan, V., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2007). Escape behavior and neuronal responses to looming stimuli in the crab Chasmagnathus granulatus (Decapoda: Grapsidae). The Journal of Experimental Biology, 210(Pt (5),), 865-880. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.02707</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliva, D., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2014). Computation of object approach by a system of visual motion-sensitive neurons in the crab Neohelice. Journal of Neurophysiology, 112(6), 1477-1490. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.00921.2013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliva, D., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2016). Object approach computation by a giant neuron and its relationship with the speed of escape in the crab Neohelice. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 219(Pt (21), 3339-3352. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.136820</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osorio, D., &amp; Bacon, J. P. (1994). A good eye for arthropod evolution. BioEssays: News and Reviews in Molecular, Cellular and Developmental Biology, 16(6), 419-424. https://doi.org/10.1002/bies.950160610</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otsuna, H., &amp; Ito, K. (2006). Systematic analysis of the visual projection neurons of Drosophila melanogaster. I. Lobula-specific pathways. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 497(6), 928-958. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paulk, A. C., Phillips-Portillo, J., Dacks, A. M., Fellous, J.-M., &amp; Gronenberg, W. (2008). The processing of color, motion, and stimulus timing are anatomically segregated in the bumblebee brain. Journal of Neuroscience, 28(25), 6319-6332. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1196-08.2008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramón y Cajal, S., &amp; Sanchez, D., Universidad Complutense de Madrid, &amp; Laboratorio de Investigaciones Biológicas. (1915). Contribución al conocimiento de los centros nerviosos de los insectos. Imprenta de Hijos de Nicolás Moya. http://www.biodiversitylibrary.org/bibliography/37839</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rind, F. C. (1996). Intracellular characterization of neurons in the locust brain signaling impending collision. Journal of neurophysiology, 75(3), 986-995. https://doi.org/10.1152/jn.1996.75.3.986</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scarano, F., Sztarker, J., Medan, V., Berón de Astrada, M., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2018). Binocular neuronal processing of object motion in an arthropod. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 38, 6933-6948. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3641-17.2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scarano, F., Tomsic, D., &amp; Sztarker, J. (2020). Direction selective neurons responsive to horizontal motion in a crab reflect an adaptation to prevailing movements in flat environments. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 40(29), 5561-5571. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0372-20.2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinakevitch, I., Douglass, J. K., Scholtz, G., Loesel, R., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2003). Conserved and convergent organization in the optic lobes of insects and isopods, with reference to other crustacean taxa. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 467(2), 150-172. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.10925</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Städele, C., Keleş, M. F., Mongeau, J.-M., &amp; Frye, M. A. (2020). Non-canonical receptive field properties and neuromodulation of feature-detecting neurons in flies. Current Biology, 30(13), 2508-2519.e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2020.04.069</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (1998). Crustacean-insect relationships: The use of brain characters to derive phylogeny amongst segmented invertebrates. Brain, Behavior and Evolution, 52(4-5), 186-206. https://doi.org/10.1159/000006563</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (2005). The evolution of crustacean and insect optic lobes and the origins of chiasmata. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 34(3), 235-256. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2005.04.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (2021). The lobula plate is exclusive to insects. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 61, 101031. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2021.101031</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Meinertzhagen, I. A. (1998). The insect neuron: Morphologies, structures and relationships to neuroarchitecture. In F. W. Harrison &amp; M. Locke (Eds.), Microscopic anatomy of invertebrates (Vol. 11b, pp. 487-538). Wiley-Liss.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Nassel, D. R. (1980). Neuroarchitecture of brain regions that subserve the compound eyes of crustacea and insect. In H Autrum (Ed.), Handbook of sensory physiology (vol. VII/6B, pp. 1-132). Springer-Verlag.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Olea-Rowe, B. (2021). Convergent evolution of optic lobe neuropil in Pancrustacea. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 61, 101040. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2021.101040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sztarker, J., Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2005). Organization of optic lobes that support motion detection in a semiterrestrial crab. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 493(3), 396-411. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.20755</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sztarker, J., Strausfeld, N., Andrew, D., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2009). Neural organization of first optic neuropils in the littoral crab Hemigrapsus oregonensis and the semiterrestrial species Chasmagnathus granulatus. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 513(2), 129-150. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21942</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sztarker, J., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2004). Binocular visual integration in the crustacean nervous system. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 190(11), 951-962. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-004-0551-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sztarker, J., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2008). Neuronal correlates of the visually elicited escape response of the crab Chasmagnathus upon seasonal variations, stimuli changes and perceptual alterations. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 194(6), 587-596. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-008-0333-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sztarker, J., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2011). Brain modularity in arthropods: Individual neurons that support “what” but not “where” memories. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 31(22), 8175-8180. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6029-10.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sztarker, J., &amp; Tomsic, D. (2014). Neural organization of the second optic neuropil, the medulla, in the highly visual semiterrestrial crab Neohelice granulata. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 522(14), 3177-3193. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23589</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thoen, H. H., Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Marshall, J. (2017). Neural organization of afferent pathways from the stomatopod compound eye. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525(14), 3010-3030. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomsic, D. (2016). Visual motion processing subserving behavior in crabs. Current Opinion in Neurobiology, 41, 113-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.conb.2016.09.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomsic, D., Berón de Astrada, M., &amp; Sztarker, J. (2003). Identification of individual neurons reflecting short- and long-term visual memory in an arthropodo. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 23(24), 8539-8546. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.23-24-08539.2003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomsic, D., &amp; Sztarker, J. (2019). Crustacean visual circuits underlying behavior. Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Neuroscience. https://doi.org/10.1093/acrefore/9780190264086.013.210</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomsic, D., Sztarker, J., Berón de Astrada, M., Oliva, D., &amp; Lanza, E. (2017). The predator and prey behaviors of crabs: From ecology to neural adaptations. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 220(Pt (13),), 2318-2327. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.143222</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, M., Nern, A., Williamson, W. R., Morimoto, M. M., Reiser, M. B., Card, G. M., &amp; Rubin, G. M. (2016). Visual projection neurons in the Drosophila lobula link feature detection to distinct behavioral programs. eLife, 5, e21022. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.21022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamawaki, Y. (2018). Unraveling the functional organization of lobula complex in the mantis brain by identification of visual interneurons. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 527(7), 1161-1178. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24603</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeil, J., &amp; Hemmi, J. M. (2006). The visual ecology of fiddler crabs. Journal of Comparative Physiology. A, Neuroethology, Sensory, Neural, and Behavioral Physiology, 192(1), 1-25. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-005-0048-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeil, J., &amp; Hofmann, M. (2001). Signals from «crabworld»: Cuticular reflections in a fiddler crab colony. The Journal of Experimental Biology, 204 Pt (14), 2561-2569. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.204.14.2561</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
