<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">34984072</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1882-7616</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>58</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Japanese dental science review</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Jpn Dent Sci Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw: Prosthodontic considerations.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>9</StartPage>
          <EndPage>12</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>9-12</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jdsr.2021.11.005</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw (MRONJ) can be triggered by several antiresorptive and antiangiogenic medications, including bisphosphonates (BRONJ), denosumab (DRONJ), and other agents used to treat osteoporosis and metastatic bone cancer. Prosthodontists and surgeons continue to face new challenges because of this condition. Despite the current evidence showing that extensive surgical intervention and laser surgery have the highest healing rates, surgical reconstruction is not always possible for large jaw defects requiring prosthetic reconstruction. Moreover, surgical treatment may not be an option in some patients because of other medical conditions. In these patients, MRONJ may develop into a chronic disease with limited resolution and they may seek prosthetic rehabilitation for aesthetic and functional reasons. Therefore, prosthetic intervention may be necessary for some patients with MRONJ even in the absence of a surgical defect. Denture trauma has been reported to be a risk factor for MRONJ, and few reports have discussed the prosthodontic considerations needed for patients with this condition. The aim of this review is to highlight the prosthodontic considerations that would decrease the risk of triggering MRONJ in susceptible patients.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ali</LastName>
            <ForeName>Islam E</ForeName>
            <Initials>IE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Maxillofacial Prosthetics, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthodontics, Faculty of Dentistry, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sumita</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuka</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Maxillofacial Prosthetics, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Jpn Dent Sci Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101481371</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1882-7616</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiresorptive agents</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bisphosphonates</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Denosumab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prosthodontic considerations</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>55</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34984072</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8693001</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdsr.2021.11.005</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1882-7616(21)00043-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruggiero S.L., Dodson T.B., Fantasia J., Goodday R., Aghaloo T., Mehrotra B., et al.  American Association of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgeons position paper on medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw—2014 update. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2014;72:1938–1956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25234529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Migliorati C.A., Casiglia J., Epstein J., Jacobsen P.L., Siegel M.A., Woo S.-B. Managing the care of patients with bisphosphonate-associated osteonecrosis: an American Academy of Oral Medicine position paper. J Am Dent Assoc. 2005;136:1658–1668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16383047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruggiero S.L., Drew S.J. Osteonecrosis of the jaws and bisphosphonate therapy. J Dent Res. 2007;86:1013–1021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17959890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marx R.E. Reconstruction of defects caused by bisphosphonate-induced osteonecrosis of the jaws. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2009;67:107–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19371821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marx R.E., Sawatari Y., Fortin M., Broumand V. Bisphosphonate-induced exposed bone (osteonecrosis/osteopetrosis) of the jaws: risk factors, recognition, prevention, and treatment. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2005;63:1567–1575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16243172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freiberger J.J., Padilla-Burgos R., Chhoeu A.H., Kraft K.H., Boneta O., Moon R.E., et al.  Hyperbaric oxygen treatment and bisphosphonate-induced osteonecrosis of the jaw: a case series. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2007;65:1321–1327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17577496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alons K., Kuijpers S.C.C., de Jong E., van Merkesteyn J.P.R. Treating low-and medium-potency bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaws with a protocol for the treatment of chronic suppurative osteomyelitis: report of 7 cases. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endodontol. 2009;107:e1–e7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19071040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rupel K., Ottaviani G., Gobbo M., Contardo L., Tirelli G., Vescovi P., et al.  A systematic review of therapeutical approaches in bisphosphonates-related osteonecrosis of the jaw (BRONJ) Oral Oncol. 2014;50:1049–1057.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25240948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mast G., Otto S., Mücke T., Schreyer C., Bissinger O., Kolk A., et al.  Incidence of maxillary sinusitis and oro-antral fistulae in bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaw. J Craniomaxillofac Surg. 2012;40:568–571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22118926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Troeltzsch M., Probst F., Troeltzsch M., Ehrenfeld M., Otto S. Conservative management of medication-related osteonecrosis of the maxilla with an obturator prosthesis. J Prosthet Dent. 2015;113:236–241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25444286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leven A.J., Preston A.J. Conservative prosthetic rehabilitation of medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw (MRONJ) Dent Update. 2016;43:939–942.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29155533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasegawa Y., Kawabe M., Kimura H., Kurita K., Fukuta J., Urade M. Influence of dentures in the initial occurrence site on the prognosis of bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaws: a retrospective study. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol. 2012;114:318–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22862971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Almeida F.C.S., Moreira M.S., Marcucci M., Marques M.M., de Araujo M.E., da Silva D.P. New uses for rehabilitation protocol for oral sinus communications in ARONJ patients. J Prosthodont. 2014;23:649–653.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24954080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Göllner M., Holst S., Fenner M., Schmitt J. Prosthodontic treatment of a patient with bisphosphonate-induced osteonecrosis of the jaw using a removable dental prosthesis with a heat-polymerized resilient liner: a clinical report. J Prosthet Dent. 2010;103:196–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20362762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marunick M., Gordon S. Prosthodontic treatment during active osteonecrosis related to radiation and bisphosphonate therapy: a clinical report. J Prosthet Dent. 2006;96:7–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16872925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dennis T., Gahan M. The prosthodontic management of medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw: a case report. Br Dent J. 2021;230:23–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33420451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otto S.  First ed. Springer-Verlag; Berlin: 2015. Medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaws.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J., Lee D.-H., Dziak R., Ciancio S. Bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaw: current clinical significance and treatment strategy review. Am J Dent. 2020;33:115–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32470236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Fede O., Panzarella V., Mauceri R., Fusco V., Bedogni A., Lo Muzio L., et al.  The dental management of patients at risk of medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw: new paradigm of primary prevention. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6164200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30306086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripathi A., Pandey S., Singh S.V., Kumar Sharma N., Singh R. Bisphosphonate therapy for skeletal malignancies and metastases: impact on jaw bones and prosthodontic concerns. J Prosthodont Implant Esthet Reconstr Dent. 2011;20:601–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21883630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawahara M., Kuroshima S., Sawase T. Clinical considerations for medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw: a comprehensive literature review. Int J Implant Dent. 2021;7:1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8119587</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33987769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saldanha S., Shenoy V.K., Eachampati P., Uppal N. Dental implications of bisphophonate-related osteonecrosis. Gerodontology. 2012;29:177–187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22486711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacob R.F., Yen T.-W. Processed record bases for the edentulous maxillofacial patient. J Prosthet Dent. 1991;65:680–685.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2051393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keyf F. Obturator prostheses for hemimaxillectomy patients. J Oral Rehabil. 2001;28:821–829.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11580820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saito M., Miura Y., Notani K., Kawasaki T. Stress distribution of abutments and base displacement with precision attachment-and telescopic crown-retained removable partial dentures. J Oral Rehabil. 2003;30:482–487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12752927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okay D.J., Genden E., Buchbinder D., Urken M. Prosthodontic guidelines for surgical reconstruction of the maxilla: a classification system of defects. J Prosthet Dent. 2001;86:352–363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11677528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedogni A., Bettini G., Totola A., Saia G., Nocini P.F. Oral bisphosphonate-associated osteonecrosis of the jaw after implant surgery: a case report and literature review. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2010;68:1662–1666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20561470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murata H., Haberham R.C., Hamada T., Taguchi N. Setting and stress relaxation behavior of resilient denture liners. J Prosthet Dent. 1998;80:714–722.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9830078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawano F., Tada N., Nagao K., Matsumoto N. The influence of soft lining materials on pressure distribution. J Prosthet Dent. 1991;65:567–575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2066898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taguchi N., Murata H., Hamada T., Hong G. Effect of viscoelastic properties of resilient denture liners on pressures under dentures. J Oral Rehabil. 2001;28:1003–1008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11722715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner W.C., Kawano F., Dootz E.R., Koran A., III Dynamic viscoelastic properties of processed soft denture liners: part I—initial properties. J Prosthet Dent. 1995;73:471–477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7658398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okita N., Ørstavik D., Ørstavik J., Østby K. In vivo and in vitro studies on soft denture materials: microbial adhesion and tests for antibacterial activity. Dent Mater. 1991;7:155–160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1813337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz H., Aydin C., Bal B.T., Õzçelik B. Effects of disinfectants on resilient denture-lining materials contaminated with Staphylococcus aureus, Streptococcus sobrinus, and Candida albicans. Quintessence Int (Berl) 2005;36:373–381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15892535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kulak-Ozkan Y., Sertgoz A., Gedik H. Effect of thermocycling on tensile bond strength of six silicone-based, resilient denture liners. J Prosthet Dent. 2003;89:303–310.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12644808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinto J.R.R., Mesquita M.F., Henriques G.E.P., de Arruda Nóbilo M.A. Effect of thermocycling on bond strength and elasticity of 4 long-term soft denture liners. J Prosthet Dent. 2002;88:516–521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12474002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Özdemir H., Özdoğan A. Bond strength of resilient lining materials to denture base resin: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Prosthodont. 2018;27:828–841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30039888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kivovics P., Jahn M., Borbely J., Marton K. Frequency and location of traumatic ulcerations following placement of complete dentures. Int J Prosthodont. 2007;20:397–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kos M., Kuebler J.F., Luczak K., Engelke W. Bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaws: a review of 34 cases and evaluation of risk. J Craniomaxillofac Surg. 2010;38:255–259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19592261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kyrgidis A., Vahtsevanos K., Koloutsos G., Andreadis C., Boukovinas I., Teleioudis Z., et al.  Bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaws: a case-control study of risk factors in breast cancer patients. J Clin Oncol. 2008;26:4634–4638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18574158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vahtsevanos K., Kyrgidis A., Verrou E., Katodritou E., Triaridis S., Andreadis C.G., et al.  Longitudinal cohort study of risk factors in cancer patients of bisphosphonate-related osteonecrosis of the jaw. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27:5356–5362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19805682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart D.L. Prosthodontic treatment of a patient taking nitrogen-containing bisphosphonates to preserve the integrity of the epithelial attachment: a clinical report. J Prosthet Dent. 2011;106:350–354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otto S., Pautke C., den Wyngaert T., Niepel D., Schiødt M. Medication-related osteonecrosis of the jaw: prevention, diagnosis and management in patients with cancer and bone metastases. Cancer Treat Rev. 2018;69:177–187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30055439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
