<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">34999600</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-0311</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>44</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The American Journal of dermatopathology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Dermatopathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Dermatologists' Impressions of Spontaneously Regressing Verruca Plana Histopathology.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>411</StartPage>
          <EndPage>415</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>411-415</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/DAD.0000000000002140</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Verruca plana in its regressing phase exhibits clinical and histological features distinct from classic verruca plana, but the ways in which these features should inform treatment plans are still under investigation. We conducted a retrospective single-center analysis of 25 patients with features of classic verruca plana, or plane warts, who exhibited self-remission within 4 weeks of skin biopsy. Measures included lesion sites, clinical findings preceding regression, and histological analysis. Histological analysis involved review by 2 dermatologists followed by impressions given by 4 board-certified dermatologists who were blinded to the clinical characteristics of the patients. Histopathological findings of regressing plane warts showed superficial perivascular infiltration (96%), spongiosis and exocytosis (84%), basal vacuolization (64%), parakeratosis (64%), apoptotic keratinocytes (60%), and lichenoid infiltration (44%). These findings were more compatible with the histological patterns of pityriasis lichenoides, lichen planus, and spongiotic eczema, rather than classic verruca plana. This suggests that regressing verruca plana may be included in the differential diagnosis of lesions exhibiting a lichenoid or spongiotic reaction, and observation may be a favorable treatment plan in these patients.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Choi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Soo Hyun</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Tulane University School of Medicine, New Orleans, LA; and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Park</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sujin</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Cutaneous Biology Research Institute, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Do-Young</ForeName>
            <Initials>DY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Cutaneous Biology Research Institute, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Dermatopathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7911005</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0193-1091</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000072085" MajorTopicYN="N">Dermatologists</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008010" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lichen Planus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014860" MajorTopicYN="Y">Warts</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>7</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34999600</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DAD.0000000000002140</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00000372-202206000-00003</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ljubojevic S, Skerlev M. HPV-associated diseases. Clin Dermatol. 2014;32:227–234.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernard HU, Burk RD, Chen Z, et al. Classification of papillomaviruses (PVs) based on 189 PV types and proposal of taxonomic amendments. Virology. 2010;401:70–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cubie HA. Diseases associated with human papillomavirus infection. Virology. 2013;445:21–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tagami H, Takigawa M, Ogino A, et al. Spontaneous regression of plane warts after inflammation: clinical and histologic studies in 25 cases. Arch Dermatol. 1977;113:1209–1213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tagami H, Oguchi M, Ofuji S. The phenomenon of spontaneous regression of numerous flat warts: immunohistological studies. Cancer. 1980;45:2557–2563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berman A, Berman JE. Efflorescence of new warts: a sign of onset of involution in flat warts. Br J Dermatol. 1978;99:179–182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berman A. Depigmented haloes associated with the involution of flag warts. Br J Dermatol. 1977;97:263–265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berman A, Winkelmann RK. Flat warts undergoing involution: histopathological findings. Arch Dermatol. 1977;113:1219–1221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sehgal VN, Srivastava G, Sharma S, et al. Lichenoid tissue reaction/interface dermatitis: recognition, classification, etiology, and clinicopathological overtones. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2011;77:418–429; quiz 430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haftek M, Jablonska S, Orth G. Specific cell-mediated immunity in patients with epidermodysplasia verruciformis and plane warts. Dermatologica. 1985;170:213–220.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drijkoningen M, De Wolf-Peeters C, Degreef H, et al. Epidermal langerhans cells, dermal dendritic cells, and keratinocytes in viral lesions of skin and mucous membranes: an immunohistochemical study. Arch Dermatol Res. 1988;280:220–227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogozinski TT, Jablonska S, Jarzabek-Chorzelska M. Role of cell-mediated immunity in spontaneous regression of plane warts. Int J Dermatol. 1988;27:322–326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abreu Velez AM, Howard MS, Brown VM. Spongioticdermatitis with Langerhans cell microvesicles. J Cutan Pathol. 2016;43:181–186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renn CN, Sanchez DJ, Ochoa MT, et al. TLR activation of Langerhans cell-like dendritic cells triggers an antiviral immune response. J Immunol. 2006;177:298–305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhawan J, Dayal Y, Bhan AK. Langerhans cells in molluscum contagiosum, verruca vulgaris, plantar wart, and condyloma acuminatum. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1986;15:645–649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tagami H, Oku T, Iwatsuki K. Primary tissue culture of spontaneously regressing flat warts. In vitro attack by mononuclear cells against wart-derived epidermal cells. Cancer. 1985;55:2437–2441.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakayama Y, Asagoe K, Yamauchi A, et al. Dendritic cell subsets and immunological milieu in inflammatory human papilloma virus-related skin lesions. J Dermatol Sci. 2011;63:173–183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leong CM, Doorbar J, Nindl I, et al. Loss of epidermal langerhans cells occurs in human papillomavirus alpha, gamma, and mu but not beta genus infections. J Invest Dermatol. 2010;130:472–480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chardonnet Y, Viac J, Thivolet J. Langerhans cells in human warts. Br J Dermatol. 1986;115:669–675.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chardonnet Y, Beauve P, Viac J, et al. T-cell subsets and langerhans cells in wart lesions. Immunol Lett. 1983;6:191–196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman N, Birley HD, Renton AM, et al. Immunological events in regressing genital warts. Am J Clin Pathol. 1994;102:768–774.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aiba S, Rokugo M, Tagami H. Immunohistologic analysis of the phenomenon of spontaneous regression of numerous flat warts. Cancer. 1986;58:1246–1251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams OM, Hart KW, Wang EC, et al. Analysis of CD4(+) T-cell responses to human papillomavirus (HPV) type 11 L1 in healthy adults reveals a high degree of responsiveness and cross-reactivity with other HPV types. J Virol. 2002;76:7418–7429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oguchi M, Komura J, Tagami H, et al. Ultrastructural studies of spontaneously regressing plane warts. Macrophages attack verruca-epidermal cells. Arch Dermatol Res. 1981;270:403–411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto T, Nishioka K. Association ofgranzyme-B-positive lymphocytes in regressing plane warts. Dermatology. 2003;207:412–414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin SP, Jeon YK, Cho KH, et al. A rapidly regressing wart following biopsy. Ann Dermatol. 2011;23:123–124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SY. A rapidly regressed giant plantar wart following biopsy. Ann Dermatol. 2013;25:113–114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson NM, Pickard CM. Resolution of diffuse facial verruca plana following nonavalent human papillomavirus immunization. Pediatr Dermatol. 2021;38:292–293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X, Kim P, Farinelli B, et al. A novel laser vaccine adjuvant increases the motility of antigen presenting cells. PLoS One. 2010;5:e13776.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
