<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35017445</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of targeted muscle reinnervation on spinal cord motor neurons in rats following tibial nerve transection.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1827</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1832</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1827-1832</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.332153</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Targeted muscle reinnervation (TMR) is a surgical procedure used to transfer residual peripheral nerves from amputated limbs to targeted muscles, which allows the target muscles to become sources of motor control information for function reconstruction. However, the effect of TMR on injured motor neurons is still unclear. In this study, we aimed to explore the effect of hind limb TMR surgery on injured motor neurons in the spinal cord of rats after tibial nerve transection. We found that the reduction in hind limb motor function and atrophy in mice caused by tibial nerve transection improved after TMR. TMR enhanced nerve regeneration by increasing the number of axons and myelin sheath thickness in the tibial nerve, increasing the number of anterior horn motor neurons, and increasing the number of choline acetyltransferase-positive cells and immunofluorescence intensity of synaptophysin in rat spinal cord. Our findings suggest that TMR may enable the reconnection of residual nerve fibers to target muscles, thus restoring hind limb motor function on the injured side.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Human Anatomy, School of Basic Medical Scinences, Guangxi Medical University, Nanning, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region; Department of Human Anatomy, Zhuhai Campus of Zunyi Medical University, Zhuhai, Guangdong Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jian-Ping</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Human Anatomy, Zhuhai Campus of Zunyi Medical University, Zhuhai, Guangdong Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhen-Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Human Anatomy, Zhuhai Campus of Zunyi Medical University, Zhuhai, Guangdong Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lin</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Human Anatomy, Zhuhai Campus of Zunyi Medical University, Zhuhai, Guangdong Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xue-Zheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>XZ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Human Anatomy, School of Basic Medical Scinences, Guangxi Medical University, Nanning, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nissl staining</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">function reconstruction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor neuron</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve implant</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal cord</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synaptophysin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">targeted muscle reinnervation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tibial nerve</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transection</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35017445</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8820695</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.332153</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_8_1827_332153</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen ZX, Lu HB, Jin XL, Feng WF, Yang XN, Qi ZL. Skeletal muscle-derived cells repair peripheral nerve defects in mice. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:152–161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6862419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31535664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conforti L, Gilley J, Coleman MP. Wallerian degeneration: an emerging axon death pathway linking injury and disease. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2014;15:394–409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24840802</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan H, Fu J, Li X, Pei Y, Li X, Pei G, Guo Z. Implantation of customized 3-D printed titanium prosthesis in limb salvage surgery: a case series and review of the literature. World J Surg Oncol. 2015;13:308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4632365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26537339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giorgetti E, Obrecht M, Ronco M, Panesar M, Lambert C, Accart N, Doelemeyer A, Nash M, Bidinosti M, Beckmann N. Magnetic resonance imaging as a biomarker in rodent peripheral nerve injury models reveals an age-related impairment of nerve regeneration. Sci Rep. 2019;9:13508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6751200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31534149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girouard MP, Bueno M, Julian V, Drake S, Byrne AB, Fournier AE. The molecular interplay between axon degeneration and regeneration. Dev Neurobiol. 2018;78:978–990.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30022605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hargrove LJ, Simon AM, Young AJ, Lipschutz RD, Finucane SB, Smith DG, Kuiken TA. Robotic leg control with EMG decoding in an amputee with nerve transfers. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:1237–1242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24066744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hazubski S, Hoppe H, Otte A. Electrode-free visual prosthesis/exoskeleton control using augmented reality glasses in a first proof-of-technical-concept study. Sci Rep. 2020;10:16279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530745</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33004950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang JP, Li WQ, Yang L, Zhu MX, Zhu XD, Li CY, Yang ZJ, Li GL. A pilot study of nerve function reinnervation on a transhumeral amputee. J Integr Technol. 2016;5:30–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itoyama T, Yoshida S, Tomokiyo A, Hasegawa D, Hamano S, Sugii H, Ono T, Fujino S, Maeda H. Possible function of GDNF and Schwann cells in wound healing of periodontal tissue. J Periodontal Res. 2020;55:830–839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim M, Kim H, Kim D, Kim D, Huh Y, Park C, Chung HJ, Jung J, Jeong NY. Heme oxygenase 1 in schwann cells regulates peripheral nerve degeneration against oxidative stress. ASN Neuro. 2019;11:1759091419838949.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6498775</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31046408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krasoulis A, Vijayakumar S, Nazarpour K. Multi-grip classification-based prosthesis control with two EMG-IMU sensors. IEEE Trans Neural Syst Rehabil Eng. 2020;28:508–518.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31841413</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuiken TA, Childress DS, Rymer WZ. The hyper-reinnervation of rat skeletal muscle. Brain Res. 1995;676:113–123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7796162</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuiken TA, Dumanian GA, Lipschutz RD, Miller LA, Stubblefield KA. The use of targeted muscle reinnervation for improved myoelectric prosthesis control in a bilateral shoulder disarticulation amputee. Prosthet Orthot Int. 2004;28:245–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15658637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuiken TA, Miller LA, Lipschutz RD, Lock BA, Stubblefield K, Marasco PD, Zhou P, Dumanian GA. Targeted reinnervation for enhanced prosthetic arm function in a woman with a proximal amputation: a case study. Lancet. 2007;369:371–380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17276777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Wang H. Peripheral nerve injury induced changes in the spinal cord and strategies to counteract/enhance the changes to promote nerve regeneration. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:189–198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6905333</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31552884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loyalka P, Liu L, Chen G, Zheng X. The cost of disability in China. Demography. 2014;51:97–118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24385200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall KL, Farah MH. Axonal regeneration and sprouting as a potential therapeutic target for nervous system disorders. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:1901–1910.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8343323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Percie du Sert N, Ahluwalia A, Alam S, Avey MT, Baker M, Browne WJ, Clark A, Cuthill IC, Dirnagl U, Emerson M, Garner P, Holgate ST, Howells DW, Hurst V, Karp NA, Lazic SE, Lidster K, MacCallum CJ, Macleod M, Pearl EJ, et al.  Reporting animal research: Explanation and elaboration for the ARRIVE guidelines 20. PLoS Biol. 2020;18 e3000411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrova ES, Kolos EA, Korzhevskii DE. Differentiation of cholinergic neurons in rat spinal cord under conditions of allotransplantation into a peripheral nerve and in situ development. Bull Exp Biol Med. 2015;160:141–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26593413</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider CA, Rasband WS, Eliceiri KW. NIH Image to ImageJ: 25 years of image analysis. Nat Methods. 2012;9:671–675.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silman I, Sussman JL. Acetylcholinesterase: how is structure related to function. Chem Biol Interact. 2008;175:3–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18586019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soendenbroe C, Heisterberg MF, Schjerling P, Karlsen A, Kjaer M, Andersen JL, Mackey AL. Molecular indicators of denervation in aging human skeletal muscle. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:453–463.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31314910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiel G. Synapsin I, synapsin II, and synaptophysin: marker proteins of synaptic vesicles. Brain Pathol. 1993;3:87–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7903586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang AL, Yuan M, Neufeld AH. Degeneration of neuronal cell bodies following axonal injury in Wld(S) mice. J Neurosci Res. 2006;84:1799–1807.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17022038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang CH, Wang B, Wendu RL, Bi HE, Cao GF, Ji C, Jiang Q, Yao J. Protective role of Wallerian degeneration slow (Wld(s)) gene against retinal ganglion cell body damage in a Wallerian degeneration model. Exp Ther Med. 2013;5:621–625.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3570087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang P, Li YH, Zhang ZJ, Lin YF, Jiang ZD, Ding XF, Yang L. Effects of functional electrical stimulation on neuromuscular function after targeted muscle reinnervation surgery in rats. Annu Int Conf IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc. 2020;2020:3823–3826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33018834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng J, Wang YH, Li M, Zhang DY, Jiang BG. GSK3beta inhibitor promotes myelination and mitigates muscle atrophy after peripheral nerve injury. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13:324–330.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5879906</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29557384</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilke MA, Niethammer C, Meyer B, Farina D, Dosen S. Psychometric characterization of incidental feedback sources during grasping with a hand prosthesis. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2019;16:155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902515</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31823792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams HE, Boser QA, Pilarsk PM, Chapman CS, Vette AH, Hebert JS. Hand function kinematics when using a simulated myoelectric prosthesis. IEEE Int Conf Rehabil Robot. 2019;2019:169–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31374625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang X, Ji C, Liu X, Zheng C, Zhang Y, Shen R, Zhou Z. The significance of the neuregulin-1/ErbB signaling pathway and its effect on Sox10 expression in the development of terminally differentiated Schwann cells in vitro. Int J Neurosci. 2020;1:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32757877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Zhou H, Yang L, Huang J, Yang W, Li G. Effects of low frequency electrical stimulation in targeted muscle reinnervation rat model. Zhongguo Kangfu Yixue Zazhi. 2015;30:3–9. 54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
