<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35020691</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-4513</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>45</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of immunotherapy (Hagerstown, Md. : 1997)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Immunother</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Pembrolizumab Achieves a Complete Response in an NF-1 Mutated, PD-L1 Positive Malignant Peripheral Nerve Sheath Tumor: A Case Report and Review of the Benchmarks.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>222</StartPage>
          <EndPage>226</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>222-226</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CJI.0000000000000410</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNSTs) represent a rare subtype of neural crest cell-derived soft tissue sarcomas (STS). Standard of care therapy comprises surgical resection followed by adjuvant radiation, and most clinical studies have demonstrated finite survival benefit of radiation and chemotherapy. In metastatic disease, palliative chemotherapy provides very limited efficacy. We report a 60-year-old male patient with a primary para vertebral tumor at T7-T8 with lung metastases who recurred after surgical resection and later progressed on epirubicin plus ifosfamide. He was an international patient and referred to the phase 1 clinic. Molecular profiling and immunohistochemistry of the tumor revealed a PD-L1 expression of 70% (2+) and pathogenic genetic alterations by next-generation sequencing in ARID1A, CDKN2A, KMT2A, NF1, and TP53. Immune checkpoint therapy (ICT) with pembrolizumab was commenced, and interval computed tomography revealed a complete remission by cycle 6. Randomized clinical trials illustrate that ICTs such as anti-PD-1 and anti-CTLA4 monoclonal antibodies in STS cohorts display low or modest response rates by variable PD-L1 expression. This and 3 other case reports of disparate PD-L1 expression demonstrate complete responses in PD-L1 positive MPNSTs treated with ICT. These case reports necessitate further study of ICT in neural crest cell subtype of STS.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Larson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kristian</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Arizona College of Medicine.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Russ</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atlantis</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Internal Medicine.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arif-Tiwari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hina</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Imaging.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mahadevan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daruka</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mays Cancer Center/MD Anderson, University of Texas Health San Antonio, San Antonio, TX.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elliott</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alex</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bhattacharyya</LastName>
            <ForeName>Achyut</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Babiker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hani</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oncology, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mayo Clinic Cancer Center, Mayo Clinic Florida, Jacksonville, FL.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mays Cancer Center/MD Anderson, University of Texas Health San Antonio, San Antonio, TX.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Immunother</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9706083</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1524-9557</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>DPT0O3T46P</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C582435">pembrolizumab</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019985" MajorTopicYN="N">Benchmarking</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009364" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Recurrence, Local</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018319" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurofibrosarcoma</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35020691</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CJI.0000000000000410</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00002371-900000000-99305</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James AW, Shurell E, Singh A, et al. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor. Surg Oncol Clin N Am. 2016;25:789–802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta G, Mammis A, Maniker A. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Neurosurg Clin N Am. 2008;19:533–543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farid M, Demicco EG, Garcia R, et al. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Oncologist. 2014;19:193–201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stucky CCH, Johnson KN, Gray RJ, et al. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNST): the Mayo Clinic experience. Ann Surg Oncol. 2012;19:878–885.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Louis DN, Perry A, Reifenberger G, et al. The 2016 World Health Organization Classification of Tumors of the Central Nervous System: a summary. Acta Neuropathol. 2016. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thway K, Fisher C. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor: pathology and genetics. Ann Diagn Pathol. 2014;18:109–116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss SW, Langloss JM, Enzinger FM. Value of S-100 protein in the diagnosis of soft tissue tumors with particular reference to benign and malignant Schwann cell tumors. Lab Invest. 1983;49:299–308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pekmezci M, Reuss DE, Hirbe AC, et al. Morphologic and immunohistochemical features of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors and cellular schwannomas. Mod Pathol. 2015;28:187–200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis JJ, Brennan MF. Soft tissue sarcomas. Curr Probl Surg. 1996;33:820–872.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goertz O, Langer S, Uthoff D, et al. Diagnosis, treatment and survival of 65 patients with malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. Anticancer Res. 2014;34:777–784.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou C, Smith KD, Liu J, et al. Clinical, pathological, and molecular variables predictive of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor outcome. Ann Surg. 2009;249:1014–1022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ducatman BS, Scheithauer BW, Piepgras DG, et al. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. A clinicopathologic study of 120 cases. Cancer. 1986;57:2006–2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tawbi HA-H, Burgess MA, Crowley J, et al. Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors. J Clin Oncol. 2016;19:1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prudner BC, Ball T, Rathore R, et al. Diagnosis and management of malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors: current practice and future perspectives. Neurooncol Adv. 2019. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroep JR, Ouali M, Gelderblom H, et al. First-line chemotherapy for malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor (MPNST) versus other histological soft tissue sarcoma subtypes and as a prognostic factor for MPNST: an EORTC soft tissue and bone sarcoma group study. Ann Oncol. 2011;22:207–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang S, Liechty B, Patel S, et al. Programmed death ligand 1 expression and tumor infiltrating lymphocytes in neurofibromatosis type 1 and 2 associated tumors. J Neurooncol. 2018;138:183–190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haworth KB, Arnold MA, Pierson CR, et al. Immune profiling of NF1-associated tumors reveals histologic subtype distinctions and heterogeneity: implications for immunotherapy. Oncotarget. 2017;8:82037–82048.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kythreotou A, Siddique A, Mauri FA, et al. Pd-L1. J Clin Pathol. 2018;71:189–194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Z-Y, Wu S-P, Liao R-Q, et al. Potential biomarker for checkpoint blockade immunotherapy and treatment strategy. Tumour Biol. 2016;37:4251–4261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cottrell TR, Taube JM. PD-L1 and emerging biomarkers in immune checkpoint blockade therapy. Cancer J (United States). 2018;24:41–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paydas S, Bagir EK, Deveci MA, et al. Clinical and prognostic significance of PD-1 and PD-L1 expression in sarcomas. Med Oncol. 2016;33:1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim C, Kim EK, Jung H, et al. Prognostic implications of PD-L1 expression in patients with soft tissue sarcoma. BMC Cancer. 2016;16:4–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budczies J, Mechtersheimer G, Denkert C, et al. PD-L1 (CD274) copy number gain, expression, and immune cell infiltration as candidate predictors for response to immune checkpoint inhibitors in soft-tissue sarcoma. Oncoimmunology. 2017;6:1–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertucci F, Finetti P, Perrot D, et al. PDL1 expression is a poor-prognosis factor in soft-tissue sarcomas. Oncoimmunology. 2017;6:1–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis LE, Nicholls LA, Babiker HM, et al. PD-1 inhibition achieves a complete metabolic response in a patient with malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor. Cancer Immunol Res. 2019;7:1396–1400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Payandeh M, Sadeghi M, Sadeghi E. Complete response to pembrolizumab in a patient with malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor: the first case reported. J Appl Pharm Sci. 2017;7:182–184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Özdemir BC, Bohanes P, Bisig B, et al. Deep response to anti-PD-1 therapy of metastatic neurofibromatosis type 1-associated malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor with CD274/PD-L1 amplification. JCO Precis Oncol. 2019. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miwa S, Yamamoto N, Hayashi K, et al. Therapeutic targets for bone and soft-tissue sarcomas. Int J Mol Sci. 2019. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tawbi HA, Burgess M, Bolejack V, et al. Pembrolizumab in advanced soft-tissue sarcoma and bone sarcoma (SARC028): a multicentre, two-cohort, single-arm, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2017;18:1493–1501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D’Angelo SP, Shoushtari AN, Keohan ML, et al. Combined KIT and CTLA-4 blockade in patients with refractory GIST and other advanced sarcomas: a phase Ib study of dasatinib plus ipilimumab. Clin Cancer Res. 2017. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Ami E, Barysauskas CM, Solomon S, et al. Immunotherapy with single agent nivolumab for advanced leiomyosarcoma of the uterus: results of a phase 2 study. Cancer. 2017. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolchok JD, Kluger H, Callahan MK, et al. Nivolumab plus Ipilimumab in advanced melanoma. N Engl J Med. 2013. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolchok JD, Chiarion-Sileni V, Gonzalez R, et al. Overall survival with combined nivolumab and ipilimumab in advanced melanoma. N Engl J Med. 2017. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okamura R, Kato S, Lee S, et al. ARID1A alterations function as a biomarker for longer progression-free survival after anti-PD-1/PD-L1 immunotherapy. J Immunother cancer. 2020. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han G, Yang G, Hao D, et al. 9p21 loss confers a cold tumor immune microenvironment and primary resistance to immune checkpoint therapy. Nat Commun. 2021;12:5606.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panageas KS. Clinical trial design for rare cancers: why a less conventional route may be required. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2015. [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
