<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35023788</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antithrombotic therapy for secondary prevention of unprovoked venous thromboembolism: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>253</StartPage>
          <EndPage>261</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>253-261</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2022.2026002</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Extended antithrombotic treatment is recommended for secondary prevention of unprovoked venous thromboembolism (VTE), however, there is no consensus on which antithrombotic strategy is preferable.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the efficacy and safety of different antithrombotic strategies for secondary prevention unprovoked VTE.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, Embase, and MEDLINE were systematically searched from inception to 22 July 2020 for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) that compared the efficacy and/or safety of extended antithrombotic strategies including aspirin, warfarin and direct oral anticoagulants (DOACs) for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE. The primary outcome was risk of major bleeding and the secondary outcomes were risks of recurrent VTE and all-cause death. Odds ratios (ORs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were estimated using pairwise and network meta-analysis with random effect. Possible ranking of extended antithrombotic strategies was plotted using the surface under the cumulative ranking curve and mean ranks.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Seventeen RCTs met the inclusion criteria, and meta-analysis results showed that warfarin was associated with significantly higher risk of major bleeding than placebo/observation (OR 2.71, 95% CI 1.32-5.55) or apixaban (OR 10.65, 95% CI 1.06-107.13). Apixaban and low-apixaban were the top two strategies according to the ranking of major bleeding. Warfarin (OR 0.25, 95%CI 0.13-0.49), rivaroxaban (OR 0.18, 95%CI 0.03-0.90), apixaban (OR 0.18, 95%CI 0.04-0.85) and low-apixaban (OR 0.18, 95%CI 0.04-0.82) were related to significantly lower risk than placebo/observation; edoxaban was non-inferior to warfarin on the risk of recurrent VTE. Furthermore, apixaban was linked with significantly lower risk of all-cause death than placebo/observation (OR 0.29, 95% CI 0.09-0.88).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Apixaban showed superiority to other antithrombotic strategies on major bleeding and all-cause death for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE. Further studies are warranted owing to the limited number of studies and positive cases.Key messagesAll antithrombotic strategies including warfarin, DOACs and aspirin were superior to placebo/observation on recurrent VTE for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE.Apixaban demonstrated lower risk of major bleeding than warfarin, and lower risk of all-cause death than placebo/observation.Further research about the efficacy and safety of antithrombotic treatments for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE is warranted.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dandan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Song</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yao</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aiping</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005343">Fibrinolytic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005343" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrinolytic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000071076" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Meta-Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055502" MajorTopicYN="N">Secondary Prevention</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054556" MajorTopicYN="Y">Venous Thromboembolism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">DOAC</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Secondary prevention</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">network meta-analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">unprovoked VTE</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35023788</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8759723</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2026002</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raskob GE, Angchaisuksiri P, Blanco AN, et al. . 
Thrombosis: a major contributor to global disease burden. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2014;34:2363–2371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25304324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naess IA, Christiansen SC, Romundstad P, et al. . 
Incidence and mortality of venous thrombosis: a population-based study. J Thromb Haemost. 2007;5:692–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17367492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beckman MG, Hooper WC, Critchley SE, et al. . 
Venous thromboembolism: a public health concern. Am J Prev Med. 2010;38:S495–S501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20331949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouget J, Viglino D, Yvetot Q, et al. . 
Major gastrointestinal bleeding and antithrombotics: characteristics and management. World J Gastroenterol. 2020;26:5463–5473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520611</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prandoni P, Noventa F, Ghirarduzzi A, et al. . 
The risk of recurrent venous thromboembolism after discontinuing anticoagulation in patients with acute proximal deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism. A prospective cohort study in 1,626 patients. Haematologica. 2007;92:199–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17296569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boutitie F, Pinede L, Schulman S, et al. . 
Influence of preceding length of anticoagulant treatment and initial presentation of venous thromboembolism on risk of recurrence after stopping treatment: analysis of individual participants' data from seven trials. BMJ. 2011;342:d3036.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21610040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan F, Rahman A, Carrier M, et al. . 
Long term risk of symptomatic recurrent venous thromboembolism after discontinuation of anticoagulant treatment for first unprovoked venous thromboembolism event: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2019;366:l4363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6651066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31340984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortel TL, Neumann I, Ageno W, et al. . 
American Society of Hematology 2020 guidelines for management of venous thromboembolism: treatment of deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism. Blood Adv. 2020;4:4693–4738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556153</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macdonald RL.
Management of intracranial hemorrhage in the anticoagulated patient. Neurosurg Clin N Am. 2018;29:605–613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30223973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrier M, Le Gal G, Wells PS, et al. . 
Systematic review: case-fatality rates of recurrent venous thromboembolism and major bleeding events among patients treated for venous thromboembolism. Ann Intern Med. 2010;152:578–589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20439576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kakkos SK, Kirkilesis GI, Tsolakis IA.. 
Editor's choice – efficacy and safety of the new oral anticoagulants dabigatran, rivaroxaban, apixaban, and edoxaban in the treatment and secondary prevention of venous thromboembolism: a systematic review and meta-analysis of phase III trials. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2014;48:565–575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24951377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alotaibi G, Alsaleh K, Wu C, et al. . 
Dabigatran, rivaroxaban and apixaban for extended venous thromboembolism treatment: network meta-analysis. Int Angiol. 2014;33:301–308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sobieraj DM, Coleman CI, Pasupuleti V, et al. . 
Comparative efficacy and safety of anticoagulants and aspirin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism: a network meta-analysis. Thromb Res. 2015;135:888–896.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25795564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rollins BM, Silva MA, Donovan JL, et al. . 
Evaluation of oral anticoagulants for the extended treatment of venous thromboembolism using a mixed-treatment comparison, meta-analytic approach. Clin Ther. 2014;36:1454–1464 e1453.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. . 
Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151(4):264–269. W264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, et al. . 
The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:777–784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins J, Sterne AD.. 
Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins J, Green S, editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions, 5.1.0 ed.
London: The Cochrane Collaboration. Available from: https://handbook-5-1.cochrane.org/2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White IR.
Network meta-analysis. Stata J. 2015;15(4):951–985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salanti G, Ades AE, Ioannidis JP.. 
Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:163–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farraj RS.
Anticoagulation period in idiopathic venous thromboembolism. How long is enough?
Saudi Med J. 2004;25:848–851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15235686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Prandoni P, Santamaria MG, et al. . 
Three months versus one year of oral anticoagulant therapy for idiopathic deep venous thrombosis. N Engl J Med. 2001;345:165–169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11463010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Prandoni P, Becattini C, et al. . 
Extended oral anticoagulant therapy after a first episode of pulmonary embolism. Ann Intern Med. 2003;139:19–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12834314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Buller HR, Cohen A, et al. . 
Apixaban for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(8):699–708.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23216615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauersachs R, Berkowitz SD, Brenner B, et al. . 
Oral rivaroxaban for symptomatic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:2499–2510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becattini C, Agnelli G, Schenone A, et al. . 
Aspirin for preventing the recurrence of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2012;366:1959–1967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22621626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradbury C, Fletcher K, Sun Y, et al. . 
A randomised controlled trial of extended anticoagulation treatment versus standard treatment for the prevention of recurrent venous thromboembolism (VTE) and post-thrombotic syndrome in patients being treated for a first episode of unprovoked VTE (the ExACT study. Br J Haematol. 2020;188(6):962–975. ).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31713863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brighton TA, Eikelboom JW, Mann K, et al. . 
Other source: low-dose aspirin for preventing recurrent venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2012;367:1979–1987.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23121403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buller HR, Decousus H, Grosso MA, et al. . 
Edoxaban versus warfarin for the treatment of symptomatic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:1406–1415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couturaud F, Sanchez O, Pernod G, et al. . 
Six months vs extended oral anticoagulation after a first episode of pulmonary embolism: the PADIS-PE randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2015;314:31–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26151264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couturaud F, Pernod G, Presles E, for the “PADIS-DVT” Investigators, et al.. 
Six months versus two years of oral anticoagulation after a first episode of unprovoked deep-vein thrombosis. The PADIS-DVT randomized clinical trial. Haematologica. 2019;104(7):1493–1501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6601089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eischer L, Gartner V, Schulman S, et al. . 
6 Versus 30 months anticoagulation for recurrent venous thrombosis in patients with high factor VIII. Ann Hematol. 2009;88:485–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Gent M, Hirsh J, et al. . 
A comparison of three months of anticoagulation with extended anticoagulation for a first episode of idiopathic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 1999;340(12):901–907.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10089183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Ginsberg JS, Kovacs MJ, et al. . 
Comparison of low-intensity warfarin therapy with conventional-intensity warfarin therapy for long-term prevention of recurrent venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2003;349:631–639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12917299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palareti G, Cosmi B, Legnani C, et al. . 
D-dimer testing to determine the duration of anticoagulation therapy. N Engl J Med. 2006;355:1780–1789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17065639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ridker PM, Goldhaber SZ, Danielson E, et al. . 
Long-term, low-intensity warfarin therapy for the prevention of recurrent venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2003;348(15):1425–1434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12601075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siragusa S, Malato A, Anastasio R, et al. . 
Residual vein thrombosis to establish duration of anticoagulation after a first episode of deep vein thrombosis: the duration of anticoagulation based on compression ultrasonography (DACUS) study. Blood. 2008;112:511–515.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18497320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazzolai L, Aboyans V, Ageno W, et al. . 
Diagnosis and management of acute deep vein thrombosis: a joint consensus document from the European Society of Cardiology Working groups of aorta and peripheral vascular diseases and pulmonary circulation and right ventricular function. Eur Heart J. 2018;39:4208–4218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konstantinides SV, Meyer G, Becattini C, et al. . 
2019 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism developed in collaboration with the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Heart J. 2020;41:543–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Akl EA, Ornelas J, et al. . 
Antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2016;149:315–352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middeldorp S, Prins MH, Hutten BA.. 
Duration of treatment with vitamin K antagonists in symptomatic venous thromboembolism. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;CD001367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7074008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marik PE, Cavallazzi R.. 
Extended anticoagulant and aspirin treatment for the secondary prevention of thromboembolic disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2015;10(11):e0143252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4654552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26587983</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs LG.
Warfarin pharmacology, clinical management, and evaluation of hemorrhagic risk for the elderly. Cardiol Clin. 2008;26:157–167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18406992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Minno A, Frigerio B, Spadarella G, et al. . 
Old and new oral anticoagulants: food, herbal medicines and drug interactions. Blood Rev. 2017;31:193–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin MC, Sussman ES, Feng AY, et al. . 
Hemorrhage risk of direct oral anticoagulants in real-world venous thromboembolism patients. Thromb Res. 2021;204:126–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34198049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz-Gimenez N, Suarez C, Gonzalez R, et al. . 
Predictive variables for major bleeding events in patients presenting with documented acute venous thromboembolism. Findings from the RIETE Registry. Thromb Haemost. 2008;100:26–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18612534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holley AB, King CS, Jackson JL, et al. . 
Different finite durations of anticoagulation and outcomes following idiopathic venous thromboembolism: a meta-analysis. Thrombosis. 2010;2010:540386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3211079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22084660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bova C, Bianco A, Mascaro V, et al. . 
Extended anticoagulation and mortality in venous thromboembolism. A meta-analysis of six randomized trials. Thromb Res. 2016;139:22–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26916292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sindet-Pedersen C, Pallisgaard JL, Olesen JB, et al. . 
Safety and efficacy of direct oral anticoagulants compared to warfarin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism – a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thromb Res. 2015;136:732–738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26277682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mai V, Bertoletti L, Cucherat M, et al. . 
Extended anticoagulation for the secondary prevention of venous thromboembolic events: an updated network meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0214134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6443183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30933993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira NL, Rihal C, Lennon R, et al. . 
Effect of CYP2C19 genotype on ischemic outcomes during oral P2Y12 inhibitor therapy: a meta-analysis. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2021;14(7):739–750.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulman S, Kearon C, Kakkar AK, et al. . 
Extended use of dabigatran, warfarin, or placebo in venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(8):709–718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Available from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00329238?term=NCT00329238&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weitz JI, Lensing AWA, Prins MH, et al. . 
Rivaroxaban or aspirin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2017;376(13):1211–1222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35023788</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antithrombotic therapy for secondary prevention of unprovoked venous thromboembolism: a systematic review and network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>253</StartPage>
          <EndPage>261</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>253-261</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2022.2026002</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Extended antithrombotic treatment is recommended for secondary prevention of unprovoked venous thromboembolism (VTE), however, there is no consensus on which antithrombotic strategy is preferable.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To compare the efficacy and safety of different antithrombotic strategies for secondary prevention unprovoked VTE.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, Embase, and MEDLINE were systematically searched from inception to 22 July 2020 for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) that compared the efficacy and/or safety of extended antithrombotic strategies including aspirin, warfarin and direct oral anticoagulants (DOACs) for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE. The primary outcome was risk of major bleeding and the secondary outcomes were risks of recurrent VTE and all-cause death. Odds ratios (ORs) and 95% confidence intervals (CIs) were estimated using pairwise and network meta-analysis with random effect. Possible ranking of extended antithrombotic strategies was plotted using the surface under the cumulative ranking curve and mean ranks.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Seventeen RCTs met the inclusion criteria, and meta-analysis results showed that warfarin was associated with significantly higher risk of major bleeding than placebo/observation (OR 2.71, 95% CI 1.32-5.55) or apixaban (OR 10.65, 95% CI 1.06-107.13). Apixaban and low-apixaban were the top two strategies according to the ranking of major bleeding. Warfarin (OR 0.25, 95%CI 0.13-0.49), rivaroxaban (OR 0.18, 95%CI 0.03-0.90), apixaban (OR 0.18, 95%CI 0.04-0.85) and low-apixaban (OR 0.18, 95%CI 0.04-0.82) were related to significantly lower risk than placebo/observation; edoxaban was non-inferior to warfarin on the risk of recurrent VTE. Furthermore, apixaban was linked with significantly lower risk of all-cause death than placebo/observation (OR 0.29, 95% CI 0.09-0.88).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Apixaban showed superiority to other antithrombotic strategies on major bleeding and all-cause death for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE. Further studies are warranted owing to the limited number of studies and positive cases.Key messagesAll antithrombotic strategies including warfarin, DOACs and aspirin were superior to placebo/observation on recurrent VTE for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE.Apixaban demonstrated lower risk of major bleeding than warfarin, and lower risk of all-cause death than placebo/observation.Further research about the efficacy and safety of antithrombotic treatments for secondary prevention of unprovoked VTE is warranted.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dandan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Song</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yao</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aiping</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005343">Fibrinolytic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005343" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrinolytic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000071076" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Meta-Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055502" MajorTopicYN="N">Secondary Prevention</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054556" MajorTopicYN="Y">Venous Thromboembolism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">DOAC</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Secondary prevention</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">network meta-analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">unprovoked VTE</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35023788</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8759723</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2026002</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raskob GE, Angchaisuksiri P, Blanco AN, et al. . 
Thrombosis: a major contributor to global disease burden. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2014;34:2363–2371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25304324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naess IA, Christiansen SC, Romundstad P, et al. . 
Incidence and mortality of venous thrombosis: a population-based study. J Thromb Haemost. 2007;5:692–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17367492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beckman MG, Hooper WC, Critchley SE, et al. . 
Venous thromboembolism: a public health concern. Am J Prev Med. 2010;38:S495–S501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20331949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouget J, Viglino D, Yvetot Q, et al. . 
Major gastrointestinal bleeding and antithrombotics: characteristics and management. World J Gastroenterol. 2020;26:5463–5473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520611</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33024397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prandoni P, Noventa F, Ghirarduzzi A, et al. . 
The risk of recurrent venous thromboembolism after discontinuing anticoagulation in patients with acute proximal deep vein thrombosis or pulmonary embolism. A prospective cohort study in 1,626 patients. Haematologica. 2007;92:199–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17296569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boutitie F, Pinede L, Schulman S, et al. . 
Influence of preceding length of anticoagulant treatment and initial presentation of venous thromboembolism on risk of recurrence after stopping treatment: analysis of individual participants' data from seven trials. BMJ. 2011;342:d3036.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21610040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan F, Rahman A, Carrier M, et al. . 
Long term risk of symptomatic recurrent venous thromboembolism after discontinuation of anticoagulant treatment for first unprovoked venous thromboembolism event: systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ. 2019;366:l4363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6651066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31340984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortel TL, Neumann I, Ageno W, et al. . 
American Society of Hematology 2020 guidelines for management of venous thromboembolism: treatment of deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism. Blood Adv. 2020;4:4693–4738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7556153</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macdonald RL.
Management of intracranial hemorrhage in the anticoagulated patient. Neurosurg Clin N Am. 2018;29:605–613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30223973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrier M, Le Gal G, Wells PS, et al. . 
Systematic review: case-fatality rates of recurrent venous thromboembolism and major bleeding events among patients treated for venous thromboembolism. Ann Intern Med. 2010;152:578–589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20439576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kakkos SK, Kirkilesis GI, Tsolakis IA.. 
Editor's choice – efficacy and safety of the new oral anticoagulants dabigatran, rivaroxaban, apixaban, and edoxaban in the treatment and secondary prevention of venous thromboembolism: a systematic review and meta-analysis of phase III trials. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2014;48:565–575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24951377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alotaibi G, Alsaleh K, Wu C, et al. . 
Dabigatran, rivaroxaban and apixaban for extended venous thromboembolism treatment: network meta-analysis. Int Angiol. 2014;33:301–308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25056161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sobieraj DM, Coleman CI, Pasupuleti V, et al. . 
Comparative efficacy and safety of anticoagulants and aspirin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism: a network meta-analysis. Thromb Res. 2015;135:888–896.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25795564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rollins BM, Silva MA, Donovan JL, et al. . 
Evaluation of oral anticoagulants for the extended treatment of venous thromboembolism using a mixed-treatment comparison, meta-analytic approach. Clin Ther. 2014;36:1454–1464 e1453.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. . 
Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Ann Intern Med. 2009;151(4):264–269. W264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19622511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, et al. . 
The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162:777–784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins J, Sterne AD.. 
Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins J, Green S, editors. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions, 5.1.0 ed.
London: The Cochrane Collaboration. Available from: https://handbook-5-1.cochrane.org/2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White IR.
Network meta-analysis. Stata J. 2015;15(4):951–985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salanti G, Ades AE, Ioannidis JP.. 
Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64:163–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farraj RS.
Anticoagulation period in idiopathic venous thromboembolism. How long is enough?
Saudi Med J. 2004;25:848–851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15235686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Prandoni P, Santamaria MG, et al. . 
Three months versus one year of oral anticoagulant therapy for idiopathic deep venous thrombosis. N Engl J Med. 2001;345:165–169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11463010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Prandoni P, Becattini C, et al. . 
Extended oral anticoagulant therapy after a first episode of pulmonary embolism. Ann Intern Med. 2003;139:19–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12834314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Buller HR, Cohen A, et al. . 
Apixaban for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(8):699–708.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23216615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauersachs R, Berkowitz SD, Brenner B, et al. . 
Oral rivaroxaban for symptomatic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:2499–2510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21128814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becattini C, Agnelli G, Schenone A, et al. . 
Aspirin for preventing the recurrence of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2012;366:1959–1967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22621626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradbury C, Fletcher K, Sun Y, et al. . 
A randomised controlled trial of extended anticoagulation treatment versus standard treatment for the prevention of recurrent venous thromboembolism (VTE) and post-thrombotic syndrome in patients being treated for a first episode of unprovoked VTE (the ExACT study. Br J Haematol. 2020;188(6):962–975. ).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31713863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brighton TA, Eikelboom JW, Mann K, et al. . 
Other source: low-dose aspirin for preventing recurrent venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2012;367:1979–1987.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23121403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buller HR, Decousus H, Grosso MA, et al. . 
Edoxaban versus warfarin for the treatment of symptomatic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:1406–1415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23991658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couturaud F, Sanchez O, Pernod G, et al. . 
Six months vs extended oral anticoagulation after a first episode of pulmonary embolism: the PADIS-PE randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2015;314:31–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26151264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couturaud F, Pernod G, Presles E, for the “PADIS-DVT” Investigators, et al.. 
Six months versus two years of oral anticoagulation after a first episode of unprovoked deep-vein thrombosis. The PADIS-DVT randomized clinical trial. Haematologica. 2019;104(7):1493–1501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6601089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eischer L, Gartner V, Schulman S, et al. . 
6 Versus 30 months anticoagulation for recurrent venous thrombosis in patients with high factor VIII. Ann Hematol. 2009;88:485–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18931845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Gent M, Hirsh J, et al. . 
A comparison of three months of anticoagulation with extended anticoagulation for a first episode of idiopathic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 1999;340(12):901–907.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10089183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Ginsberg JS, Kovacs MJ, et al. . 
Comparison of low-intensity warfarin therapy with conventional-intensity warfarin therapy for long-term prevention of recurrent venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2003;349:631–639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12917299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palareti G, Cosmi B, Legnani C, et al. . 
D-dimer testing to determine the duration of anticoagulation therapy. N Engl J Med. 2006;355:1780–1789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17065639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ridker PM, Goldhaber SZ, Danielson E, et al. . 
Long-term, low-intensity warfarin therapy for the prevention of recurrent venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2003;348(15):1425–1434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12601075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siragusa S, Malato A, Anastasio R, et al. . 
Residual vein thrombosis to establish duration of anticoagulation after a first episode of deep vein thrombosis: the duration of anticoagulation based on compression ultrasonography (DACUS) study. Blood. 2008;112:511–515.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18497320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazzolai L, Aboyans V, Ageno W, et al. . 
Diagnosis and management of acute deep vein thrombosis: a joint consensus document from the European Society of Cardiology Working groups of aorta and peripheral vascular diseases and pulmonary circulation and right ventricular function. Eur Heart J. 2018;39:4208–4218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konstantinides SV, Meyer G, Becattini C, et al. . 
2019 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism developed in collaboration with the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Heart J. 2020;41:543–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Akl EA, Ornelas J, et al. . 
Antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest. 2016;149:315–352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middeldorp S, Prins MH, Hutten BA.. 
Duration of treatment with vitamin K antagonists in symptomatic venous thromboembolism. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;CD001367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7074008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25092359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marik PE, Cavallazzi R.. 
Extended anticoagulant and aspirin treatment for the secondary prevention of thromboembolic disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2015;10(11):e0143252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4654552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26587983</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs LG.
Warfarin pharmacology, clinical management, and evaluation of hemorrhagic risk for the elderly. Cardiol Clin. 2008;26:157–167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18406992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Minno A, Frigerio B, Spadarella G, et al. . 
Old and new oral anticoagulants: food, herbal medicines and drug interactions. Blood Rev. 2017;31:193–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin MC, Sussman ES, Feng AY, et al. . 
Hemorrhage risk of direct oral anticoagulants in real-world venous thromboembolism patients. Thromb Res. 2021;204:126–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34198049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz-Gimenez N, Suarez C, Gonzalez R, et al. . 
Predictive variables for major bleeding events in patients presenting with documented acute venous thromboembolism. Findings from the RIETE Registry. Thromb Haemost. 2008;100:26–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18612534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holley AB, King CS, Jackson JL, et al. . 
Different finite durations of anticoagulation and outcomes following idiopathic venous thromboembolism: a meta-analysis. Thrombosis. 2010;2010:540386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3211079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22084660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bova C, Bianco A, Mascaro V, et al. . 
Extended anticoagulation and mortality in venous thromboembolism. A meta-analysis of six randomized trials. Thromb Res. 2016;139:22–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26916292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sindet-Pedersen C, Pallisgaard JL, Olesen JB, et al. . 
Safety and efficacy of direct oral anticoagulants compared to warfarin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism – a systematic review and meta-analysis. Thromb Res. 2015;136:732–738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26277682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mai V, Bertoletti L, Cucherat M, et al. . 
Extended anticoagulation for the secondary prevention of venous thromboembolic events: an updated network meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2019;14:e0214134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6443183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30933993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira NL, Rihal C, Lennon R, et al. . 
Effect of CYP2C19 genotype on ischemic outcomes during oral P2Y12 inhibitor therapy: a meta-analysis. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2021;14(7):739–750.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulman S, Kearon C, Kakkar AK, et al. . 
Extended use of dabigatran, warfarin, or placebo in venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(8):709–718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23425163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Available from: https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00329238?term=NCT00329238&amp;draw=2&amp;rank=1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weitz JI, Lensing AWA, Prins MH, et al. . 
Rivaroxaban or aspirin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2017;376(13):1211–1222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
