<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35034049</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-4521</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>49</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Sexually transmitted diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sex Transm Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Risk of Human Immunodeficiency Virus Acquisition Among High-Risk Heterosexuals With Nonviral Sexually Transmitted Infections: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>383</StartPage>
          <EndPage>397</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>383-397</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/OLQ.0000000000001601</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Nonviral sexually transmitted infections (STIs) increase risk of sexually acquired human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection. Updated risk estimates carefully scrutinizing temporality bias of studies are needed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a systematic review (PROSPERO CRD42018084299) of peer-reviewed studies evaluating variation in risk of HIV infection among high-risk heterosexuals diagnosed with any of: Chlamydia trachomatis, Mycoplasma genitalium, Neisseria gonorrhoeae, Treponema pallidum, and/or Trichomonas vaginalis. We searched PubMed, Web of Science, and Embase databases through December 2017 and included studies where STIs and HIV were assessed using laboratory tests or medical examinations and where STI was diagnosed before HIV. After dual screening, data extraction, and risk of bias assessment, we meta-analytically pooled risk ratios (RRs).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We found 32 eligible studies reporting k = 97 effect size estimates of HIV acquisition risk due to infection with one of the abovementioned STIs. Most data were based on women engaged in sex work or other high-risk occupations in developing countries. Many studies did not measure or adjust for known confounders, including drug injection and condom use, and most were at medium or high risk of bias because of the potential for undetected HIV infection to have occurred before STI infection. Human immunodeficiency virus acquisition risk increased among women infected with any pathogen; the effect was greatest for women infected with Mycoplasma genitalium (RR, 3.10; 95% confidence interval [CI], 1.63-5.92; k = 2) and gonorrhea (RR, 2.81; 95% CI, 2.25-3.50; k = 16) but also statistically significant for women infected with syphilis (RR, 1.67; 95% CI, 1.23-2.27; k = 17), trichomonas (RR, 1.54; 95% CI, 1.31-1.82; k = 17), and chlamydia (RR, 1.49; 95% CI, 1.08-2.04; k = 14). For men, data were space except for syphilis (RR, 1.77; 95% CI, 1.22-2.58; k = 5).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nonviral STI increases risk of heterosexual HIV acquisition, although uncertainty remains because of risk of bias in primary studies.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 American Sexually Transmitted Diseases Association. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Erin K</ForeName>
            <Initials>EK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Philip R. Lee Institute for Health Policy Studies.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Malekinejad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohsen</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Merai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rikita</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Global Health Sciences.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lyles</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cynthia M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of HIV/AIDS Prevention.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sipe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Theresa Ann</ForeName>
            <Initials>TA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of HIV/AIDS Prevention.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>DeLuca</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julia B</ForeName>
            <Initials>JB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of HIV/AIDS Prevention.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ridpath</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alison D</ForeName>
            <Initials>AD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gift</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas L</ForeName>
            <Initials>TL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tailor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amrita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of HIV/AIDS Prevention.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kahn</LastName>
            <ForeName>James G</ForeName>
            <Initials>JG</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Sex Transm Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7705941</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-5717</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>10</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35034049</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/OLQ.0000000000001601</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00007435-202206000-00001</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman L, Rowley J, Vander Hoorn S, et al. Global estimates of the prevalence and incidence of four curable sexually transmitted infections in 2012 based on systematic review and global reporting. PLoS One 2015; 10:e0143304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wasserheit JN. Epidemiological synergy. Interrelationships between human immunodeficiency virus infection and other sexually transmitted diseases. Sex Transm Dis 1992; 19:61–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rottingen JA, Cameron DW, Garnett GP. A systematic review of the epidemiologic interactions between classic sexually transmitted diseases and HIV: How much really is known?Sex Transm Dis 2001; 28:579–597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sexton J, Garnett G, Rottingen JA. Metaanalysis and metaregression in interpreting study variability in the impact of sexually transmitted diseases on susceptibility to HIV infection. Sex Transm Dis 2005; 32:351–357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman EE, Weiss HA, Glynn JR, et al. Herpes simplex virus 2 infection increases HIV acquisition in men and women: Systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal studies. AIDS 2006; 20:73–83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonell C, Hickson F, Beaumont M, et al. Sexually transmitted infections as risk factors for HIV infection among MSMs: Systematic review. Sex Transm Dis 2008; 35:209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boily MC, Baggaley RF, Wang L, et al. Heterosexual risk of HIV-1 infection per sexual act: Systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Lancet Infect Dis 2009; 9:118–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mutua FM, M’Imunya JM, Wiysonge CS. Genital ulcer disease treatment for reducing sexual acquisition of HIV. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2012; 8:CD007933.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilber AM, Francis SC, Chersich M, et al. Intravaginal practices, vaginal infections and HIV acquisition: Systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One 2010; 5:e9119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson LF, Lewis DA. The effect of genital tract infections on HIV-1 shedding in the genital tract: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sex Transm Dis 2008; 35:946–959.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ward H, Ronn M. Contribution of sexually transmitted infections to the sexual transmission of HIV. Curr Opin HIV AIDS 2010; 5:305–310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arora P, Nagelkerke NJ, Jha P. A systematic review and meta-analysis of risk factors for sexual transmission of HIV in India. PLoS One 2012; 7:e44094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houlihan CF, Larke NL, Watson-Jones D, et al. Human papillomavirus infection and increased risk of HIV acquisition. A systematic review and meta-analysis. AIDS 2012; 26:2211–2222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papp JR, Schachter J, Gaydos CA, et al., Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Recommendations for the laboratory-based detection of Chlamydia trachomatis and Neisseria gonorrhoeae—2014. MMWR Recomm Rep 2014; 63(Rr-02):1–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC. 2015 Sexually Transmitted Diseases Treatment Guidelines. CDC; 2015. Available at: https://www.cdc.gov/std/tg2015/default.htm. Accessed June 12, 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melo MG, Sprinz E, Gorbach PM, et al. HIV-1 heterosexual transmission and association with sexually transmitted infections in the era of treatment as prevention. Int J Infect Dis 2019; 87:128–134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li HM, Peng RR, Li J, et al. HIV incidence among men who have sex with men in China: A meta-analysis of published studies. PLoS One 2011; 6:e23431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng Y, Bu K, Li M, et al. Meta-analysis of HIV infection incidence and risk factors among men who have sex with men in China. Zhonghua Liu Xing Bing Xue Za Zhi 2015; 36:752–758.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wald A, Link K. Risk of human immunodeficiency virus infection in herpes simplex virus type 2-seropositive persons: A meta-analysis. J Infect Dis 2002; 185:45–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malekinejad M, Barker EK, Merai R, et al. Risk of HIV acquisition among men who have sex with men infected with bacterial sexually transmitted infections: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sex Transm Dis 2021; 48:e138–e148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions, Version 5.1.0. The Cochrane Collaboration; 2011. Available at: http://www.cochrane-handbook.org. Accessed September 18, 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malekinejad M, Horvath H, Kahn JG, et al. Risk of HIV transmission and acquisition among HIV high-risk populations infected with other sexually transmitted infections. 2018. Available at: https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/PROSPERO/display_record.php?RecordID=84299. Accessed November 5, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>PROSPERO International Prospective Register of Systematic Reviews. Available at: https://www.crd.york.ac.uk/prospero/. Accessed November 25, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>GRADE handbook for grading quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. GRADE Working Group; 2013. Available at: http://www.guidelinedevelopment.org/handbook/. Accessed January 21, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. BMJ 2009; 339:b2535.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tool to Assess Risk of Bias in Cohort Studies. Available at: http://help.magicapp.org/knowledgebase/topics/32139-grade-and-methodology-for-development-of-guideline. Accessed November 25, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>How to rate Risk of bias in Observational studies. Available at: http://help.magicapp.org/knowledgebase/articles/294933-how-to-rate-risk-of-bias-in-observational-studies. Accessed November 25, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>StataCorp. Stata Statistical Software: Release 14.2. College Station, TX: StataCorp LP, 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Yu KF. What's the relative risk? A method of correcting the odds ratio in cohort studies of common outcomes. JAMA 1998; 280:1690–1691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Looker KJ, Elmes JAR, Gottlieb SL, et al. Effect of HSV-2 infection on subsequent HIV acquisition: An updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Infect Dis 2017; 17:1303–1316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
