<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35048169</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>01</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-0350</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
              <Day>20</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Childs Nerv Syst</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Giant cystic hypothalamic hamartoma in an infant associated with persistent syndrome of inappropriate antidiuretic hormone secretion.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00381-021-05439-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A giant hypothalamic hamartoma (GHH) is a rare congenital malformation only reported in a few cases in the literature and is often associated with precocious puberty, gelastic seizures, or less commonly, Pallister-Hall syndrome. Persistent syndrome of inappropriate antidiuretic hormone secretion (SIADH) is very rare in infancy, and most patients with GHH do not develop persistent SIADH, usually only transient electrolyte disturbances postoperatively. Previous cases of GHH have not been associated with persistent derangements in antidiuretic hormone levels.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CASE DESCRIPTION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 7-month-old male infant presented to our hospital with a history of an intracranial cystic lesion diagnosed at 23 weeks gestational age (GA), later impressed as a solid-cystic mass at 37 weeks GA by ultrasound prenatally. Postnatal MRI after birth showed a large mass with a dorsal cyst occupying the hypothalamus, causing hydrocephalus and brainstem compression. The patient started to have subtle seizures on the seventh day after birth and eventually developed dacrystic seizures. Hyponatremia with persistent SIADH was observed at 3 months of age before surgery. He received long-term oral sodium supplementation, polytherapy of anti-epileptic medications, ventriculocystostomy for progressive enlargement of the cystic cavity, and later surgical treatment for disconnection and partial resection which confirmed a histological diagnosis of hypothalamic hamartoma.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this case study, we present a novel association of GHH with persistent SIADH and a rare presentation of a cystic component at the dorsal part of the tumor. Clinicians should be aware of this potential endocrine derangement and provide emergent treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andy Yu-Der</ForeName>
            <Initials>AY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Tufts University School of Medicine, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tai-Tong</ForeName>
            <Initials>TT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Neurosurgery, Department of Neurosurgery, Taipei Medical University Hospital, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Clinical Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hsieh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kevin Li-Chun</ForeName>
            <Initials>KL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Imaging, Taipei Medical University Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Min-Lan</ForeName>
            <Initials>ML</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3125-0056</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Neurology, Department of Pediatrics, Taipei Medical University Hospital, Taipei Medical University, 252 Wuxing St, Taipei, 11031, Taiwan. minlan456@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan. minlan456@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chen</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Taipei Medical University Hospital, Taipei Medical University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Childs Nerv Syst</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8503227</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0256-7040</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dacrystic seizure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Giant hypothalamic hamartoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Newborn</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SIADH</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35048169</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-021-05439-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00381-021-05439-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves C, Barbosa V, Machado M (2013) Giant hypothalamic hamartoma: case report and literature review. Childs Nerv Syst 29(3):513–516</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-013-2022-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guibaud L, Rode V, Saint-Pierre G, Pracros JP, Foray P, Tran-Minh VA (1995) Giant hypothalamic hamartoma: an unusual neonatal tumor. Pediatr Radiol 25(1):17–18</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02020833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cristobal A, Vorona G, Ritter A, Lanni S, Urbine J (2020) Pre- and postnatal MR imaging of an asymptomatic giant hypothalamic hamartoma. Radiol Case Rep 15(8):1250–1255</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radcr.2020.05.041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall JG, Pallister PD, Clarren SK, Beckwith JB, Wiglesworth FW, Fraser FC, Cho S, Benke PJ, Reed SD (1980) Congenital hypothalamic hamartoblastoma, hypopituitarism, imperforate anus and postaxial polydactyly— a new syndrome? Part I: clinical, causal, and pathogenetic considerations. Am J Med Genet 7(1):47–74</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.1320070110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guimiot F, Marcorelles P, Aboura A, Bonyhay G, Patrier S, Menez F, Drouin-Garraud V, Icowick V, Eurin D, Garel C, Moirot H, Verspyck E, Saugier-Veber P, Attie-Bitach T, Picone O, Oury JF, Verloes A, Delezoide AL, Laquerrière A (2009) Giant diencephalic harmartoma and related anomalies: a newly recognized entity distinct from the Pallister-Hall syndrome. Am J Med Genet A 149A(6):1108–1115. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.32859 (PMID: 19449422)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.32859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19449422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Lee D, de Bruin C, Steggerda SJ, Vlaardingerbroek H (2020) Idiopathic SIADH in the premature newborn, a case report. J Neonatal Perinatal Med 13(2):283–285. https://doi.org/10.3233/NPM-180149.PMID:31707375;PMCID:PMC7369120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/NPM-180149.PMID:31707375;PMCID:PMC7369120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31707375</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7369120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zieg J (2017) Pathophysiology of hyponatremia in children. Front Pediatr 5: 213. Published online 2017 Oct 16.  https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2017.00213</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bret J, Skodová I (1986) Ventriculocystostomy. A new method of percutaneous intracranial shunting. Acta Radiol Suppl 369:631–633 (PMID: 2980579)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2980579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Laso E, González ME, León RC, González MD, Rodríguez JE (2007) Giant hypothalamic hamartoma and dacrystic seizures. Epileptic Disord 9(1):90–93. https://doi.org/10.1684/epd.2007.0068 (Epub 2007 Feb 15 PMID: 17307718)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2007.0068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17307718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kahane P, Ryvlin P, Hoffmann D, Minotti L, Benabid AL (2003) From hypothalamic hamartoma to cortex: what can be learnt from depth recordings and stimulation? Epileptic Disord 5(4):205–217 (PMID: 14975789)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14975789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorfer C, Kasprian G, Mühlebner A, Czech T (2011) Giant solid-cystic hypothalamic hamartoma. Case report Neurosurg Focus 30(2):E7. https://doi.org/10.3171/2011.1.FOCUS10240 (PMID: 21284453)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2011.1.FOCUS10240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21284453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JY, Yoon HK, Khang SK (2016) Giant hypothalamic hamartoma associated with an intracranial cyst in a newborn. Ultrasonography 35(4):353–358. https://doi.org/10.14366/usg.15080</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14366/usg.15080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27101982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5040142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prasad S, Shah J, Patkar D, Gala B, Patankar T (2000) Giant hypothalamic hamartoma with cystic change: report of two cases and review of the literature. Neuroradiology 42(9):648–650. https://doi.org/10.1007/s002340000350 (PMID: 11071436)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s002340000350</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11071436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isaacs H Jr (2016) Perinatal (fetal and neonatal) astrocytoma: a review. Childs Nerv Syst 32(11):2085–2096. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00381-016-3215-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-016-3215-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27568373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5086342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen CP (2007) Prenatal diagnosis of arachnoid cysts. Taiwan J Obstet Gynecol 46(3):187–198. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1028-4559(08)60020-0 (PMID: 17962096)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1028-4559(08)60020-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17962096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabel BC, Yoon J, Levy ML, Crawford JR (2014) A diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma in a neonate diagnosed by MRI. BMJ Case Rep 2014:bcr2013202270.  https://doi.org/10.1136/bcr-2013-202270 . PMID: 24448472; PMCID: PMC3902521</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellison DH, Berl T (2007) Clinical practice. The syndrome of inappropriate antidiuresis. N Engl J Med 356(20):2064–2072.  https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMcp066837 . PMID: 17507705</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim DK, Joo KW (2009) Hyponatremia in patients with neurologic disorders. Electrolyte Blood Press 7(2):51–57.  https://doi.org/10.5049/EBP.2009.7.2.51 . Epub 2009 Dec 31. PMID: 21468186; PMCID: PMC3041486</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuli G, Tessaris D, Einaudi S, De Sanctis L, Matarazzo P (2017) Tolvaptan Treatment in children with chronic hyponatremia due to inappropriate antidiuretic hormone secretion: a report of three cases. J Clin Res Pediatr Endocrinol 9(3):288–292.  https://doi.org/10.4274/jcrpe.4531 . Epub 2017 May 17. PMID: 28515029; PMCID: PMC5596813</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
