<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35060207</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>55</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effect of remote limb ischemic post-conditioning on the expression of miR-21-5p/PirB in the brain of rats with focal cerebral ischemia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1105</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1117</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1105-1117</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.15600</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Cerebral ischemia causes great damage to ischemic brain regions. Remote limb post-conditioning (RLIPostC) has neuroprotective effects on cerebral ischemia. Paired immunoglobulin receptor B (PirB) has been confirmed to affect the cerebral ischemia injury. Therefore, this study investigated the mechanism of RLIPostC on cerebral ischemia injury. The middle cerebral artery occlusion (MCAO) model was established in rats, followed by RLIPostC (by blocking the blood flow in the distal limb for 10 min after MCAO, and restored for 10 min, three cycles), or in vivo lentivirus infection of miR-21-5p agomir, sh-PirB and oe-PirB. The locomotor abilities were assessed using the foot fault test and balance beam walking test at 48 h, 7 and 21 days after operation, and neurological function was measured on day 21. The cerebral infarct area, Nissl bodies and the pathology of brain tissues were examined using histological staining, followed by the assessment of miR-21-5p and PirB levels and the binding relationship between miR-21-5p and PirB. miR-21-5p was poorly expressed in MCAO rats. Both RLIPostC and overexpression of miR-21-5p reduced motor dysfunction, neurological function score, cerebral infarction area and brain edema; increased Nissl bodies in MCAO rats and thus alleviated the brain damage caused by cerebral ischemia. RLIPostC promoted miR-21-5p expression. PirB was highly expressed in cerebral ischemia, and miR-21-5p targeted PirB. Overall, RLIPostC promotes miR-21-5p expression and then inhibits PirB to alleviate cerebral ischemia injury, which provides theoretical basis for basic research on motor dysfunction and neuron injury after cerebral ischemia and the development of neuroscience.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yiming</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cerebrovascular Diseases, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jinlan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cerebrovascular Diseases, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xue</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mengzhou</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7462-6634</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cerebrovascular Diseases, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>France</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D035683">MicroRNAs</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C491380">Pirb protein, rat</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011971">Receptors, Immunologic</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C546082">mirn21 microRNA, rat</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002545" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Ischemia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020244" MajorTopicYN="N">Infarction, Middle Cerebral Artery</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057775" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ischemic Postconditioning</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D035683" MajorTopicYN="Y">MicroRNAs</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011971" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Immunologic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015427" MajorTopicYN="Y">Reperfusion Injury</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">PirB</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cerebral ischemia injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">miR-21-5p</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">middle cerebral artery occlusion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">remote limb post-conditioning</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35060207</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.15600</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adelson, J. D., Barreto, G. E., Xu, L., Kim, T., Brott, B. K., Ouyang, Y. B., Naserke, T., Djurisic, M., Xiong, X., Shatz, C. J., &amp; Giffard, R. G. (2012). Neuroprotection from stroke in the absence of MHCI or PirB. Neuron, 73, 1100-1107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, G., Ye, X., Zhang, J., Tang, T., Li, L., Lu, P., Wu, Q., Yu, B., &amp; Kou, J. (2016). Limb remote ischemic postconditioning reduces ischemia-reperfusion injury by inhibiting NADPH oxidase activation and MyD88-TRAF6-P38MAP-kinase pathway of neutrophils. Int J Mol Sci, 17(12), 1971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng, Z., Li, L., Mo, X., Zhang, L., Xie, Y., Guo, Q., &amp; Wang, Y. (2014). Non-invasive remote limb ischemic postconditioning protects rats against focal cerebral ischemia by upregulating STAT3 and reducing apoptosis. Int J Mol Med, 34, 957-966.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng, B., Bai, F., Zhou, H., Zhou, D., Ma, Z., Xiong, L., &amp; Wang, Q. (2016). Electroacupuncture enhances rehabilitation through miR-181b targeting PirB after ischemic stroke. Sci Rep, 6, 38997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gou, X., Zhang, Q., Xu, N., Deng, B., Wang, H., Xu, L., &amp; Wang, Q. (2013). Spatio-temporal expression of paired immunoglobulin-like receptor-B in the adult mouse brain after focal cerebral ischaemia. Brain Inj, 27, 1311-1315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han, D., Wang, J., Wen, L., Sun, M., Liu, H., &amp; Gao, Y. (2021). Remote limb ischemic postconditioning protects against ischemic stroke via modulating microglia/macrophage polarization in mice. J Immunol Res, 2021, 6688053.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández, I. H., Villa-González, M., Martín, G., Soto, M., &amp; Pérez-Álvarez, M. J. (2021). Glial cells as therapeutic approaches in brain ischemia-reperfusion injury. Cells, 10, 1639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, J., Wei, L., Han, Z., &amp; Chen, Z. (2019). Mesenchymal stromal cells-derived exosomes alleviate ischemia/reperfusion injury in mouse lung by transporting anti-apoptotic miR-21-5p. Eur J Pharmacol, 852, 68-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, L., Deng, B., Li, S., Liu, Z., Jiang, T., Xiao, Z., &amp; Wang, Q. (2017). TAT-PEP, a novel blocker of PirB, enhances the recovery of cognitive function in mice after transient global cerebral ischemia. Behav Brain Res, 326, 322-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, X., Zheng, L., Xia, Q., Liu, L., Mao, M., Zhou, H., Zhao, Y., &amp; Shi, J. (2019). A novel cell-penetrating peptide protects against neuron apoptosis after cerebral ischemia by inhibiting the nuclear translocation of annexin A1. Cell Death Differ, 26, 260-275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, D., He, X. B., Wang, Z., Li, C., Gao, B. Y., Wu, J. F., &amp; Bai, Y. L. (2018). Remote limb ischemic postconditioning promotes motor function recovery in a rat model of ischemic stroke via the up-regulation of endogenous tissue kallikrein. CNS Neurosci Ther, 24, 519-527.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, C., Yang, J., Zhang, C., Geng, X., &amp; Zhao, H. (2019). The changes of systemic immune responses during the neuroprotection induced by remote ischemic postconditioning against focal cerebral ischemia in mice. Neurol Res, 41, 26-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Livak, K. J., &amp; Schmittgen, T. D. (2001). Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2(-Delta Delta C(T)) Method. Methods, 25, 402-408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Longa, E. Z., Weinstein, P. R., Carlson, S., &amp; Cummins, R. (1989). Reversible middle cerebral artery occlusion without craniectomy in rats. Stroke, 20, 84-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mo, Y., Yue, E., Shi, N., &amp; Liu, K. (2021). The protective effects of curcumin in cerebral ischemia and reperfusion injury through PKC-theta signaling. Cell Cycle, 20, 550-560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Donnell, M. E., Tran, L., Lam, T. I., Liu, X. B., &amp; Anderson, S. E. (2004). Bumetanide inhibition of the blood-brain barrier Na-K-Cl cotransporter reduces edema formation in the rat middle cerebral artery occlusion model of stroke. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab, 24, 1046-1056.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan, W., Xu, X., Zhang, M., &amp; Song, X. (2021). Human urine-derived stem cell-derived exosomal miR-21-5p promotes neurogenesis to attenuate Rett syndrome via the EPha4/TEK axis. Lab Invest, 101, 824-836.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramagiri, S., &amp; Taliyan, R. (2017). Remote limb ischemic post conditioning during early reperfusion alleviates cerebral ischemic reperfusion injury via GSK-3beta/CREB/BDNF pathway. Eur J Pharmacol, 803, 84-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, B., Xu, J., Zhong, P., &amp; Fang, L. (2021). MiR-125a-5p silencing inhibits cerebral ischemia-induced injury through targeting IGFBP3. Folia Neuropathol, 59, 121-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vinciguerra, A., Cepparulo, P., Anzilotti, S., Cuomo, O., Valsecchi, V., Amoroso, S., Annunziato, L., &amp; Pignataro, G. (2020). Remote postconditioning ameliorates stroke damage by preventing let-7a and miR-143 up-regulation. Theranostics, 10, 12174-12188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, F., Long, G., Zhao, C., Li, H., Chaugai, S., Wang, Y., Chen, C., &amp; Wang, D. W. (2014). Atherosclerosis-related circulating miRNAs as novel and sensitive predictors for acute myocardial infarction. PLoS One, 9, e105734.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, J., Zhang, Y., Xia, J., Cai, T., Du, J., Chen, J., Li, P., Shen, Y., Zhang, A., Fu, B., &amp; Gao, X. (2018). Neuronal PirB upregulated in cerebral ischemia acts as an attractive theranostic target for ischemic stroke. J Am Heart Assoc, 7, e007197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y., Zhang, Z., Zhang, L., Yang, H., &amp; Shen, Z. (2018). RLIPostC protects against cerebral ischemia through improved synaptogenesis in rats. Brain Inj, 32, 1429-1436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, J., Balkaya, M., Beltran, C., Heo, J. H., &amp; Cho, S. (2019). Remote postischemic conditioning promotes stroke recovery by shifting circulating monocytes to CCR2(+) proinflammatory subset. J Neurosci, 39, 7778-7789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu, Y., Zhou, H., Xiong, Y., &amp; Liu, J. (2020). Exosomal miR-199a-5p derived from endothelial cells attenuates apoptosis and inflammation in neural cells by inhibiting endoplasmic reticulum stress. Brain Res, 1726, 146515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, H., Xia, J., Hu, Q., Xu, L., Cao, H., Wang, X., &amp; Cao, M. (2021). Long noncoding RNA XIST promotes cerebral ischemia/reperfusion injury by modulating miR27a3p/FOXO3 signaling. Mol Med Rep, 24, 566.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, H. S., Liu, M. F., Ji, X. Y., Jiang, C. R., Li, Z. L., &amp; OuYang, B. (2019). Gastrodin combined with rhynchophylline inhibits cerebral ischaemia-induced inflammasome activation via upregulating miR-21-5p and miR-331-5p. Life Sci, 239, 116935.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, J. J., Xiao, H., Zhao, W. B., Zhang, X. P., Xiang, Y., Ye, Z. J., Mo, M. M., Peng, X. T., &amp; Wei, L. (2018). Remote ischemic postconditioning for ischemic stroke: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Chin Med J (Engl), 131, 956-965.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, G., Li, M. H., Tudor, G., Lu, H. T., Kadirvel, R., &amp; Kallmes, D. (2015). Limb remote ischemic postconditioning protects cerebral ischemia from injury associated with expression of HIF-1alpha in rats. BMC Neurosci, 16, 97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, G., Li, M. H., Tudor, G., Lu, H. T., Kadirvel, R., &amp; Kallmes, D. (2018). Remote ischemic conditioning in cerebral diseases and neurointerventional procedures: Recent research progress. Front Neurol, 9, 339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
