<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35062045</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0801</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Biomedical chromatography : BMC</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Chromatogr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>HPLC-PDA identification and resolution of rufinamide forced degradation impurities: A congregated chemometric expedite optimization coupled with factorials and desirability.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e5345</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e5345</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bmc.5345</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Rufinamide is used presently to treat Lenaux-Gastaut syndrome. A full factorial design and desirability approach was investigated for the optimization of hydrolytic stress via response surface curves (RSCs). The degradation impurities were identified and resolved using reversed-phase high-performance liquid chromatography (RP-HPLC) on the Qualisil® BDS C<sub>8</sub> column. Acetonitrile-water (29:71, v/v) was optimized for the mobile phase and used at a flow rate of 1.0 ml/min with detection at a wavelength of 230 nm. Rufinamide showed appreciable susceptibility to hydrolysis under acidic and alkaline stress, and substantial degradation in the neutral condition. It degraded much less under oxidative stress. Exposure towards thermal and photolytic stress conditions indicated appreciable stability. The developed method was subjected to validation as per the recommendations of the International Conference on Harmonization. The proposed method showed no influence from the excipients and the degradation products. As well as good precision and accuracy in determination, the method showed a linear response between 2 and 12 μg ml<sup>-1</sup> . The method was extended for determination in a human plasma sample, which resulted in excellent recovery without interference from matrix effects. The combined use of desirability and design for the optimization of acidic and alkaline hydrolytic stress led to simple and rapid analysis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ganorkar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Saurabh B</ForeName>
            <Initials>SB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3924-6265</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, R. C. Patel Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Shirpur, MS, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chaudhari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Suraj R</ForeName>
            <Initials>SR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9778-5478</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, R. C. Patel Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Shirpur, MS, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bobade</LastName>
            <ForeName>Preeti S</ForeName>
            <Initials>PS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Quality Assurance, R. C. Patel Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Shirpur, Dhule, MS, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pawar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sagar H</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, R. C. Patel Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Shirpur, MS, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shirkhedkar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atul A</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, R. C. Patel Institute of Pharmaceutical Education and Research, Shirpur, MS, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Biomed Chromatogr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8610241</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0269-3879</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014230">Triazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>WFW942PR79</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C079703">rufinamide</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002851" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromatography, High Pressure Liquid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056148" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chromatography, Reverse-Phase</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004355" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Stability</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014230" MajorTopicYN="N">Triazoles</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HPLC</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">desirability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forced degradation impurities</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">full factorial design</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rufinamide</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>4</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35062045</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bmc.5345</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annapurna, M., Kumar, B. S., &amp; Srinivas, L. (2012). Stability indicating liquid chromatographic method for the quantitative determination of rufinamide in pharmaceutical dosage forms. Journal of Drug Delivery and Therapeutics, 2, 167-174. https://doi.org/10.22270/jddt.v2i4.253</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annapurna, M. M., Krishna, G. S., Padmakar, B., &amp; Kiran, B. S. (2013). Novel spectrophotometric method for the quantitative analysis of rufinamide in pharmaceutical dosage forms. Chemical Science Transactions, 2, 13-18. https://doi.org/10.7598/cst2013.224</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakshi, M., &amp; Singh, S. (2002). Development of validated stability indicating assay methods-Critical review. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 28, 1011-1040. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0731-7085(02)00047-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Contin, M., Mohamed, S., Candela, C., Albani, F., Riva, R., &amp; Baruzzi, A. (2010). Simultaaneous HPLC-UV analysis of rufinamide, zonisamide, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine monohydroxy derivative and felbamate in deproteinized plasma of patients with epilepsy. Journal of Chromatography B, 878, 461-465. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2009.11.039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gáll, Z., Vancea, S., Dogaru, M. T., &amp; Szilágyi, T. (2013). Liquid chromatography-mass spectrometric determination of rufinamide in low volume plasma samples. Journal of Chromatography B, 940, 42-46. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2013.07.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganorkar, S. B., Dhumal, D. M., &amp; Shirkhedkar, A. A. (2017). Development and validation of simple RP-HPLC-PDA analytical protocol for zileuton assisted with Design of Experiments for robustness determination. Arabian Journal of Chemistry, 10, 273-282. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2014.03.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganorkar, S. B., Heyden, Y. V., Shirkhedkar, A. A., Lokwani, D. K., Dhumal, D. M., &amp; Bobade, P. S. (2020). Pharmaceutical analysis combined with in-silico therapeutic and toxicological profiling on zileuton and its impurities to assist in modern drug discovery. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 179, 112982. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpba.2019.112982</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganorkar, S. B., &amp; Shirkhedkar, A. A. (2017). Design of experiments in liquid chromatography (HPLC) analysis of pharmaceuticals: Analytics, applications, implications and future prospects. Reviews in Analytical Chemistry, 36(3), 20160025. https://doi.org/10.1515/revac-2016-0025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gavan, A., Porfire, A., Marina, C., &amp; Tomuta, I. (2017). Formulation and pharmaceutical development of quetiapine fumarate sustained release matrix tablets using a QbD approach. Acta Pharmceutica, 67, 53-70. https://doi.org/10.1515/acph-2017-0009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>George, N. (2010). Forced degradation studies: Forced degradation as an integral part of HPLC stability-indicating method development. Drug Delivery Technologies, 10, XX.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ICH. (1995). ICH guideline Q2 (R1) Validation of analytical procedures: text and methodology, Step 5, June 1995. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/ich-q2-r1-validation-analytical-procedures-text-methodology (Accessed on 1 February 2022)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain, D., &amp; Basniwal, P. (2013). Forced degradation and impurity profiling: Recent trends in analytical perspectives. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 86, 11-35. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpba.2013.07.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kothare, S., Kluger, G., Sachdeo, R., Williams, B., Olhaye, O., Perdomo, C., &amp; Bibbiani, F. (2017). Dosing considerations for rufinamide in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: Phase III trial results and real-world clinical data. Seizure, 47, 25-33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seizure.2017.02.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kovacs, B., Kantor, L. K., Kroitoru, M. D., Kelemen, E. K., Obreja, M., Nagy, E. E., Székely-szentmiklósi, B., &amp; Gyeresi, A. (2018). Reversed phase HPLC for strontium ranelate: Method development and validation applying experimental design. Acta Pharmaceutica, 68, 171-183. https://doi.org/10.2478/acph-2018-0019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, B. S., Annapurna, M. M., &amp; Pavani, S. (2013). Development and validation of a stability indicating RP-HPLC method for the determination of rufinamide. Journal of Pharmaceutical Analysis, 3, 66-70. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpha.2012.08.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>La Marca, G., Malvagia, S., Filippi, L., Innocenti, M., Rosati, A., Falchi, M., Pellacani, S., Moneti, G., &amp; Guerrini, R. (2011). Rapid assay of rufinamide in dried blood spots by a new liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometric method. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 54, 192-197. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpba.2010.07.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leardi, R. (2009). Experimental design in chemistry: A tutorial. Analytica Chimica Acta, 625, 161-172. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aca.2009.06.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazzucchelli, I., Rapetti, M., Fattore, C., Franco, V., Gatti, G., &amp; Perucca, E. (2011). Development and validation of an HPLC-UV detection assay for the determination of rufinamide in human plasma and saliva. Analytical and Bioanalytical Chemistry, 401, 1013-1021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00216-011-5126-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nancy, F. S. N., Fong, J. S., Morrison, S., Wang, L., &amp; Bena, J. (2016). Lacosamide tolerability in adult patients with partial-onset seizures: Impact of planned reduction and mechanism of action of concomitant antiepileptic drugs. Epilepsy and Behavior, 57, 155-160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patil, M. R., Ganorkar, S. B., Patil, A. S., Shirkhedkar, A. A., &amp; Surana, S. J. (2021a). A converged pharmaceutical analysis supported with hydrotropy &amp; DoE with dual HPTLC and stress studies for estimation of tolvaptan. Microchemical Journal, 167, 106328. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.microc.2021.106328</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patil, M. R., Ganorkar, S. B., Patil, A. S., Shirkhedkar, A. A., &amp; Surana, S. J. (2021b). Hydrotropic solubilization in pharmaceutical analysis: Origin, evolution, cumulative trend and precise applications. Critical Reviews in Analytical Chemistry, 51(3), 278-288. https://doi.org/10.1080/10408347.2020.1718484</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds, D. W., Facchine, K. L., Mullaney, J. F., Alsante, K. M., Hatajik, T. D., &amp; Motto, M. G. (2002). Available guidance, and best practices for conducting forced degradation studies. Pharmaceutical Techniques, 48-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shirkhedkar, A. A., &amp; Chaudhari, S. R. (2021). Exploring an experimental combination of analytical quality by design and green analytical chemistry approaches for development of HPTLC densitometric protocol for the analysis of barnidipine hydrochloride. Biomedical Chromatography, 16, e5244. https://doi.org/10.1002/bmc.5244</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonawane, S., &amp; Gide, P. (2011). Optimization of forced degradation using experimental design and development of a stability-indicating liquid chromatographic assay method for rebamipide in bulk and tablet dosage form. Scientia Pharmaceutica, 79, 85-96. https://doi.org/10.3797/scipharm.1011-06</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonawane, S., &amp; Gide, P. (2013). Study on approaches to expedite and simplify forced degradation of eplerenone. Journal of Liquid Chromatography Related Technology, 36, 2156-2165. https://doi.org/10.1080/10826076.2012.717054</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonawane, S., &amp; Gide, P. (2016). Application of experimental design for the optimization of forced degradation and development of a validated stability-indicating LC method for luliconazole in bulk and cream formulation. Arabian Journal of Chemistry, 9, S1428-S1434. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.arabjc.2012.03.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonawane, S., Jadhav, S., Rahade, P., Chhajed, S., &amp; Kshirsagar, S. (2016). Development and validation of stability-indicating method for estimation of chlorthalidone in bulk and tablets with the use of experimental design in forced degradation experiments. Scientifica, 2016, 1-9. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/4286482</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szabó, Z. I., Székely-Szentmiklósi, B., Deák, B., Székely-Szentmiklósi, I., Kovács, B., Zöldi, K., &amp; Sipos, E. (2016). Study of the effect of formulation variables on the characteristics of combination tablets containing enalapril maleate and indapamide as active substances using experimental design. Acta Pharmceutica, 66, 191-206. https://doi.org/10.1515/acph-2016-0019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The United States Pharmacopeia. (2015). 38 National Formulary 33 (USP 38 NF 33). United States Pharmacopoeial Convention Inc.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vander, Y. V., Nijhuis, A., Smeyers-Verbeke, J., Vandeginste, B. G. M., &amp; Massart, D. L. (2011). Guidance for robustness: Ruggedness tests in method validation. Journal of Pharmaceutical and Biomedical Analysis, 24, 723-753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
