<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35076352</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1875-5941</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>42</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The veterinary quarterly</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Vet Q</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Review on skeletal disorders caused by <i>Staphylococcus</i> spp. in poultry.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>21</StartPage>
          <EndPage>40</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>21-40</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/01652176.2022.2033880</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Lameness or leg weakness is the main cause of poor poultry welfare and serious economic losses in meat-type poultry production worldwide. Disorders related to the legs are often associated with multifactorial aetiology which makes diagnosis and proper treatment difficult. Among the infectious agents, bacteria of genus <i>Staphylococcus</i> are one of the most common causes of bone infections in poultry and are some of the oldest bacterial infections described in poultry. Staphylococci readily infect bones and joints and are associated with bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis (BCO), spondylitis, arthritis, tendinitis, tenosynovitis, osteomyelitis, turkey osteomyelitis complex (TOC), bumblefoot, dyschondroplasia with osteomyelitis and amyloid arthropathy. Overall, 61 staphylococcal species have been described so far, and 56% of them (34/61) have been isolated from clinical cases in poultry. Although <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> is the principal cause of poultry staphylococcosis, other <i>Staphylococcus</i> species, such as <i>S. agnetis, S. cohnii</i>, <i>S. epidermidis, S. hyicus, S. simulans</i>, have also been isolated from skeletal lesions. Antimicrobial treatment of staphylococcosis is usually ineffective due to the location and type of lesion, as well as the possible occurrence of multidrug-resistant strains. Increasing demand for antibiotic-free farming has contributed to the use of alternatives to antibiotics. Other prevention methods, such as better management strategies, early feed restriction or use of slow growing broilers should be implemented to avoid rapid growth rate, which is associated with locomotor problems. This review aims to summarise and address current knowledge on skeletal disorders associated with <i>Staphylococcus</i> spp. infection in poultry.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Szafraniec</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gustaw M</ForeName>
            <Initials>GM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5997-8976</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Veterinary Diagnostics, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences - SGGW, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Szeleszczuk</LastName>
            <ForeName>Piotr</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1830-4232</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Veterinary Diagnostics, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences - SGGW, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dolka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Beata</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8836-5351</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Veterinary Diagnostics, Institute of Veterinary Medicine, Warsaw University of Life Sciences - SGGW, Warsaw, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Vet Q</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7909485</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0165-2176</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002645" MajorTopicYN="N">Chickens</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007794" MajorTopicYN="N">Lameness, Animal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011200" MajorTopicYN="N">Poultry</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011201" MajorTopicYN="Y">Poultry Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Staphylococcal Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013210" MajorTopicYN="N">Staphylococcus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Poultry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Staphylococcus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial chondronecrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chicken</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">femoral head necrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infectious disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lameness</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skeletal disorders</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">welfare</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the authors.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35076352</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8843168</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01652176.2022.2033880</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adhikari B, Tellez-Isaias G, Jiang T, Wooming B, Kwon YM.. 
2020. Comprehensive survey of the litter bacterial communities in commercial turkey farms. Front Vet Sci. 7:596933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7746545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33344533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alabdullah HA, Overgaard E, Scarbrough D, Williams JE, Mohammad Mousa O, Dunn G, Bond L, McGuire MA, Tinker JK.. 
2020. Evaluation of the efficacy of a cholera-toxin-based Staphylococcus aureus vaccine against bovine intramammary challenge. Vaccines. 9(1):6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7824273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33374191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alderson M, Speers D, Emslie K, Nade S.. 
1986. Acute haematogenous osteomyelitis and septic arthritis-a single disease. An hypothesis based upon the presence of transphyseal blood vessels. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 68(2):268–274.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3958014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Algammal AM, Hetta HF, Elkelish A, Alkhalifah DHH, Hozzein WN, Batiha GE-S, El Nahhas N, Mabrok MA.. 
2020. Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA): one health perspective approach to the bacterium epidemiology, virulence factors, antibiotic-resistance, and zoonotic impact. Infect Drug Resist. 13:3255–3265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7519829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33061472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allain V, Mirabito L, Arnould C, Colas M, Le Bouquin S, Lupo C, Michel V.. 
2009. Skin lesions in broiler chickens measured at the slaughterhouse: relationships between lesions and between their prevalence and rearing factors. Br Poult Sci. 50(4):407–417.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19735009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alrubaye AAK, Ekesi NS, Hasan A, Koltes DA, Wideman RF, Rhoads DD.. 
2020. Chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis in broilers: further defining a bacterial challenge model using standard litter flooring and protection with probiotics. Poult Sci. 99(12):6474–6480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7704996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Rubaye AAK, Couger MB, Ojha S, Pummill JF, Koon
JA, IIWideman
RF, Jr, Rhoads DD.. 
2015. Genome analysis of Staphylococcus agnetis, an agent of lameness in broiler chickens. PLOS One. 10(11):e0143336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4659636</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26606420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Rubaye AAK, Ekesi NS, Zaki S, Emami NK, Wideman RF, Rhoads DD.. 
2017. Chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis in broilers: further defining a bacterial challenge model using the wire flooring model. Poult Sci. 96(2):332–340.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27587724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amer M, Elbayoumi K, Girh Z, Mekky H, Rabie N.. 
2017. A study on bacterial contamination of dead in shell chicken embryos and culled one day chicks. Int J Pharm Phytopharmacol Res. 7:5–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreasen CB.
2020. Staphylococcosis. In: Swayne DE, editor. Diseases of poultry. 14th ed. Hoboken (NJ): John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd; p. 995–1003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreasen JR, Andreasen CB, Anwer M, Sonn AE.. 
1993. Heterophil chemotaxis in chickens with natural Staphylococcal infections. Avian Dis. 37(2):284–289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8363494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anyanwu M, Shoyinka S, Ngwu M.. 
2015. Case report of simultaneous occurrence of head swelling and bumble foot in turkey staphylococcosis. Anim Res Int. 11:2035–2040.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Awan M, Matsumoto M.. 
1998. Heterogeneity of staphylococci and other bacteria isolated from six-week-old broiler chickens. Poult Sci. 77(7):944–949.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9657601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bassler AW, Arnould C, Butterworth A, Colin L, De Jong IC, Ferrante V, Ferrari P, Haslam S, Wemelsfelder F, Blokhuis HJ.. 
2013. Potential risk factors associated with contact dermatitis, lameness, negative emotional state, and fear of humans in broiler chicken flocks. Poult Sci. 92(11):2811–2826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24135583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumel J, King A, Breazile J, Evans H, Vanden Berge J, editors.. 
1993. Handbook of avian anatomy: nomina anatomica avium. 2nd ed. Cambridge (MA): Nuttall Ornithological Club.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayyari GR, Huff WE, Norton RA, Skeeles JK, Beasley JN, Rath NC, Balog JM.. 
1994. A Longitudinal study of green-liver osteomyelitis complex in commercial turkeys. Avian Dis. 38(4):744–754.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7702507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benrabia I, Hamdi TM, Shehata AA, Neubauer H, Wareth G.. 
2020. Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA) in poultry species in Algeria: long-term study on prevalence and antimicrobial resistance. Vet Sci. 7(2):54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7356745</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32349228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bentley A, Porter L, Van Blois L, Van Wyk B, Vuong CN, Tellez-Isaias G, Shafer D, Tucker Z, Fraley SM, Hargis BM, et al. . 
2020. A feed restriction milieu for Pekin meat ducks that may improve gait characteristics but also affects gut leakiness. Poult Sci. 99(1):39–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7587728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32416824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bilgili SF, Hess JB, Blake JP, Macklin KS, Saenmahayak B, Sibley JL.. 
2009. Influence of bedding material on footpad dermatitis in broiler chickens. J Appl Poult Res. 18(3):583–589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanco AE, Barz M, Icken W, Cavero D, Mazaheri A, Voss M, Schmutz M, Preisinger R.. 
2016. Twenty years of amyloid arthropathy research in chickens. Worlds Poult Sci J. 72(3):495–508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bogut A, Magryś A.. 
2021. The road to success of coagulase-negative staphylococci: clinical significance of small colony variants and their pathogenic role in persistent infections. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 40(11):2249–2270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8520507</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34296355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradshaw RH, Kirkden RD, Broom D.. 
2002. A review of the aetiology and pathology of leg weakness in broilers in relation to welfare. Avian &amp; Poul Biolog Rev. 13(2):45–103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braga JFV, Silva CC, Teixeira M. d P F, Martins N. R d S, Ecco R.. 
2016. Vertebral osteomyelitis associated with single and mixed bacterial infection in broilers. Avian Pathol. 45(6):640–648.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27315453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brash ML, Charlton BR, Fitz-Coy SH, Fulton RM, Julian RJ, Jackwood MW, Ojkic D, Newman L, Sander JE, Shivaprasad HL.. 
2013. Staphylococcosis. In: Boulianne M, editor. Avian disease manual. 7th ed. Jacksonville (FL): American Association of Avian Pathologists; p. 134–136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bródka K, Kozajda A, Buczyńska A, Szadkowska-Stańczyk I.. 
2012. The variability of bacterial aerosol in poultry houses depending on selected factors. Int J Occup Med Environ Health. 25(3):281–293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22729495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brooks JP, McLaughlin MR, Scheffler B, Miles DM.. 
2010. Microbial and antibiotic resistant constituents associated with biological aerosols and poultry litter within a commercial poultry house. Sci Total Environ. 408(20):4770–4777.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20655094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bui LMG, Hoffmann P, Turnidge JD, Zilm PS, Kidd SP.. 
2015. Prolonged growth of a clinical Staphylococcus aureus strain selects for a stable small-colony-variant cell type. Infect Immun. 83(2):470–481.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4294242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25385795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butterworth A.
1999. Infectious components of broiler lameness: a review. Worlds Poult Sci J. 55(4):327–352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnaghan RB.
1966. Spinal cord compression in fowls due to spondylitis caused by Staphylococcus pyogenes. J Comp Pathol. 76(1):9–14. (66)90042-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5907819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassat JE, Hammer ND, Campbell JP, Benson MA, Perrien DS, Mrak LN, Smeltzer MS, Torres VJ, Skaar EP.. 
2013. A secreted bacterial protease tailors the Staphylococcus aureus virulence repertoire to modulate bone remodeling during osteomyelitis. Cell Host Microbe. 13(6):759–772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721972</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23768499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang BS, Moon JS, Kang H-M, Kim Y-I, Lee H-K, Kim J-D, Lee B-S, Koo HC, Park YH.. 
2008. Protective effects of recombinant staphylococcal enterotoxin type C mutant vaccine against experimental bovine infection by a strain of Staphylococcus aureus isolated from subclinical mastitis in dairy cattle. Vaccine. 26(17):2081–2091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18387721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chavakis T, Wiechmann K, Preissner KT, Herrmann M.. 
2005. Staphylococcus aureus interactions with the endothelium: the role of bacterial "secretable expanded repertoire adhesive molecules" (SERAM) in disturbing host defense systems. Thromb Haemost. 94(2):278–285.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16113816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chénier S, Lallier L.. 
2012. Acantholytic folliculitis and epidermitis associated with Staphylococcus hyicus in a line of white leghorn laying chickens. Vet Pathol. 49(2):284–287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21856871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung AL, Bayer AS, Zhang G, Gresham H, Xiong Y-Q.. 
2004. Regulation of virulence determinants in vitro and in vivo in Staphylococcus aureus. FEMS Immunol Med Microbiol. 40(1):1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14734180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheville NF, Tappe J, Ackermann M, Jensen A.. 
1988. Acute fibrinopurulent blepharitis and conjunctivitis associated with Staphylococcus hyicus, Escherichia coli, and Streptococcus sp. in chickens and turkeys. Vet Pathol. 25(5):369–375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3068894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ciurescu G, Dumitru M, Gheorghe A, Untea AE, Drăghici R.. 
2020. Effect of Bacillus subtilis on growth performance, bone mineralization, and bacterial population of broilers fed with different protein sources. Poult Sci. 99(11):5960–5971.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7647910</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33142513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Claes J, Liesenborghs L, Peetermans M, Veloso TR, Missiakas D, Schneewind O, Mancini S, Entenza JM, Hoylaerts MF, Heying R, et al. . 
2017. Clumping factor A, von Willebrand factor-binding protein and von Willebrand factor anchor Staphylococcus aureus to the vessel wall. J Thromb Haemost. 15(5):1009–1019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6232194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28182324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarke SR, Foster SJ. 
2006. Surface adhesins of Staphylococcus aureus. Adv Microb Physiol. 51:187–224. doi: 10.1016/S0065-2911(06)51004-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-2911(06)51004-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17010697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper JE, Needham JR.. 
1976. An investigation into the prevalence of S aureus on avian feet. Vet Rec. 98(9):172–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1258319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawkins MS, Donnelly CA, Jones TA.. 
2004. Chicken welfare is influenced more by housing conditions than by stocking density. Nature. 427(6972):342–344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14737165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Jong IC, Moya TP, Gunnink H.. 
2011. Simplifying the welfare quality assessment protocol for broilers. Wageningen: Wageningen UR Livestock Research. https://edepot.wur.nl/196648.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26306882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devriese LA.
1980. Pathogenic staphylococci in poultry. Worlds Poult Sci J. 36(4):227–236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devriese LA.
1990. Staphylococci in healthy and diseased animals. Soc Appl Bacteriol Symp Ser. 19 (S19):71S–80S.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2119067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DG SANTE. 
2016. Report from the Commission to the European Parliament and the Council on the impact of genetic selection on the welfare of chickens kept for meat production COM/2016/0182. https://ec.europa.eu/transparency/regdoc/rep/1/2016/EN/1-2016-182-EN-F1-1.PDF.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dinev I.
2009. Clinical and morphological investigations on the prevalence of lameness associated with femoral head necrosis in broilers. Br Poult Sci. 50(3):284–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19637027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dixon LM.
2020. Slow and steady wins the race: the behaviour and welfare of commercial faster growing broiler breeds compared to a commercial slower growing breed. PloS One. 15(4):e0231006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7135253</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolka B, Szeleszczuk P.. 
2012. Enterokokowa choroba zwyrodnieniowa stawów kręgosłupa u kur. Med Weter. 68(3):157–162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dowling PM.
2013. Antimicrobial therapy of selected organ systems. In: Giguère S, Prescott JF, Dowling PM, editors. Antimicrobial therapy in veterinary medicine. 5th ed. Ames, Iowa, US: Wiley-Blackwell; p. 395–419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Droual R, Chin RP, Rezvani M.. 
1996. Synovitis, osteomyelitis, and green liver in turkeys associated with Escherichia coli. Avian Dis. 40(2):417–424.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8790894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durairaj V, Okimoto R, Rasaputra K, Clark FD, Rath NC.. 
2009. Histopathology and serum clinical chemistry evaluation of broilers with femoral head separation disorder. Avian Dis. 53(1):21–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19431999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards HM.
2000. Nutrition and skeletal problems in poultry. Poult Sci. 79(7):1018–1023.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10901205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ekesi NS, Dolka B, Alrubaye AAK, Rhoads DD.. 
2021. Analysis of genomes of bacterial isolates from lameness outbreaks in broilers. Poult Sci. 100(7):101148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34077848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elasri MO, Thomas JR, Skinner RA, Blevins JS, Beenken KE, Nelson CL, Smelter MS.. 
2002. Staphylococcus aureus collagen adhesin contributes to the pathogenesis of osteomyelitis. Bone. 30(1):275–280. (01)00632-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11792597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Maghraby A, Aziz S, Mwafy A.. 
2020. Efficacy of Staphylococcus aureus vaccine in chicken. J World's Poultry Res. 10(2s):203–213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emslie KR, Ozanne NR, Nade SM.. 
1983. Acute haematogenous osteomyelitis: an experimental model. J Pathol. 141(2):157–167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6663384</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Entenza JM, Foster TJ, Ni Eidhin D, Vaudaux P, Francioli P, Moreillon P.. 
2000. Contribution of clumping factor B to pathogenesis of experimental endocarditis due to Staphylococcus aureus. Infect Immun. 68(9):5443–5446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC101814</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10948180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster TJ, Höök M.. 
1998. Surface protein adhesins of Staphylococcus aureus. Trends Microbiol. 6(12):484–488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10036727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster TJ.
2019. The MSCRAMM family of cell-wall-anchored surface proteins of gram-positive cocci. Trends Microbiol. 27(11):927–941.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31375310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fowler VG, Proctor RA.. 
2014. Where does a Staphylococcus aureus vaccine stand?
Clin Microbiol Infect. 20:66–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4067250</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24476315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraimow HS.
2009. Systemic antimicrobial therapy in osteomyelitis. Semin Plast Surg. 23(2):90–99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2884905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20567731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friese A, Schulz J, Zimmermann K, Tenhagen B-A, Fetsch A, Hartung J, Rösler U.. 
2013. Occurrence of livestock-associated methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus in Turkey and broiler barns and contamination of air and soil surfaces in their vicinity. Appl Environ Microbiol. 79(8):2759–2766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623196</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23417001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giraudo AT, Cheung AL, Nagel R.. 
1997. The sae locus of Staphylococcus aureus controls exoprotein synthesis at the transcriptional level. Arch Microbiol. 168(1):53–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9211714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gocsik É, Silvera AM, Hansson H, Saatkamp HW, Blokhuis HJ.. 
2017. Exploring the economic potential of reducing broiler lameness. Br Poult Sci. 58(4):337–347.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28294637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-Martín M, Corbera JA, Suárez-Bonnet A, Tejedor-Junco MT.. 
2020. Virulence factors in coagulase-positive staphylococci of veterinary interest other than Staphylococcus aureus. Vet Q. 40(1):118–131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7178840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32223696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gordon RJ, Lowy FD.. 
2008. Pathogenesis of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus infection. Clin Infect Dis. 46(S5):S350–S359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2474459</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18462090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gornatti-Churria CD, Crispo M, Shivaprasad HL, Uzal FA.. 
2018. Gangrenous dermatitis in chickens and turkeys. J Vet Diagn Invest. 30(2):188–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6505868</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29145799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granquist EG, Vasdal G, de Jong IC, Moe RO.. 
2019. Lameness and its relationship with health and production measures in broiler chickens. Animal. 13(10):2365–2372.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6749567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffiths GL, Hopkinson WI, Lloyd J.. 
1984. Staphylococcal necrosis of the head of the femur in broiler chickens. Aust Vet J. 61(9):293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6517780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hananeh WM, Al-Natour MQ, Alaboudi AR, Abo-Shehada MN, Bani Ismail ZA.. 
2021. Congenital abnormalities in dead-in-shell chicks associated with mixed bacterial infections. Heliyon. 7(2):e06272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893430</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haque MH, Sarker S, Islam MS, Islam MA, Karim MR, Kayesh MEH, Shiddiky MJA, Anwer MS.. 
2020. Sustainable antibiotic-free broiler meat production: current trends, challenges, and possibilities in a developing country perspective. Biology. 9(11):411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7700346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33238534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harry EG.
1967. Some characteristics of staphylococcus aureus isolated from the skin and upper respiratory tract of domesticated and wild (feral) birds. Res Vet Sci. 8(4):490–499. (18)34609-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5183295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauck CR, Ohlsen K.. 
2006. Sticky connections: extracellular matrix protein recognition and integrin-mediated cellular invasion by Staphylococcus aureus. Curr Opin Microbiol. 9(1):5–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16406780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Havenstein G, Ferket P, Qureshi M.. 
2003. Growth, livability, and feed conversion of 1957 versus 2001 broilers when fed representative 1957 and 2001 broiler diets. Poult Sci. 82(10):1500–1508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14601725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Havenstein GB, Ferket PR, Scheideler SE, Larson BT.. 
1994. Growth, livability, and feed conversion of 1957 vs 1991 broilers when fed “typical” 1957 and 1991 broiler diets. Poult Sci. 73(12):1785–1794.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7877934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heidemann Olsen R, Christensen H, Kabell S, Bisgaard M.. 
2018. Characterization of prevalent bacterial pathogens associated with pododermatitis in table egg layers. Avian Pathol. 47(3):281–285.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29517269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hennekinne J-A, De Buyser M-L, Dragacci S.. 
2012. Staphylococcus aureus and its food poisoning toxins: characterization and outbreak investigation. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 36(4):815–836.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22091892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hester PY.
1994. The role of environment and management on leg abnormalities in meat-type fowl. Poult Sci. 73(6):904–915.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8072936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hinshaw WR, McNeil E.. 
1952. Staphylococcosis (synovitis) in turkeys. Poult Sci. 31(2):320–327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howlett CR, Dickson M, Sheridan AK.. 
1984. The fine structure of the proximal growth plate of the avian tibia: vascular supply. J Anat. 139(Pt 1):115–132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1164451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6469851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howlett CR.
1979. The fine structure of the proximal growth plate of the avian tibia. J Anat. 128(Pt 2):377–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1232943</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">438096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huff G, Huff W, Balog J, Rath N.. 
1999. The effect of a second dexamethasone treatment on turkeys previously challenged in an experimental Escherichia coli respiratory model of turkey osteomyelitis complex. Poult Sci. 78(8):1116–1125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10472837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huff GR, Huff WE, Balog JM, Rath NC.. 
2001. Effect of early handling of turkey poults on later responses to multiple dexamethasone-Escherichia coli Challenge. 2. Resistance to air sacculitis and Turkey osteomyelitis complex1. Poult Sci. 80(9):1314–1322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11558917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huff GR, Huff WE, Rath NC, Balog JM.. 
2000. Turkey osteomyelitis complex. Poult Sci. 79(7):1050–1056.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10901209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hulan HW, Proudfoot FG, Ramey D, McRae KB.. 
1980. Influence of genotype and diet on general performance and incidence of leg abnormalities of commercial broilers reared to roaster weight1. Poult Sci. 59(4):748–757.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7375422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Igbokwe I, Adawaren E, Abba Y.. 
2012. Concurrent outbreak of staphylococcal pneumonia with infectious bursal disease in broiler chickens. Comp Clin Pathol. 21(6):1571–1575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jahejo AR, Tian WX.. 
2021. Cellular, molecular and genetical overview of avian tibial dyschondroplasia. Res Vet Sci. 135:569–579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33066991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang S, Yan F-F, Hu J-Y, Mohammed A, Cheng H-W.. 
2021. Bacillus subtilis-based probiotic improves skeletal health and immunity in broiler chickens exposed to heat stress. Animals. 11(6):1494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8224346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34064126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang T, Mandal RK, Wideman RF, Khatiwara A, Pevzner I, Min Kwon Y.. 
2015. Molecular survey of bacterial communities associated with bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis (BCO) in broilers. PLOS One. 10(4):e0124403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4400152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25881241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones PJ, Niemi J, Christensen J-P, Tranter RB, Bennett RM.. 
2019. A review of the financial impact of production diseases in poultry production systems. Anim Prod Sci. 59(9):1585–1597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jordan FTW, Williams NJ, Wattret A, Jones T.. 
2005. Observations on salpingitis, peritonitis and salpingoperitonitis in a layer breeder flock. Vet Rec. 157(19):573–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16272543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Josefsson E, Hartford O, O'Brien L, Patti JM, Foster T.. 
2001. Protection against experimental Staphylococcus aureus arthritis by vaccination with clumping factor A, a novel virulence determinant. J Infect Dis. 184(12):1572–1580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11740733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Josse J, Laurent F, Diot A.. 
2017. Staphylococcal adhesion and host cell invasion: fibronectin-binding and other mechanisms. Front Microbiol. 8:2433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5723312</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29259603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Julian RJ.
2005. Production and growth related disorders and other metabolic diseases of poultry-a review. Vet J. 169(3):350–369.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15848778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung A, Chen LR, Suyemoto MM, Barnes HJ, Borst LB.. 
2018. A Review of Enterococcus cecorum Infection in Poultry. Avian Dis. 62(3):261–271. 10.1637/11825-030618-Review.1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1637/11825-030618-Review.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30339512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Just NA, Létourneau V, Kirychuk SP, Singh B, Duchaine C.. 
2011. Potentially pathogenic bacteria and antimicrobial resistance in bioaerosols from cage-housed and floor-housed poultry operations. Ann Occup Hyg. 56(4):440–449.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22156572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaul MK, Tanwani SK, Sharda R.. 
2001. Preliminary studies on bacterin against gangrenous dermatitis. Indian Vet J. 78:282–285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kestin SC, Gordon S, Su G, Sørensen P.. 
2001. Relationships in broiler chickens between lameness, liveweight, growth rate and age. Vet Rec. 148(7):195–197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11265995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kestin SC, Knowles TG, Tinch AE, Gregory NG.. 
1992. Prevalence of leg weakness in broiler chickens and its relationship with genotype. Vet Rec. 131(9):190–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1441174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kibenge FS, Wilcox GE, Pass DA.. 
1983. Pathogenicity of four strains of staphylococci isolated from chickens with clinical tenosynovitis. Avian Pathol. 12(2):213–220.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18766778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kittelsen KE, David B, Moe RO, Poulsen HD, Young JF, Granquist EG.. 
2017. Associations among gait score, production data, abattoir registrations, and postmortem tibia measurements in broiler chickens. Poult Sci. 96(5):1033–1040.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27965410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klaas IC, Zadoks RN.. 
2018. An update on environmental mastitis: challenging perceptions. Transbound Emerg Dis. 65(Suppl 1):166–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29083115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knowles TG, Kestin SC, Haslam SM, Brown SN, Green LE, Butterworth A, Pope SJ, Pfeiffer D, Nicol CJ.. 
2008. Leg disorders in broiler chickens: prevalence, risk factors and prevention. PLOS One. 3(2):e1545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2212134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18253493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kogut MH.
2013. The gut microbiota and host innate immunity: Regulators of host metabolism and metabolic diseases in poultry?1 1Presented as a part of the Informal Nutrition Symposium “Metabolic Responses to Nutrition and Modifiers” at the Poultry Science Association’s annual meeting in Athens, Georgia, July 9, 2012. J Appl Poult Res. 22(3):637–646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolbjørnsen Ø, David B, Gilhuus M.. 
2011. Bacterial osteomyelitis in a 3-week-old broiler chicken associated with Enterococcus hirae. Vet Pathol. 48(6):1134–1137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21273384</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landman WJM, Bogaard A v d, Doornenbal P, Tooten PCJ, Elbers ARW, Gruys E.. 
1998. The role of various agents in chicken amyloid arthropathy. Amyloid. 5(4):266–278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10036585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landman WJM.
1999. Amyloid arthropathy in chickens. Vet Q. 21(3):78–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10427631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lay DC, Fulton RM, Hester PY, Karcher DM, Kjaer JB, Mench JA, Mullens BA, Newberry RC, Nicol CJ, O'Sullivan NP, et al. . 
2011. Hen welfare in different housing systems. Poult Sci. 90(1):278–294.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J, Zilm PS, Kidd SP.. 
2020. Novel research models for Staphylococcus aureus small colony variants (SCV) development: co-pathogenesis and growth rate. Front Microbiol. 11:321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7058586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32184775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leimer N, Rachmühl C, Palheiros Marques M, Bahlmann AS, Furrer A, Eichenseher F, Seidl K, Matt U, Loessner MJ, Schuepbach RA, et al. . 
2016. Nonstable Staphylococcus aureus small-colony variants are induced by low pH and sensitized to antimicrobial therapy by phagolysosomal alkalinization. J Infect Dis. 213(2):305–313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26188074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linares JA, Wigle WL.. 
2001. Staphylococcus aureus pneumonia in turkey poults with gross lesions resembling aspergillosis. Avian Dis. 45(4):1068–1072.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11785881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lonc E, Plewa K.. 
2009. Microbiological air contamination in poultry houses. Pol J Environ Stud. 19:15–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maali Y, Martins-Simões P, Valour F, Bouvard D, Rasigade J-P, Bes M, Haenni M, Ferry T, Laurent F, Trouillet-Assant S.. 
2016. Pathophysiological mechanisms of Staphylococcus non-aureus bone and joint infection: interspecies homogeneity and specific behavior of S. pseudintermedius. Front Microbiol. 7:1063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27462303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maki JJ, Bobeck EA, Sylte MJ, Looft T.. 
2020. Eggshell and environmental bacteria contribute to the intestinal microbiota of growing chickens. J Anim Sci Biotechnol. 11:60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7288515</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32537141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mandal RK, Jiang T, Al-Rubaye AA, Rhoads DD, Wideman RF, Zhao J, Pevzner I, Kwon YM.. 
2016. An investigation into blood microbiota and its potential association with Bacterial Chondronecrosis with Osteomyelitis (BCO) in Broilers. Sci Rep. 6(1):25882.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4865835</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marek A, Stepień-Pyśniak D, Pyzik E, Adaszek Ł, Wilczyński J, Winiarczyk S.. 
2016. Occurrence and characterization of Staphylococcus bacteria isolated from poultry in Western Poland. Berl Munch Tierarztl Wochenschr. 129(3–4):147–152.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27169153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martland MF.
1984. Wet litter as a cause of plantar pododermatitis, leading to foot ulceration and lameness in fattening turkeys. Avian Pathol. 13(2):241–252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18766841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCullagh JJ, McNamee PT, Smyth JA, Ball HJ.. 
1998. The use of pulsed field gel electrophoresis to investigate the epidemiology of Staphylococcus aureus infection in commercial broiler flocks. Vet Microbiol. 63(2–4):275–281. (98)00240-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9851005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamee PT, McCullagh JJ, Rodgers JD, Thorp BH, Ball HJ, Connor TJ, McConaghy D, Smyth JA.. 
1999. Development of an experimental model of bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis in broilers following exposure to Staphylococcus aureus by aerosol, and inoculation with chicken anaemia and infectious bursal disease viruses. Avian Pathol. 28(1):26–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16147547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNamee PT, Smyth JA.. 
2000. Bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis ('femoral head necrosis') of broiler chickens: a review. Avian Pathol. 29(4):253–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19184815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Middleton JR.
2008. Staphylococcus aureus antigens and challenges in vaccine development. Expert Rev Vaccines. 7(6):805–815.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18665778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller LS, Fowler VG, Shukla SK, Rose WE, Proctor RA.. 
2020. Development of a vaccine against Staphylococcus aureus invasive infections: evidence based on human immunity, genetics and bacterial evasion mechanisms. FEMS Microbiol Rev. 44(1):123–153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31841134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miner ML, Smart RA, Olson AE.. 
1968. Pathogenesis of Staphylococcal synovitis in turkeys: pathologic changes. Avian Dis. 12(1):46–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5643700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misra N, Wines TF, Knopp CL, Hermann R, Bond L, Mitchell B, McGuire MA, Tinker JK.. 
2018. Immunogenicity of a Staphylococcus aureus-cholera toxin A2/B vaccine for bovine mastitis. Vaccine. 36(24):3513–3521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6014625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29739718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreillon P, Entenza JM, Francioli P, McDevitt D, Foster TJ, François P, Vaudaux P.. 
1995. Role of Staphylococcus aureus coagulase and clumping factor in pathogenesis of experimental endocarditis. Infect Immun. 63(12):4738–4743.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC173679</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7591130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moscoso M, García P, Cabral MP, Rumbo C, Bou G.. 
2018. A D-Alanine auxotrophic live vaccine is effective against lethal infection caused by Staphylococcus aureus. Virulence. 9(1):604–620.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5955480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29297750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munger LL, Kelly BL.. 
1973. Staphylococcal granulomas in a Leghorn hen. Avian Dis. 17(4):858–860.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4766570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muszyński S, Tomaszewska E, Kwiecień M, Dobrowolski P, Tomczyk A.. 
2018. Effect of dietary phytase supplementation on bone and hyaline cartilage development of broilers fed with organically complexed copper in a cu-deficient diet. Biol Trace Elem Res. 182(2):339–353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5838127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mutalib A, Miguel B, Brown T, Maslin W.. 
1996. Distribution of arthritis and osteomyelitis in turkeys with green liver discoloration. Avian Dis. 40(3):661–664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8883798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mutalib A, Riddell C, Osborne AD.. 
1983. Studies on the pathogenesis of staphylococcal osteomyelitis in chickens. I. Effect of stress on experimentally induced osteomyelitis. Avian Dis. 27(1):141–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6847538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nääs I, Bueno L, Moura D, Vercellino R, Salgado D.. 
2012. Use of vitamin D to reduce lameness in broilers reared in harsh environments. Rev Bras Ciênc Avícola. 14:159–232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagase N, Sasaki A, Yamashita K, Shimizu A, Wakita Y, Kitai S, Kawano J.. 
2002. Isolation and species distribution of staphylococci from animal and human skin. J Vet Med Sci. 64(3):245–250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11999444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nairn ME, Watson ARA.. 
1972. Leg weakness of poultry-a clinical and pathological characterisation. Aust Vet J. 48(12):645–656.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4576900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nairn ME.
1973. Bacterial osteomyelitis and synovitis of the turkey. Avian Dis. 17(3):504–517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4583954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura K, Shirai J, Imai K, Hihara H, Tanimura N.. 
1997. Outbreak of comb necrosis in layer breeder chickens. Avian Dis. 41(1):252–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9087344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicol CJ.
2013. Welfare issues in commercial broiler production. Poultry Development Review, Roma, Italy: FAO; p. 117–118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nonnenmann MW, Bextine B, Dowd SE, Gilmore K, Levin JL.. 
2010. Culture-independent characterization of bacteria and fungi in a poultry bioaerosol using pyrosequencing: a new approach. J Occup Environ Hyg. 7(12):693–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21058154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onyango LA, Dunstan RH, Roberts TK, Macdonald MM, Gottfries J.. 
2013. Phenotypic variants of staphylococci and their underlying population distributions following exposure to stress. PLOS One. 8(10):e77614.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799968</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24204894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oppliger A, Charrière N, Droz P-O, Rinsoz T.. 
2008. Exposure to bioaerosols in poultry houses at different stages of fattening; use of real-time PCR for airborne bacterial quantification. Ann Occup Hyg. 52(5):405–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2488377</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18497431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orajaka LJE, Mohan K.. 
1985. Aerobic bacterial flora from dead-in-shell chicken embryos from Nigeria. Avian Dis. 29(3):583–589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4074232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orth MW, Cook ME.. 
1994. Avian tibial dyschondroplasia: a morphological and biochemical review of the growth plate lesion and its causes. Vet Pathol. 31(4):403–404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7941228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parte AC, Sardà Carbasse J, Meier-Kolthoff JP, Reimer LC, Göker M.. 
2020. List of Prokaryotic names with Standing in Nomenclature (LPSN) moves to the DSMZ. Int J Syst Evol Microbiol. 70(11):5607–5612. (accessed on 20 November 2021).</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7723251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parveen A, Rahman MM, Fakhruzzaman M, Akter MR, Islam MS.. 
2017. Characterization of bacterial pathogens from egg shell, egg yolk, feed and air samples of poultry houses. Asian J Med Biol Res. 3(2):168–174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patti JM, Bremell T, Krajewska-Pietrasik D, Abdelnour A, Tarkowski A, Rydén C, Höök M.. 
1994. The Staphylococcus aureus collagen adhesin is a virulence determinant in experimental septic arthritis. Infect Immun. 62(1):152–161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC186080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8262622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez K, Patel R.. 
2017. Staphylococcusepidermidis small-colony variants are induced by low pH and their frequency reduced by lysosomal alkalinization. J Infect Dis. 215(3):488–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5853244</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27974434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peton V, Le Loir Y.. 
2014. Staphylococcus aureus in veterinary medicine. Infect Genet Evol. 21:602–615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23974078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinchuk IV, Beswick EJ, Reyes VE.. 
2010. Staphylococcal enterotoxins. Toxins (Basel)). 2(8):2177–2197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3153290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22069679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pondit A, Haque ZF, Sabuj AAM, Khan MSR, Saha S.. 
2018. Characterization of Staphylococcus aureus isolated from chicken and quail eggshell. J Adv Vet Anim Res. 5(4):466–471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6702911</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31453159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poulsen LL, Thøfner I, Bisgaard M, Olsen RH, Christensen JP, Christensen H.. 
2017. Staphylococcus agnetis, a potential pathogen in broiler breeders. Vet Microbiol. 212:1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prisby R, Menezes T, Campbell J, Benson T, Samraj E, Pevzner I, Wideman R.. 
2014. Kinetic examination of femoral bone modeling in broilers. Poult Sci. 93(5):1122–1129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24795304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proctor RA, von Eiff C, Kahl BC, Becker K, McNamara P, Herrmann M, Peters G.. 
2006. Small colony variants: a pathogenic form of bacteria that facilitates persistent and recurrent infections. Nat Rev Microbiol. 4(4):295–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16541137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proctor RA.
2012. Challenges for a universal Staphylococcus aureus vaccine. Clin Infect Dis. 54(8):1179–1186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22354924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pyzik E, Marek A, Stępień-Pyśniak D, Urban-Chmiel R, Jarosz ŁS, Jagiełło-Podębska I.. 
2019. Detection of antibiotic resistance and classical enterotoxin genes in coagulase -negative staphylococci isolated from poultry in Poland. J Vet Res. 63(2):183–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6598191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31276057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rath NC, Bayyari GR, Beasley JN, Huff WE, Balog JM.. 
1994. Age-related changes in the incidence of tibial dyschondroplasia in turkeys. Poult Sci. 73(8):1254–1259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7971668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rayner AC, Newberry RC, Vas J, Mullan S.. 
2020. Slow-growing broilers are healthier and express more behavioural indicators of positive welfare. Sci Rep. 10(1):15151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7494998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32938994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reda A, Amin A, Shiferaw A, Nazir S.. 
2013. Yolk Sac Infection (Omphalitis) in Kombolcha poultry farm, Ethiopia . Am-Eurasian J Sci Res. 8:10–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redi D, Raffaelli CS, Rossetti B, De Luca A, Montagnani F.. 
2018. Staphylococcus aureus vaccine preclinical and clinical development: current state of the art. New Microbiol. 41(3):208–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29874390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly SS, Hudson MC, Kellam JF, Ramp WK.. 
2000. In vivo internalization of Staphylococcus aureus by embryonic chick osteoblasts. Bone. 26(1):63–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10617158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rich M.
2005. Staphylococci in animals: prevalence, identification and antimicrobial susceptibility, with an emphasis on methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus. Br J Biomed Sci. 62(2):98–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15997888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter A, Sting R, Popp C, Rau J, Tenhagen B-A, Guerra B, Hafez HM, Fetsch A.. 
2012. Prevalence of types of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus in turkey flocks and personnel attending the animals. Epidemiol Infect. 140(12):2223–2232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3487481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22321516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riddell C.
1983. Pathology of the skeleton and tendons of broiler chickens reared to roaster weights. I. Crippled chickens. Avian Dis. 27(4):950–962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6651706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson FE, Classen HL, Hanson JA, Onderka DK.. 
1992. Growth performance, feed efficiency and the incidence of skeletal and metabolic disease in full-fed and feed restricted broiler and roaster chickens. J Appl Poult Res. 1(1):33–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodgers JD, McCullagh J, McNamee PT, Bell C, Brice N, Smyth JA, Ball HJ.. 
2003. Recovery of pathogenic Staphylococcus aureus from broiler hatchery air samples. Vet Rec. 153(21):656–657.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14667087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodgers JD, McCullagh JJ, McNamee PT, Smyth JA, Ball HJ.. 
1999. Comparison of Staphylococcus aureus recovered from personnel in a poultry hatchery and in broiler parent farms with those isolated from skeletal disease in broilers. Vet Microbiol. 69(3):189–198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10512043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojas-Núñez I, Moore AF, Lorenzoni AG.. 
2020. Incidence of bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis (femoral head necrosis) induced by a model of skeletal stress and its correlation with subclinical necrotic enteritis. Microorganisms. 8(2):205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7074720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenbach AJF.. 
1884. Mikroorganismen bei den Wund-infections-krankheiten des Menschen. Wiesbaden: J. F. Bergmann.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahu SP, Munro DA.. 
1969. Case report: observations of systemic and localized infection associated with the isolation of Staphylococcus in chickens in North Carolina. Avian Dis. 13(3):684–689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5818069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saint-Cyr MJ, Guyard-Nicodème M, Messaoudi S, Chemaly M, Cappelier J-M, Dousset X, Haddad N.. 
2016. Recent advances in screening of anti-Campylobacter activity in probiotics for use in poultry. Front Microbiol. 7:553.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4885830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27303366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanotra GS, Lund JD, Ersøll AK, Petersen JS, Vestergaard KS.. 
2001. Monitoring leg problems in broilers: a survey of commercial broiler production in Denmark. Worlds Poult Sci J. 57(1):55–69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanz S, Olarte C, Hidalgo-Sanz R, Ruiz-Ripa L, Fernández-Fernández R, García-Vela S, Martínez-Álvarez S, Torres C.. 
2021. Airborne dissemination of bacteria (Enterococci, Staphylococci and Enterobacteriaceae) in a modern broiler farm and its environment. Anim Open Access J MDPI. 11(6):1783.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8232102</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34203681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satterfield WC, O'Rourke KI.. 
1981. Staphylococcal bumblefoot: vaccination and immunomodulation in the early treatment and management. J Zoo Anim Med. 12(3):95–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scanlan CM, Hargis BM.. 
1989. A bacteriologic study of scabby-hip lesions from broiler chickens in Texas. J Vet Diagn Invest. 1(2):170–173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2562194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sergelidis D, Angelidis AS.. 
2017. Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus: a controversial food-borne pathogen. Lett Appl Microbiol. 64(6):409–418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28304109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shepherd EM, Fairchild BD.. 
2010. Footpad dermatitis in poultry. Poult Sci. 89(10):2043–2051.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20852093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith HW.
1954. Experimental staphylococcal infection in chickens. J Pathol Bacteriol. 67(1):81–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13152620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stalker M, Brash M, Weisz A, Ouckama R, Slavic D.. 
2010. Arthritis and osteomyelitis associated with enterococcus cecorum infection in broiler and broiler breeder chickens in Ontario, Canada. J Vet Diagn Invest. 22(4):643–645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stępień-Pyśniak D, Wilczyński J, Marek A, Śmiech A, Kosikowska U, Hauschild T.. 
2017. Staphylococcus simulans associated with endocarditis in broiler chickens. Avian Pathol. 46(1):44–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su G, Sorensen P, Kestin S.. 
1999. Meal feeding is more effective than early feed restriction at reducing the prevalence of leg weakness in broiler chickens. Poult Sci. 78(7):949–955.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10404674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan TW.
1994. Skeletal problems in poultry: estimated annual cost and descriptions. Poult Sci. 73(6):879–882.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8072932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syed MA, Ullah H, Tabassum S, Fatima B, Woodley TA, Ramadan H, Jackson CR.. 
2020. Staphylococci in poultry intestines: a comparison between farmed and household chickens. Poult Sci. 99(9):4549–4557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7598113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32867999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szafraniec GM, Szeleszczuk P, Dolka B.. 
2020. A review of current knowledge on Staphylococcus agnetis in poultry. Animals. 10(8):1421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32823920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tate CR, Mitchell WC, Miller RG.. 
1993. Staphylococcus hyicus associated with Turkey stifle joint osteomyelitis. Avian Dis. 37(3):905–907.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8257392</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thabit AK, Fatani DF, Bamakhrama MS, Barnawi OA, Basudan LO, Alhejaili SF.. 
2019. Antibiotic penetration into bone and joints: an updated review. Int J Infect Dis. 81:128–136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30772469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thøfner ICN, Poulsen LL, Bisgaard M, Christensen H, Olsen RH, Christensen JP.. 
2019. Correlation between footpad lesions and systemic bacterial infections in broiler breeders. Vet Res. 50(1):38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6532141</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31118094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson JK, Gibbs PA, Patterson JT.. 
1980. Staphylococcus aureus in commercial laying flocks: incidence and characteristics of strains isolated from chicks, pullets and hens in an integrated commercial enterprise. Br Poult Sci. 21(4):315–330.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7407665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorp BH, Waddington D.. 
1997. Relationships between the bone pathologies, ash and mineral content of long bones in 35-day-old broiler chickens. Res Vet Sci. 62(1):67–73. (97)90183-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9160428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorp BH, Whitehead CC, Dick L, Bradbury JM, Jones RC, Wood A.. 
1993. Proximal femoral degeneration in growing broiler fowl. Avian Pathol. 22(2):325–342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18671021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thwaites GE, Gant V.. 
2011. Are bloodstream leukocytes Trojan Horses for the metastasis of Staphylococcus aureus?
Nat Rev Microbiol. 9(3):215–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21297670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong X, Rehman MU, Huang S, Jiang X, Zhang H, Li J.. 
2018. Comparative analysis of gut microbial community in healthy and tibial dyschondroplasia affected chickens by high throughput sequencing. Microbiol Pathog. 118:133–139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29555507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trudeau S, Thibodeau A, Côté J-C, Gaucher M-L, Fravalo P.. 
2020. Contribution of the broiler breeders’ fecal microbiota to the establishment of the eggshell microbiota. Front Microbiol. 11:666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7176364</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai S-S, Chen L-J, Shih C-Y, Chang T-C, Chiou M-T, Chuang KP.. 
2015. Joint lesions in Taiwan native colored broiler chicken with natural and experimental Staphylococcus aureus or S. cohnii infection. Taiwan Vet J. 41(04):237–244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venäläinen E, Valaja J, Jalava T.. 
2006. Effects of dietary metabolisable energy, calcium and phosphorus on bone mineralisation, leg weakness and performance of broiler chickens. Br Poult Sci. 47(3):301–310.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16787854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volf J, Crhanova M, Karasova D, Faldynova M, Kubasova T, Seidlerova Z, Sebkova A, Zeman M, Juricova H, Matiasovicova J, et al. . 
2021. Eggshell and feed microbiota do not represent major sources of gut anaerobes for chickens in commercial production. Microorganisms. 9(7):1480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8305510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34361916</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watkins BA, Miller BF.. 
1983. Competitive gut exclusion of avian pathogens by Lactobacillus acidophilus in gnotobiotic chicks. Poult Sci. 62(9):1772–1779.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6415644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weeks CA, Danbury TD, Davies HC, Hunt P, Kestin SC.. 
2000. The behaviour of broiler chickens and its modification by lameness. Appl Anim Behav Sci. 67(1–2):111–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10719194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wideman RF, Al-Rubaye A, Kwon YM, Blankenship J, Lester H, Mitchell KN, Pevzner IY, Lohrmann T, Schleifer J.. 
2015. Prophylactic administration of a combined prebiotic and probiotic, or therapeutic administration of enrofloxacin, to reduce the incidence of bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis in broilers. Poult Sci. 94(1):25–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25577793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wideman RF, Hamal KR, Stark JM, Blankenship J, Lester H, Mitchell KN, Lorenzoni G, Pevzner I.. 
2012. A wire-flooring model for inducing lameness in broilers: Evaluation of probiotics as a prophylactic treatment. Poult Sci. 91(4):870–883.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22399726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wideman RF, Pevzner I.. 
2012. Dexamethasone triggers lameness associated with necrosis of the proximal tibial head and proximal femoral head in broilers. Poult Sci. 91(10):2464–2474.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22991529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wideman RF, Prisby RD.. 
2012. Bone circulatory disturbances in the development of spontaneous bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis: a translational model for the pathogenesis of femoral head necrosis. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne)). 3:183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3550519</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23346077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wideman RF.
2016. Bacterial chondronecrosis with osteomyelitis and lameness in broilers: a review. Poult Sci. 95(2):325–344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26527707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wieliczko A, Król J, Piasecki T, Mazurkiewicz M, Staroniewicz Z.. 
2002. Występowanie i charakterystyka gronkowców wyizolowanych od drobiu. Med Weter. 58(5):348–352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wijesurendra DS, Chamings AN, Bushell RN, Rourke DO, Stevenson M, Marenda MS, Noormohammadi AH, Stent A.. 
2017. Pathological and microbiological investigations into cases of bacterial chondronecrosis and osteomyelitis in broiler poultry. Avian Pathol. 46(6):683–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28669198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilcox CS, Patterson J, Cheng HW.. 
2009. Use of thermography to screen for subclinical bumblefoot in poultry. Poult Sci. 88(6):1176–1180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wise DR.
1971. Staphylococcal osteomyelitis of the avian vertebral column. Res Vet Sci. 12(2):169–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5572538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood AM, MacKenzie G, McGiliveray NC, Brown L, Devriese LA, Baele M.. 
2002. Isolation of Enterococcus cecorum from bone lesions in broiler chickens. Vet Rec. 150(1):27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11822370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright JA, Nair SP.. 
2010. Interaction of staphylococci with bone. Int J Med Microbiol. 300(2–3):193–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2814006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19889575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wyers M, Cherel Y, Plassiart G.. 
1991. Late clinical expression of lameness related to associated osteomyelitis and tibial dyschondroplasia in male breeding turkeys. Avian Dis. 35(2):408–414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1854325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y, Rivas JM, Brown EL, Liang X, Höök M.. 
2004. Virulence potential of the staphylococcal adhesin CNA in experimental arthritis is determined by its affinity for collagen. J Infect Dis. 189(12):2323–2333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15181582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youssef F, Soliman AA, Ibrahim G, Saleh H.. 
2019. Advanced bacteriological studies on bumblefoot infections in broiler chicken with some clinicopathological alteration. Vet Sci Res. 1(1): 1–9. https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Advanced-Bacteriological-Studies-on-Bumblefoot-in-Youssef-Soliman/12cc7117660c83576810ca9cd98171330b4e5bd1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu MW, Robinson FE.. 
1992. The application of short-term feed restriction to broiler chicken production: a review. J Appl Poult Res. 1(1):147–153.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
