<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35085159</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5830</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>33</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Coronary artery disease</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Coron Artery Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Association between coronary artery calcium score and in-stent restenosis after drug-eluting stent implantation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>284</StartPage>
          <EndPage>294</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>284-294</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MCA.0000000000001124</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Coronary artery calcium (CAC) is a modifiable contributor of in-stent restenosis (ISR), but quantitative analyses using a noninvasive approach are limited. We aimed to investigate the associations between CAC score derived from ECG-gated coronary computed tomography angiography (CCTA) or non-gated non-contrast chest computed tomography (NCCT) and ISR.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We included 368 lesions in 194 patients with coronary drug-eluting stent implantations in final analyses. CAC was quantified using the Agatston score. Primary endpoint was ISR, defined as lumen diameter stenosis over 50% at the stent segment or its proximal or distal edges (5-mm segments adjacent to the stent), at angiographic follow-up.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The CAC scores in either CCTA/2.5 mm group (r = 0.7702; P &lt; 0.0001) or NCCT/5 mm group (r = 0.7105; P &lt; 0.0001) were both correlated with in-stent diameter stenosis. The receiver-operating characteristic curve analysis identified a CAC score &gt;245 in CCTA/2.5 mm group as the optimal ISR cutoff (sensitivity, 60.0%; specificity, 83.7%; area under the curve, 0.744; P &lt; 0.001), and &gt;209 in NCCT/5 mm group (sensitivity, 46.7%; specificity, 91.9%; area under the curve, 0.704; P &lt; 0.001). Multivariable logistic regression models indicated a CAC score &gt;245 in CCTA/2.5 mm group and &gt;209 in NCCT/5 mm group independently associated with an 8.46- and 21.89-fold increase in ISR, respectively (all P &lt; 0.01).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Either a CAC score &gt;245 in CCTA/2.5 mm or &gt;209 in NCCT/5 mm was significantly associated with increased risk in ISR.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaowen</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ke</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaoxiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wentao</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Weifeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yue</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yipeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Qiu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xingbiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hongyu</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lisheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Linghong</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ben</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Coron Artery Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9011445</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0954-6928</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>SY7Q814VUP</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D002118">Calcium</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002118" MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003251" MajorTopicYN="N">Constriction, Pathologic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017023" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Angiography</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D023903" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coronary Restenosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003331" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Vessels</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054855" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug-Eluting Stents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062645" MajorTopicYN="Y">Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35085159</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MCA.0000000000001124</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00019501-202206000-00005</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torrado J, Buckley L, Durán A, Trujillo P, Toldo S, Valle Raleigh J, et al. Restenosis, stent thrombosis, and bleeding complications: navigating between scylla and charybdis. J Am Coll Cardiol 2018; 71:1676–1695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moussa ID, Mohananey D, Saucedo J, Stone GW, Yeh RW, Kennedy KF, et al. Trends and outcomes of restenosis after coronary stent implantation in the United States. J Am Coll Cardiol 2020; 76:1521–1531.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dangas GD, Claessen BE, Caixeta A, Sanidas EA, Mintz GS, Mehran R. In-stent restenosis in the drug-eluting stent era. J Am Coll Cardiol 2010; 56:1897–1907.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henneke KH, Regar E, König A, Werner F, Klauss V, Metz J, et al. Impact of target lesion calcification on coronary stent expansion after rotational atherectomy. Am Heart J 1999; 137:93–99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujino A, Mintz GS, Matsumura M, Lee T, Kim SY, Hoshino M, et al. A new optical coherence tomography-based calcium scoring system to predict stent underexpansion. EuroIntervention 2018; 13:e2182–e2189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X, Matsumura M, Mintz GS, Lee T, Zhang W, Cao Y, et al. In vivo calcium detection by comparing optical coherence tomography, intravascular ultrasound, and angiography. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging 2017; 10:869–879.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maejima N, Hibi K, Saka K, Akiyama E, Konishi M, Endo M, et al. Relationship between thickness of calcium on optical coherence tomography and crack formation after balloon dilatation in calcified plaque requiring rotational atherectomy. Circ J 2016; 80:1413–1419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubo T, Shimamura K, Ino Y, Yamaguchi T, Matsuo Y, Shiono Y, et al. Superficial calcium fracture after PCI as assessed by OCT. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging 2015; 8:1228–1229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agatston AS, Janowitz WR, Hildner FJ, Zusmer NR, Viamonte M Jr, Detrano R. Quantification of coronary artery calcium using ultrafast computed tomography. J Am Coll Cardiol 1990; 15:827–832.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanabe K, Kishi S, Aoki J, Tanimoto S, Onuma Y, Yachi S, et al. Impact of coronary calcium on outcome following sirolimus-eluting stent implantation. Am J Cardiol 2011; 108:514–517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekimoto T, Akutsu Y, Hamazaki Y, Sakai K, Kosaki R, Yokota H, et al. Regional calcified plaque score evaluated by multidetector computed tomography for predicting the addition of rotational atherectomy during percutaneous coronary intervention. J Cardiovasc Comput Tomogr 2016; 10:221–228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin JM, Kim TH, Kim JY, Park CH. Coronary artery calcium scoring on non-gated, non-contrast chest computed tomography (CT) using wide-detector, high-pitch and fast gantry rotation: comparison with dedicated calcium scoring CT. J Thorac Dis 2020; 12:5783–5793.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehran R, Dangas G, Abizaid AS, Mintz GS, Lansky AJ, Satler LF, et al. Angiographic patterns of in-stent restenosis: classification and implications for long-term outcome. Circulation 1999; 100:1872–1878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Windecker S, Serruys PW, Wandel S, Buszman P, Trznadel S, Linke A, et al. Biolimus-eluting stent with biodegradable polymer versus sirolimus-eluting stent with durable polymer for coronary revascularisation (LEADERS): a randomised non-inferiority trial. Lancet 2008; 372:1163–1173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone GW, Ellis SG, Cox DA, Hermiller J, O’Shaughnessy C, Mann JT, et al.; TAXUS-IV Investigators. A polymer-based, paclitaxel-eluting stent in patients with coronary artery disease. N Engl J Med 2004; 350:221–231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morice MC, Colombo A, Meier B, Serruys P, Tamburino C, Guagliumi G, et al.; REALITY Trial Investigators. Sirolimus- vs paclitaxel-eluting stents in de novo coronary artery lesions: the REALITY trial: a randomized controlled trial. JAMA 2006; 295:895–904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen LO, Vikman S, Antonsen L, Kosonen P, Niemelä M, Christiansen EH, et al. Intravascular ultrasound assessment of minimum lumen area and intimal hyperplasia in in-stent restenosis after drug-eluting or bare-metal stent implantation. The Nordic Intravascular Ultrasound Study (NIVUS). Cardiovasc Revasc Med 2017; 18:577–582.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimoto H, Nakamura M, Yokoi H. Impact of calcification on the long-term outcomes of sirolimus-eluting stent implantation: subanalysis of the Cypher Post-Marketing Surveillance Registry. Circ J 2012; 76:57–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie X, Zhao Y, de Bock GH, de Jong PA, Mali WP, Oudkerk M, Vliegenthart R. Validation and prognosis of coronary artery calcium scoring in nontriggered thoracic computed tomography: systematic review and meta-analysis. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging 2013; 6:514–521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jørgensen E, Kelbaek H, Helqvist S, Jensen GV, Saunamäki K, Kastrup J, et al. Predictors of coronary in-stent restenosis: importance of angiotensin-converting enzyme gene polymorphism and treatment with angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors. J Am Coll Cardiol 2001; 38:1434–1439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amemiya K, Yamamoto MH, Maehara A, Oyama Y, Igawa W, Ono M, et al. Effect of cutting balloon after rotational atherectomy in severely calcified coronary artery lesions as assessed by optical coherence tomography. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv 2019; 94:936–944.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-Wahab M, Toelg R, Byrne RA, Geist V, El-Mawardy M, Allali A, et al. High-speed rotational atherectomy versus modified balloons prior to drug-eluting stent implantation in severely calcified coronary lesions. Circ Cardiovasc Interv 2018; 11:e007415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redfors B, Sharma SK, Saito S, Kini AS, Lee AC, Moses JW, et al. Novel micro crown orbital atherectomy for severe lesion calcification: Coronary Orbital Atherectomy System Study (COAST). Circ Cardiovasc Interv 2020; 13:e008993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ojeda S, Azzalini L, Suárez de Lezo J, Johal GS, González R, Barman N, et al. Excimer laser coronary atherectomy for uncrossable coronary lesions. A multicenter registry. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv 2021; 98:1241–1249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill JM, Kereiakes DJ, Shlofmitz RA, Klein AJ, Riley RF, Price MJ, et al.; Disrupt CAD III Investigators. Intravascular lithotripsy for treatment of severely calcified coronary artery disease. J Am Coll Cardiol 2020; 76:2635–2646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
