<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35081095</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-0315</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medicine and science in sports and exercise</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Med Sci Sports Exerc</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Shoulder Pain, Function, and Ultrasound-Determined Structure in Elite Wheelchair-Using Para Athletes: An Observational Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>896</StartPage>
          <EndPage>904</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>896-904</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002875</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to determine the relationship between shoulder pain, physical examination, and tissue pathology in manual wheelchair users competing in elite sport.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eighty elite para athletes who used a manual wheelchair for daily mobility were recruited from international track (n = 40), field (n = 19), and powerlifting (n = 21) competitions. Athletes were surveyed regarding shoulder pain history and symptoms (Wheelchair User's Shoulder Pain Index (WUSPI)), whereas independent blind observers measured signs (Physical Examination of the Shoulder Scale (PESS)) and tissue pathology (Ultrasound Shoulder Pathology Rating Scale (USPRS)). Relationships between measures for the total cohort and for subgroups defined by sporting discipline were calculated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A large proportion of athletes reported a history of upper limb pain (39% dominant and 35% nondominant). For the total cohort, WUSPI score was 22.3 ± 26.9, PESS score was 7.4 ± 6.7, and USPRS score was 5.2 ± 4.0. There were no USPRS score differences between athlete subgroups; however, track athletes had lower WUSPI and PESS scores, especially compared with field athletes. The first principal component explained most of the variance in the WUSPI and PESS, which were strongly correlated (r = 0.71), and the second orthogonal component explained the USPRS, which did not correlate with either the PESS (r = 0.21) or WUSPI (r = 0.20). Subgroup analysis showed that track athletes had lower symptom scores for a given physical examination score.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Elite para athletes who use manual wheelchairs for daily mobility have a high prevalence of shoulder symptoms, positive signs on physical examination, and ultrasound-determined tissue pathology. Ultrasound-determined tissue pathology does not correlate with symptoms or signs. This information can help to guide clinicians in managing shoulder problems in this athlete population at high risk of injury.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by the American College of Sports Medicine.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Blauwet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cheri A</ForeName>
            <Initials>CA</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chakraverty</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julian</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University Hospitals of Bristol &amp; Weston NHS Foundation Trust, Bristol, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Derman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wayne</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Idrisova</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guzel</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>English Institute of Sport, Manchester Institute of Health and Performance, Manchester, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stuart C</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sport and Exercise Medicine, Queen Mary University of London, London, UNITED KINGDOM.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morrissey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dylan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Webborn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nick</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Med Sci Sports Exerc</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8005433</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0195-9131</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056352" MajorTopicYN="N">Athletes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000080050" MajorTopicYN="Y">Para-Athletes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012782" MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020069" MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder Pain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014910" MajorTopicYN="Y">Wheelchairs</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35081095</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000002875</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00005768-202206000-00002</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krahn GL, Walker DK, Correa-De-Araujo R. Persons with disabilities as an unrecognized health disparity population. Am J Public Health. 2015;105(2 Suppl):S198–206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blauwet CA, Iezzoni LI. From the Paralympics to public health: increasing physical activity through legislative and policy initiatives. PM R. 2014;6(8 Suppl):S4–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayley JC, Cochran TP, Sledge CB. The weight-bearing shoulder. The impingement syndrome in paraplegics. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1987;69(5):676–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyson-Hudson TA, Kirshblum SC. Shoulder pain in chronic spinal cord injury, part I: epidemiology, etiology, and pathomechanics. J Spinal Cord Med. 2004;27(1):4–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis KA, Black K. Shoulder pain in female wheelchair basketball players. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1999;29(4):225–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soo Hoo JA, Latzka E, Harrast MA. A descriptive study of self-reported injury in non-elite adaptive athletes. PM R. 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derman W, Schwellnus MP, Jordaan E, et al. Sport, sex and age increase risk of illness at the Rio 2016 Summer Paralympic Games: a prospective cohort study of 51 198 athlete days. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(1):17–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willick SE, Webborn N, Emery C, et al. The epidemiology of injuries at the London 2012 Paralympic Games. Br J Sports Med. 2013;47(7):426–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akbar M, Brunner M, Ewerbeck V, et al. Do overhead sports increase risk for rotator cuff tears in wheelchair users?Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015;96(3):484–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blauwet CA, Cushman D, Emery C, et al. Risk of injuries in Paralympic track and field differs by impairment and event discipline: a prospective cohort study at the London 2012 Paralympic Games. Am J Sports Med. 2016;44(6):1455–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boninger ML, Towers JD, Cooper RA, et al. Shoulder imaging abnormalities in individuals with paraplegia. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2001;38(4):401–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobedo EM, Hunter JC, Hollister MC, et al. MR imaging of rotator cuff tears in individuals with paraplegia. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 1997;168(4):919–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kivimaki J, Ahoniemi E. Ultrasonographic findings in shoulders of able-bodied, paraplegic and tetraplegic subjects. Spinal Cord. 2008;46(1):50–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brose SW, Boninger ML, Fullerton B, et al. Shoulder ultrasound abnormalities, physical examination findings, and pain in manual wheelchair users with spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;89(11):2086–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finley M, Ebaugh D, Trojian T. Agreement of musculoskeletal ultrasound and clinical assessment of shoulder impairment in manual wheelchair users with various duration of spinal cord injury. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2018;99(4):615–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fullerton HD, Borckardt JJ, Alfano AP. Shoulder pain: a comparison of wheelchair athletes and nonathletic wheelchair users. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2003;35(12):1958–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geneen LJ, Moore RA, Clarke C, et al. Physical activity and exercise for chronic pain in adults: an overview of Cochrane reviews. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;1(1):CD011279.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis KA, Roach KE, Applegate EB, et al. Reliability and validity of the Wheelchair User’s Shoulder Pain Index (WUSPI). Paraplegia. 1995;33(10):595–601.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis KA, Roach KE, Applegate EB, et al. Development of the Wheelchair User’s Shoulder Pain Index (WUSPI). Paraplegia. 1995;33(5):290–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mair P, Wilcox R. Robust statistical methods in R using the WRS2 package. Behav Res Methods. 2020;52(2):464–88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilcox RR. Introduction to Robust Estimation and Hypothesis Testing. 3rd ed. Waltham (MA): Elsevier; 2012. 713 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rousselet GA, Pernet CR, Wilcox RR. Beyond differences in means: robust graphical methods to compare two groups in neuroscience. Eur J Neurosci. 2017;46(2):1738–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hogaboom NS, Worobey LA, Boninger ML. Transfer technique is associated with shoulder pain and pathology in people with spinal cord injury: a cross-sectional investigation. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2016;97(10):1770–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason BS, Vegter RJK, Paulson TAW, et al. Bilateral scapular kinematics, asymmetries and shoulder pain in wheelchair athletes. Gait Posture. 2018;65:151–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ract I, Meadeb JM, Mercy G, et al. A review of the value of MRI signs in low back pain. Diagn Interv Imaging. 2015;96(3):239–49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McAuliffe S, McCreesh K, Culloty F, et al. Can ultrasound imaging predict the development of Achilles and patellar tendinopathy? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50(24):1516–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strakowski J, Visco C. Diagnostic and therapeutic musculoskeletal ultrasound applications of the shoulder. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(1):1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
