<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35088429</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2265</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>96</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical endocrinology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>TSH receptor specific monoclonal autoantibody K1-70<sup>TM</sup> targeting of the TSH receptor in subjects with Graves' disease and Graves' orbitopathy-Results from a phase I clinical trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>878</StartPage>
          <EndPage>887</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>878-887</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cen.14681</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In Graves' disease (GD), autoantibodies to the thyroid stimulating hormone receptor (TSHR) cause hyperthyroidism. The condition is often associated with eye signs including proptosis, oedema, and diplopia (collectively termed Graves' orbitopathy [GO]). The safety profile of K1-70<sup>TM</sup> (a human monoclonal TSHR specific autoantibody, which blocks ligand binding and stimulation of the receptor) in patients with GD was evaluated in a phase I clinical trial.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eighteen GD patients stable on antithyroid drug medication received a single intramuscular (IM) or intravenous (IV) dose of K1-70<sup>TM</sup> during an open label phase I ascending dose, safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic (PD) study. Immunogenic effects of K1-70<sup>TM</sup> were also determined.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">K1-70<sup>TM</sup> was well-tolerated in all subjects at all doses and no significant immunogenic response was observed. There were no deaths or serious adverse events. Increased systemic exposure to K1-70<sup>TM</sup> was observed following a change to IV dosing, indicating this was the correct dosage route. Expected PD effects occurred after a single IM dose of 25 mg or single IV dose of 50 mg or 150 mg with fT3, fT4, and TSH levels progressing into hypothyroid ranges. There were also clinically significant improvements in symptoms of both GD (reduced tremor, improved sleep, improved mental focus, reduced toilet urgency) and GO (reduced exophthalmos measurements, reduced photosensitivity).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">K1-70<sup>TM</sup> was safe, well tolerated and produced the expected PD effects with no immunogenic responses. It shows considerable promise as a new drug to block the actions of thyroid stimulators on the TSHR.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 AV7 Limited and RSR Limited. Clinical Endocrinology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Furmaniak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jadwiga</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2623-1128</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AV7 Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>RSR Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sanders</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jane</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AV7 Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>RSR Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sanders</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>RSR Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yang</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>RSR Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rees Smith</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bernard</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AV7 Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>RSR Limited, FIRS Laboratories, Parc Ty Glas, Cardiff, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D017426">Clinical Trial, Phase I</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Endocrinol (Oxf)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0346653</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0300-0664</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013956">Antithyroid Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011989">Receptors, Thyrotropin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013956" MajorTopicYN="N">Antithyroid Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006111" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graves Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D049970" MajorTopicYN="Y">Graves Ophthalmopathy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011989" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Thyrotropin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Graves' disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Graves' ophthalmopathy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune diseases</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperthyroidism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyroid diseases</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>57</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35088429</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cen.14681</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rees Smith B, McLachlan SM, Furmaniak J. Autoantibodies to the thyrotropin receptor. Endocr Rev. 1988;9(1):106-121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furmaniak J, Sanders J, Núñez Miguel R, et al. Mechanisms of Action of TSHR Autoantibodies. Horm Metab Res. 2015;47(10):735-752.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lane LC, Cheetham TD, Perros P, Pearce SHS. New therapeutic horizons for Graves' hyperthyroidism. Endocr Rev. 2020;41:873-884.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nalla P, Young S, Sanders J, et al. Thyrotrophin receptor antibody concentration and activity, several years after treatment for Graves' disease. Clin Endocrinol. 2019;90:369-374.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandai S, Okamura K, Fujikawa M, Sato K, Ikenoue H, Kitazono T. The long-term follow-up of patients with thionamide-treated Graves' hyperthyroidism. Endocr J. 2019;66:535-545.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartalena L, Baldeschi L, Boboridis K, et al. The 2016 European Thyroid Association/European Group on Graves' orbitopathy guidelines for the management of Graves' orbitopathy. Eur Thyroid J. 2016;(5):9-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Genere N, Stan MN. Current and emerging treatment strategies for Graves' orbitopathy. Drugs. 2019;79:109-124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans M, Sanders J, Tagami T, et al. Monoclonal autoantibodies to the TSH receptor, one with stimulating activity and one with blocking activity, obtained from the same blood sample: monoclonal autoantibodies to the TSH receptor. Clin Endocrinol. 2010;73:404-412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stan MN, Salvi M. Rituximab therapy for Graves' orbitopathy-lessons from randomized control trials. Eur J Endocrinol. 2017;176:R101-109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venkiteshwaran A. Tocilizumab. Mabs. 2009;1:432-438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winn BJ, Kersten RC. Teprotumumab-interpreting the clinical trials in the context of thyroid eye disease pathogenesis and current therapies. Ophthalmology. 2021:28. doi:10.1016/j.ophtha.2021.04.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearce SHS, Dayan C, Wraith DC, et al. Antigen-specific immunotherapy with thyrotropin receptor peptides in Graves' hyperthyroidism: a phase I study. Thyroid. 2019;29:1003-1011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furmaniak J, Sanders J, Young S, et al. In vivo effects of a human thyroid-stimulating monoclonal autoantibody (M22) and a human thyroid-blocking autoantibody (K1-70). Autoimmun Highlights. 2012;3:19-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furmaniak J, Sanders J, Clark J, et al. Preclinical studies on the toxicology, pharmacokinetics and safety of K1-70™ a human monoclonal autoantibody to the TSH receptor with TSH antagonist activity. Autoimmun Highlights. 2019;10:11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WMA-The World Medical Association-WMA Declaration of Helsinki - Ethical Principles for Medical Research Involving Human Subjects. https://www.wma.net/policies-post/wma-declaration-of-helsinki-ethical-principles-for-medical-research-involving-human-subjects. accessed 12 Aug 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ICH E6 (R2) Good clinical practice. European Medicines Agency 2018. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/ich-e6-r2-good-clinical-practice. accessed 12 Aug 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AV7 Limited. K1-70 - A Phase I, Single Ascending Intramuscular Dose or Single Ascending Intravenous Dose, Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Study in Subjects With Graves' Disease. Report No.: NCT02904330. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02904330. accessed 10 Aug 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estimating the Maximum Safe Starting Dose in Initial Clinical Trials for Therapeutics in Adult Healthy Volunteers. U.S. Food and Drug Administration https://www.fda.gov/regulatory-information/search-fda-guidance-documents/estimating-maximum-safe-starting-dose-initial-clinical-trials-therapeutics-adult-healthy-volunteers. accessed 28 Jul 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>RSR Limited In Vitro Diagnostics. Manufacturer of Medical Diagnostic Devices, Reagents &amp; Kits for the Test and Diagnosis of Autoimmune Diseases. http://www.rsrltd.com accessed 22 Jul 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>https://www.regulations.gov/docket/FDA-2009-D-0539. accessed 25 Aug 2021. ‘Immunogenicity Testing of Therapeutic Protein Products - Developing and Validating Assays for Anti-Drug Antibody Detection’.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hypothyroidism. British Thyroid Foundation. https://www.btf-thyroid.org/hypothyroidism-leaflet. accessed 12 Aug 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang TH, Jung ST. Boosting therapeutic potency of antibodies by taming Fc domain functions. Exp Mol Med. 2019;51:138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryder M, Wentworth M, Algeciras-Schimnich A, et al. Blocking the thyrotropin receptor with K1-70 in a patient with follicular thyroid cancer, Graves' disease, and Graves' ophthalmopathy. Thyroid. 2021;31(10):1597-1602. doi:10.1089/thy.2021.0053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen H, Mester T, Raychaudhuri N, et al. Teprotumumab, an IGF-1R blocking monoclonal antibody inhibits TSH and IGF-1 action in fibroblasts. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2014;99(9):E1635-E1640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA Approves TEPEZZATM (teprotumumab-trbw) for the Treatment of Thyroid Eye Disease (TED). Horizon Therapeutics plc. https://ir.horizontherapeutics.com/news-releases/news-release-details/fda-approves-tepezzatm-teprotumumab-trbw-treatment-thyroid-eye. accessed 2 Jul 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith TJ, Kahaly GJ, Ezra DG, et al. Teprotumumab for thyroid-associated ophthalmopathy. N Engl J Med. 2017;376:1748-1761.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bednarczuk T, Pearce SH. The knowns and unknowns of teprotumumab for thyroid eye disease. Lancet Diabetes &amp; Endocrinol. 2021;9:323-325.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belinsky I, Creighton FX, Mahoney N, et al. Teprotumumab and hearing loss: Case series and proposal for audiologic monitoring. Opthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg. 2021;38(1):73-78. doi:10.1097/IOP.0000000000001995</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chern A, Glass LRD, Gudis DA. Thyroid eye disease, teprotumumab, and hearing loss: An evolving role for otolarnyngologists. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2021;165(6):757-758. doi:10.1177/01945998211004240</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Highland J, Gordon S, Reddy D, et al. Ototoxicity and teprotumumab. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol. 2021. online ahead of print. doi:10.1177/00034894211042740</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoang TD, Nguyen NT, Chou E, et al. Rapidly progressive cognitive decline associated with teprotumumab in thyroid eye disease. BMJ Case Rep. 2021;14:e242153.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartalena L, Wiersinga WM. Proposal for standardization of primary and secondary outcomes in patients with active, moderate-to-severe Graves' orbitopathy. Eur Thyroid J. 2020;9:3-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
