<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35093999</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Association Between Real-time Polymerase Chain Reaction Cycle Threshold Value and Clinical Severity in Neonates and Infants Infected With Bordetella pertussis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>388</StartPage>
          <EndPage>393</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>388-393</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003471</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is highly sensitive and is thus the standard method for diagnosing pertussis. Real-time PCR is widely used because of its accuracy and the simplicity of the simultaneous cycle threshold (Ct) value, which represents the copy numbers of the target gene. Little is known of the association of Ct value with pertussis severity in neonates and infants.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study determined Ct values in neonates and infants diagnosed with pertussis by real-time PCR using nasopharyngeal samples at Vietnam National Children's Hospital in Hanoi in 2017 and 2019. The association of disease severity and clinical parameters were analyzed using univariate and multivariate analyses.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We evaluated 108 patients with pertussis [median age: 63 days, interquartile range (IQR): 41-92 days]. Only 6/108 (6%) received at least 1 dose of a pertussis-containing vaccine. Among them, 24 (22.2%) had severe disease requiring care in a pediatric intensive care unit, 16 (13.8%) required mechanical ventilation, and 3 (2.6%) died. The median Ct value was lower in patients with severe disease (19.0, IQR: 16.5-22.0, n = 24) than in those without severe disease (25.5, IQR: 20.0-30.0, n = 84) (P = 0.002). Logistic regression analyses demonstrated that PCR Ct value [odds ratio (OR): 1.783, 95% confidence interval (CI): 1.013-3.138, P = 0.045], age (OR: 3.118, 95% CI: 1.643-5.920, P = 0.001), and white blood cell counts (OR: 0.446, 95% CI: 0.261-0.763, P = 0.003) remained significantly associated with severe disease.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Real-time PCR Ct values for pertussis might be useful as a predictor of severe disease in neonates and infants.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved..</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thuy Nga</LastName>
            <ForeName>Do Thi</ForeName>
            <Initials>DT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of General Internal Medicine, The Center for Tropical Diseases, Vietnam National Children's Hospital, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thi Bich Thuy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Phung</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology for Infectious Disease, Vietnam National Children's Hospital, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ainai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akira</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, National Institute of Infectious Diseases, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Takayama</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ikuyo</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Influenza and Respiratory Virus Research, National Institute of Infectious Diseases, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Do Thu</ForeName>
            <Initials>DT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology for Infectious Disease, Vietnam National Children's Hospital, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Saitoh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aya</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Niigata University Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakagawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Critical Care Medicine, National Center for Child Health and Development, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Minh Dien</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tran</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Surgical Intensive Care Unit, Vietnam National Children's Hospital, Hanoi, Vietnam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakajima</LastName>
            <ForeName>Noriko</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, National Institute of Infectious Diseases, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Saitoh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akihiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Niigata University Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010567">Pertussis Vaccine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001886" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bordetella pertussis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009305" MajorTopicYN="N">Nasopharynx</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010567" MajorTopicYN="N">Pertussis Vaccine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D060888" MajorTopicYN="N">Real-Time Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014917" MajorTopicYN="Y">Whooping Cough</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35093999</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003471</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202205000-00006</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plotkin SA. The pertussis problem. Clin Infect Dis. 2014;58:830–833.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan T, Dalby T, Forsyth K, et al. Pertussis across the globe: Recent epidemiologic trends from 2000 to 2013. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015;34:e222–e232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Greeff SC, de Melker HE, van Gageldonk PG, et al. Seroprevalence of pertussis in The Netherlands: evidence for increased circulation of Bordetella pertussis. PLoS One. 2010;5:e14183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coutte L, Locht C. Investigating pertussis toxin and its impact on vaccination. Future Microbiol. 2015;10:241–254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng Y, Chiu CH, Heininger U, et al. Emerging macrolide resistance in Bordetella pertussis in mainland China: Findings and warning from the global pertussis initiative. Lancet Reg Health West Pac. 2021;8:100098.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuan TA, Xoay TD, Nakajima N, et al. Pertussis infants needing mechanical ventilation and extracorporeal membrane oxygenation: Single-center retrospective series in Vietnam. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2021;22:e471–e479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chow MY, Khandaker G, McIntyre P. Global childhood deaths from pertussis: A historical review. Clin Infect Dis. 2016;63(suppl 4):S134–S141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United Nations Children’s Fund. Children in Vietnam. https://www.unicef.org/vietnam/children-viet-nam.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maertens K, Hoang TT, Nguyen TD, et al. The effect of maternal pertussis immunization on infant vaccine responses to a booster pertussis-containing vaccine in Vietnam. Clin Infect Dis. 2016;63(suppl 4):S197–S204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoang HT, Leuridan E, Maertens K, et al. Pertussis vaccination during pregnancy in Vietnam: Results of a randomized controlled trial Pertussis vaccination during pregnancy. Vaccine. 2016;34:151–159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pham NTH, Le NDT, Le NK, et al. Pertussis epidemiology and effect of vaccination among diagnosed children at Vietnam, 2015-2018. Acta Paediatr. 2020;109:2685–2691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanotte P, Plouzeau C, Burucoa C, et al. Evaluation of four commercial real-time PCR assays for detection of Bordetella spp. in nasopharyngeal aspirates. J Clin Microbiol. 2011;49:3943–3946.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall H, Clarke M, Rasiah K, et al. Predictors of disease severity in children hospitalized for pertussis during an epidemic. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2015;34:339–345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barlow RS, Reynolds LE, Cieslak PR, et al. Vaccinated children and adolescents with pertussis infections experience reduced illness severity and duration, Oregon, 2010-2012. Clin Infect Dis. 2014;58:1523–1529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierce C, Klein N, Peters M. Is leukocytosis a predictor of mortality in severe pertussis infection? Intensive Care Med. 2000;26:1512–1514.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cherry JD, Wendorf K, Bregman B, et al. An observational study of severe pertussis in 100 infants ≤120 days of age. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2018;37:202–205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C, Yang L, Cheng Y, et al. Risk factors associated with death in infants &lt;120 days old with severe pertussis: a case-control study. BMC Infect Dis. 2020;20:852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazantzi MS, Prezerakou A, Kalamitsou SN, et al. Characteristics of Bordetella pertussis infection among infants and children admitted to paediatric intensive care units in Greece: A multicentre, 11-year study. J Paediatr Child Health. 2017;53:257–262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikelova LK, Halperin SA, Scheifele D, et al.; Members of the Immunization Monitoring Program, Active (IMPACT). Predictors of death in infants hospitalized with pertussis: a case-control study of 16 pertussis deaths in Canada. J Pediatr. 2003;143:576–581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brotons P, de Paz HD, Toledo D, et al.; Working Group “Transmission of Pertussis in Households”. Differences in Bordetella pertussis DNA load according to clinical and epidemiological characteristics of patients with whooping cough. J Infect. 2016;72:460–467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura Y, Kamachi K, Toyoizumi-Ajisaka H, et al. Marked difference between adults and children in Bordetella pertussis DNA load in nasopharyngeal swabs. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2011;17:365–370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. National Expanded Program on Immunization. Comprehensive Multi-Year Plan (cMYP) for Extended Program on Immunization 2016-2020. https://extranet.who.int/countryplanningcycles/sites/default/files/planning_cycle_repository/viet_nam/cmyp_vietnam_2016-2020.pdf. 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health and Health Partnership Group. Joint Annual Health Review 2016: Towards Healthy Aging in Vietnam. 2018:242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamachi K, Duong HT, Dang AD, et al. Macrolide-resistant Bordetella pertussis, Vietnam, 2016-2017. Emerg Infect Dis. 2020;26:2511–2513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dellit TH, Owens RC, McGowan JE Jr, et al.; Infectious Diseases Society of America; Society for Healthcare Epidemiology of America. Infectious Diseases Society of America and the Society for Healthcare Epidemiology of America guidelines for developing an institutional program to enhance antimicrobial stewardship. Clin Infect Dis. 2007;44:159–177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganeshalingham A, McSharry B, Anderson B, et al. Identifying children at risk of malignant Bordetella pertussis infection. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2017;18:e42–e47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birru F, Al-Hinai Z, Awlad Thani S, et al. Critical pertussis: A multi-centric analysis of risk factors and outcomes in Oman. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;107:53–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C, Zhang H, Zhang Y, et al. Analysis of clinical characteristics of severe pertussis in infants and children: a retrospective study. BMC Pediatr. 2021;21:65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowlands HE, Goldman AP, Harrington K, et al. Impact of rapid leukodepletion on the outcome of severe clinical pertussis in young infants. Pediatrics. 2010;126:e816–e827.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oñoro G, Salido AG, Martínez IM, et al. Leukoreduction in patients with severe pertussis with hyperleukocytosis. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31:873–876.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
