<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35107412</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1654-9880</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
              <Day>31</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Global health action</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Glob Health Action</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Valid and reliable neonatal near-miss assessment scale in Ethiopia: a psychometric validation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2029334</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2029334</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2029334</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/16549716.2022.2029334</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The concept of a neonatal near miss is used to explain neonates who nearly died but survived a life-threatening complication in the first 28 days of life. We have left many ill surviving (near-miss) neonates, due to a lack of valid and reliable assessment scale, particularly in Ethiopia.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">We aim to psychometrically validate the neonatal near-miss assessment scale (NNMAS) for Ethiopia.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 465 live birth neonates were included with the assumption of a participant-to-item ratio of 15:1. A new contextually validated NNMAS was used to collect data. The Kaiseri--Mayer--Olkin (KMO) measure of sampling adequacy with a cutoff value of ≥0.50 for each item was applied. For reliability and validity of NNMAS, exploratory factor analysis using principal component analysis with oblique varimax rotation was used. Internal consistency and reliability were assessed using Cronbach's alpha. Convergent and discriminant validity was assessed using composite reliability (CR) and average variance extracted (AVE).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The Kaiser--Mayer--Olkin (KMO = 0.74) measure of sampling adequacy and Bartlett's Sphericity test for the appropriateness of the identity matrix (<i>χ</i><sup>2</sup> <b>= </b>2903.9, df = 276, and P = 0.000) were suitable for exploratory factor analysis (EFA). The correlation matrix determinant of the study was 0.002. The principal component analysis (PCA) identified six factors and together explained 54.3% of the variation in the Neonatal Near miss. The Cronbach-alpha coefficient was 0.80 for the entire scale. The composite reliability values of the factors ranged from 0.87 to 0.95. The AVEs, CR, and factor loadings were above 0.5 for all factors indicating that convergent validity was met. The square roots of the AVEs were greater than factor correlation values. It was revealed that discriminated validity was also met.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The neonatal near-miss assessment scale was found to be valid and reliable in the present context. The scale can be used to identify near-miss neonates in Ethiopia.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Melkamu Asaye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mengstu</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7889-5578</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Women and Family Health, School of Midwifery, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gelaye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kassahun Alemu</ForeName>
            <Initials>KA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4647-5178</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Institute of Public Health, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matebe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yohannes Hailu</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics and Child Health, School of Medicine, College of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Gondar, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lindgren</LastName>
            <ForeName>Helena</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4875-1407</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institute, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Erlandsson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kerstin</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6910-7047</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Women's and Children's Health, Karolinska Institute, Solna, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institution for Health and Welfare, Dalarna University, Falun, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Glob Health Action</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101496665</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1654-9880</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005002" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ethiopia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005163" MajorTopicYN="N">Factor Analysis, Statistical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000067491" MajorTopicYN="Y">Near Miss, Healthcare</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011594" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychometrics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Construct validity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">average variance extracted</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">composite reliability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">factor analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">neonatal near miss scale</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107412</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8812796</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16549716.2022.2029334</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UNICEF, WHO, World Bank, UN-DESA Population Division . Levels and trends in child mortality report 2018 estimate developed by the UN inter-agency group for child mortality estimation. 2018:1–8. Available from: https://wwwwhoint/maternal_child_adolescent/documents/levels_trends_child_mortality_2018/en/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Directorate MaCH, Health FMo . Nationalstrategy-for-newborn-and-child-survival-in-Ethiopia (2015/16–2019/20). 2015:1–83. Availabe from: https://wwwhealthynewbornnetworkorg/resource/national-strategy-newborn-child-survival-ethiopia/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ICF and EPHIEEa . Ethiopia mini demographic and health survey 2019: key indicators. Rockville (MD): EPHI and ICF; 2019. p. 1–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ICF and CSACEa . Ethiopia demographic and health survey 2016. Addis Ababa (Ethiopia) and Rockville (MD): CSA and ICF; 2016. p. 1–551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashako RM, Ngbonda D, Alworong’a OJ, et al. Predictive factors of neonatal mortality in intensive neonatal care unit at Goma Eastern Democratic Republic of Congo. J Pediatr Neonatal Care. 2019;9:58–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bell AJ, Wynn LV, Bakari A, et al. “We call them miracle babies”: how health care providers understand neonatal near-misses at three teaching hospitals in Ghana. PLoS One. 2018;13:1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5976150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29847603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pileggi-Castro C, Camelo JS Jr, Perdoná GC, et al. Development of criteria for identifying neonatal near-miss cases: analysis of two WHO multicountry cross-sectional studies. BJOG. 2014;121:110–118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24641541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pileggi C, Souza JP, Cecatti JG, et al. Neonatal near-miss approach in the 2005 WHO global survey Brazil. J Pediatr (Rio J). 2010;86:21–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20151094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shroff BD, Ninama NH.. 
A call for eminence obstetrics care by way of “Neonatal Near Miss” events (NNM): a hospital-based case-control study. J Obstet Gynaecol India. 2019;69:50–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6361179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30814810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Lima THB, Katz L, Kassar SB, et al. Neonatal near miss determinants at a maternity hospital for high-risk pregnancy in Northeastern Brazil: a prospective study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2018;18:1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30314456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ronsmans C, Cresswell JA, Goufodji S, et al. Characteristics of neonatal near miss in hospitals in Benin, Burkina Faso and Morocco in 2012–2013. Trop Med Int Health. 2016;21:535–545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26892469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Say L. Neonatal near miss: a potentially useful approach to assess the quality of newborn care. J Pediatr (Rio J). 2010;86:1–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20151097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos JP, Pileggi-Castro C, Camelo JS, et al. Neonatal near miss: a systematic review. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2015;15:320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4667407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26625905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ninama NH, Shroff BD. Will outlining neonatal near-miss events make a change? A hospital-based case-control study. Int J Community Med Public Health. 2019;6:5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kale PL, Jorge M, Laurenti R, et al. Pragmatic criteria of the definition of neonatal near miss: a comparative study. Revista de Saude Publica. 2017;51:1–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5704642</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29211204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva AA, Leite AJ, Lamy ZC, et al. Neonatal near miss in the birth in Brazil survey. Cad Saude Publica. 2014;30:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25167178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva G, Rosa K, Saguier E, et al. A populational based study on the prevalence of neonatal near-miss in a city located in the South of Brazil: prevalence and associated factors. Revista Brasileira de Saúde Materno Infantil. 2017;17:159–167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho OMC, Xavier A, Gouveia APM, et al. Identificação de casos de near miss neonatal: que critérios são usados no cenário brasileiro – revisão integrativa. Revista de Medicina da UFC. 2019;59:53–59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morais LR, Patz BC, Campanharo FF, et al. Neonatal near miss among newborns of women with type 1 diabetes mellitus. Obstet Gynecol Int. 2019;2019:8594158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701311</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31467554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos JP, Cecatti JG, Serruya SJ, et al. Neonatal near miss: the need for a standard definition and appropriate criteria and the rationale for a prospective surveillance system. Clinics (Sao Paulo). 2015;70:820–826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4676313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26735223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakimuli A, Mbalinda SN, Nabirye RC, et al. Stillbirths, neonatal deaths and neonatal near-miss cases attributable to severe obstetric complications: a prospective cohort study in two referral hospitals in Uganda. BMC Pediatr. 2015;15:44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4416266</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25928880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tekelab T, Chojenta C, Smith R, et al. Incidence and determinants of neonatal near miss in south Ethiopia: a prospective cohort study. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2020;20:354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7285716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghadi I, Alwi N, Abu Bakar K, et al. Construct validity examination of critical thinking dispositions for undergraduate students in University Putra Malaysia. Higher Educ Stud. 2012;2:138–145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manandhar SR, Dsm M, Adhikari D, et al. Neonatal near miss cases of different health facilities. Nepal Paediatr Soc. 2014;34:115–118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avenant T. Neonatal near miss: a measure of the quality of obstetric care. Best Pract Res Clin Obstetrics Gynecol. 2009;23:369–374.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19201262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asaye M, Gelaye K, Matebe YH, et al. Assessment of content validity for a neonatal near miss scale in the context of Ethiopia. Glob Health Action. 2021;14:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8547862</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34694977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reio TG, Shuck B. Exploratory factoranalysis. Adv Dev Hum Resour. 2014;17:12–25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taherdoost H, Sahibuddin S, and Jalaliyoon N. Exploratory factor analysis; concepts and theory. In: Jerzy B , editor. Advances in applied and pure mathematics. mathematics and computers in science and 680engineering series. 27.HAL open science. WSEAS; 2014. p. 375–382.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zijlmans EA, Tijmstra J, van der Ark LA, et al. Item-score reliability in empirical-data sets and its relationship with other item indices. Educ Psychol Meas. 2018;78:998–1020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6236637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30542214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watkins MW. Exploratory factor analysis: a guide to best practice. J Black Psychol. 2018;44:219–246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bah S. Discovering statistics using spss for windows: advanced techniques for beginners by A. Field. J R Stat Soc Ser D. 2001;50:545–560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yong AG, Pearce S. A beginner’s guide to factor analysis: focusing on exploratory factor analysis. Tutorials Quant Methods Psychol. 2013;9:79–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cronbach LJ. Coefficient alpha and the internal structure of tests. Psychometrika. 1951;16:297–334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gungor I, Kizilkaya Beji N. Development and psychometric testing of the scales for measuring maternal satisfaction in normal and cesarean birth. Midwifery. 2011;28:348–357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21546142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farrell A, Rudd J. Factor analysis and discriminant validity: a brief review of some practical issues. 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mushtari F, Hamnawozada S. Perceptions on birth positions among midwives and obstetricians at malalai maternity hospital and badakhshan provincial hospital, Afghanistan. J Midwifery Women’s Health. 2011;56:528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fornell C, Larcker DF. Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. J Marketing Res. 1981;18:39–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hair J, Black W, Babin B, et al. Multivariate data analysis: a global perspective. 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakari A, Bell AJ, Oppong SA, et al. Neonatal near-misses in Ghana: a prospective, observational, multi-center study. BMC Pediatr. 2019;19:509.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6927122</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31870340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rana HB, Banjara MR, Joshi MP, et al. Assessing maternal and neonatal near-miss reviews in rural Nepal: an implementation research study to inform scale-up. Acta Paediatrica. 2018;107:17–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30570789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brasil D, Vilela MBR, França K, et al. Neonatal morbidity near miss in tertiary hospitals in a capital of Northeast Brazil. Rev Paulista Pediatria. 2019;37:275–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6868548</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
