<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35107362</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2165-0497</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>23</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Microbiology spectrum</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Microbiol Spectr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Bacterial Surface Detachment during Nebulization with Contaminated Reusable Home Nebulizers.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0253521</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0253521</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e02535-21</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/spectrum.02535-21</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Patients with chronic respiratory diseases use home nebulizers that are often contaminated with pathogenic microbes to deliver aerosolized medications. The conditions under which these microbes leave the surface as bioaerosols during nebulization are not well characterized. The objectives of this study were to (i) determine whether different pathogens detach and disperse from the nebulizer surface during aerosolization and (ii) measure the effects of relative humidity and drying times on bacterial surface detachment and aerosolization. Bacteria were cultured from bioaerosols after Pari LC Plus albuterol nebulization using two different sources, as follows: (i) previously used nebulizers donated by anonymous patients with cystic fibrosis (CF) and (ii) nebulizers inoculated with bacteria isolated from the lungs of CF patients. Fractionated bioaerosols were collected with a Next-Generation Impactor. For a subset of bacteria, surface adherence during rewetting was measured with fluorescence microscopy. Bacteria dispersed from the surface of used CF patient nebulizers during albuterol nebulization. Eighty percent (16/20) of clinical isolates inoculated on the nebulizer in the laboratory formed bioaerosols. Detachment from the plastic surface into the chamber solution predicted bioaerosol production. Increased relative humidity and decreased drying times after inoculation favored bacterial dispersion on aerosols during nebulized therapy. Pathogenic bacteria contaminating nebulizer surfaces detached from the surface as bioaerosols during nebulized therapies, especially under environmental conditions when contaminated nebulizers were dried or stored at high relative humidity. This finding emphasizes the need for appropriate nebulizer cleaning, disinfection, and complete drying during storage and informs environmental conditions that favor bacterial surface detachment during nebulization. <b>IMPORTANCE</b> Studies from around the world have demonstrated that many patients use contaminated nebulizers to deliver medication into their lungs. While it is known that using contaminated medications in a nebulizer can lead to a lung infection, whether bacteria on the surface of a contaminated nebulizer detach as bioaerosols capable of reaching the lung has not been studied. This work demonstrates that a subset of clinical bacteria enter solution from the surface during nebulization and are aerosolized. Environmental conditions of high relative humidity during storage favor dispersion from the surface. We also provide results of an <i>in vitro</i> assay conducted to monitor bacterial surface detachment during multiple cycles of rewetting that correlate with the results of nebulizer/bacterial surface interactions. These studies demonstrate for the first time that pathogenic bacteria on the nebulizer surface pose a risk of bacterial inhalation to patients who use contaminated nebulizers.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Harris</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jamie C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Connecticut Children's Medical Center, Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Hartford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Collins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melanie S</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Connecticut Children's Medical Center, Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Hartford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pamela H</ForeName>
            <Initials>PH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Yale School of Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Infectious Diseases and Global Health, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schramm</LastName>
            <ForeName>Craig M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Connecticut Children's Medical Center, Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Hartford, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nero</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Yale University, Department of Molecular, Cellular and Developmental Biology, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Yale University, Department of Molecular, Cellular and Developmental Biology, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Murray</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas S</ForeName>
            <Initials>TS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6829-7213</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Yale School of Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Infectious Diseases and Global Health, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>UL1 TR001863</GrantID>
            <Acronym>TR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Microbiol Spectr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101634614</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2165-0497</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000336">Aerosols</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000336" MajorTopicYN="N">Aerosols</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001419" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteria</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000145" MajorTopicYN="N">classification</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000254" MajorTopicYN="N">growth &amp; development</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000302" MajorTopicYN="Y">isolation &amp; purification</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001422" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial Adhesion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003550" MajorTopicYN="N">Cystic Fibrosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004866" MajorTopicYN="N">Equipment Contamination</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009330" MajorTopicYN="N">Nebulizers and Vaporizers</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="Y">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">bacterial aerosolization</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">nebulizer contamination</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">surface rewetting</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35107362</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8809330</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/spectrum.02535-21</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harun SN, Wainwright C, Klein K, Hennig S. 2016. A systematic review of studies examining the rate of lung function decline in patients with cystic fibrosis. Paediatr Respir Rev
20:55–66. doi:10.1016/j.prrv.2016.03.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prrv.2016.03.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27259460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breuer O, Caudri D, Stick S, Turkovic L. 2018. Predicting disease progression in cystic fibrosis. Expert Rev Respir Med
12:905–917. doi:10.1080/17476348.2018.1519400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17476348.2018.1519400</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30173593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emerson J, Rosenfeld M, McNamara S, Ramsey B, Gibson RL. 2002. Pseudomonas aeruginosa and other predictors of mortality and morbidity in young children with cystic fibrosis. Pediatr Pulmonol
34:91–100. doi:10.1002/ppul.10127.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.10127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12112774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzzetti R, Salvatore D, Baldo E, Forneris MP, Lucidi V, Manunza D, Marinelli I, Messore B, Neri AS, Raia V, Furnari ML, Mastella G. 2009. An overview of international literature from cystic fibrosis registries: 1. Mortality and survival studies in cystic fibrosis. J Cyst Fibros
8:229–237. doi:10.1016/j.jcf.2009.04.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcf.2009.04.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19419909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murray TS, O'Rourke
TK, Jr, Feinn R, Drapeau G, Collins MS. 2019. Nebulizer cleaning and disinfection practices in families with cystic fibrosis: the relationship between attitudes, practice and microbe colonization. J Cyst Fibros
18:823–828. doi:10.1016/j.jcf.2019.05.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcf.2019.05.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31126899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blau H, Mussaffi H, Mei Zahav M, Prais D, Livne M, Czitron BM, Cohen HA. 2007. Microbial contamination of nebulizers in the home treatment of cystic fibrosis. Child Care Health Dev
33:491–495. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2214.2006.00669.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2214.2006.00669.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17584406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabatabaii SA, Khanbabaee G, Sadr S, Farahbakhsh N, Aghdam MK, Lotfollahzadeh S, Hosseini A, Dara N, Nanbakhsh M, Gorji FA. 2020. Microbial contamination of home nebulizers in children with cystic fibrosis and clinical implication on the number of pulmonary exacerbations. BMC Pulm Med
20:33. doi:10.1186/s12890-020-1059-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-020-1059-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7006379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32028925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz YC, Ergenekon AP, Mursaloglu HH, Cenk M, Uzunoglu BS, Tastan G, Gokdemir Y, Erdem EE, Karakoc F, Nasr SZ, Karadag B. 2021. The effects of nebulizer hygiene training on the practices of cystic fibrosis patients and caregivers. Pediatr Pulmonol
56:1527–1533. doi:10.1002/ppul.25307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.25307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saiman L, Siegel JD, LiPuma JJ, Brown RF, Bryson EA, Chambers MJ, Downer VS, Fliege J, Hazle LA, Jain M, Marshall BC, O'Malley C, Pattee SR, Potter-Bynoe G, Reid S, Robinson KA, Sabadosa KA, Schmidt HJ, Tullis E, Webber J, Weber DJ, Cystic FF, Society for Healthcare Epidemiology of America. 2014. Infection prevention and control guideline for cystic fibrosis: 2013 update. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol
35:S1–S67. doi:10.1086/676882.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/676882</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25025126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hohenwarter K, Prammer W, Aichinger W, Reychler G. 2016. An evaluation of different steam disinfection protocols for cystic fibrosis nebulizers. J Cyst Fibros
15:78–84. doi:10.1016/j.jcf.2015.07.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcf.2015.07.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26233897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore JE, Moore RE, Bell J, Millar BC. 2020. Importance of nebulizer drying for patients with cystic fibrosis. Respir Care
65:1443–1450. doi:10.4187/respcare.07362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.07362</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobben NA, Drent M, Jonkers M, Wouters EF, Vaneechoutte M, Stobberingh EE. 1996. Outbreak of severe Pseudomonas aeruginosa respiratory infections due to contaminated nebulizers. J Hosp Infect
33:63–70. doi:10.1016/s0195-6701(96)90030-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0195-6701(96)90030-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8738203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deegan RD, Bakajin O, Dupont TF, Huber G, Nagel SR, Witten TA. 1997. Capillary flow as the cause of ring stains from dried liquid drops. Nature
389:827–829. doi:10.1038/39827.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/39827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esbelin J, Santos T, Hebraud M. 2018. Desiccation: an environmental and food industry stress that bacteria commonly face. Food Microbiol
69:82–88. doi:10.1016/j.fm.2017.07.017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fm.2017.07.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin K, Marr LC. 2020. Humidity-dependent decay of viruses, but not bacteria, in aerosols and droplets follows disinfection kinetics. Environ Sci Technol
54:1024–1032. doi:10.1021/acs.est.9b04959.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.est.9b04959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31886650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alsved M, Holm S, Christiansen S, Smidt M, Rosati B, Ling M, Boesen T, Finster K, Bilde M, Londahl J, Santl-Temkiv T. 2018. Effect of aerosolization and drying on the viability of Pseudomonas syringae cells. Front Microbiol
9:3086. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2018.03086.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2018.03086</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6305290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30619167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone W, Kroukamp O, Korber DR, McKelvie J, Wolfaardt GM. 2016. Microbes at surface-air interfaces: the metabolic harnessing of relative humidity, surface hygroscopicity, and oligotrophy for resilience. Front Microbiol
7:1563. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2016.01563.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmicb.2016.01563</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5043023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27746774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krasowska A, Sigler K. 2014. How microorganisms use hydrophobicity and what does this mean for human needs?
Front Cell Infect Microbiol
4:112. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2014.00112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2014.00112</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25191645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsikogianni MG, Missirlis YF. 2010. Interactions of bacteria with specific biomaterial surface chemistries under flow conditions. Acta Biomater
6:1107–1118. doi:10.1016/j.actbio.2009.08.006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.actbio.2009.08.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19671455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maier B, Wong GCL. 2015. How bacteria use type IV pili machinery on surfaces. Trends Microbiol
23:775–788. doi:10.1016/j.tim.2015.09.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tim.2015.09.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26497940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schniederberend M, Williams JF, Shine E, Shen C, Jain R, Emonet T, Kazmierczak BI. 2019. Modulation of flagellar rotation in surface-attached bacteria: a pathway for rapid surface-sensing after flagellar attachment. PLoS Pathog
15:e1008149. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1008149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1008149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6855561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31682637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hentzer M, Teitzel GM, Balzer GJ, Heydorn A, Molin S, Givskov M, Parsek MR. 2001. Alginate overproduction affects Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilm structure and function. J Bacteriol
183:5395–5401. doi:10.1128/JB.183.18.5395-5401.2001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JB.183.18.5395-5401.2001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC95424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11514525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haddrell AE, Thomas RJ. 2017. Aerobiology: experimental considerations, observations, and future tools. Appl Environ Microbiol
83:e00809-17. doi:10.1128/AEM.00809-17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.00809-17</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5561278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28667111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn RJ, Lubin AH, Jones PR, Nahata MC. 1982. Bacterial contamination of aerosol solutions used to treat cystic fibrosis. Am J Hosp Pharm
39:308–309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7058804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vassal S, Taamma R, Marty N, Sardet A, d'athis P, Bremont F, Dalphin ML, Plesiat P, Rault G, Thubert J, Dominique S, Lemeland JF, Derelle J, Blech MF, Roussey M, Perrin M, Sautegeau A. 2000. Microbiologic contamination study of nebulizers after aerosol therapy in patients with cystic fibrosis. Am J Infect Control
28:347–351. doi:10.1067/mic.2000.110214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mic.2000.110214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11029133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Towle D, Callan DA, Farrel PA, Egan ME, Murray TS. 2013. Baby bottle steam sterilizers disinfect home nebulizers inoculated with bacterial respiratory pathogens. J Cyst Fibros
12:512–516. doi:10.1016/j.jcf.2012.11.013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcf.2012.11.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23267773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berlinski A, Waldrep JC. 1998. Four hours of continuous albuterol nebulization. Chest
114:847–853. doi:10.1378/chest.114.3.847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.114.3.847</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9743177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
