<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35102533</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1969</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>39</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Drugs &amp; aging</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Drugs Aging</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Onychomycosis in Older Adults: Prevalence, Diagnosis, and Management.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>191</StartPage>
          <EndPage>198</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>191-198</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40266-021-00917-8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The risk of having onychomycosis increases with age. Data suggest that the prevalence of onychomycosis may be ≥ 20% in subjects aged ≥ 60 years and ≥ 50% in those aged ≥ 70 years. Older males are 2.1 times more prone to onychomycosis than are females. Although most nail dystrophies (approximately 50%) are caused by onychomycosis, proper clinical assessment followed by mycological examination is recommended to exclude other conditions such as nail trauma, lichen planus, and psoriasis. The US FDA-approved onychomycosis treatments are systemic antifungals (terbinafine and itraconazole) for severe onychomycosis and topical antifungals (ciclopirox 8%, efinaconazole 10%, and tavaborole 5%) for mild-to-moderate onychomycosis. Oral fluconazole is used off-label, and itraconazole may be considered for non-dermatophyte onychomycosis. Recently, fosravuconazole was approved in Japan for onychomycosis treatment. Although the treatment options and durations are the same for older patients as for other age groups, a clinical decision should take into account various age-related factors such as comorbidities, polypharmacy, hepatic and renal insufficiency, and noncompliance. Clinicians should also consider possible drug interactions and side effects when choosing a particular antifungal. Since the recurrence rate of onychomycosis is high, older patients should practice sanitization techniques, consider lifestyle changes, and perhaps consider using a topical antifungal as long-term maintenance therapy one to three times per week to prevent the recurrence of onychomycosis or to treat early disease.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gupta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aditya K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8664-7723</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., 645 Windermere Road, London, ON, N5X 2P1, Canada. agupta@mediproberesearch.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada. agupta@mediproberesearch.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Venkataraman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maanasa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., 645 Windermere Road, London, ON, N5X 2P1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Talukder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mesbah</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., 645 Windermere Road, London, ON, N5X 2P1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>New Zealand</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Drugs Aging</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9102074</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1170-229X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000935">Antifungal Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>304NUG5GF4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017964">Itraconazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000287" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Topical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000935" MajorTopicYN="N">Antifungal Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017964" MajorTopicYN="N">Itraconazole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014009" MajorTopicYN="Y">Onychomycosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35102533</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40266-021-00917-8</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40266-021-00917-8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK. Onychomycosis in the elderly. Drugs Aging. 2000;16(6):397–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10939306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Stec N, Summerbell RC, Shear NH, Piguet V, Tosti A, et al. Onychomycosis: a review. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34(9):1972–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32239567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski BE. Onychomycosis. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2000;1(1):19–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11702301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Jain HC, Lynde CW, Watteel GN, Summerbell RC. Prevalence and epidemiology of unsuspected onychomycosis in patients visiting dermatologists’ offices in Ontario, Canada-a multicenter survey of 2001 patients. Int J Dermatol. 1997;36(10):783–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9372358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen PR, Scher RK. Geriatric nail disorders: diagnosis and treatment. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1992;26(4):521–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1597537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdullah L, Abbas O. Common nail changes and disorders in older people: diagnosis and management. Can Fam Physician. 2011;57(2):173–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21321168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3038811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A, Gupta G, Jain H, Lynde C, Foley K, Daigle D, et al. The prevalence of unsuspected onychomycosis and its causative organisms in a multicentre Canadian sample of 30 000 patients visiting physicians’ offices. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2016;30(9):1567–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27168494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loo DS. Onychomycosis in the elderly. Drugs Aging. 2007;24(4):293–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17432924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas J, Jacobson G, Narkowicz C, Peterson G, Burnet H, Sharpe C. Toenail onychomycosis: an important global disease burden. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2010;35(5):497–519.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20831675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Jain HC, Lynde CW, MacDonald P, Cooper EA, Summerbell RC. Prevalence and epidemiology of onychomycosis in patients visiting physicians’ offices: a multicenter Canadian survey of 15,000 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2000;43(2):244–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10906646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakkas H, Kittas C, Kapnisi G, Priavali E, Kallinteri A, Bassukas ID, et al. Onychomycosis in Northwestern Greece over a 7-year period. Pathogens. 2020;9(10):851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7603248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piérard G. Onychomycosis and other superficial fungal infections of the foot in the elderly: a pan-European survey. Dermatology. 2001;202(3):220–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11385227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yalçın B, Tamer E, Toy GG, Öztaş P, Hayran M, Allı N. The prevalence of skin diseases in the elderly: analysis of 4099 geriatric patients. Int J Dermatol. 2006;45(6):672–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16796625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Gupta AK, Amichai B, Baum S, Barzilai A, Farhi R, et al. Increased risk of tinea pedis and onychomycosis among swimming pool employees in Netanya area, Israel. Mycopathologia. 2016;181(11):851–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27435974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szepietowski JC, Reich A, Garlowska E, Kulig M, Baran E. Factors influencing coexistence of toenail onychomycosis with tinea pedis and other dermatomycoses: a survey of 2761 patients. Arch Dermatol. 2006;142(10):1279–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17043182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Sibbald RG, Andriessen A, Belley R, Boroditsky A, Botros M, et al. Toenail onychomycosis—a Canadian approach with a new transungual treatment: development of a clinical pathway. J Cutan Med Surg. 2015;19(5):440–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25857439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joyce A, Gupta AK, Koenig L, Wolcott R, Carviel J. Fungal diversity and onychomycosis: an analysis of 8,816 toenail samples using quantitative PCR and next-generation sequencing. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc. 2019;109(1):57–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30964314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Taborda VB, Taborda PR, Shemer A, Summerbell RC, Nakrieko K-A. High prevalence of mixed infections in global onychomycosis. PLoS ONE. 2020;15(9):e0239648.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991597</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7523972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piérard GE, Arrese JE, Piérard-Franchimont C, Quatresooz P. Onychomycosis in older patients. Aging Health. 2006;2(5).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Talukder M. Efinaconazole in onychomycosis. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiwary AK, Sapra B. High failure rate of transungal drug delivery: need for new strategies. Ther Deliv. 2017;8(5):239–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28361611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Gupta AK, Kamshov S, Babaev M, Hermush V, Farhi R, et al. Continuous terbinafine and pulse itraconazole for the treatment of non-dermatophyte mold toenail onychomycosis. J Dermatolog Treat. 2021;32(3):310–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31415182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipner SR, Joseph WS, Vlahovic TC, Scher RK, Rich P, Ghannoum M, et al. Therapeutic recommendations for the treatment of toenail onychomycosis in the US. J Drugs Dermatol. 2021;20(10):s93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noguchi H, Matsumoto T, Kimura U, Hiruma M, Kano R, Kubo M, et al. Fosravuconazole to treat severe onychomycosis in the elderly. J Dermatol. 2021;48(2):228–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33099769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA. Long-term efficacy and safety of once-daily efinaconazole 10% topical solution (Jublia) for dermatophyte toenail onychomycosis: an interim analysis. Skin Ther Lett. 2021;26(1):5–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Konnikov N, Lynde C, Summerbell R, Albreski D, Baran R, et al. Onychomycosis: predisposed populations and some predictors of suboptimal response to oral antifungal agents. Eur J Dermatol. 1999;9(8):633–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10586132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araiza-Santibánez J, Tirado-Sanchez A, Gonzalez-Rodriguez A, Vazquez-Escorcia L, Ponce-Olivera R, Bonifaz A. Onychomycosis in the elderly. A 2-year retrospective study of 138 cases. Rev Méd del Hosp Gen de México. 2016;79(1):5–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shivanna R. Management of dermatophytosis in elderly and with systemic comorbidities. Clin Dermatol Rev. 2017;1(3):38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elewski B, Tavakkol A. Safety and tolerability of oral antifungal agents in the treatment of fungal nail disease: a proven reality. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2005;1(4):299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18360572</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1661633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glassock RJ, Winearls C. Ageing and the glomerular filtration rate: truths and consequences. Trans Am Clin Climatol Assoc. 2009;120:419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19768194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2744545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Konnikov N, MacDonald P, Rich P, Rodger N, Edmonds M, et al. Prevalence and epidemiology of toenail onychomycosis in diabetic subjects: a multicentre survey. Br J Dermatol. 1998;139(4):665–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9892911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Humke S. The prevalence and management of onychomycosis in diabetic patients. Eur J Dermatol. 2000;10(5):379–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10882947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan JS, Joseph WS. Common fungal infections of the feet in patients with diabetes mellitus. Drugs Aging. 2004;21(2):101–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14960127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romano C, Massai L, Asta F, Signorini A. Prevalence of dermatophytic skin and nail infections in diabetic patients. Mycoses. 2001;44(3–4):83–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11413928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogra S, Kumar B, Bhansali A, Chakrabarty A. Epidemiology of onychomycosis in patients with diabetes mellitus in India. Int J Dermatol. 2002;41(10):647–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12390186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadighha A, Mohagheghzahed G. Onychomycosis: report on experience with itraconazole in 37 patients aged older than 50 years: a multivariate regression. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2009;34(8):924–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19438527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salem A, Gamil H, Hamed M, Galal S. Nail changes in patients with liver disease. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2010;24(6):649–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19888943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Highlights of prescribing information, LAMISIL (terbinafine hydrochloride) tablets, for oral use (FDA label). 2019. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2019/020539s033lbl.pdf . Cited 6 Aug 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SPORANOX®(itraconazole) capsules (FDA label) 2019. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2019/020083s063lbl.pdf . Cited 6 Aug 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tercedor J, López Hernández B, Ródenas JM. Nail diseases in haemodialysis patients: case–control study. Br J Dermatol. 2001;144(2):445–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11251608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuvandik G, Çetin M, Genctoy G, Horoz M, Duru M, Akcali C, et al. The prevalance, epidemiology and risk factors for onychomycosis in hemodialysis patients. BMC Infect Dis. 2007;7(1):1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irimie M, Tătaru A, Oantă A, Moga M. In vitro susceptibility of dermatophytes isolated from patients with end-stage renal disease: a case–control study. Mycoses. 2014;57(3):129–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23889207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Gupta MA, Summerbell RC, Cooper EA, Konnikov N, Albreski D, et al. The epidemiology of onychomycosis: possible role of smoking and peripheral arterial disease. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2000;14(6):466–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11444267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall M, Monka C, Krupp P, O’Sullivan D. Safety of oral terbinafine: results of a postmarketing surveillance study in 25 884 patients. Arch Dermatol. 1997;133(10):1213–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9382559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Venkataraman M, Renaud HJ, Summerbell R, Shear NH, Piguet V. A paradigm shift in the treatment and management of onychomycosis. Skin Appendage Disorders. 2021;7(4):251–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Intriago J. Elderly nail fungus: prevention and early treatment. 2021; https://www.seniorsmatter.com/treating-preventing-nail-fungus-elderly/2491913/ . Cited 02 Sept 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Elewski BE, Rosen T, Caldwell B, Pariser DM, Kircik LH, et al. Onychomycosis: strategies to minimize recurrence. J Drugs Dermatol. 2016;15(3):279–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26954312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA, Paquet M. Recurrences of dermatophyte toenail onychomycosis during long-term follow-up after successful treatments with mono-and combined therapy of terbinafine and itraconazole. J Cutan Med Surg. 2013;17(3):201–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23673304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosti A, Piraccini B, Stinchi C, Colombo M. Relapses of onychomycosis after successful treatment with systemic antifungals: a three-year follow-up. Dermatology. 1998;197(2):162–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9732167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigurgeirsson B, Ólafsson JH, Steinsson J, Paul C, Billstein S, Evans EGV. Long-term effectiveness of treatment with terbinafine vs itraconazole in onychomycosis: a 5-year blinded prospective follow-up study. Arch Dermatol. 2002;138(3):353–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11902986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Versteeg SG. The role of shoe and sock sanitization in the management of superficial fungal infections of the feet. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc. 2019;109(2):141–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29521517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zatcoff RC, Smith MS, Borkow G. Treatment of tinea pedis with socks containing copper-oxide impregnated fibers. Foot. 2008;18(3):136–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Brintnell WC. Sanitization of contaminated footwear from onychomycosis patients using ozone gas: a novel adjunct therapy for treating onychomycosis and tinea pedis? J Cutan Med Surg. 2013;17(4):243–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23815956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer TR, Mucha H, Hoefer D. Infection risk by dermatophytes during storage and after domestic laundry and their temperature-dependent inactivation. Mycopathologia. 2011;171(1):43–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20652833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amichai B, Grunwald MH, Davidovici B, Farhi R, Shemer A. The effect of domestic laundry processes on fungal contamination of socks. Int J Dermatol. 2013;52(11):1392–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23879806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum MA, Isham N, Long L. Optimization of an infected shoe model for the evaluation of an ultraviolet shoe sanitizer device. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc. 2012;102(4):309–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22826329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beoughton R. Reinfection from socks and shoes in tinea pedis. Br J Dermatol. 1955;67(7):249–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ara K, Hama M, Akiba S, Koike K, Okisaka K, Hagura T, et al. Foot odor due to microbial metabolism and its control. Can J Microbiol. 2006;52(4):357–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16699586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dixon HA. The study of fungi in diseases of the skin. Can Med Assoc J. 1924;14(11):1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20315181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1707786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer TR, Mucha H, Hoefer D. Dermatophyte susceptibility varies towards antimicrobial textiles. Mycoses. 2012;55(4):344–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honisch M, Stamminger R, Bockmühl DP. Impact of wash cycle time, temperature and detergent formulation on the hygiene effectiveness of domestic laundering. J Appl Microbiol. 2014;117(6):1787–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25207988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borkow G. Using copper to improve the well-being of the skin. Curr Chem Biol. 2014;8(2):89–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361585</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4556990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borkow G, Kanmukhla V, Monk A. Improvement to foot and skin appearance by using copper oxide impregnated socks-a report of a large scale internet based user survey. J Cosmo Trichol. 2017;3(116):2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouf SA, Moussa TA, Abd-Elmegeed AM, Eltahlawy SR. Anti-fungal potential of ozone against some dermatophytes. Braz J Microbiol. 2016;47:697–702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27287337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4927674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Brintnell W. Ozone gas effectively kills laboratory strains of Trichophyton rubrum and Trichophyton mentagrophytes using an in vitro test system. J Dermatolog Treat. 2014;25(3):251–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22827529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reed NG. The history of ultraviolet germicidal irradiation for air disinfection. Public Health Rep. 2010;125(1):15–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20402193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2789813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katara G, Hemvani N, Chitnis S, Chitnis V, Chitnis D. Surface disinfection by exposure to germicidal UV light. Indian J Med Microbiol. 2008;26(3):241–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18695322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai T, Tegos G, Rolz-Cruz G, Cumbie W, Hamblin M. Ultraviolet C inactivation of dermatophytes: implications for treatment of onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol. 2008;158(6):1239–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18410410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2808700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nematollahi AR, Badiee P, Nournia E. The efficacy of ultraviolet irradiation on Trichophyton species isolated from nails. Jundishapur J Microbiol 2015;8(6).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai T, Vrahas MS, Murray CK, Hamblin MR. Ultraviolet C irradiation: an alternative antimicrobial approach to localized infections? Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2012;10(2):185–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22339192</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3292282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budihardja D, Mayser P. The effect of microwave irradiation on the vitality of various dermatophytes. Mycoses. 2014;57(4):209–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24612041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
