<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35114013</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3468</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>596</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>FEBS letters</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>FEBS Lett</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Amyloid protein-induced sequestration of the eukaryotic ribosome: effect of stoichiometry and polyphenolic inhibitors.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1190</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1202</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1190-1202</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/1873-3468.14308</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is characterized by the appearance of neurofibrillary tangles comprising of the Tau protein and aggregation of amyloid-β peptides (Aβ 1-40 and Aβ 1-42). A concomitant loss of the ribosomal population is also observed in AD-affected neurons. Our studies demonstrate that, similarly to Tau protein aggregation, in vitro aggregation of Aβ peptides in the vicinity of the yeast 80S ribosome can induce co-aggregation of ribosomal components. The RNA-stimulated aggregation of Aβ peptides and the Tau-K18 variant is dependent on the RNA:protein stoichiometric ratio. A similar effect of stoichiometry is also observed on the ribosome-protein co-aggregation process. Polyphenolic inhibitors of amyloid aggregation, such as rosmarinic acid and myricetin, inhibit RNA-stimulated Aβ and Tau-K18 aggregation and can mitigate the co-aggregation of ribosomal components.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Federation of European Biochemical Societies.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ferdosh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sehnaz</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, St. Xavier's College, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Banerjee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Senjuti</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, St. Xavier's College, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Singh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jayshree</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, St. Xavier's College, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barat</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chandana</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2629-5383</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, St. Xavier's College, Kolkata, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>FEBS Lett</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0155157</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0014-5793</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016229">Amyloid beta-Peptides</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D058227">Amyloidogenic Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016875">tau Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>63231-63-0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D012313">RNA</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016229" MajorTopicYN="N">Amyloid beta-Peptides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058227" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amyloidogenic Proteins</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D056890" MajorTopicYN="N">Eukaryota</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016874" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurofibrillary Tangles</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012313" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012270" MajorTopicYN="N">Ribosomes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016875" MajorTopicYN="N">tau Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer's disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tau protein</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aggregation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amyloid-β</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polyphenolic inhibitors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ribosomal RNA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ribosome</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35114013</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/1873-3468.14308</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drew L. An age-old story of dementia. Nature. 2018;559:S2-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuello AC. Early and late CNS inflammation in Alzheimer’s disease: two extremes of a continuum? Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2017;38:956-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LaFerla FM, Green KN, Oddo S. Intracellular amyloid-β in Alzheimer's disease. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2007;8:499-509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen GF, Xu TH, Yan Y, Zhou YR, Jiang Y, Melcher K, et al. Amyloid beta: structure, biology and structure-based therapeutic development. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2017;38:1205-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SJC, Nam E, Lee HJ, Savelieff MG, Lim MH. Towards an understanding of amyloid-β oligomers: characterization, toxicity mechanisms, and inhibitors. Chem Soc Rev. 2017;46:310-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding Q, Markesbery WR, Cecarini V, Keller JN. Decreased RNA, and increased RNA oxidation, in ribosomes from early Alzheimer’s disease. Neurochem Res. 2006;31:705-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee S, Ferdosh S, Ghosh AN, Barat C. Tau protein-induced sequestration of the eukaryotic ribosome: implications in neurodegenerative disease. Sci Rep. 2020;10:5225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Q, Kebede MT, Kemeh MM, Islam S, Lee B, Bleck SD, et al. Inhibition of the self-assembly of Aβ and of Tau by polyphenols: mechanistic studies. Molecules. 2019;24:2316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freyssin A, Page G, Fauconneau B, Bilan AR. Natural polyphenols effects on protein aggregates in Alzheimer's and Parkinson's prion-like diseases. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13:955-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakraborty B, Bhakta S, Sengupta J. Disassembly of yeast 80S ribosomes into subunits is a concerted action of ribosome-assisted folding of denatured protein. Biochem Biophys Res Comm. 2016;469:923-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsh DM, Thulin E, Minogue AM, Gustavsson N, Pang E, Teplow DB, et al. A facile method for expression and purification of the Alzheimer’s disease-associated amyloid β-peptide. FEBS J. 2009;276:1266-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ono K, Li L, Takamura Y, Yoshiike Y, Zhu L, Han F, et al. Phenolic compounds prevent amyloid β-protein oligomerization and synaptic dysfunction by site-specific binding. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:14631-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge JF, Qiao JP, Qi CC, Wang CW, Zhou JN. The binding of resveratrol to monomer and fibril amyloid beta. Neurochem Int. 2012;61:1192-201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramachandran G, Udgaonkar JB. Understanding the kinetic roles of the inducer heparin and of rod-like protofibrils during amyloid fibril formation by Tau protein. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:38948-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cornejo A, Aguilar Sandoval F, Caballero L, Machuca L, Muñoz P, Caballero J, et al. Rosmarinic acid prevents fibrillization and diminishes vibrational modes associated to β sheet in tau protein linked to Alzheimer’s disease. J Enzyme Inhib Med Chem. 2017;32:945-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piir K, Tamm T, Kisly I, Tammsalu T, Remme J. Stepwise splitting of ribosomal proteins from yeast ribosomes by LiCl. PLoS One. 2014;9:e101561.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhigalova NN, Zozulya VN, Ryazanova OA, Zozulya VN, Voloshin IM, Fyodorov VF, et al. Quinacrine interaction with single-stranded polynucleotides from the laser polarized fluorescence Data. Biopolymers and Cell. 1992;8(1):73-78. https://doi.org/10.7124/bc.000312</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kovachev PS, Banerjee D, Rangel LP, Eriksson J, Pedrote MM, Martins-Dinis MMD, et al. Distinct modulatory role of RNA in the aggregation of the tumor suppressor protein p53 core domain. J Biol Chem. 2017;292:9345-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourhim M, Kruzel M, Srikrishnan T, Nicotera T. Linear quantitation of Aβ aggregation using thioflavin T: reduction in fibril formation by colostrinin. J Neurosci Methods. 2007;160:264-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vandersteen A, Masman MF, De Baets G, Jonckheere W, Van Der Werf K, Marrink SJ, et al. Molecular plasticity regulates oligomerization and cytotoxicity of the multipeptide-length amyloid-β peptide pool. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:36732-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cremers CM, Knoefler D, Gates S, Martin N, Dahl JU, Lempart J, et al. Polyphosphate: a conserved modifier of amyloidogenic processes. Mol Cell. 2016;63:768-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun S, Humphreys C, Fraser E, Brancale A, Bochtler M, Dale TC. Amyloid-associated nucleic acid hybridisation. PLoS One. 2011;6:e19125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginsberg SD, Galvin JE, Chiu TS, Lee VMY, Masliah E, Trojanowski JQ. RNA sequestration to pathological lesions of neurodegenerative diseases. Acta Neuropathol. 1998;96:487-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meli M, Gasset M, Colombo G. Are amyloid fibrils RNA-traps? A molecular dynamics perspective. Front Mol Biosci. 2018;5:53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pathak BK, Mondal S, Ghosh AN, Barat C. The ribosome can prevent aggregation of partially folded protein intermediates: studies using the Escherichia coli ribosome. PLoS One. 2014;9:e96425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mondal S, Pathak BK, Ray S, Barat C. Impact of P-Site tRNA and antibiotics on ribosome mediated protein folding: studies using the Escherichia coli ribosome. PLoS One. 2014;9:e101293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pathak BK, Mondal S, Banerjee S, Ghosh AN, Barat C. Sequestration of ribosome during protein aggregate formation: contribution of ribosomal RNA. Sci Rep. 2017;7:42017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kampers T, Friedhoff P, Biernat J, Mandelkow EM, Mandelkow E. RNA stimulates aggregation of microtubule-associated protein Tau into Alzheimer-like paired helical filaments. FEBS Lett. 1996;399:344-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taguchi R, Hatayama K, Takahashi T, Hayashi T, Sato Y, Sato D, et al. Structure-activity relations of rosmarinic acid derivatives for the amyloid β aggregation inhibition and antioxidant properties. European Journal of Medicinal Chemistry. 2017;138:1066-1075. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejmech.2017.07.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Jiang G, Shigemori H. Inhibitory Activity on Amyloid Aggregation of Rosmarinic Acid and Its Substructures From Isodon japonicus. Natural Product Communications. 2019;14(5):1934578X1984303. https://doi.org/10.1177/1934578x19843039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Louka A, Zacco E, Temussi PA, Tartaglia GG, Pastore A. RNA as the stone guest of protein aggregation. Nucleic Acids Res. 2020;48:11880-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cordeiro Y, Macedo B, Silva JL, Gomes MP. Pathological implications of nucleic acid interactions with proteins associated with neurodegenerative diseases. Biophys Rev. 2014;6:97-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rha AK, Das D, Taran O, Ke Y, Mehta AK, Lynn DG. Electrostatic complementarity drives amyloid/nucleic acid co-assembly. Angew Chem Int Ed. 2020;59:358-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang H, Hu HY. Sequestration of cellular interacting partners by protein aggregates: implication in a loss-of-function pathology. FEBS J. 2016;283:3705-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakraborty P, Rivière G, Liu S, de Opakua AI, Dervişoğlu R, Hebestreit A, et al. Co-factor-free aggregation of tau into seeding-competent RNA-sequestering amyloid fibrils. Nat Commun. 2021;12:4231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginsberg SD, Crino PB, Lee VMY, Eberwine JH, Trojanowski JQ. Sequestration of RNA in Alzheimer's disease neurofibrillary tangles and senile plaques. Ann Neurol. 1997;41:200-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meier S, Bell M, Lyons DN, Rodriguez-Rivera J, Ingram A, Fontaine SN, et al. Pathological tau promotes neuronal damage by impairing ribosomal function and decreasing protein synthesis. J Neurosci. 2016;36:1001-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shmookler Reis RJ, Atluri R, Balasubramaniam M, Johnson J, Ganne A, Ayyadevara S. “Protein aggregates” contain RNA and DNA, entrapped by misfolded proteins but largely rescued by slowing translational elongation. Aging Cell. 2021;20:e13326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gouras GK, Tsai J, Naslund J, Vincent B, Edgar M, Checler F, et al. Intraneuronal Aβ42 accumulation in human brain. Am J Pathol. 2000;156:15-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kovachev PS, Gomes MP, Cordeiro Y, Ferreira NC, Valadão LPF, Ascari LM, et al. RNA modulates aggregation of the recombinant mammalian prion protein by direct interaction. Sci Rep. 2019;9:12406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cordeiro Y, Vieira T, Kovachev PS, Sanyal S, Silva JL. Modulation of p53 and prion protein aggregation by RNA. Biochim Biophys Acta Proteins Proteom. 2019;1867:933-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pichla M, Bartosz G, Sadowska-Bartosz I. The antiaggregative and antiamyloidogenic properties of nanoparticles: a promising tool for the treatment and diagnostics of neurodegenerative diseases. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2020;2020:3534570.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Q, Huang T, Zhang L, Zhou Y, Luo H, Xu H, et al. Dysregulation of ubiquitin-proteasome system in neurodegenerative diseases. Front Aging Neurosci. 2016;8:303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arispe N, Pollard HB, Rojas E. Giant multilevel cation channels formed by Alzheimer disease amyloid beta-protein [A beta P-(1-40)] in bilayer membranes. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1993;90:10573-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue S. In situ A beta pores in AD brain are cylindrical assembly of A beta protofilaments. Amyloid. 2008;15:223-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart KL, Radford SE. Amyloid plaques beyond Aβ: a survey of the diverse modulators of amyloid aggregation. Biophys Rev. 2017;9:405-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eshraghi M, Karunadharma PP, Blin J, Shahani N, Ricci EP, Michel A, et al. Mutant Huntingtin stalls ribosomes and represses protein synthesis in a cellular model of Huntington disease. Nat Commun. 2021;12:1461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jinwal UK, O'Leary JC, Borysov SI, Jones JR, Li Q, Koren J, et al. Hsc70 rapidly engages Tau after microtubule destabilization. J Biol Chem. 2010;285:16798-805.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
