<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35118759</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2702</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>03</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical nursing</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Nurs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Peripheral intravenous catheter securement: An integrative review of contemporary literature around medical adhesive tapes and supplementary securement products.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jocn.16237</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesise evidence related to medical adhesive tapes and supplementary securement products for peripheral intravenous catheters in adults, to prevent complications and device failure.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Integrative review informed by Whittemore and Knafl and reported in accordance with the PRISMA 2020 statement.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, US National Library of Medicine National Institutes of Health, EMBASE/MEDLINE and Cumulative Index to Nursing and Allied Health were searched from 2000-21 September 2020.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="REVIEW METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Studies enrolling hospitalised participants &gt;16 years with peripheral intravenous catheters secured by medical adhesive tapes, or supplementary products (bandage, splint and sutureless securement device), were eligible. Quality appraisal was performed using Critical Appraisal Skills Program checklists.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Nineteen studies met criteria, including 43,683 peripheral intravenous catheters. Quality appraisal identified high or unclear risk of bias in 58% of studies. Nonsterile tape was the most common intervention tested (14 studies), alone or in multiproduct combinations. Nonsterile tape directly over insertion sites was associated with increased PIVC failure and complications. Sutureless securement devices potentially reduce failure and complications. Multiproduct combinations were very common. Practice recommendations regarding other tapes and secondary securement products are challenging, due to conflicting, or lack of, evidence.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Tapes and secondary securement product evidence are limited, and over half of the studies are of low methodological quality. This review found nonsterile tape was associated with increased failure and complications; multiproduct dressing and securement bundles were prevalent; and significant evidence gaps exist particularly regarding bandages and splints. The results provide nurses with evidence of medical adhesive tapes and supplementary product effectiveness for peripheral intravenous catheter securement, and future research directions to reduce unacceptably high failure and complication rates. Larger rigorously conducted randomised controlled trials are needed to add to current evidence.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Journal of Clinical Nursing published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Corley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amanda</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4250-4077</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery &amp; AVATAR Group, Menzies Health Queensland, Griffith University, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nursing and Midwifery Research Centre, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Herston, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing, Midwifery and Social Work, University of Queensland, Saint Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marsh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicole</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5779-1304</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery &amp; AVATAR Group, Menzies Health Queensland, Griffith University, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nursing and Midwifery Research Centre, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Herston, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing, Midwifery and Social Work, University of Queensland, Saint Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Herston Infectious Diseases Institute, Metro North Hospitals and Health Service, Herston, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ullman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amanda J</ForeName>
            <Initials>AJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8860-5319</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery &amp; AVATAR Group, Menzies Health Queensland, Griffith University, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nursing and Midwifery Research Centre, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Herston, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing, Midwifery and Social Work, University of Queensland, Saint Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Children's Health Queensland Hospital and Health Service, South Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rickard</LastName>
            <ForeName>Claire M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6341-7415</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Midwifery &amp; AVATAR Group, Menzies Health Queensland, Griffith University, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nursing and Midwifery Research Centre, Royal Brisbane and Women's Hospital, Herston, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing, Midwifery and Social Work, University of Queensland, Saint Lucia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Herston Infectious Diseases Institute, Metro North Hospitals and Health Service, Herston, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Nurs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9207302</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0962-1067</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intravenous</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">literature review</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nurses</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occlusive dressings</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral venous catheterization</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">securement device</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical tape</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>56</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35118759</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.16237</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexandrou, E., Ray-Barruel, G., Carr, P. J., Frost, S. A., Inwood, S., Higgins, N., Lin, F., Alberto, L., Mermel, L., Rickard, C. M., &amp; OMG Study Group (2018). Use of Short Peripheral Intravenous Catheters: Characteristics, Management, and Outcomes Worldwide. Journal of Hospital Medicine, 13(5), https://doi.org/10.12788/jhm.3039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bausone-Gazda, D., Lefaiver, C. A., &amp; Walters, S. A. (2010). A randomized controlled trial to compare the complications of 2 peripheral intravenous catheter-stabilization systems. Journal of Infusion Nursing, 33(6), 371-384. https://doi.org/10.1097/NAN.0b013e3181f85be2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beringer, R. M. (2008). Study of the adhesiveness of medical tapes when wet, dry or following application of Friars’ balsam. Paediatric Anaesthesia, 18(6), 520-524. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9592.2008.02494.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolton, D. (2010). Improving peripheral cannulation practice at an NHS Trust. Br J Nurs, 19(21), 1346-1350. https://doi.org/10.12968/bjon.2010.19.21.79998</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broadhurst, D., Moureau, N., &amp; Ullman, A. J. (2017). Management of central venous access device-associated skin impairment: An evidence-based algorithm. J Wound Ostomy Continence Nurs, 44(3), 211-220. https://doi.org/10.1097/won.0000000000000322</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cady, M., &amp; Gross, L. (2011). I.V. Tape: A Potential Vector for Infection Newsletter: The Official Journal of the Anesthesia Patient Safety Foundation, 25(3).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chico-Padron, R. M., Carrion-Garcia, L., Delle-Vedove-Rosales, L., Gonzalez-Vargas, C. S., Marrero-Perera, M., Medina-Chico, S., … &amp; Jimenez-Sosa, A. (2011). Comparative safety and costs of transparent versus gauze wound dressings in intravenous catheterization. Journal of Nursing Care Quality, 26(4), 371-376. https://doi.org/10.1097/NCQ.0b013e318210741b</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corley, A. (2019). SECUREment bundles for Peripheral IntraVenous Catheters in general medical and surgical patients: a feasibility trial. http://www.who.int/trialsearch/Trial2.aspx?TrialID=ACTRN12619000026123</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corley, A., Ullman, A. J., Marsh, N., Larsen, E. N., Mihala, G., Harris, P. N. A., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2019). SECUREment bundles to prevent peripheral vascular access device failure - The SECURE-PVAD trial: Study protocol for a pilot randomized control trial. Vascular Access: Canaidan Vascular Access Association, 13(3), 8-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corley, A., Ullman, A. J., Mihala, G., Ray-Barruel, G., Alexandrou, E., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2019). Peripheral intravenous catheter dressing and securement practice is associated with site complications and suboptimal dressing integrity: A secondary analysis of 40,637 catheters. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 100, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2019.103409. 103409</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crowell, J., O'Neil, K., &amp; Drager, L. (2017). Project HANDS: A bundled approach to increase short peripheral catheter dwell time. J Infus Nurs, 40(5), 274-280. https://doi.org/10.1097/NAN.0000000000000237</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalal, S. S., Chawla, D., Singh, J., Agarwal, R. K., Deorari, A. K., &amp; Paul, V. K. (2009). Limb splinting for intravenous cannulae in neonates: A randomised controlled trial. Archives of Disease in Childhood. Fetal and Neonatal Edition, 94(6), F394-396. https://doi.org/10.1136/adc.2008.147595</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delp, J., &amp; Hadaway, L. (2011). New product decisions-the process and outcome for a community health system. Journal of the Association for Vascular Access, 16(2), 74-84. https://doi.org/10.2309/java.16-2-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frey, A. M., &amp; Schears, G. J. (2006). Why are we stuck on tape and suture? A review of catheter securement devices. Journal of Infusion Nursing, 29(1), 34-38. https://doi.org/10.1097/00129804-200601000-00007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorski, L. A., Hadaway, L., Hagle, M. E., Broadhurst, D., Clare, S., Kleidon, T., Meyer, B. M., Nickel, B., Rowley, S., Sharpe, E., &amp; Alexander, M. (2021). Infusion therapy standards of practice, 8th edition. Journal of Infusion Nursing, 44(1S), S1-S224. https://doi.org/10.1097/NAN.0000000000000396</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gunther, S. C., Schwebel, C., Hamidfar-Roy, R., Bonadona, A., Lugosi, M., Ara-Somohano, C.,… &amp; Timsit, J. F. (2016). Complications of intravascular catheters in ICU: Definitions, incidence and severity. A randomized controlled trial comparing usual transparent dressings versus new-generation dressings (the ADVANCED study). Intensive Care Medicine, 42(11), 1753-1765. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00134-016-4582-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris, P. N. A., Ashhurst-Smith, C., Berenger, S. J., Shoobert, A., &amp; Ferguson, J. K. (2012). Adhesive tape in the health care setting: another high-risk fomite? Medical Journal of Australia, 196(1), 34. https://doi.org/10.5694/mja11.11211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helm, R. E., Klausner, J. D., Klemperer, J. D., Flint, L. M., &amp; Huang, E. (2015). Accepted but unacceptable: peripheral IV catheter failure. J Infus Nurs, 38(3), 189-203. https://doi.org/10.1097/nan.0000000000000100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopia, H., Latvala, E., &amp; Liimatainen, L. (2016). Reviewing the methodology of an integrative review. Scandinavian Journal of Caring Sciences, 30(4), 662-669. https://doi.org/10.1111/scs.12327</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larsen, E. N., Marsh, N., O'Brien, C., Monteagle, E., Friese, C., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2020). Inherent and modifiable risk factors for peripheral venous catheter failure during cancer treatment: A prospective cohort study. Supportive Care in Cancer, 29(3), 1487-1496. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00520-020-05643-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maki, D. G., Kluger, D. M., &amp; Crnich, C. J. (2006). The risk of bloodstream infection in adults with different intravascular devices: A systematic review of 200 published prospective studies. Mayo Clinic Proceedings, 81(9), 1159-1171. https://doi.org/10.4065/81.9.1159</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malyon, L., Ullman, A. J., Phillips, N., Young, J., Kleidon, T., Murfield, J., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2014). Peripheral intravenous catheter duration and failure in paediatric acute care: A prospective cohort study. Emerg Med Australas, 26(6), 602-608. https://doi.org/10.1111/1742-6723.12305</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marsh, N., Webster, J., Flynn, J., Mihala, G., Hewer, B., Fraser, J., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2015). Securement methods for peripheral venous catheters to prevent failure: A randomised controlled pilot trial. The Journal of Vascular Access, 16(3), 237-244. https://doi.org/10.5301/jva.5000348</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marsh, N., Webster, J., Larsen, E., Cooke, M., Mihala, G., &amp; Rickard, C. (2018). Observational study of peripheral intravenous catheter outcomes in adult hospitalized patients: A multivariable analysis of peripheral intravenous catheter failure. Journal of Hospital Medicine, 13(2), 83-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marsh, N., Webster, J., Mihala, G., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2015). Devices and dressings to secure peripheral venous catheters to prevent complications. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, https://doi.org/10.1002/14651858.CD011070.pub2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNeill, E. E., Hines, N. L., &amp; Phariss, R. (2009). A clinical trial of a new all-in-one peripheral-short catheter. JAVA - Journal of the Association for Vascular Access, 14(1), 46-51. https://doi.org/10.2309/java.14-1-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miliani, K., Taravella, R., Thillard, D., Chauvin, V., Martin, E., Edouard, S., &amp; Astagneau, P. (2017). Peripheral venous catheter-related adverse events: Evaluation from a multicentre epidemiological study in France (the CATHEVAL Project). PLoS One, 12(1), e0168637. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0168637</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Health and Medical Research Council (2009). NHMRC levels of evidence and grades for recommendations for developers of guidelines. Australian. Government Retrieved from https://www.nhmrc.gov.au/sites/default/files/images/NHMRC%20Levels%20and%20Grades%20(2009).pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>New, K. A., Webster, J., Marsh, N. M., &amp; Hewer, B. (2014). Intravascular device use, management, documentation and complications: a point prevalence survey. Australian Health Review, 38(3), 345-349. https://doi.org/10.1071/ah13111</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Penney-Timmons, E. (2005). Decreased costs/improved outcomes with standardized intravenous equipment. Journal of the Association for Vascular Access, 10(1), 20-23. https://doi.org/10.2309/1552-8855-10.1.20</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ray-Barruel, G., Polit, D. F., Murfield, J. E., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2014). Infusion phlebitis assessment measures: a systematic review. Journal of Evaluation in Clinical Practice, 20(2), 191-202. https://doi.org/10.1111/jep.12107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redelmeier, D. A., &amp; Livesley, N. J. (1999). Adhesive tape and intravascular-catheter-associated infections. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 14(6), 373-375. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1525-1497.1999.00355.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rickard, C., Marsh, N., Webster, J., Runnegar, N., Larsen, E., McGrail, M., &amp; Playford, E. G. (2018). Dressings and securements for the prevention of peripheral intravenous catheter failure (SAVE Trial) in adults: a pragmatic, randomised, controlled, superiority trial. The Lancet, 392(10145), 419-430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rickard, C. M., &amp; Ray-Barruel, G. (2017). Peripheral intravenous catheter assessment: Beyond phlebitis. Lancet Haematol, 4(9), e402-e403. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2352-3026(17)30145-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Royal College of Nursing (2016). Standards for infusion therapy, 4th ed. Royal College of Nursing.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Royer, T. (2003). Improving short peripheral IV outcomes: A clinical trial of two securement methods. The Journal of the Association for Vascular Access, 8(4), 45-49. https://doi.org/10.2309/155288503774651805</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell, E., Chan, R. J., Marsh, N., &amp; New, K. (2014). A point prevalence study of cancer nursing practices for managing intravascular devices in an Australian tertiary cancer center. European Journal of Oncology Nursing, 18(3), 231-235. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejon.2013.11.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salles, F. T., Santos, V. L., Secoli, S. R., Aron, S., Debbio, C. B., Baptista, C. C., &amp; Rogenski, N. M. (2007). A comparison and cost-effectiveness analysis of peripheral catheter dressings. Ostomy Wound Manage, 53(9), 26-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schears, G. J. (2006). Summary of product trials for 10, 164 patients: comparing an intravenous stabilizing device to tape. Journal of Infusion Nursing, 29(4), 225-231. https://doi.org/10.1097/00129804-200607000-00009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulz, K. F., Altman, D. G., &amp; Moher, D. (2010). CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. PLoS Med, 7(3), e1000251. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pmed.1000251</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simin, D., Milutinović, D., Turkulov, V., &amp; Brkic, S. (2019). Incidence, severity and risk factors of peripheral intravenous cannula-induced complications: An observational prospective study. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 28(9-10), 1585-1599. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.14760</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, B. (2006). Peripheral intravenous catheter dwell times: a comparison of 3 securement methods for implementation of a 96-hour scheduled change protocol. Journal of Infusion Nursing, 29(1), 14-17. https://doi.org/10.1097/00129804-200601000-00004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ter, N., Yavuz, M., Aydoğdu, S., &amp; Kaya Bicer, E. (2015). The effect of 2 adhesive products on skin integrity used for fixation of hip and knee surgical dressings: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Wound, Ostomy &amp; Continence Nursing, 42(2), 145-150. https://doi.org/10.1097/won.0000000000000112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thayer, D. (2012). Skin damage associated with intravenous therapy: common problems and strategies for prevention. J Infus Nurs, 35(6), 390-401. https://doi.org/10.1097/NAN.0b013e318270a91e</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullman, A. J., Cooke, M., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2015). Examining the role of securement and dressing products to prevent central venous access device failure: a narrative review. The Journal of the Association for Vascular Access, 20(2), 99-110. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.java.2015.03.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullman, A. J., Mihala, G., O'Leary, K., Marsh, N., Woods, C., Bugden, S., Scott, M., &amp; Rickard, C. M. (2019). Skin complications associated with vascular access devices: A secondary analysis of 13 studies involving 10,859 devices. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 91, 6-13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2018.10.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whittemore, R., &amp; Knafl, K. (2005). The integrative review: updated methodology. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 52(5), 546-553. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2648.2005.03621.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
