<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35139848</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2474</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>09</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMC musculoskeletal disorders</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of Kinesio taping on forearm supination/pronation performance fatigability.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>131</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>131</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">131</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12891-022-05068-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Repetitive exertion in supination/pronation could increase the risk of forearm diseases due to fatigue. Kinesio taping (KT) is a physical therapy technique that decreases muscle tone and musculoskeletal disorders (MSDs) risk. Many assumptions about taping have been made and several studies have considered the taping applications; however, the effect of KT on strength and fatigue of the forearm supination/pronation remains unclear. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the effect of KT on forearm performance fatigability.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A screwing test was constructed to measure the forearm force loss and screwing efficiency during repetitive supination/pronation. Data from 18 healthy adults who underwent both KT and no taping (NT) sessions were used to investigate the forearm strength change in terms of grip force (GF), driving torque (DT), and push force (PF). The maximal isometric forces before and after the screwing test and force decreasing rate (efficiency) during screwing were evaluated to assess the performance fatigability in KT and NT conditions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A statistically significant force loss (FL) in maximal isometric GF (p = 0.039) and maximal isometric DT (p = 0.044); however, no significant difference was observed in maximal isometric PF (p = 0.426) between NT and KT. KT provides greater screwing efficiency than NT.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">KT could not improve FL in the maximal muscle strength of the forearm in healthy subjects. KT on the forearm was associated with a lesser decline in DT efficiency than NT, implying that KT could decrease the loss rate of muscle strength and delay the development of fatigue; however, the KT did not yield improvements in PF while performing screwing tasks.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hsiao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chih-Kun</ForeName>
            <Initials>CK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, E-Da Hospital, No. 1 E-Da Rd, Yuan-Chau District, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi-Jung</ForeName>
            <Initials>YJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, E-Da Hospital, No. 1 E-Da Rd, Yuan-Chau District, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chih-Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>CW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Industrial and Systems Engineering, Chung Yuan Christian University, Chung Li, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hsiung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jen-Chou</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, Cheng Shiu University, No.840, Chengcing Rd., Niaosong Dist, Kaohsiung City, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hsiao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hao-Yuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>HY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, E-Da Hospital, No. 1 E-Da Rd, Yuan-Chau District, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yung-Chuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>YC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Vehicle Engineering, National Pingtung University of Science and Technology, No. 1, Shuefu Road, Neipu, Pingtung, 91201, Taiwan. chuan@mail.npust.edu.tw.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuan-Kun</ForeName>
            <Initials>YK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, E-Da Hospital, No. 1 E-Da Rd, Yuan-Chau District, Kaohsiung, Taiwan. ed100130@edah.org.tw.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMC Musculoskelet Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100968565</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1471-2474</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005542" MajorTopicYN="Y">Forearm</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011403" MajorTopicYN="N">Pronation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013484" MajorTopicYN="N">Supination</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Force loss</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesio taping</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Performance fatigability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Supination/pronation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>29</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35139848</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8826704</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-022-05068-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12891-022-05068-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent-Braun JA, Fitts RH, Christie A. Skeletal muscle fatigue. Compr Physiol. 2012;2:997Y1044.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cullen W, Kearney Y, Bury G. Prevalence of fatigue in general practice. Ir J Med Sci. 2002;171:10–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11993585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuda K, Dobbins JG, Wilson LJ, Dunn RA, Wilcox K, Smallwood D. An epidemiologic study of fatigue with relevance for the chronic fatigue syndrome. J Psychiatr Res. 1997;31:19–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9201644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen DG, Lamb GD, Westerblad H. Skeletal muscle fatigue: cellular mechanisms. Physiol Rev. 2008;88:287Y332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18195089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor JL, Amann M, Duchateau J, Meeusen R, Rice CL. Neural contributions to muscle fatigue: from the brain to the muscle and back again. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2016;48(11):2294–2306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5033663</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27003703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hashemi L, Webster BS, Clancy EA, Courtney TC. Length of disability and cost of work-related musculoskeletal disorders of the upper extremity. J Occup Environ Med. 1998;40(3):261–269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9531097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsiao CK, Tu YK, Tsai YJ, Yang CY, Lu CW. Forearm muscular strength and performance fatigability in orthopaedic surgeons when performing bone screw fixations. Appl Ergon. 2020;87:103135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32501253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drury CG. Handles for manual materials handles. Appl Ergon. 1980;11(1):35–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15676373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang CH, Wang MJJ. Evaluating the effects of activation mode, torque and horizontal operating distance on the hand-arm response while operating pneumatic screwdrivers. Int J Ind Ergon. 2001;28(3–4):171–179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang CH, Wang MJJ. Evaluating factors that influence hand-arm stress while operating an electric screwdriver. Appl Ergon. 2000;31(3):283–289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10855451</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snook SH, Vaillancourt DR, Ciriello VM, Webster BS. Psychophysical studies of repetitive wrist flexion and extension. Ergonomics. 1995;38(7):1488–1507.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7635136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snook SH, Vaillancourt DR, Ciriello VM, Webster BS. Maximum acceptable forces for repetitive ulnar deviation of the wrist. Am Ind Hyg Assoc J. 1997;58(7):509–517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9208467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snook SH, Ciriello VM, Webster BS. Maximum acceptable forces for repetitive wrist extension with a pinch grip. Int J Ind Ergon. 1999;24(6):579–590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JH, Yoo WG, Lee KS. Effect of the head-neck rotation and kinesio taping of the flexor muscles on dominant- hand grip strength. J Phys Ther Sci. 2010;22(3):285–289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osterhues DJ. The use of kinesio taping in the management of traumatic patella dislocation. A case study. Physiother Theory Pract. 2004;20(4):267–270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semple S, Esterhuysen C, Grace J. The effect of kinesio ankle taping on postural stability in semiprofessional rugby union playes. J Phys Ther Sci. 2012;24(12):1239–1242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang HY, Chou KY, Lin JJ, Lin CF, Wang CH. Immediate effect of forearm Kinesio taping on maximal grip strength and force sense in healthy collegiate athletes. Phys Ther Sport. 2010;11(4):122–127.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21055705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fratocchi G, Mattia FD, Rossi R, Mangone M, Santilli V, Paoloni M. Influence of Kinesio taping applied over biceps brachii on isokinetic elbow peak torque. A placebo controlled study in a population of young healthy subjects. J Sci Med Sport. 2013;16(3):245–249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22771110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin J, Guo ML, Wang H, Lin C, Xu G, Chen A, Chen S, Wang S. Effects of Kinesio tape on delayed onset muscle soreness: a systematic review and Meta-analysis. Biomed Res Int. 2021;2021:6692828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8188598</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34159201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanik ZH, Citaker S, Yilmaz Demirtas C, Celik Bukan N, Celik B, Gunaydin G. Effects of Kinesio taping on the relief of delayed onset muscle soreness: a randomized, Placebo-Controlled Trial. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;28(8):781–786.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30040009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaya E, Zinnuroglu M, Tugcu I. Kinesio taping compared to physical therapy modalities for the treatment of shoulder impingement syndrome. Clin Rheumatol. 2011;30(2):201–207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20443039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee NH, Jung HC, Ok G, Lee S. Acute effects of kinesio taping on muscle function and self-perceived fatigue level in healthy adults. Eur J Sport Sci. 2017;17(6):757–764.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28287046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lemos TV, Júnior JRS, Santos MGRD, Rosa MMN, Silva LGCD, Matheus JPC. Kinesio taping effects with different directions and tensions on strength and range of movement of the knee: a randomized controlled trial. Braz J Phys Ther. 2018;22(4):283–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6095100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29728298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armstrong TJ. An ergonomic guide to carpal tunnel syndrome. Am Ind Hyg Assoc J. 1984.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez JE, Fredericks TK, Marley RJ. The psychophysical approach in upper extremities work. Contemp Ergonom. 1995:456–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murillo-Escobar J, Jaramillo-Munera YE, Orrego-Metaute DA, Delgado-Trejos E, Cuesta-Frau D. Muscle fatigue analysis during dynamic contractions based on biomechanical features and permutation entropy. Math Biosci Eng. 2020;17(3):2592–2615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32233556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Muscle fatigue: what, why and how it influences muscle function. J Physiol. 2008;586(1):11–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375565</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17702815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Constantin-Teodosiu D, Constantin D. Molecular mechanisms of muscle fatigue. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(21):11587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8584022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34769017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartels B, de Groot JF, Habets LE, Wadman RI, Asselman FL, Nieuwenhuis EES, van Eijk RPA, Goedee HS, van der Pol WL. Correlates of fatigability in patients with spinal muscular atrophy. Neurology. 2021;96(6):e845–e852.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33219141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh NB, Nussbaum MA, Madigan MA. Evaluation of circumferential pressure as an intervention to mitigate postural instability induced by localized muscle fatigue at the ankle. Int J Ind Ergon. 2009;39(5):821–827.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naugle KE, Hackett J, Aqeel D, Naugle KM. Effect of different Kinesio tape tensions on experimentally-induced thermal and muscle pain in healthy adults. PLoS One. 2021;16(11):e0259433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8570489</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34739522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu K, Duan Z, Chen L, Wen Z, Zhu S, Qu Q, Chen W, Zhang S, Yu B. Short-term effect of different taping methods on local skin temperature in healthy adults. Front Physiol. 2020;11:488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251151</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32508677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boobphachart D, Manimmanakorn N, Manimmanakorn A, Thuwakum W, Hamlin MJ. Effects of elastic taping, non-elastic taping and static stretching on recovery after intensive eccentric exercise. Res Sports Med. 2017;25(2):181–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28121177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thelen MD, Dauber JA, Stoneman PD. The clinical efficacy of kinesio tape for shoulder pain: a randomized, double-blinded, clinical trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2008;38(7):389–395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18591761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fenech RK, Ryan CR. Mechanistic insights on muscle fatigue in ageing adults. J Physiol. 2019;97:5749–5750.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31598968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida A, Kahanov L. The effect of kinesio taping on lower trunk range of motions. Res Sports Med. 2007;15(2):103–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17578750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aktas G, Baltaci G. Does does kinesiotaping increase knee muscles strength and functional performance? Isokinet Exerc Sci. 2011;19(2):149–155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osorio JA, Vairo GL, Rozea GD, Bosha PJ, Millard RL, Aukerman DF, Aukerman DF, Sebastianelli WJ. The effects of two therapeutic patellofemoral taping techniques on strength, endurance, and pain responses. Phys Ther Sport. 2013;14(4):199–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23557728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaheen AF, Villa C, Lee YN, Bull AM, Alexander CM. Scapular taping alters kinematics in asymptomatic subjects. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2013;23(2):326–333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23261085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bicici S, Karatas N, Baltaci G. Effect of athletic taping and kinesiotaping on measurements of functional performance in basketball players with chronic inversion ankle sprains. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2012;7(2):154–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3325641</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firth BL, Dingley P, Davies ER, Lewis JS, Alexander CM. The effect of kinesiotape on function, pain, and motoneuronal excitability in healthy people and people with Achilles tendinopathy. Clin J Sport Med. 2010;20(6):416–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21079436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lins CA, Neto FL, Amorim AB, Macedo Lde B, Brasileiro JS. Kinesio taping does not alter neuromuscular performance of femoral quadriceps or lower limb function in healthy subjects: randomized, blind, controlled, clinical trial. Man Ther. 2013;18(1):41–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong OM, Cheung RT, Li RC. Isokinetic knee function in healthy subjects with and without kinesio taping. Phys Ther Sport. 2012;13(4):255–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23068902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yam ML, Yang Z, Zee BC, Chong KC. Effects of Kinesio tape on lower limb muscle strength, hop test, and vertical jump performances: a meta-analysis. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2019;20(1):212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31088546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandes de Jesus J, de Almeida NA, Bezerra Nakaoka G, Curcio Dos Reis A, Fukuda TY, Fernandes BF. Kinesio taping effect on quadriceps strength and lower limb function of healthy individuals: a blinded, controlled, randomized, clinical trial. Phys Ther Sport. 2016;18:27–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26708093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cid MM, Januario LB, Moreira RFC, Côté JN, Madeleine P, Oliveira AB. Does sEMG normalization change results on sex differences in the activation of the shoulder girdle muscles during a simulated work task? Appl Ergon. 2020;85:103044.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31932265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soo Y, Sugi M, Yokoi H, Arai T, Kato R, Ota J. Quantitative estimation of muscle fatigue on cyclic handgrip tasks. Int J Ind Ergon. 2012;42(1):103–112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konz S. Environmental fatigue allowances. Int J Ind Ergon. 1995;2(1):5–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasti ZA, Shamsoddini A, Dalvand H, Labaf S. The effect of Kinesio taping on handgrip and active range of motion of hand in children with cerebral palsy. Iran J Child Neurol. 2017;11(4):43–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5703628</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29201123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grassi B, Rossiter HB, Zoladz JA. Skeletal muscle fatigue and decreased efficiency: two sides of the same coin? Exerc Sport Sci Rev. 2015;43(2):75–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25688762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
