<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35138654</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-765X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>74</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Letters in applied microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lett Appl Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Cytolysin A-mediated protein exportation efficiency and its role in enhancing the fitness of live recombinant Salmonella Typhi vaccine strain.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>820</StartPage>
          <EndPage>830</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>820-830</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/lam.13669</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The genetic fusion of cytolysin A (clyA) to heterologous antigen expressed in live Salmonella vector demonstrated efficient translocation into periplasmic space and extracellular medium. Accumulating evidence has shown that clyA-mediated antigen delivery improved growth fitness and enhanced immunogenicity of live vector vaccine, but the factors influencing this protein exportation has not been investigated. In this study, Toxoplasma gondii antigen fused at C-terminal of clyA protein was expressed in live S. Typhi vector via both plasmid and chromosomal-based expressions. The bivalent strains showed comparable growth rates as monovalent strains, but in varies antigen exportation efficiency. ClyA-fusion antigen with positive charges was translocated to the extracellular spaces, whereas those with negative charges were retained in the cytoplasm. Furthermore, excessive cellular resources expenditure on antigen expression, especially antigen with larger size, could limit the clyA-fusion antigen exportation, resulting in undesirable metabolic burden that eventually affects the growth fitness. Altogether, the present work indicates potential linkage of factors mainly on antigen properties and expression platforms that may affect clyA-mediated antigen delivery to enhance the growth fitness of live vector strain.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Letters in Applied Microbiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society for Applied Microbiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Loh</LastName>
            <ForeName>F-K</ForeName>
            <Initials>FK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biomedical Sciences, School of Pharmacy, University of Nottingham Malaysia, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nathan</LastName>
            <ForeName>S</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Science &amp; Technology, Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chow</LastName>
            <ForeName>S-C</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Science, Monash University Malaysia, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fang</LastName>
            <ForeName>C-M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4934-5697</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biomedical Sciences, School of Pharmacy, University of Nottingham Malaysia, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Lett Appl Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8510094</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0266-8254</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001426">Bacterial Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014613">Vaccines, Attenuated</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014614">Vaccines, Synthetic</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>126465-35-8</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D054353">Perforin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001426" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bacterial Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054353" MajorTopicYN="N">Perforin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012485" MajorTopicYN="Y">Salmonella typhi</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014613" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Attenuated</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014614" MajorTopicYN="N">Vaccines, Synthetic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Salmonella Typhi</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial growth kinetics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytolysin A</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">live vector vaccine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein exportation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35138654</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/lam.13669</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avelino, A.R. (2014) Designing a pore-forming toxin cytolysin A (ClyA) specific to target cancer cells, Masters Theses. 67, University of Massachusetts Amherst.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachmann, M.F. and Jennings, G.T. (2010) Vaccine delivery: a matter of size, geometry, kinetics and molecular patterns. Nat Rev Immunol 10, 787-796.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beitelshees, M., Hill, A., Li, Y., Chen, M., Ahmadi, M.K., Smith, R.J.J., Andreadis, S.T., Rostami, P. et al. (2019) Antigen delivery format variation and formulation stability through use of a hybrid vector. Vaccine: X 1, 100012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cesbron-Delauw, M.F., Lecordier, L. and Mercier, C. (1996) Role of secretory dense granule organelles in the pathogenesis of toxoplasmosis. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol 219, 59-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, D.J., Osterrieder, N., Metzger, S.M., Buckles, E., Doody, A.M., DeLisa, M.P. and Putnam, D. (2010) Delivery of foreign antigens by engineered outer membrane vesicle vaccines. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 107, 3099-3104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chowdhury, M.Y.E., Li, R., Kim, J.H., Park, M.E., Kim, T.H., Pathinayake, P., Weeratunga, P., Song, M.K. et al. (2014) Mucosal vaccination with recombinant Lactobacillus casei-displayed CTA1-conjugated consensus matrix protein-2 (sM2) induces broad protection against divergent influenza subtypes in BALB/c mice. PLoS One 9, e94051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Datsenko, K.A. and Wanner, B.L. (2000) One-step inactivation of chromosomal genes in Escherichia coli K-12 using PCR products. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 97, 6640-6645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dodangeh, S., Fasihi-Ramandi, M., Daryani, A., Valadan, R., Asgarian-Omran, H., Hosseininejad, Z., Nayeri Chegeni, T., Pagheh, A.S. et al. (2021) Protective efficacy by a novel multi-epitope vaccine, including MIC3, ROP8, and SAG1, against acute Toxoplasma gondii infection in BALB/c mice. Microb Pathog 153, 104764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freudl, R. (2018) Signal peptides for recombinant protein secretion in bacterial expression systems. Microb Cell Fact 17, 52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galen, J.E., Chinchilla, M., Pasetti, M.F., Wang, J.Y., Zhao, L., Arciniega-Martinez, I., Silverman, D.J. and Levine, M.M. (2009) Mucosal immunization with attenuated Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi expressing protective antigen of anthrax toxin (PA83) primes monkeys for accelerated serum antibody responses to parenteral PA83 vaccine. J Infect Dis 199, 326-335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galen, J.E. and Levine, M.M. (2001) Can a “flawless” live vector vaccine strain be engineered? Trends Microbiol 9, 372-376.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galen, J.E., Wang, J.Y., Carrasco, J.A., Lloyd, S.A., Mellado-Sanchez, G., Diaz-McNair, J., Franco, O., Buskirk, A.D. et al. (2015) A bivalent typhoid live vector vaccine expressing both chromosome- and plasmid-encoded Yersinia pestis antigens fully protects against murine lethal pulmonary plague infection. Infect Immun 83, 161-172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galen, J.E., Zhao, L., Chinchilla, M., Wang, J.Y., Pasetti, M.F., Green, J. and Levine, M.M. (2004) Adaptation of the endogenous Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi clyA-encoded hemolysin for antigen export enhances the immunogenicity of anthrax protective antigen domain 4 expressed by the attenuated live-vector vaccine strain CVD 908-htrA. Infect Immun 72, 7096-7106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaupp, R., Lei, S., Reed, J.M., Peisker, H., Boyle-Vavra, S., Bayer, A.S., Bischoff, M., Herrmann, M. et al. (2015) Staphylococcus aureus metabolic adaptations during the transition from a daptomycin susceptibility phenotype to a daptomycin nonsusceptibility phenotype. Antimicrob Agents Chemother 59, 4226-4238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerritzen, M.J.H., Martens, D.E., Wijffels, R.H., van der Pol, L. and Stork, M. (2017) Bioengineering bacterial outer membrane vesicles as vaccine platform. Biotechnol Adv 35, 565-574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giordano, N., Mairet, F., Gouzé, J.L., Geiselmann, J. and de Jong, H. (2016) Dynamical allocation of cellular resources as an optimal control problem: novel insights into microbial growth strategies. PLoS Comput Biol 12, e1004802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang, W., Wang, S., Yao, Y., Xia, Y., Yang, X., Li, K., Sun, P., Liu, C. et al. (2016) Employing Escherichia coli-derived outer membrane vesicles as an antigen delivery platform elicits protective immunity against Acinetobacter baumannii infection. Sci Rep 6, 37242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeffers, V., Tampaki, Z., Kim, K. and Sullivan, W.J. (2018) A latent ability to persist: differentiation in Toxoplasma gondii. Cell Mol Life Sci 75, 2355-2373.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaur, J., Kumar, A. and Kaur, J. (2018) Strategies for optimization of heterologous protein expression in E. coli: roadblocks and reinforcements. Int J Biol Macromol 106, 803-822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuipers, K., Daleke-Schermerhorn, M.H., Jong, W.S.P., ten Hagen-Jongman, C.M., van Opzeeland, F., Simonetti, E., Luirink, J. and de Jonge, M.I. (2015) Salmonella outer membrane vesicles displaying high densities of pneumococcal antigen at the surface offer protection against colonization. Vaccine 33, 2022-2029.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loh, F.-K., Nathan, S., Chow, S.-C. and Fang, C.-M. (2021) Immunogenicity and protection efficacy of enhanced fitness recombinant Salmonella Typhi monovalent and bivalent vaccine strains against acute toxoplasmosis. Pathog Glob Health 115, 392-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ludwig, A., Bauer, S., Benz, R., Bergmann, B. and Goebel, W. (1999) Analysis of the SlyA-controlled expression, subcellular localization and pore-forming activity of a 34 kDa haemolysin (ClyA) from Escherichia coli K-12. Mol Microbiol 31, 557-567.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maresca, M., Erler, A., Fu, J., Friedrich, A., Zhang, Y. and Stewart, A.F. (2010) Single-stranded heteroduplex intermediates in λ Red homologous recombination. BMC Mol Biol, 11, 54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng, D.T.W. and Sarkar, C.A. (2013) Engineering signal peptides for enhanced protein secretion from Lactococcus lactis. Appl Environ Microbiol 79, 347-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pathangey, L., Kohler, J.J., Isoda, R. and Brown, T.A. (2009) Effect of expression level on immune responses to recombinant oral Salmonella enterica serovar Typhimurium vaccines. Vaccine 27, 2707-2711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piao, H.H., Seong, J., Song, M.K., Kim, Y.U., Shin, D.J., Choy, H.E. and Hong, Y. (2009) The bacterial surface expression of SARS viral epitope using Salmonella Typhi cytolysin A. J Bacteriol Virol 39, 103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proshkin, S., Rahmouni, A.R., Mironov, A. and Nudler, E. (2010) Cooperation between translating ribosomes and RNA polymerase in transcription elongation. Science 328, 504-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pyne, M.E., Moo-Young, M., Chung, D.A. and Chou, C.P. (2015) Coupling the CRISPR/Cas9 system with lambda red recombineering enables simplified chromosomal gene replacement in Escherichia coli. Appl Environ Microbiol 81, 5103-5114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roche, J.K., Rojo, A.L., Costa, L.B., Smeltz, R., Manque, P., Woehlbier, U., Bartelt, L., Galen, J. et al. (2013) Intranasal vaccination in mice with an attenuated Salmonella enterica serovar 908htr A expressing Cp15 of Cryptosporidium: impact of malnutrition with preservation of cytokine secretion. Vaccine 31, 912-918.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roderer, D. and Glockshuber, R. (2017) Assembly mechanism of the α-pore-forming toxin cytolysin a from Escherichia coli. Philos Trans R Soc B Biol Sci 372, 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shachrai, I., Zaslaver, A., Alon, U. and Dekel, E. (2010) Cost of unneeded proteins in E. coli is reduced after several generations in exponential growth. Mol Cell 38, 758-767.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siachoque, H., Guzman, F., Burgos, J., Patarroyo, M.E. and Gomez Marin, J.E. (2006) Toxoplasma gondii: immunogenicity and protection by P30 peptides in a murine model. Exp Parasitol 114, 62-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, M.A. and Bidochka, M.J. (1998) Bacterial fitness and plasmid loss: the importance of culture conditions and plasmid size. Can J Microbiol 44, 351-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart, S.E., Kondos, S.C., Matthews, A.Y., D’Angelo, M.E., Dunstone, M.A., Whisstock, J.C., Trapani, J.A. and Bird, P.I. (2014) The perforin pore facilitates the delivery of cationic cargos. J Biol Chem 289, 9172-9181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stokes, M.G.M., Titball, R.W., Neeson, B.N., Galen, J.E., Walker, N.J., Stagg, A.J., Jenner, D.C., Thwaite, J.E. et al. (2007) Oral administration of a Salmonella enterica-based vaccine expressing Bacillus anthracis protective antigen confers protection against aerosolized B. anthracis. Infect Immun 75, 1827-1834.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wai, S.N., Lindmark, B., Söderblom, T., Takade, A., Westermark, M., Oscarsson, J., Jass, J., Richter-Dahlfors, A. et al. (2003a) Vesicle-mediated export and assembly of pore-forming oligomers of the enterobacterial ClyA cytotoxin. Cell 115, 25-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wai, S.N., Westermark, M., Oscarsson, J., Jass, J., Maier, E., Benz, R. and Uhlin, B.E. (2003b) Characterization of dominantly negative mutant ClyA cytotoxin proteins in Escherichia coli. J Bacteriol 185, 5491-5499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, J.Y., Harley, R.H. and Galen, J.E. (2013) Novel methods for expression of foreign antigens in live vector vaccines. Hum Vaccines Immunother 9, 1558-1564.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willems, K., Van Meervelt, V., Wloka, C. and Maglia, G. (2017) Single-molecule nanopore enzymology. Philos Trans R Soc B Biol Sci 372, 20160230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zahn, K. (1996) Overexpression of an mRNA dependent on rare codons inhibits protein synthesis and cell growth. Journal of Bacteriology 178, 2926-2933.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Y., Fang, Z., Li, R., Huang, X. and Liu, Q. (2019) Design of outer membrane vesicles as cancer vaccines: a new toolkit for cancer therapy. Cancers 11, 1314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
