<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35142694</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Nerve root magnetic stimulation improves locomotor function following spinal cord injury with electrophysiological improvements and cortical synaptic reconstruction.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2036</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2042</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2036-2042</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.335161</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Following a spinal cord injury, there are usually a number of neural pathways that remain intact in the spinal cord. These residual nerve fibers are important, as they could be used to reconstruct the neural circuits that enable motor function. Our group previously designed a novel magnetic stimulation protocol, targeting the motor cortex and the spinal nerve roots, that led to significant improvements in locomotor function in patients with a chronic incomplete spinal cord injury. Here, we investigated how nerve root magnetic stimulation contributes to improved locomotor function using a rat model of spinal cord injury. Rats underwent surgery to clamp the spinal cord at T10; three days later, the rats were treated with repetitive magnetic stimulation (5 Hz, 25 pulses/train, 20 pulse trains) targeting the nerve roots at the L5-L6 vertebrae. The treatment was repeated five times a week over a period of three weeks. We found that the nerve root magnetic stimulation improved the locomotor function and enhanced nerve conduction in the injured spinal cord. In addition, the nerve root magnetic stimulation promoted the recovery of synaptic ultrastructure in the sensorimotor cortex. Overall, the results suggest that nerve root magnetic stimulation may be an effective, noninvasive method for mobilizing the residual spinal cord pathways to promote the recovery of locomotor function.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ya</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Tongji Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Tongji Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xue</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dong-Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>DD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatobiliary Surgery, Hebei General Hospital, Shijiazhuang, Hebei Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ye-Ran</ForeName>
            <Initials>YR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Baoshan Branch, Shuguang Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ling-Yun</ForeName>
            <Initials>LY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Science, Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ye</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, The Sixth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guang-Yue</ForeName>
            <Initials>GY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Tongji Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Tongji Hospital, School of Medicine, Tongji University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dong-Sheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>DS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Science, Shanghai University of Traditional Chinese Medicine; Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Yueyang Hospital of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine; Rehabilitation Engineering Research Center for Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine, Ministry of Education, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">H-reflex</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">evoked potentials</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motor activity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve conduction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural plasticity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensorimotor cortex</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spinal cord injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synapses</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcranial magnetic stimulation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142694</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848603</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.335161</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_9_2036_335161</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barker AT, Jalinous R, Freeston IL. Non-invasive magnetic stimulation of human motor cortex. Lancet. 1985;1:1106–1107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2860322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basso DM, Beattie MS, Bresnahan JC. Graded histological and locomotor outcomes after spinal cord contusion using the NYU weight-drop device versus transection. Exp Neurol. 1996;139:244–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8654527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulenguez P, Vinay L. Strategies to restore motor functions after spinal cord injury. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2009;19:587–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19896827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bunday KL, Urbin MA, Perez MA. Potentiating paired corticospinal-motoneuronal plasticity after spinal cord injury. Brain Stimul. 2018;11:1083–1092.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29848448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cafferty WB, McGee AW, Strittmatter SM. Axonal growth therapeutics: regeneration or sprouting or plasticity? Trends Neurosci. 2008;31:215–220.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2678051</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18395807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chand P, Jain N. Intracortical and thalamocortical connections of the hand and face representations in somatosensory area 3b of macaque monkeys and effects of chronic spinal cord injuries. J Neurosci. 2015;35:13475–13486.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6605473</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26424892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cirillo G, Di Pino G, Capone F, Ranieri F, Florio L, Todisco V, Tedeschi G, Funke K, Di Lazzaro V. Neurobiological after-effects of non-invasive brain Stimul. Brain Stimul. 2017;10:1–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27931886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Concerto C, Lanza G, Cantone M, Ferri R, Pennisi G, Bella R, Aguglia E. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation in patients with drug-resistant major depression: a six-month clinical follow-up study. Int J Psychiatry Clin Pract. 2015;19:252–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26398527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dattalo P. A review of software for sample size determination. Eval Health Prof. 2009;32:229–248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Lorenzo F, Bonnì S, Picazio S, Motta C, Caltagirone C, Martorana A, Koch G. Effects of cerebellar theta burst stimulation on contralateral motor cortex excitability in patients with Alzheimer's disease. Brain Topogr. 2020;33:613–617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32564167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duan HQ, Wu QL, Yao X, Fan BY, Shi HY, Zhao CX, Zhang Y, Li B, Sun C, Kong XH, Zhou XF, Feng SQ. Nafamostat mesilate attenuates inflammation and apoptosis and promotes locomotor recovery after spinal cord injury. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2018;24:429–438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6489917</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29352519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edgerton VR, Courtine G, Gerasimenko YP, Lavrov I, Ichiyama RM, Fong AJ, Cai LL, Otoshi CK, Tillakaratne NJ, Burdick JW, Roy RR. Training locomotor networks. Brain Res Rev. 2008;57:241–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2288528</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18022244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elmgreen SB, Krogh S, Løve US, Forman A, Kasch H. Neuromodulation in spinal cord injury rehabilitation. Ugeskr Laeger. 2019;181:V02190104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31267931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu J, Wang H, Deng L, Li J. Exercise training promotes functional recovery after spinal cord injury. Neural Plast 2016. 2016 4039580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5168470</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28050288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganzer PD, Darrow MJ, Meyers EC, Solorzano BR, Ruiz AD, Robertson NM, Adcock KS, James JT, Jeong HS, Becker AM, Goldberg MP, Pruitt DT, Hays SA, Kilgard MP, Rennaker RL., 2nd Closed-loop neuromodulation restores network connectivity and motor control after spinal cord injury. eLife. (2018);7:e32058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5849415</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29533186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldring S, Aras E, Weber PC. Comparative study of sensory input to motor cortex in animals and man. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1970;29:537–550.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4098576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Güldner FH, Ingham CA. Increase in postsynaptic density material in optic target neurons of the rat suprachiasmatic nucleus after bilateral enucleation. Neurosci Lett. 1980;17:27–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6302580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo M, Wu L, Song Z, Yang B. Enhancement of neural stem cell proliferation in rats with spinal cord injury by a combination of repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS) and human umbilical cord blood mesenchymal stem cells (hUCB-MSCs) Med Sci Monit. 2020;26:e924445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453755</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32814758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harel R, Schleifer D, Appel S, Attia M, Cohen ZR, Knoller N. Spinal intradural extramedullary tumors: the value of intraoperative neurophysiologic monitoring on surgical outcome. Neurosurg Rev. 2017;40:613–619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harkema S, Gerasimenko Y, Hodes J, Burdick J, Angeli C, Chen Y, Ferreira C, Willhite A, Rejc E, Grossman RG, Edgerton VR. Effect of epidural stimulation of the lumbosacral spinal cord on voluntary movement, standing, and assisted stepping after motor complete paraplegia: a case study. Lancet. 2011;377:1938–1947.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3154251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21601270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hebb D.  The organization of behavior: a neuropsychological theory. New York: Wiley; 1949. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu XC, Lu YB, Yang YN, Kang XW, Wang YG, Ma B, Xing S. Progress in clinical trials of cell transplantation for the treatment of spinal cord injury: how many questions remain unanswered? Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:405–413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7996007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32985458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iarikov DE, Kim BG, Dai HN, McAtee M, Kuhn PL, Bregman BS. Delayed transplantation with exogenous neurotrophin administration enhances plasticity of corticofugal projections after spinal cord injury. J Neurotrauma. 2007;24:690–702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17439351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang JL, Guo XD, Zhang SQ, Wang XG, Wu SF. Repetitive magnetic stimulation affects the microenvironment of nerve regeneration and evoked potentials after spinal cord injury. Neural Regen Res. 2016;11:816–822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4904474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27335567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones DG. Synaptic plasticity and perforated synapses: their relevance for an understanding of abnormal synaptic organization. APMIS Supplementum. 1993;40:25–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8311991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jo HJ, Perez MA. Corticospinal-motor neuronal plasticity promotes exercise-mediated recovery in humans with spinal cord injury. Brain. 2020;143:1368–1382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaegi S, Schwab ME, Dietz V, Fouad K. Electromyographic activity associated with spontaneous functional recovery after spinal cord injury in rats. Eur J Neurosci. 2002;16:249–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12169107</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kakulas BA. Neuropathology: the foundation for new treatments in spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2004;42:549–563.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15346131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katoh H, Yokota K, Fehlings MG. Regeneration of spinal cord connectivity through stem cell transplantation and biomaterial scaffolds. Front Cell Neurosci. 2019;13:248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31244609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khorasanizadeh M, Yousefifard M, Eskian M, Lu Y, Chalangari M, Harrop JS, Jazayeri SB, Seyedpour S, Khodaei B, Hosseini M, Rahimi-Movaghar V. Neurological recovery following traumatic spinal cord injury: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurosurg Spine. 2019;15:1–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30771786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kjell J, Olson L. Rat models of spinal cord injury: from pathology to potential therapies. Dis Models Mechan. 2016;9:1125–1137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5087825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27736748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko MJ, Lim CY. General considerations for sample size estimation in animal study. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2021;74:23–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7862939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33535728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanza G, Cantone M, Arico D, Lanuzza B, Cosentino FII, Paci D, Papotto M, Pennisi M, Bella R, Pennisi G, Paulus W, Ferri R. Clinical and electrophysiological impact of repetitive low-frequency transcranial magnetic stimulation on the sensory-motor network in patients with restless legs syndrome. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2018;11:1756286418759973.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5833163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29511386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lemon RN. Descending pathways in motor control. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2008;31:195–218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18558853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liau LL, Looi QH, Chia WC, Subramaniam T, Ng MH, Law JX. Treatment of spinal cord injury with mesenchymal stem cells. Cell Biosci. 2020;10:112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7510077</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32983406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovett-Barr MR, Satriotomo I, Muir GD, Wilkerson JE, Hoffman MS, Vinit S, Mitchell GS. Repetitive intermittent hypoxia induces respiratory and somatic motor recovery after chronic cervical spinal injury. J Neurosci. 2012;32:3591–3600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3349282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22423083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mao Y, Jin Z, Xu D. Modified transcranial magnetic stimulation for spinal cord injury: report of one case. Zhong Guo Kang Fu Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2019;12:1479–1481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marino RJ, Barros T, Biering-Sorensen F, Burns SP, Donovan WH, Graves DE, Haak M, Hudson LM, Priebe MM. International standards for neurological classification of spinal cord injury. J Spinal Cord Med 26 Suppl. 2003;1:S50–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16296564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng Z, Ng S, Nga V, Teo K, Lwin S, Ning C, Yeo TT. Intradural spinal tumors-review of postoperative outcomes comparing intramedullary and extramedullary tumors from a single institution's experience. World Neurosurg. 2018;109:e229–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28974413</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Shea TM, Burda JE, Sofroniew MV. Cell biology of spinal cord injury and repair. J Clin Invest. 2017;127:3259–3270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5669582</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28737515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oudega M, Perez MA. Corticospinal reorganization after spinal cord injury. J Physiol. 2012;590:3647–3663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3476625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22586214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Percie du Sert N, Ahluwalia A, Alam S, Avey MT, Baker M, Browne WJ, Clark A, Cuthill IC, Dirnagl U, Emerson M, Garner P, Holgate ST, Howells DW, Hurst V, Karp NA, Lazic SE, Lidster K, MacCallum CJ, Macleod M, Pearl EJ, et al.  Reporting animal research: Explanation and elaboration for the ARRIVE guidelines 2.0. PLoS Biol. 2020;18:e3000411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7360025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen CC, Crochet S. Synaptic computation and sensory processing in neocortical layer 2/3. Neuron. 2013;78:28–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivlin AS, Tator CH. Effect of duration of acute spinal cord compression in a new acute cord injury model in the rat. Surg Neurol. 1978;10:38–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">684604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenzweig ES, Courtine G, Jindrich DL, Brock JH, Ferguson AR, Strand SC, Nout YS, Roy RR, Miller DM, Beattie MS, Havton LA, Bresnahan JC, Edgerton VR, Tuszynski MH. Extensive spontaneous plasticity of corticospinal projections after primate spinal cord injury. Nat Neurosci. 2010;13:1505–1510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3144760</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21076427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossini PM, Barker AT, Berardelli A, Caramia MD, Caruso G, Cracco RQ, Dimitrijević MR, Hallett M, Katayama Y, Lücking CH. Non-invasive electrical and magnetic stimulation of the brain, spinal cord and roots: basic principles and procedures for routine clinical application. Report of an IFCN committee. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1994;91:79–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7519144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakmann B. From single cells and single columns to cortical networks: dendritic excitability, coincidence detection and synaptic transmission in brain slices and brains. Exp Physiol. 2017;102:489–521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5435930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28139019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato S, Kakuda W, Sano M, Kitahara T, Kiko R. Therapeutic application of transcranial magnetic stimulation combined with rehabilitative training for incomplete spinal cord injury: a case report. Prog Rehabil Med. 2018;3:20180014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7365222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32789239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sauer RS, Kirchner J, Yang S, Hu L, Leinders M, Sommer C, Brack A, Rittner HL. Blood-spinal cord barrier breakdown and pericyte deficiency in peripheral neuropathy. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2017;1405:71–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28753236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serradj N, Agger SF, Hollis ER., 2nd Corticospinal circuit plasticity in motor rehabilitation from spinal cord injury. Neurosci Lett. 2017;652:94–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27939980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shang Y, Wang X, Shang X, Zhang H, Liu Z, Yin T, Zhang T. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation effectively facilitates spatial cognition and synaptic plasticity associated with increasing the levels of BDNF and synaptic proteins in Wistar rats. Neurobiol Learn Mem 134 Pt. 2016;B:369–378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27555233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song S, Miller KD, Abbott LF. Competitive Hebbian learning through spike-timing-dependent synaptic plasticity. Nat Neurosci. 2000;3:919–926.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10966623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staudt MD, Herring EZ, Gao K, Miller JP, Sweet JA. Evolution in the treatment of psychiatric disorders: from psychosurgery to psychopharmacology to neuromodulation. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6384258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30828289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefan K, Kunesch E, Cohen LG, Benecke R, Classen J. Induction of plasticity in the human motor cortex by paired associative stimulation. Brain 123 Pt. 2000;3:572–584.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10686179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefan K, Kunesch E, Benecke R, Cohen LG, Classen J. Mechanisms of enhancement of human motor cortex excitability induced by interventional paired associative stimulation. J Physiol. 2002;543:699–708.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290505</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12205201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugeno A, Piao W, Yamazaki M, Takahashi K, Arikawa K, Matsunaga H, Hosokawa M, Tominaga D, Goshima Y, Takeyama H, Ohshima T. Cortical transcriptome analysis after spinal cord injury reveals the regenerative mechanism of central nervous system in CRMP2 knock-in mice. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:1258–1265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8284262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33318403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toledo DR, Manzano GM, Barela JA, Kohn AF. Cortical correlates of response time slowing in older adults: ERP and ERD/ERS analyses during passive ankle movement. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127:655–663.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26024982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbin MA, Ozdemir RA, Tazoe T, Perez MA. Spike-timing-dependent plasticity in lower-limb motoneurons after human spinal cord injury. J Neurophysiol. 2017;118:2171–2180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626895</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28468994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner FB, Mignardot JB, Le Goff-Mignardot CG, Demesmaeker R, Komi S, Capogrosso M, Rowald A, Seáñez I, Caban M, Pirondini E, Vat M, McCracken LA, Heimgartner R, Fodor I, Watrin A, Seguin P, Paoles E, Van Den Keybus K, Eberle G, Schurch B, et al.  Targeted neurotechnology restores walking in humans with spinal cord injury. Nature. 2018;563:65–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30382197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner T, Valero-Cabre AL. A (2007) Noninvasive human brain stimulation. Ann Rev Biomed Eng. 9:527–565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17444810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weeks AC, Ivanco TL, Leboutillier JC, Racine RJ, Petit TL. Sequential changes in the synaptic structural profile following long-term potentiation in the rat dentate gyrus. II. Induction/early maintenance phase. Synapse. 2000;36:286–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10819906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weidner N, Ner A, Salimi N, Tuszynski MH. Spontaneous corticospinal axonal plasticity and functional recovery after adult central nervous system injury. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2001;98:3513–3518.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC30684</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11248109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wessel MJ, Hummel FC. Non-invasive cerebellar stimulation: a promising approach for stroke recovery? Cerebellum. 2018;17:359–371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29243202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao X, Sun C, Fan B, Zhao C, Zhang Y, Duan H, Pang Y, Shen W, Li B, Wang X, Liu C, Zhou H, Kong X, Feng S. Neurotropin exerts neuroprotective effects after spinal cord injury by inhibiting apoptosis and modulating cytokines. J Orthop Translat. 2021;26:74–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7773959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33437626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang KX, Zhao JJ, Chai W, Chen JY. Synaptic remodeling in mouse motor cortex after spinal cord injury. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:744–749.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang N, Xing M, Wang Y, Tao H, Cheng Y. Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation enhances spatial learning and synaptic plasticity via the VEGF and BDNF-NMDAR pathways in a rat model of vascular dementia. Neuroscience. 2015;311:284–291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26518460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang YP, Shields LB, Zhang Y, Pei J, Xu XM, Hoskins R, Cai J, Qiu MS, Magnuson DS, Burke DA, Shields CB. Use of magnetic stimulation to elicit motor evoked potentials, somatosensory evoked potentials, and H-reflexes in non-sedated rodents. J Neurosci Methods. 2007;165:9–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17628688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao D, Zhang Y, Xu D. Double-targets neural circuit magnetic stimulation promotes locomotor recovery with SCI by regulating activation of astrocytes in rats. Zhong Guo Kang Fu Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2020;35:1284–1289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zijdewind I, Thomas CK. Motor unit firing during and after voluntary contractions of human thenar muscles weakened by spinal cord injury. J Neurophysiol. 2003;89:2065–2071.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12612012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
