<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35142665</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Role of exosomes in the pathogenesis of inflammation in Parkinson's disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1898</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1906</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1898-1906</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.335143</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Inflammatory responses, including glial cell activation and peripheral immune cell infiltration, are involved in the pathogenesis of Parkinson's disease (PD). These inflammatory responses appear to be closely related to the release of extracellular vesicles, such as exosomes. However, the relationships among different forms of glial cell activation, synuclein dysregulation, mitochondrial dysfunction, and exosomes are complicated. This review discusses the multiple roles played by exosomes in PD-associated inflammation and concludes that exosomes can transport toxic α-synuclein oligomers to immature neurons and into the extracellular environment, inducing the oligomerization of α-synuclein in normal neurons. Misfolded α-synuclein causes microglia and astrocytes to activate and secrete exosomes. Glial cell-derived exosomes participate in communications between glial cells and neurons, triggering anti-stress and anti-inflammatory responses, in addition to axon growth. The production and release of mitochondrial vesicles and exosomes establish a new mechanism for linking mitochondrial dysfunction to systemic inflammation associated with PD. Given the relevance of exosomes as mediators of neuron-glia communication in neuroinflammation and neuropathogenesis, new targeted treatment strategies are currently being developed that use these types of extracellular vesicles as drug carriers. Exosome-mediated inflammation may be a promising target for intervention in PD patients.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ke-Lu</ForeName>
            <Initials>KL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Neurology, First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, Yunnan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hong-Yan</ForeName>
            <Initials>HY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ren</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hui</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Neurology, First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, Yunnan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xing-Long</ForeName>
            <Initials>XL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Neurology, First Affiliated Hospital of Kunming Medical University, Kunming, Yunnan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson’s disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocytes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exosomes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mitochondria</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuron-glia communication</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synucleins</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142665</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848593</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.335143</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_9_1898_335143</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen Reish H, Standaert D. Role of α-synuclein in inducing innate and adaptive immunity in Parkinson disease. J Parkinsons Dis. 2015;5:1–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4405142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25588354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvarez-Erviti L, Seow Y, Yin H, Betts C, Lakhal S, Wood M. Delivery of siRNA to the mouse brain by systemic injection of targeted exosomes. Nat Biotechnol. 2011;29:341–345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21423189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andican G, Konukoglu D, Bozluolcay M, Bayülkem K, Firtiına S, Burcak G. Plasma oxidative and inflammatory markers in patients with idiopathic Parkinson’s disease. Acta Neurol Belg. 2012;112:155–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22426659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arai H, Furuya T, Mizuno Y, Mochizuki H. Inflammation and infection in Parkinson’s disease. Histol Histopathol. 2006;21:673–678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16528677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barile L, Vassalli G. Exosomes: therapy delivery tools and biomarkers of diseases. Pharmacol Ther. 2017;174:63–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauernfeind FG, Horvath G, Stutz A, Alnemri ES, MacDonald K, Speert D, Fernandes-Alnemri T, Wu J, Monks BG, Fitzgerald KA, Hornung V, Latz E. Cutting edge: NF-kappaB activating pattern recognition and cytokine receptors license NLRP3 inflammasome activation by regulating NLRP3 expression. J Immunol. 2009;183:787–791.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824855</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19570822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellingham S, Guo B, Coleman B, Hill A. Exosomes: vehicles for the transfer of toxic proteins associated with neurodegenerative diseases. Front Physiol. 2012;3:124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3342525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22563321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaylock RL. Parkinson’s disease: microglial/macrophage-induced immunoexcitotoxicity as a central mechanism of neurodegeneration. Surg Neurol Int. 2017;8:65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421223</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28540131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boka G, Anglade P, Wallach D, Javoy-Agid F, Agid Y, Hirsch E. Immunocytochemical analysis of tumor necrosis factor and its receptors in Parkinson’s disease. Neurosci Lett. 1994;172:151–154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8084523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bornebroek M, de Lau L, Haag M, Koudstaal P, Hofman A, Stricker B, Breteler M. Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and the risk of Parkinson disease. Neuroepidemiology. 2007;28:193–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17851257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouvier-Muller A, Duconge F. Nucleic acid aptamers for neurodegenerative diseases. Biochimie. 2018;145:73–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29104136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braak H, Sastre M, Del Tredici K. Development of alpha-synuclein immunoreactive astrocytes in the forebrain parallels stages of intraneuronal pathology in sporadic Parkinson’s disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2007;114:231–241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17576580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brites D, Fernandes A. Neuroinflammation and depression: microglia, activation, extracellular microvesicles and microRNA dysregulation. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;9:476.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4681811</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26733805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brundin P, Ma J, Kordower JH. How strong is the evidence that Parkinson’s disease is a prion disorder. Curr Opin Neurol. 2016;29:459–466.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5054685</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27257944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caby M, Lankar D, Vincendeau-Scherrer C, Raposo G, Bonnerot C. Exosomal-like vesicles are present in human blood plasma. Int Immunol. 2005;17:879–887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15908444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvani R, Picca A, Landi G, Marini F, Biancolillo A, Coelho-Junior HJ, Gervasoni J, Persichilli S, Primiano A, Arcidiacono A, Urbani A, Bossola M, Bentivoglio AR, Cesari M, Bernabei R, Monaco MRL, Marzetti E. A novel multi-marker discovery approach identifies new serum biomarkers for Parkinson’s disease in older people: an EXosomes in PArkiNson Disease (EXPAND) ancillary study. Geroscience. 2020;42:1323–1334.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7525911</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32458283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao S, Standaert D, Harms A. The gamma chain subunit of Fc receptors is required for alpha-synuclein-induced pro-inflammatory signaling in microglia. J Neuroinflammation. 2012;9:259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3526448</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23186369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao X, Lu J, Zhao Z, Li M, Lu T, An X, Xue L. MicroRNA biomarkers of Parkinson’s disease in serum exosome-like microvesicles. Neurosci Lett. 2017;644:94–99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28223160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caputi V, Giron Maria C. Microbiome-gut-brain axis and toll-like receptors in Parkinson’s disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19:1689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6032048</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29882798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrière J, Bretin A, Darfeuille-Michaud A, Barnich N, Nguyen H. Exosomes released from cells infected with Crohn’s disease-associated adherent-invasive escherichia coli activate host innate immune responses and enhance bacterial intracellular replication. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2016;22:516–528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26595556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan B, Wong W, Lee M, Cho W, Yee B, Kwan Y, Tai W. Exosomes in inflammation and inflammatory disease. Proteomics. 2019;19:e1800149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30758141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang C, Lang H, Geng N, Wang J, Li N, Wang X. Exosomes of BV-2 cells induced by alpha-synuclein: important mediator of neurodegeneration in PD. Neurosci Lett. 2013a;548:190–195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23792198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatterjee K, Roy A, Banerjee R, Choudhury S, Mondal B, Halder S, Basu P, Shubham S, Dey S, Kumar H. Inflammasome and α-synuclein in Parkinson’s disease: a cross-sectional study. J Neuroimmunol. 2020;338:577089.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31704453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen H, Liang F, Gu P, Xu B, Xu H, Wang W, Hou J, Xie D, Chai X, An S. Exosomes derived from mesenchymal stem cells repair a Parkinson’s disease model by inducing autophagy. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11:288.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7184757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32341347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chistiakov DA, Chistiakov AA. α-Synuclein-carrying extracellular vesicles in Parkinson’s disease: deadly transmitters. Acta Neurol Belg. 2017;117:43–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27473175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ciregia F, Urbani A, Palmisano G. Extracellular vesicles in brain tumors and neurodegenerative diseases. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5583211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28912682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins L, Hajizadeh S, Holme E, Jonsson I, Tarkowski A. Endogenously oxidized mitochondrial DNA induces in vivo and in vitro inflammatory responses. J Leukoc Biol. 2004;75:995–1000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14982943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins L, Toulouse A, Connor T, Nolan Y. Contributions of central and systemic inflammation to the pathophysiology of Parkinson’s disease. Neuropharmacology. 2012;62:2154–2168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22361232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connor-Robson N, Booth H, Martin JG, Gao B, Li K, Doig N, Vowles J, Browne C, Klinger L, Juhasz P, Klein C, Cowley SA, Bolam P, Hirst W, Wade-Martins R. An integrated transcriptomics and proteomics analysis reveals functional endocytic dysregulation caused by mutations in LRRK2. Neurobiol Dis. 2019;127:512–526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6597903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30954703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Console L, Scalise M, Indiveri C. Exosomes in inflammation and role as biomarkers. Clin Chim Acta. 2019;488:165–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30419221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>d’Angelo M, Cimini A, Castelli V. Insights into the effects of mesenchymal stem cell-derived secretome in Parkinson’s disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:5241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7432166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32718092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danzer K, Kranich L, Ruf W, Cagsal-Getkin O, Winslow A, Zhu L, Vanderburg C, McLean P. Exosomal cell-to-cell transmission of alpha synuclein oligomers. Mol Neurodegener. 2012;7:42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22920859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Rivero Vaccari JP, Brand F, 3rd 
, Adamczak S, Lee SW, Perez-Barcena J, Wang MY, Bullock MR, Dietrich WD, Keane RW. Exosome-mediated inflammasome signaling after central nervous system injury. J Neurochem 136 Suppl. 2016;1:39–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4516699</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25628216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deleidi M, Gasser T. The role of inflammation in sporadic and familial Parkinson’s disease. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2013;70:4259–4273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23665870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickson D. Neuropathology of Parkinson disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2018;46(Suppl 1):S30–S33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5718208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28780180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorszewska J, Prendecki M, Lianeri M, Kozubski W. Molecular effects of l-dopa therapy in parkinson’s disease. Curr Genomics. 2014;15:11–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3958954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24653659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dursun E, Gezen-Ak D, Hanağası H, Bilgiç B, Lohmann E, Ertan S, Atasoy İ, Alaylıoğlu M, Araz Ö, Önal B, Gündüz A, Apaydın H, Kızıltan G, Ulutin T, Gürvit H, Yılmazer S. The interleukin 1, alpha, interleukin 1, beta, interleukin 6 and alpha-2-macroglobulin serum levels in patients with early or late onset Alzheimer’s, disease, mild cognitive impairment or Parkinson’s disease. J Neuroimmunol. 2015;283:50–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26004156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>EL Andaloussi S, Mäger I, Breakefield X, Wood M. Extracellular vesicles: biology and emerging therapeutic opportunities. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2013;12:347–357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23584393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esposito E, Di Matteo V, Benigno A, Pierucci M, Crescimanno G, Di Giovanni G. Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs in Parkinson’s disease. Exp Neurol. 2007;205:295–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17433296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fellner L, Irschick R, Schanda K, Reindl M, Klimaschewski L, Poewe W, Wenning G, Stefanova N. Toll-like receptor 4 is required for α-synuclein dependent activation of microglia and astroglia. Glia. 2013;61:349–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568908</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23108585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franco-Iborra S, Vila M, Perier C. Mitochondrial quality control in neurodegenerative diseases: focus on parkinson’s disease and huntington’s disease. Front Neurosci. 2018;12:342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974257</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franco R, Fernandez-Suarez D. Alternatively activated microglia and macrophages in the central nervous system. Prog Neurobiol. 2015;131:65–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26067058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fruhbeis C, Frohlich D, Kramer-Albers EM. Emerging roles of exosomes in neuron-glia communication. Front Physiol. 2012;3:119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3339323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22557979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fruhbeis C, Frohlich D, Kuo WP, Amphornrat J, Thilemann S, Saab AS, Kirchhoff F, Mobius W, Goebbels S, Nave KA, Schneider A, Simons M, Klugmann M, Trotter J, Kramer-Albers EM. Neurotransmitter-triggered transfer of exosomes mediates oligodendrocyte-neuron communication. PLoS Biol. 2013;11:e1001604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3706306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23874151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu C, Peng P, Loschko J, Feng L, Pham P, Cui W, Lee K, Krug A, Jiang A. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells cross-prime naive CD8 T cells by transferring antigen to conventional dendritic cells through exosomes. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117:23730–23741.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7519282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32879009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gambardella S, Limanaqi F, Ferese R, Biagioni F, Campopiano R, Centonze D, Fornai F. ccf-mtDNA as a potential link between the brain and immune system in neuro-immunological disorders. Front Immunol. 2019;10:1064.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6520662</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31143191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghidoni R, Benussi L, Binetti G. Exosomes: the Trojan horses of neurodegeneration. Med Hypotheses. 2008;70:1226–1227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18226468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibbings D, Ciaudo C, Erhardt M, Voinnet O. Multivesicular bodies associate with components of miRNA effector complexes and modulate miRNA activity. Nat Cell Biol. 2009;11:1143–1149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19684575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giunta S. Is inflammaging an auto[innate]immunity subclinical syndrome. Immun Ageing. 2006;3:12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1716179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17173699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goetzl EJ, Schwartz JB, Abner EL, Jicha GA, Kapogiannis D. High complement levels in astrocyte-derived exosomes of Alzheimer disease. Ann Neurol. 2018;83:544–552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29406582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grey M, Dunning CJ, Gaspar R, Grey C, Brundin P, Sparr E, Linse S. Acceleration of alpha-synuclein aggregation by exosomes. J Biol Chem. 2015;290:2969–2982.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4317028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25425650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo M, Wang J, Zhao Y, Feng Y, Han S, Dong Q, Cui M, Tieu K. Microglial exosomes facilitate alpha-synuclein transmission in Parkinson’s disease. Brain. 2020;143:1476–1497.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241957</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A, Pulliam L. Exosomes as mediators of neuroinflammation. J Neuroinflammation. 2014;11:68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3994210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24694258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halliday G, Stevens C. Glia: initiators and progressors of pathology in Parkinson’s disease. Mov Disord. 2011;26:6–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21322014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han C, Xiong N, Guo X, Huang J, Ma K, Liu L, Xia Y, Shen Y, Li J, Jiang H, Wang L, Guo S, Xu X, Zhang G, Liu J, Cao X, Zhang Z, Lin Z, Wang T. Exosomes from patients with Parkinson’s disease are pathological in mice. J Mol Med. 2019;97:1329–1344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31302715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haney M, Klyachko N, Zhao Y, Gupta R, Plotnikova E, He Z, Patel T, Piroyan A, Sokolsky M, Kabanov A, Batrakova E. Exosomes as drug delivery vehicles for Parkinson’s disease therapy. J Control Release. 2015;207:18–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4430381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25836593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haney M, Zhao Y, Li S, Higginbotham S, Booth S, Han H, Vetro J, Mosley R, Kabanov A, Gendelman H, Batrakova E. Cell-mediated transfer of catalase nanoparticles from macrophages to brain, endothelial, glial and neuronal cells. Nanomedicine (Lond) 2011;6:1215–1230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3166447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21449849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haney M, Zhao Y, Harrison E, Mahajan V, Ahmed S, He Z, Suresh P, Hingtgen S, Klyachko N, Mosley R, Gendelman H, Kabanov A, Batrakova E. Specific transfection of inflamed brain by macrophages: a new therapeutic strategy for neurodegenerative diseases. PLoS One. 2013;8:e61852.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23620794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanisch U, Kettenmann H. Microglia: active sensor and versatile effector cells in the normal and pathologic brain. Nat Neurosci. 2007;10:1387–1394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17965659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harischandra DS, Ghaisas S, Rokad D, Zamanian M, Jin H, Anantharam V, Kimber M, Kanthasamy A, Kanthasamy AG. Environmental neurotoxicant manganese regulates exosome-mediated extracellular miRNAs in cell culture model of Parkinson’s disease: relevance to alpha-synuclein misfolding in metal neurotoxicity. Neurotoxicology. 2018;64:267–277.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5654692</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28450057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hessvik N, Llorente A. Current knowledge on exosome biogenesis and release. Cellular Mol Life Sci. 2018;75:193–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5756260</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hou Y, Dan X, Babbar M, Wei Y, Hasselbalch S, Croteau D, Bohr V. Ageing as a risk factor for neurodegenerative disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2019;15:565–581.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31501588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang Y, Halliday G. Aspects of innate immunity and Parkinson’s disease. Front Pharmacol. 2012;3:33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3296959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22408621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imamura K, Hishikawa N, Sawada M, Nagatsu T, Yoshida M, Hashizume Y. Distribution of major histocompatibility complex class II-positive microglia and cytokine profile of Parkinson’s disease brains. Acta Neuropathol. 2003;106:518–526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14513261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janda E, Boi L, Carta A. Microglial phagocytosis and its regulation: a therapeutic target in parkinson’s disease. Front Mol Neurosci. 2018;11:144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5934476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnstone R, Adam M, Hammond J, Orr L, Turbide C. Vesicle formation during reticulocyte maturation. Association of plasma membrane activities with released vesicles (exosomes) J Biol Chem. 1987;262:9412–9420.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3597417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joshi N, Singh S. Updates on immunity and inflammation in Parkinson disease pathology. J Neurosci Res. 2018;96:379–390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29072332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jucker M, Walker L. Self-propagation of pathogenic protein aggregates in neurodegenerative diseases. Nature. 2013;501:45–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3963807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim C, Lee H, Masliah E, Lee S. Non-cell-autonomous neurotoxicity of α-synuclein through microglial toll-like receptor 2. Exp Neurobiol. 2016;25:113–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4923355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27358579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klegeris A, Pelech S, Giasson B, Maguire J, Zhang H, McGeer E, McGeer P. Alpha-synuclein activates stress signaling protein kinases in THP-1 cells and microglia. Neurobiol Aging. 2008;29:739–752.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17166628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kojima R, Bojar D, Rizzi G, Hamri G, El-Baba M, Saxena P, Ausländer S, Tan K, Fussenegger M. Designer exosomes produced by implanted cells intracerebrally deliver therapeutic cargo for Parkinson’s disease treatment. Nat Commun. 2018;9:1305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5880805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29610454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kourembanas S. Exosomes: vehicles of intercellular signaling biomarkers and vectors of cell therapy. Ann Rev Physiol. 2015;77:13–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25293529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreutzberg G. Microglia: a sensor for pathological events in the CNS. Trends Neurosci. 1996;19:312–318.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8843599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krysko D, Agostinis P, Krysko O, Garg A, Bachert C, Lambrecht B, Vandenabeele P. Emerging role of damage-associated molecular patterns derived from mitochondria in inflammation. Trends Immunol. 2011;32:157–164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21334975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawson L, Perry V, Dri P, Gordon S. Heterogeneity in the distribution and morphology of microglia in the normal adult mouse brain. Neuroscience. 1990;39:151–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2089275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee H, James W, Cowley S. LRRK2 in peripheral and central nervous system innate immunity: its link to Parkinson’s disease. Biochem Soc Trans. 2017;45:131–139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5652224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28202666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee HJ, Suk JE, Patrick C, Bae EJ, Cho JH, Rho S, Hwang D, Masliah E, Lee SJ. Direct transfer of alpha-synuclein from neuron to astroglia causes inflammatory responses in synucleinopathies. J Biol Chem. 2010;285:9262–9272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S. Origins and effects of extracellular alpha-synuclein: implications in Parkinson's disease. J Mol Neurosci. 2008;34:17–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18157654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee Y, Lee S, Chang S, Lee J. Significant roles of neuroinflammation in Parkinson’s disease: therapeutic targets for PD prevention. Arch Pharm Res. 2019;42:416–425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30830660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leggio L, Paternò G, Vivarelli S, L’Episcopo F, Tirolo C, Raciti G, Pappalardo F, Giachino C, Caniglia S, Serapide M, Marchetti B, Iraci N. Extracellular vesicles as nanotherapeutics for Parkinson’s disease. Biomolecules. 2020;10:1327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7563168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32948090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, Luo Y, Zhu L, Hua W, Zhang Y, Zhang H, Zhang L, Li Z, Xing P, Zhang Y, Hong B, Yang P, Liu J. Glia-derived exosomes: promising therapeutic targets. Life Sci. 2019;239:116951.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31626787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Wang B, Kodali M, Chen C, Kim E, Patters B, Lan L, Kumar S, Wang X, Yue J, Liao F. In vivo evidence for the contribution of peripheral circulating inflammatory exosomes to neuroinflammation. J Neuroinflamm. 2018;15:8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5759808</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li M, Rai A, DeCastro G, Zeringer E, Barta T, Magdaleno S, Setterquist R, Vlassov A. An optimized procedure for exosome isolation and analysis using serum samples: application to cancer biomarker discovery. Methods. 2015;87:26–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25814440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liddelow SA, Guttenplan KA, Clarke LE, Bennett FC, Bohlen CJ, Schirmer L, Bennett ML, Münch AE, Chung WS, Peterson TC, Wilton DK, Frouin A, Napier BA, Panicker N, Kumar M, Buckwalter MS, Rowitch DH, Dawson VL, Dawson TM, Stevens B, et al.  Neurotoxic reactive astrocytes are induced by activated microglia. Nature. 2017;541:481–487.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28099414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindenbergh M, Wubbolts R, Borg E, van ’t Veld E, Boes M, Stoorvogel W. Dendritic cells release exosomes together with phagocytosed pathogen; potential implications for the role of exosomes in antigen presentation. J Extracell Vesicles. 2020;9:1798606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7480536</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32944186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindqvist D, Kaufman E, Brundin L, Hall S, Surova Y, Hansson O. Non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson’s disease -correlations with inflammatory cytokines in serum. PLoS One. 2012;7:e47387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3474801</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23082161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Sun M, Cai C, Ren C, Niu H. Research progress on neural mechanism of peripheral inflammation in Parkinson’s disease. Sheng Li Xue Bao. 2019;71:732–740.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31646327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Longoni B, Fasciani I, Kolachalam S, Pietrantoni I, Marampon F, Petragnano F, Aloisi G, Coppolino MF, Rossi M, Scarselli M, Maggio R. Neurotoxic and neuroprotective role of exosomes in Parkinson’s disease. Curr Pharm Des. 2019;25:4510–4522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31724509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo H, Zhang J, Miao F. Effects of pramipexole treatment on the α-synuclein content in serum exosomes of Parkinson’s disease patients. Exp Ther Med. 2016;12:1373–1376.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4998109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27588058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matheoud D, Sugiura A, Bellemare-Pelletier A, Laplante A, Rondeau C, Chemali M, Fazel A, Bergeron JJ, Trudeau LE, Burelle Y, Gagnon E, McBride HM, Desjardins M. Parkinson’s disease-related proteins PINK1 and Parkin repress mitochondrial antigen presentation. Cell. 2016;166:314–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27345367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGeer P, Itagaki S, Boyes B, McGeer E. Reactive microglia are positive for HLA-DR in the substantia nigra of Parkinson’s and Alzheimer’s disease brains. Neurology. 1988;38:1285–1291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3399080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miklossy J, Doudet DD, Schwab C, Yu S, McGeer EG, McGeer PL. Role of ICAM-1 in persisting inflammation in Parkinson disease and MPTP monkeys. Exp Neurol. 2006;197:275–283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16336966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mizukami H, Mi Y, Wada R, Kono M, Yamashita T, Liu Y, Werth N, Sandhoff R, Sandhoff K, Proia R. Systemic inflammation in glucocerebrosidase-deficient mice with minimal glucosylceramide storage. J Clin Invest. 2002;109:1215–1221.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150961</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11994410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mogi M, Harada M, Kondo T, Riederer P, Inagaki H, Minami M, Nagatsu T. Interleukin-1, beta, interleukin-6, epidermal growth factor and transforming growth factor-alpha are elevated in the brain from parkinsonian patients. Neurosci Lett. 1994b;180:147–150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7700568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mogi M, Harada M, Narabayashi H, Inagaki H, Minami M, Nagatsu T. Interleukin (IL)-1,beta,IL-2,IL-4,IL-6 and transforming growth factor-alpha levels are elevated in ventricular cerebrospinal fluid in juvenile parkinsonism and Parkinson’s disease. Neurosci Lett. 1996;211:13–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8809836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mogi M, Harada M, Riederer P, Narabayashi H, Fujita K, Nagatsu T. Tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-alpha) increases both in the brain and in the cerebrospinal fluid from parkinsonian patients. Neurosci Lett. 1994a;165:208–210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8015728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosley RL, Codolo G, Plotegher N, Pozzobon T, Brucale M, Tessari I, Bubacco L, de Bernard M. Triggering of inflammasome by aggregated α-synuclein an inflammatory response in synucleinopathies. PLoS One. 2013;8:e55375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3561263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23383169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mouton-Liger F, Jacoupy M, Corvol J, Corti O. PINK1/Parkin-dependent mitochondrial surveillance: from pleiotropy to Parkinson’s disease. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5410576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28507507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu M, Li Y, Li G, Zhou L, Luo N, Yao M, Kang W, Liu J. A longitudinal study on alpha-synuclein in plasma neuronal exosomes as a biomarker for Parkinson’s disease development and progression. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:967–974.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32150777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olanow CW, Savolainen M, Chu Y, Halliday GM, Kordower JH. Temporal evolution of microglia and alpha-synuclein accumulation following foetal grafting in Parkinson’s disease. Brain. 2019;142:1690–1700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31056668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orenstein S, Kuo S, Tasset I, Arias E, Koga H, Fernandez-Carasa I, Cortes E, Honig L, Dauer W, Consiglio A, Raya A, Sulzer D, Cuervo A. Interplay of LRRK2 with chaperone-mediated autophagy. Nat Neurosci. 2013;16:394–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3609872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23455607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortega A, Martinez-Arroyo O, Forner M, Cortes R. Exosomes as drug delivery systems: endogenous nanovehicles for treatment of systemic lupus erythematosus. Pharmaceutics. 2020;13:3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821934</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33374908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouchi Y, Yoshikawa E, Sekine Y, Futatsubashi M, Kanno T, Ogusu T, Torizuka T. Microglial activation and dopamine terminal loss in early Parkinson’s disease. Ann Neurol. 2005;57:168–175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15668962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paolicelli RC, Bergamini G, Rajendran L. Cell-to-cell communication by extracellular vesicles: focus on microglia. Neuroscience. 2019;405:148–157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29660443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pascual M, Ibáñez F, Guerri C. Exosomes as mediators of neuron-glia communication in neuroinflammation. Neural Regen Res. 2020;15:796–801.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31719239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picca A, Guerra F, Calvani R, Marini F, Biancolillo A, Landi G, Beli R, Landi F, Bernabei R, Bentivoglio AR, Monaco MRL, Bucci C, Marzetti E. Mitochondrial signatures in circulating extracellular vesicles of older adults with parkinson’s disease: results from the EXosomes in PArkiNson’s Disease (EXPAND) Study. J Clin Med. 2020;9:504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7074517</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32059608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picca A, Guerra F, Calvani R, Bucci C, Lo Monaco M, Bentivoglio A, Landi F, Bernabei R, Marzetti E. Mitochondrial-derived vesicles as candidate biomarkers in parkinson’s disease: rationale design and methods of the EXosomes in PArkiNson disease (EXPAND) study. Int J Mo Sci. 2019;20:2373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6566801</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31091653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picca A, Lezza AMS, Leeuwenburgh C, Pesce V, Calvani R, Landi F, Bernabei R, Marzetti E. Fueling inflamm-aging through mitochondrial dysfunction: mechanisms and molecular targets. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5454846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28452964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picca A, Lezza AMS, Leeuwenburgh C, Pesce V, Calvani R, Bossola M, Manes-Gravina E, Landi F, Bernabei R, Marzetti E. Circulating mitochondrial DNA at the crossroads of mitochondrial dysfunction and inflammation during aging and muscle wasting disorders. Rejuvenation Res. 2018;21:350–359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6103247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29125070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poly TN, Islam MMR, Yang HC, Li YJ. Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and risk of Parkinson’s disease in the elderly population: a meta-analysis. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2019;75:99–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30280208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porro C, Panaro MA, Lofrumento DD, Hasalla E, Trotta T. The multiple roles of exosomes in Parkinson’s disease: an overview. Immunopharmacol Immunotoxicol. 2019;41:469–476.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31405314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Préhaud C, Mégret F, Lafage M, Lafon M. Virus infection switches TLR-3-positive human neurons to become strong producers of beta interferon. J Virol. 2005;79:12893–12904.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1235836</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16188991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prabhakaran K, Chapman G, Gunasekar P. α-Synuclein overexpression enhances manganese-induced neurotoxicity through the NF-κB-mediated pathway. Toxicol Mech Methods. 2011;21:435–443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21417633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prigent A, Gonzales J, Durand T, Le Berre-Scoul C, Rolli-Derkinderen M, Neunlist M, Derkinderen P. Acute inflammation down-regulates alpha-synuclein expression in enteric neurons. J Neurochem. 2019;148:746–760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30589944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiao C, Sun M, Jia X, Li Y, Zhang B, Zhao L, Shi Y, Zhou Z, Zhu Y, Cui C, Shen Y. Sodium butyrate exacerbates Parkinson’s disease by aggravating neuroinflammation and colonic inflammation in MPTP-induced mice model. Neurochem Res. 2020;45:2128–2142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin X, Zhang S, Cao C, Loh Y, Cheng Y. Aberrations in peripheral inflammatory cytokine levels in parkinson disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Neurol. 2016;73:1316–1324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27668667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qu M, Lin Q, Huang L, Fu Y, Wang L, He S, Fu Y, Yang S, Zhang Z, Zhang L, Sun X. Dopamine-loaded blood exosomes targeted to brain for better treatment of Parkinson’s disease. J Control Release. 2018;287:156–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raivich G. Like cops on the beat: the active role of resting microglia. Trends Neurosci. 2005;28:571–573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16165228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rees K, Stowe R, Patel S, Ives N, Breen K, Clarke C, Ben-Shlomo Y. Non-steroidal antiinflammatory drugs as disease-modifying agents for Parkinson's disease: evidence from observational studies. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011 doi:10.1002/14651858.CD008454.pub2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22071848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren W, Tian Z, Yin F, Sun J, Zhang J. Extracellular α-synuclein--a possible initiator of inflammation in Parkinson’s disease. Pharmazie. 2016;71:51–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27004367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren Y, Yang J, Xie R, Gao L, Yang Y, Fan H, Qian K. Exosomal-like vesicles with immune-modulatory features are present in human plasma and can induce CD4+ T-cell apoptosis in vitro. Transfusion. 2011;51:1002–1011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21044087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riazifar M, Mohammadi MR, Pone EJ, Yeri A, Lässer C, Segaliny AI, McIntyre LL, Shelke GV, Hutchins E, Hamamoto A, Calle EN, Crescitelli R, Liao W, Pham V, Yin Y, Jayaraman J, Lakey JRT, Walsh CM, Van Keuren-Jensen K, Lotvall J, et al.  Stem cell-derived exosomes as nanotherapeutics for autoimmune and neurodegenerative disorders. ACS Nano. 2019;13:6670–6688.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6880946</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31117376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richardson JR, Hossain MM. Microglial ion channels as potential targets for neuroprotection in Parkinson’s disease. Neural Plast. 2013;2013:587418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3832972</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24288626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rocha EM, De Miranda B, Sanders LH. Alpha-synuclein: pathology, mitochondrial dysfunction and neuroinflammation in Parkinson's disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2018;109:249–257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28400134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rufino-Ramos D, Albuquerque P, Carmona V, Perfeito R, Nobre R, Pereira de Almeida L. Extracellular vesicles: novel promising delivery systems for therapy of brain diseases. J Controlled Release. 2017;262:247–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28687495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salvioli S, Capri M, Valensin S, Tieri P, Monti D, Ottaviani E, Franceschi C. Inflamm-aging cytokines and aging: state of the art new hypotheses on the role of mitochondria and new perspectives from systems biology. Curr Pharm Design. 2006;12:3161–3171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16918441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sampson TR, Debelius JW, Thron T, Janssen S, Shastri GG, Ilhan ZE, Challis C, Schretter CE, Rocha S, Gradinaru V, Chesselet MF, Keshavarzian A, Shannon KM, Krajmalnik-Brown R, Wittung-Stafshede P, Knight R, Mazmanian SK. Gut Microbiota Regulate Motor Deficits and Neuroinflammation in a Model of Parkinson’s Disease. Cell. 2016;167:1469–1480. e12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5718049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27912057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanjari Moghaddam H, Ghazi Sherbaf F, Mojtahed Zadeh M, Ashraf-Ganjouei A, Aarabi MH. Association between peripheral inflammation and DATSCAN data of the striatal nuclei in different motor subtypes of parkinson Disease. Front Neurol. 2018;9:234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5911462</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29713303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarkar S, Rokad D, Malovic E, Luo J, Harischandra D, Jin H, Anantharam V, Huang X, Lewis M, Kanthasamy A, Kanthasamy A. Manganese activates NLRP3 inflammasome signaling and propagates exosomal release of ASC in microglial cells. Sci Signal. 2019;12:eaat9900.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6420319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30622196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi M, Liu C, Cook TJ, Bullock KM, Zhao Y, Ginghina C, Li Y, Aro P, Dator R, He C, Hipp MJ, Zabetian CP, Peskind ER, Hu SC, Quinn JF, Galasko DR, Banks WA, Zhang J. Plasma exosomal alpha-synuclein is likely CNS-derived and increased in Parkinson’s disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2014;128:639–650.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201967</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24997849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimoji M, Pagan F, Healton E, Mocchetti I. CXCR4 and CXCL12 expression is increased in the nigro-striatal system of Parkinson’s disease. Neurotoxic Res. 2009;16:318–328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19551455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simons M, Raposo G. Exosomes--vesicular carriers for intercellular communication. 2009;21:575–581.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stuendl A, Kunadt M, Kruse N, Bartels C, Moebius W, Danzer KM, Mollenhauer B, Schneider A. Induction of α-synuclein aggregate formation by CSF exosomes from patients with Parkinson’s disease and dementia with Lewy bodies. Brain. 2016;139:481–494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4805087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26647156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su X, Chen Q, Chen W, Chen T, Li W, Li Y, Dou X, Zhang Y, Shen Y, Wu H, Yu C. Mycoepoxydiene inhibits activation of BV2 microglia stimulated by lipopolysaccharide through suppressing NF-κB, ERK 1/2 and toll-like receptor pathways. Int Immunopharmacol. 2014;19:88–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24447679</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su X, Maguire-Zeiss K, Giuliano R, Prifti L, Venkatesh K, Federoff H. Synuclein activates microglia in a model of Parkinson’s disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2008;29:1690–1701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2621109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17537546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun D, Zhuang X, Xiang X, Liu Y, Zhang S, Liu C, Barnes S, Grizzle W, Miller D, Zhang H. A novel nanoparticle drug delivery system: the anti-inflammatory activity of curcumin is enhanced when encapsulated in exosomes. Mol Ther. 2010;18:1606–1614.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20571541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thome A, Harms A, Volpicelli-Daley L, Standaert D. microRNA-155 regulates alpha-synuclein-induced inflammatory responses in models of Parkinson disease. J Neurosci. 2016;36:2383–2390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4764660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26911687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsutsumi R, Hori Y, Seki T, Kurauchi Y, Sato M, Oshima M, Hisatsune A, Katsuki H. Involvement of exosomes in dopaminergic neurodegeneration by microglial activation in midbrain slice cultures. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2019;511:427–433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van den Boorn J, Schlee M, Coch C, Hartmann G. SiRNA delivery with exosome nanoparticles. Nat Biotechnol. 2011;29:325–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21478846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vekrellis K, Xilouri M, Emmanouilidou E, Rideout HJ, Stefanis L. Pathological roles of α-synuclein in neurological disorders. Lancet Neurol. 2011;10:1015–1025.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22014436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vella L, Hill A, Cheng L. Focus on extracellular vesicles: exosomes and their role in protein trafficking and biomarker potential in Alzheimer’s and Parkinson’s disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2016;17:173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4783907</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26861304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veselý B, Dufek M, Thon V, Brozman M, Királová S, Halászová T, Koriťáková E, Rektor I. Interleukin 6 and complement serum level study in Parkinson’s disease. J Neural Transm. 2018;125:875–881.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29435648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilaça-Faria H, Salgado A, Teixeira F. Mesenchymal stem cells-derived exosomes: a new possible therapeutic strategy for Parkinson’s disease. Cells. 2019;8:118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6406999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30717429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villarán R, Espinosa-Oliva A, Sarmiento M, De Pablos R, Argüelles S, Delgado-Cortés M, Sobrino V, Van Rooijen N, Venero J, Herrera A, Cano J, Machado A. Ulcerative colitis exacerbates lipopolysaccharide-induced damage to the nigral dopaminergic system: potential risk factor in Parkinson's disease. J Neurochem. 2010;114:1687–1700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20584104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waak J, Weber S, Waldenmaier A, Görner K, Alunni-Fabbroni M, Schell H, Vogt-Weisenhorn D, Pham T, Reumers V, Baekelandt V, Wurst W, Kahle P. Regulation of astrocyte inflammatory responses by the Parkinson’s disease-associated gene DJ-1. FASEB J. 2009;23:2478–2489.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waehler R, Russell S, Curiel D. Engineering targeted viral vectors for gene therapy. Nat Rev Genet. 2007;8:573–587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17607305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakabayashi K, Hayashi S, Yoshimoto M, Kudo H, Takahashi H. NACP/alpha-synuclein-positive filamentous inclusions in astrocytes and oligodendrocytes of Parkinson’s disease brains. Acta Neuropathol. 2000;99:14–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10651022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker DG, Lue LF. Immune phenotypes of microglia in human neurodegenerative disease: challenges to detecting microglial polarization in human brains. Alzheimers Res Ther. 2015;7:56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4543480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26286145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Q, Liu Y, Zhou J. Neuroinflammation in Parkinson’s disease and its potential as therapeutic target. Transl Neurodegener. 2015;4:19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4603346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26464797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wani T, Mohi-Ud-Din R, Mir R, Itoo A, Mir K, Fazli A, Pottoo F. Exosomes harnessed as nanocarriers for cancer therapy - current status and potential for future clinical applications. Curr Mol Med. 2020 doi: 10.2174/1566524020666200915111618.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32933459</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West AP, Khoury-Hanold W, Staron M, Tal MC, Pineda CM, Lang SM, Bestwick M, Duguay BA, Raimundo N, MacDuff DA, Kaech SM, Smiley JR, Means RE, Iwasaki A, Shadel GS. Mitochondrial DNA stress primes the antiviral innate immune response. Nature. 2015;520:553–557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4409480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25642965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White AJ, Wijeyekoon RS, Scott KM, Gunawardana NP, Hayat S, Solim IH, McMahon HT, Barker RA, Williams-Gray CH. The peripheral inflammatory response to alpha-synuclein and endotoxin in Parkinson’s disease. Front Neurol. 2018;9:946.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6256248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30524354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitton PS. Inflammation as a causative factor in the aetiology of Parkinson’s disease. Br J Pharm. 2007;150:963–976.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2013918</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xia Y, Zhang G, Han C, Ma K, Guo X, Wan F, Kou L, Yin S, Liu L, Huang J, Xiong N, Wang T. Microglia as modulators of exosomal alpha-synuclein transmission. Cell Death Dis. 2019;10:174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6382842</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30787269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang J, Luo S, Zhang J, Yu T, Fu Z, Zheng Y, Xu X, Liu C, Fan M, Zhang Z. Exosome-mediated delivery of antisense oligonucleotides targeting α-synuclein ameliorates the pathology in a mouse model of Parkinson’s disease. Neurobiol Dis. 2021;148:105218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33296726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokoyama H, Uchida H, Kuroiwa H, Kasahara J, Araki T. Role of glial cells in neurotoxin-induced animal models of Parkinson’s disease. Neurol Sci. 2011;32:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21107876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu H, Sun T, An J, Wen L, Liu F, Bu Z, Cui Y, Feng J. Potential roles of exosomes in parkinson’s disease: from pathogenesis diagnosis and treatment to prognosis. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8:86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7047039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32154247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yun SP, Kam TI, Panicker N, Kim S, Oh Y, Park JS, Kwon SH, Park YJ, Karuppagounder SS, Park H, Kim S, Oh N, Kim NA, Lee S, Brahmachari S, Mao X, Lee JH, Kumar M, An D, Kang SU, et al.  Block of A1 astrocyte conversion by microglia is neuroprotective in models of Parkinson's disease. Nat Med. 2018;24:931–938.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29892066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Li S, Li L, Li M, Guo C, Yao J, Mi S. Exosome and exosomal microRNA: trafficking sorting and function. Genomics Proteomics Bioinformatics. 2015;13:17–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4411500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25724326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Q, Heng Y, Yuan Y, Chen N. Pathological α-synuclein exacerbates the progression of Parkinson’s disease through microglial activation. Toxicol Lett. 2017;265:30–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27865851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou T, Lin D, Chen Y, Peng S, Jing X, Lei M, Tao E, Liang Y. α-Synuclein accumulation in SH-SY5Y cell impairs autophagy in microglia by exosomes overloading miR-19a-3p. Epigenomics. 2019;11:1661–1677.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31646884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Y, Lu M, Du R, Qiao C, Jiang C, Zhang K, Ding J, Hu G. MicroRNA-7 targets Nod-like receptor protein 3 inflammasome to modulate neuroinflammation in the pathogenesis of Parkinson’s disease. Mol Neurodegener. 2016;11:28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27084336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhuang X, Xiang X, Grizzle W, Sun D, Zhang S, Axtell R, Ju S, Mu J, Zhang L, Steinman L, Miller D, Zhang H. Treatment of brain inflammatory diseases by delivering exosome encapsulated anti-inflammatory drugs from the nasal region to the brain. Mol Ther. 2011;19:1769–1779.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3188748</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21915101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
