<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35142664</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neuron-fibrous scaffold interfaces in the peripheral nervous system: a perspective on the structural requirements.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1893</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1897</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1893-1897</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.329003</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The nerves of the peripheral nervous system are not able to effectively regenerate in cases of severe neural injury. This can result in debilitating consequences, including morbidity and lifelong impairments affecting the quality of the patient's life. Recent findings in neural tissue engineering have opened promising avenues to apply fibrous tissue-engineered scaffolds to promote tissue regeneration and functional recovery. These scaffolds, known as neural scaffolds, are able to improve neural regeneration by playing two major roles, namely, by being a carrier for transplanted peripheral nervous system cells or biological cues and by providing structural support to direct growing nerve fibers towards the target area. However, successful implementation of scaffold-based therapeutic approaches calls for an appropriate design of the neural scaffold structure that is capable of up- and down-regulation of neuron-scaffold interactions in the extracellular matrix environment. This review discusses the main challenges that need to be addressed to develop and apply fibrous tissue-engineered scaffolds in clinical practice. It describes some promising solutions that, so far, have shown to promote neural cell adhesion and growth and a potential to repair peripheral nervous system injuries.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Behtaj</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sanaz</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clem Jones Centre for Neurobiology and Stem Cell Research, Griffith University, Queensland; Menzies Health Institute Queensland, Griffith University, Southport, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>St John</LastName>
            <ForeName>James A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clem Jones Centre for Neurobiology and Stem Cell Research, Griffith University, Queensland; Menzies Health Institute Queensland, Griffith University, Southport; Griffith Institute for Drug Discovery, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ekberg</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jenny A K</ForeName>
            <Initials>JAK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clem Jones Centre for Neurobiology and Stem Cell Research, Griffith University, Queensland; Menzies Health Institute Queensland, Griffith University, Southport; Griffith Institute for Drug Discovery, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rybachuk</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maksym</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Engineering and Built Environment; Centre for Quantum Dynamics and Australian Attosecond Science Facility, Griffith University, Nathan, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrospun scaffold</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extracellular matrix</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nerve conduit</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural tissue engineering</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical lumen filler</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scaffold topography</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural support</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surface interaction</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142664</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848624</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.329003</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_9_1893_329003</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aijie C, Xuan L, Huimin L, Yanli Z, Yiyuan K, Yuqing L, Longquan S. Nanoscaffolds in promoting regeneration of the peripheral nervous system. Nanomedicine. 2018;13:1067–1085.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29790811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali B, Litvinyuk IV, Rybachuk M. Femtosecond laser micromachining of diamond: Current research status applications and challenges. Carbon. 2021;179:209–226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amini S, Salehi H, Setayeshmehr M, Ghorbani M. Natural and synthetic polymeric scaffolds used in peripheral nerve tissue engineering: Advantages and disadvantages. Polym Adv Technol. 2021 doi:10.1002/pat.5283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asadian M, Chan KV, Norouzi M, Grande S, Cools P, Morent R, De Geyter N. Fabrication and plasma modification of nanofibrous tissue engineering scaffolds. Nanomaterials. 2020;10:119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7023287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31936372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashraf R, Sofi HS, Beigh MA, Majeed S, Arjamand S, Sheikh FA.  Prospects of natural polymeric scaffolds in peripheral nerve tissue-regeneration. In: Advances in experimental medicine and biology. In: Chun H, editor. Signapore: Springer; 2018. pp. 501–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badea S, Wu W.  Nanoengineered biomaterials for bridging gaps in damaged nerve tissue. In: Nanoengineered biomaterials for regenerative medicine. In: Mozafari M, Rajadas J, Kaplan D, editors. Amsterdam, Netherlands: Elsevier; 2018. pp. 187–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balguid A, Mol A, Van Marion MH, Bank RA, Bouten CVC, Baaijens FPT. Tailoring fiber diameter in electrospun poly(ε-Caprolactone) scaffolds for optimal cellular infiltration in cardiovascular tissue engineering. Tissue Eng Part A. 2009;15:437–444.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18694294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barton MJ, John JS, Clarke M, Wright A, Ekberg J. The glia response after peripheral nerve injury: a comparison between Schwann cells and olfactory ensheathing cells and their uses for neural regenerative therapies. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5343823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28146061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behtaj S, Rybachuk M. Strategies on the application of stem cells based therapies for the treatment of optic neuropathies. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:1190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8224130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33269770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behtaj S, Öchsner A, Anissimov YG, Rybachuk M. Retinal tissue bioengineering materials and methods for the treatment of glaucoma. Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2020;17:253–269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7260329</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32390117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behtaj S, Karamali F, Masaeli E, Anissimov YG, Rybachuk M. Electrospun PGS/PCL, PLLA/PCL, PLGA/PCL and pure PCL scaffolds for retinal progenitor cell cultivation. Bioche Eng J. 2021a;166:107846.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Behtaj S, Karamali F, Najafian S, Masaeli E, Esfahani MHN, Rybachuk M. The role of PGS/PCL scaffolds in promoting differentiation of human embryonic stem cells into retinal ganglion cells. Acta Biomater. 2021b;126:238–248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33771718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Binan L, Ajji A, De Crescenzo G, Jolicoeur M. Approaches for neural tissue regeneration. Stem Cell Rev Rep. 2014;10:44–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24092527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blumenthal NR, Hermanson O, Heimrich B, Shastri VP. Stochastic nanoroughness modulates neuron–astrocyte interactions and function via mechanosensing cation channels. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2014;111:16124–16129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4234571</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25349433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bramini M, Rocchi A, Benfenati F, Cesca F. Neuronal cultures and nanomaterials. Adv Neurobiol. 2019;22:51–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31073932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brushart TM, Mathur V, Sood R, Koschorke GM. Dispersion of regenerating axons across enclosed neural gaps. J Hand Surg. 1995;20:557–564.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7594278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao H, Liu T, Chew SY. The application of nanofibrous scaffolds in neural tissue engineering. Adv Drug Deliv Rev. 2009;61:1055–1064.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19643156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang WC, Kliot M, Sretavan DW. Microtechnology and nanotechnology in nerve repair. Neurol Res. 2008;30:1053–1062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19079980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen C, Kong X, Lee IS. Modification of surface/neuron interfaces for neural cell-type specific responses: a review. Biomed Mater. 2015;11:014108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26694886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chew SY, Mi R, Hoke A, Leong KW. The effect of the alignment of electrospun fibrous scaffolds on Schwann cell maturation. Biomaterials. 2008;29:653–661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2713097</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17983651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Luca AC, Lacour SP, Raffoul W, Di Summa PG. Extracellular matrix components in peripheral nerve repair: how to affect neural cellular response and nerve regeneration. Neural Regen Res. 2014;9:1943.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4283273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25598773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Ruiter GC, Onyeneho IA, Liang ET, Moore MJ, Knight AM, Malessy MJ, Spinner RJ, Lu L, Currier BL, Yaszemski MJ. Methods for in vitro characterization of multichannel nerve tubes. J Biomed Mater Res A. 2008;84:643–651.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17635012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dębski T, Kijeńska-Gawrońska E, Zołocińska A, Siennicka K, Słysz A, Paskal W, Włodarski PK, Święszkowski W, Pojda Z. Bioactive nanofiber-based conduits in a peripheral nerve gap management—an animal model study. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:5588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8197537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34070436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong X, Liu S, Yang Y, Gao S, Li W, Cao J, Wan Y, Huang Z, Fan G, Chen Q, Wang H, Zhu M, Kong D. Aligned microfiber-induced macrophage polarization to guide schwann-cell-enabled peripheral nerve regeneration. Biomaterials. 2021;272:120767.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33813259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta RC, Dey M, Dutta AK, Basu B. Competent processing techniques for scaffolds in tissue engineering. Biotechnol Adv. 2017;35:240–250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28095322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Entekhabi E, Haghbin Nazarpak M, Shafieian M, Mohammadi H, Firouzi M, Hassannejad Z. Fabrication and in vitro evaluation of 3D composite scaffold based on collagen/hyaluronic acid sponge and electrospun polycaprolactone nanofibers for peripheral nerve regeneration. J Biomed Mater Res A. 2021;109:300–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32490587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ermis M, Antmen E, Hasirci V. Micro and Nanofabrication methods to control cell-substrate interactions and cell behavior: A review from the tissue engineering perspective. Bioact Mater. 2018;3:355–369.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026330</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghane N, Khalili S, Nouri Khorasani S, Esmaeely Neisiany R, Das O, Ramakrishna S. Regeneration of the peripheral nerve via multifunctional electrospun scaffolds. J Biomed Mater Res A. 2021;109:437–452.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32856425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu X, Ding F, Yang Y, Liu J. Construction of tissue engineered nerve grafts and their application in peripheral nerve regeneration. Prog Neurobiol. 2011;93:204–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21130136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He L, Tian L, Sun Y, Zhang Y, Xue W, So KF, Ramakrishna S, Wu W. Nano-engineered environment for nerve regeneration: Scaffolds functional molecules and stem cells. Curr Stem Cell Res Ther. 2016;11:605–617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26423299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández JCR, Sánchez MS, Soria JM, Ribelles JLG, Pradas MM. Substrate chemistry-dependent conformations of single laminin molecules on polymer surfaces are revealed by the phase signal of atomic force microscopy. Biophys J. 2007;93:202–207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1914422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17416620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jahromi M, Razavi S, Seyedebrahimi R, Reisi P, Kazemi M. Regeneration of rat sciatic nerve using PLGA conduit containing rat ADSCs with controlled release of BDNF and gold nanoparticles. J Mol Neurosci. 2021;71:746–760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33029736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang X, Lim SH, Mao Hai-Quan HQ, Chew SY. Current applications and future perspectives of artificial nerve conduits. Exp Neurol. 2010;223:86–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19769967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katiyar KS, Das S, Burrell JC, Kacy Cullen D.  Scaffolds for bridging sciatic nerve gaps. In: Handbook of tissue engineering scaffolds. In: Mozafari M, Sefat F, Atala A, editors. San Diego: Elsevier Science &amp; Technology; 2019. pp. 67–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JI, Kim CS, Park CH. Harnessing nanotopography of electrospun nanofibrous nerve guide conduits (NGCs) for neural tissue engineering. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2018;1078:395–408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JY, Kim YH, Kim BY, Jang DH, Choi SW, Joen SH, Kim H, Lee SU. Peripheral nerve regeneration using a nerve conduit with olfactory ensheathing cells in a rat model. Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2021;18:453–465.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8169740</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33515167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim JY, Donahue HJ. Cell sensing and response to micro-and nanostructured surfaces produced by chemical and topographic patterning. Tissue Eng. 2007;13:1879–1891.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17583997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S, Xie YY, Wang LD, Tai CX, Chen D, Mu D, Cui YY, Wang B. A multi-channel collagen scaffold loaded with neural stem cells for the repair of spinal cord injury. Neural Regen Res. 2021a;16:2284–2292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33818514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, Yan J, Liu J, Wang Y, Yin J, Fu J. Fabrication of a dual-layer cell-laden tubular scaffold for nerve regeneration and bile duct reconstruction. Biofabrication. 2021b:13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33873178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mackinnon SE, Hudson AR. Clinical application of peripheral nerve transplantation. Plast Reconstr Surg. 1992;90:695–699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1410009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masaeli E, Morshed M, Nasr-Esfahani MH, Sadri S, Hilderink J, van Apeldoorn A, van Blitterswijk CA, Moroni L. Fabrication characterization and cellular compatibility of poly (hydroxy alkanoate) composite nanofibrous scaffolds for nerve tissue engineering. PLoS One. 2013;8:e57157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3584130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mu Y, Wu F, Lu Y, Wei L, Yuan W. Progress of electrospun fibers as nerve conduits for neural tissue repair. Nanomedicine. 2014;9:1869–1883.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25325242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muangsanit P, Roberton V, Costa E, Phillips JB. Engineered aligned endothelial cell structures in tethered collagen hydrogels promote peripheral nerve regeneration. Acta Biomater. 2021;126:224–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33766800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen TY, Liu H. A review of current advances in biomaterials for neural tissue regeneration. Recent Pat Biomed Eng. 2013;6:29–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onode E, Uemura T, Takamatsu K, Yokoi T, Shintani K, Hama S, Miyashima Y, Okada M, Nakamura H. Bioabsorbable nerve conduits three-dimensionally coated with human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived neural stem/progenitor cells promote peripheral nerve regeneration in rats. Sci Rep. 2021;11:1–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7893001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33602991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel NP, Lyon KA, Huang JH. An update-tissue engineered nerve grafts for the repair of peripheral nerve injuries. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13:764–774.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5998615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29862995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahmati M, Mills DK, Urbanska AM, Saeb MR, Venugopal JR, Ramakrishna S, Mozafari M. Electrospinning for tissue engineering applications. Prog Mater Sci. 2021;117:100721.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santoro F, Zhao W, Joubert LM, Duan L, Schnitker J, van de Burgt Y, Lou HY, Liu B, Salleo A, Cui L. Revealing the cell–material interface with nanometer resolution by focused ion beam/scanning electron microscopy. ACS Nano. 2017;11:8320–8328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806611</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28682058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos-Ferreira TF, Borsch O, Ade M. Rebuilding the missing Part—A review on photoreceptor transplantation. Front Syst Neurosci. 2017;10:105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5214672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28105007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satish A, Korrapati PS. Tailored release of triiodothyronine and retinoic acid from a spatio-temporally fabricated nanofiber composite instigating neuronal differentiation. Nanoscale. 2017;9:14565–14580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28932862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidlits SK, Lee JY, Schmidt CE. Nanostructured scaffolds for neural applications. Nanomedicine. 2008;3:183–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18373425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silver J, Miller JH. Regeneration beyond the glial scar. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2004;5:146–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14735117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soman SS, Vijayavenkataraman S. Perspectives on 3d bioprinting of peripheral nerve conduits. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:1–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32806758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tajdaran K, Chan K, Gordon T, Borschel GH. Matrices scaffolds and carriers for protein and molecule delivery in peripheral nerve regeneration. Exp Neurol. 2019;319:112817.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30176220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian L, Prabhakaran MP, Ramakrishna S. Strategies for regeneration of components of nervous system: scaffolds cells and biomolecules. Regen Biomater. 2015;2:31–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4669026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26813399</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres AJ, Wu M, Holowka D, Baird B. Nanobiotechnology and cell biology: micro-and nanofabricated surfaces to investigate receptor-mediated signaling. Annu Rev Biophys. 2008;37:265–288.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18573082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsui C, Koss K, Churchward MA, Todd KG. Biomaterials and glia: Progress on designs to modulate neuroinflammation. Acta Biomaterialia. 2019;83:13–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson PMD, Kavanagh E, Allenby G, Vassey M. Bioengineered 3D glial cell culture systems and applications for neurodegeneration and neuroinflammation. SLAS Discov. 2017;22:583–601.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28346104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue J, Xie J, Liu W, Xia Y. Electrospun nanofibers: new concepts materials and applications. Acc Chem Res. 2017;50:1976–1987.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6589094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28777535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang CY, Huang WY, Chen LH, Liang NW, Wang HC, Lu J, Wang X, Wang TW. Neural tissue engineering: the influence of scaffold surface topography and extracellular matrix microenvironment. J Mater Chem B. 2021;9:567–584.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33289776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi S, Xu L, Gu X. Scaffolds for peripheral nerve repair and reconstruction. Exp Neurol. 2019;319:112761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29772248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yousefzadeh M, Ghasemkhah F.  Design of porous, core-shell, and hollow nanofibers. In: Handbook of nanofibers. In: Barhocem A, editor. Berlin, Germany: Springer International Publishing; 2018. pp. 1–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W, Yang Y, Cui B. New perspectives on the roles of nanoscale surface topography in modulating intracellular signaling. Curr Opin Solid State Mater Sci. 2021;25:100873.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7751896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33364912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
