<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35143427</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Clinical Characteristics and Etiology of Community-acquired Pneumonia in US Children, 2015-2018.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>381</StartPage>
          <EndPage>387</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>381-387</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003475</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Pneumonia has a major impact on childhood health and health care costs. This study was designed to obtain contemporary information on the clinical characteristics and etiology of community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) in children from both inpatient and outpatient settings in the USA.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a prospective, multicenter, observational study of CAP among previously healthy children 2 months to 18 years of age in 6 children's hospitals in Ohio from 2015 to 2018. For pathogen detection, nasopharyngeal swabs were collected from all subjects. Blood and pleural fluid cultures were available per standard of care.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We enrolled a convenience sample of 441 patients: 380 hospitalized and 61 outpatients. Tachypnea and radiologic findings of consolidation and pleural effusion were more frequent among inpatients than outpatients. A pathogen was detected in 64.6% of patients: viruses in 55.6%, atypical bacteria in 8.8% and pyogenic bacteria in 4.3%. Eighteen (4.1%) patients had both viruses and bacteria detected. Rhinovirus/enterovirus (RV; 18.6%) and respiratory syncytial virus (RSV; 16.8%) were the viruses most frequently detected, and Mycoplasma pneumoniae (8.2%) and Streptococcus pneumoniae (2.3%) were the most common bacteria. Except for S. pneumoniae, which was identified more frequently in inpatients, there were no significant differences between inpatients and outpatients in the proportions of children with specific pathogens detected.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Rhinovirus/enterovirus and RSV among viruses and M. pneumoniae and S. pneumoniae among bacteria were the most common pathogens detected in children with CAP. Tachypnea and chest radiographs with consolidation and/or pleural effusion were associated with hospitalization.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ki Wook</ForeName>
            <Initials>KW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Center for Vaccines and Immunity, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Seoul National University College of Medicine and Seoul National University Children's Hospital, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wallihan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Division of Infectious Diseases, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Desai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ankita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center/Rainbow Babies and Children's Hospital, Cleveland, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alter</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sherman</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Dayton Children's Hospital, Dayton, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ambroggio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lilliam</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Sections of Emergency Medicine and Hospital Medicine, Children's Hospital Colorado and the University of Colorado, Aurora, Colorado.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cohen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Division of Emergency Medicine, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>El-Assal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ossama</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Division of Emergency Medicine, Akron Children's Hospital, Akron, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marzec</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sarah</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Division of Hospital Medicine, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Florin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Todd A</ForeName>
            <Initials>TA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine &amp; Division of Emergency Medicine, Ann &amp; Robert H. Lurie Children's Hospital of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Keaton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Meghan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, ProMedica Toledo Children's Hospital, Toledo, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shah</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samir S</ForeName>
            <Initials>SS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center and the University of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ruddy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Richard M</ForeName>
            <Initials>RM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center and the University of Cincinnati College of Medicine, Cincinnati, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sharpe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samantha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leber</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amy L</ForeName>
            <Initials>AL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Everhart</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kathy</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mejias</LastName>
            <ForeName>Asuncion</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Center for Vaccines and Immunity, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Division of Infectious Diseases, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ramilo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Octavio</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Center for Vaccines and Immunity, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Division of Infectious Diseases, Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <CollectiveName>Children’s Hospitals Initiative for Research in Pneumonia</CollectiveName>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001419" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacteria</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017714" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community-Acquired Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009177" MajorTopicYN="N">Mycoplasma pneumoniae</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010996" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pleural Effusion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011014" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pneumonia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018113" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Syncytial Virus, Human</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013296" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus pneumoniae</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059246" MajorTopicYN="N">Tachypnea</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014780" MajorTopicYN="Y">Viruses</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>A.M. has received research grants from the NIH and Janssen and fees from Janssen and Roche for participation in advisory boards. O.R. has received research grants from Janssen, NIH, and the Bill &amp; Melinda and Gates Foundation; fees from Merck, Sanofi/Medimmune, and Pfizer for participation in advisory boards; and fees from Pfizer for educational lectures. A.L.L. has received research funding and participated in advisory boards for BioFire Diagnostics. The remaining authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143427</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003475</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-202205000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu L, Oza S, Hogan D, et al. Global, regional, and national causes of under-5 mortality in 2000-15: an updated systematic analysis with implications for the Sustainable Development Goals. Lancet. 2016;388:3027–3035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madhi SA, De Wals P, Grijalva CG, et al. The burden of childhood pneumonia in the developed world: a review of the literature. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2013;32:e119–e127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leyenaar JK, Ralston SL, Shieh MS, et al. Epidemiology of pediatric hospitalizations at general hospitals and freestanding children’s hospitals in the United States. J Hosp Med. 2016;11:743–749.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain S, Williams DJ, Arnold SR, et al.; CDC EPIC Study Team. Community-acquired pneumonia requiring hospitalization among U.S. children. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:835–845.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bénet T, Sánchez Picot V, Messaoudi M, et al.; Global Approach to Biological Research, Infectious diseases and Epidemics in Low-income countries (GABRIEL) Network; Global Approach to Biological Research, Infectious diseases and Epidemics in Low-income countries (GABRIEL) Network. Microorganisms associated with pneumonia in children &lt;5 years of age in developing and emerging countries: the GABRIEL pneumonia multicenter, prospective, case-control study. Clin Infect Dis. 2017;65:604–612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pneumonia Etiology Research for Child Health (PERCH) Study Group. Causes of severe pneumonia requiring hospital admission in children without HIV infection from Africa and Asia: the PERCH multi-country case-control study. Lancet. 2019;394:757–779.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho Mda G, Tondella ML, McCaustland K, et al. Evaluation and improvement of real-time PCR assays targeting lytA, ply, and psaA genes for detection of pneumococcal DNA. J Clin Microbiol. 2007;45:2460–2466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunne EM, Marshall JL, Baker CA, et al. Detection of group a streptococcal pharyngitis by quantitative PCR. BMC Infect Dis. 2013;13:312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okolie CE. Real-time PCR to identify staphylococci and assay for virulence from blood. Methods Mol Biol. 2017;1616:183–207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hardegger D, Nadal D, Bossart W, et al. Rapid detection of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in clinical samples by real-time PCR. J Microbiol Methods. 2000;41:45–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipshaw MJ, Eckerle M, Florin TA, et al. Antibiotic use and outcomes in children in the emergency department with suspected pneumonia. Pediatrics. 2020;145:e20193138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morpeth SC, Deloria Knoll M, Scott JAG, et al.; PERCH Study Group. Detection of pneumococcal DNA in blood by polymerase chain reaction for diagnosing pneumococcal pneumonia in young children from low- and middle-income countries. Clin Infect Dis. 2017;64(suppl_3):S347–S356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Sakthivel SK, Bramley A, et al. Serology enhances molecular diagnosis of respiratory virus infections other than influenza in children and adults hospitalized with community-acquired pneumonia. J Clin Microbiol. 2017;55:79–89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oumei H, Xuefeng W, Jianping L, et al. Etiology of community-acquired pneumonia in 1500 hospitalized children. J Med Virol. 2018;90:421–428.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamano-Hasegawa K, Morozumi M, Nakayama E, et al.; Acute Respiratory Diseases Study Group. Comprehensive detection of causative pathogens using real-time PCR to diagnose pediatric community-acquired pneumonia. J Infect Chemother. 2008;14:424–432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kutty PK, Jain S, Taylor TH, et al. Mycoplasma pneumoniae among children hospitalized with community-acquired pneumonia. Clin Infect Dis. 2019;68:5–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spuesens EB, Fraaij PL, Visser EG, et al. Carriage of Mycoplasma pneumoniae in the upper respiratory tract of symptomatic and asymptomatic children: an observational study. PLoS Med. 2013;10:e1001444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zar HJ, Barnett W, Stadler A, et al. Aetiology of childhood pneumonia in a well vaccinated South African birth cohort: a nested case-control study of the Drakenstein Child Health Study. Lancet Respir Med. 2016;4:463–472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Self WH, Williams DJ, Zhu Y, et al. Respiratory viral detection in children and adults: comparing asymptomatic controls and patients with community-acquired pneumonia. J Infect Dis. 2016;213:584–591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlaberg R, Queen K, Simmon K, et al. Viral pathogen detection by metagenomics and pan-viral group polymerase chain reaction in children with pneumonia lacking identifiable etiology. J Infect Dis. 2017;215:1407–1415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mejias A, Suarez NM, Ramilo O. Detecting specific infections in children through host responses: a paradigm shift. Curr Opin Infect Dis. 2014;27:228–235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
