<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35142659</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Sep</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Astrocytes protect dopaminergic neurons against aminochrome neurotoxicity.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1861</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1866</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1861-1866</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.335690</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Astrocytes protect neurons by modulating neuronal function and survival. Astrocytes support neurons in several ways. They provide energy through the astrocyte-neuron lactate shuttle, protect neurons from excitotoxicity, and internalize neuronal lipid droplets to degrade fatty acids for neuronal metabolic and synaptic support, as well as by their high capacity for glutamate uptake and the conversion of glutamate to glutamine. A recent reported astrocyte system for protection of dopamine neurons against the neurotoxic products of dopamine, such as aminochrome and other o-quinones, were generated under neuromelanin synthesis by oxidizing dopamine catechol structure. Astrocytes secrete glutathione transferase M2-2 through exosomes that transport this enzyme into dopaminergic neurons to protect these neurons against aminochrome neurotoxicity. The role of this new astrocyte protective mechanism in Parkinson´s disease is discussed.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Segura-Aguilar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Molecular and Clinical Pharmacology ICBM Faculty of Medicine University of Chile, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mannervik</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bengt</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Biophysics, Arrhenius Laboratories, Stockholm University, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Inzunza</LastName>
            <ForeName>José</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biosciences and Nutrition, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Varshney</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mukesh</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biosciences and Nutrition, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nalvarte</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ivan</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biosciences and Nutrition, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Muñoz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Patricia</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Molecular and Clinical Pharmacology ICBM Faculty of Medicine University of Chile; Nucleo de Química y Bioquímica, Facultad de Estudios Interdisciplinarios, Universidad Mayor, Santiago, Chile.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson’s disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aminochrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocytes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dopaminergic neurons</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exosomes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glutathione transferase M2-2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroprotection</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142659</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8848618</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.335690</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_9_1861_335690</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson DW, Schray RC, Duester G, Schneider JS. Functional significance of aldehyde dehydrogenase ALDH1A1 to the nigrostriatal dopamine system. Brain Res. 2011;1408:81–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3995134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baxter PS, Bell KF, Hasel P, Kaindl AM, Fricker M, Thomson D, Cregan SP, Gillingwater TH, Hardingham GE. Synaptic NMDA receptor activity is coupled to the transcriptional control of the glutathione system. Nat Commun. 2015;6:6761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4403319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25854456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bisaglia M, Mammi S, Bubacco L. Kinetic and structural analysis of the early oxidation products of dopamine: analysis of the interactions with alpha-synuclein. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:15597–15605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bisaglia M, Soriano ME, Arduini I, Mammi S, Bubacco L. Molecular characterization of dopamine-derived quinones reactivity toward NADH and glutathione: implications for mitochondrial dysfunction in Parkinson disease. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2010;1802:699–706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20600874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolaños JP. Bioenergetics and redox adaptations of astrocytes to neuronal activity. J Neurochem 139 Suppl. 2016;2:115–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5018236</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26968531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braak H, Del Tredici K, Rüb U, de Vos RA, Jansen Steur EN, Braak E. Staging of brain pathology related to sporadic Parkinson’s disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2003;24:197–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12498954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruning JM, Wang Y, Oltrabella F, Tian B, Kholodar SA, Liu H, Bhattacharya P, Guo S, Holton JM, Fletterick RJ, Jacobson MP, England PM. Covalent modification and regulation of the nuclear receptor Nurr1 by a dopamine metabolite. Cell Chem Biol. 2019;26:674–685.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7185887</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30853418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassidy CM, Zucca FA, Girgis RR, Baker SC, Weinstein JJ, Sharp ME, Bellei C, Valmadre A, Vanegas N, Kegeles LS, Brucato G, Kang UJ, Sulzer D, Zecca L, Abi-Dargham A, Horga G. Neuromelanin-sensitive MRI as a noninvasive proxy measure of dopamine function in the human brain. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2019;116:5108–5117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6421437</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30796187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Rui M, Inelmen EM, Trevisan C, Pigozzo S, Manzato E, Sergi G. Parkinson's disease and the non-motor symptoms: hyposmia, weight loss, osteosarcopenia. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2020 10.1007/s40520-020-01470-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dienel GA. Brain glucose metabolism: integration of energetics with function. Physiol Rev. 2019;99:949–1045.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30565508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du XY, Xie XX, Liu RT. The role of α-synuclein oligomers in Parkinson’s disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:8645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7697105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33212758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durkee CA, Covelo A, Lines J, Kofuji P, Aguilar J, Araque A. Gi/o protein-coupled receptors inhibit neurons but activate astrocytes and stimulate gliotransmission. Glia. 2019;67:1076–1093.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6462242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30801845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farmer BC, Kluemper J, Johnson LA. Apolipoprotein E4 alters astrocyte fatty acid metabolism and lipid droplet formation. Cells. 2019;8:182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6406677</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernández-Moncada I, Robles-Maldonado D, Castro P, Alegría K, Epp R, Ruminot I, Barros LF. Bidirectional astrocytic GLUT1 activation by elevated extracellular K. Glia. 2021;69:1012–1021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33277953</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fields CR, Bengoa-Vergniory N, Wade-Martins R. Targeting alpha-synuclein as a therapy for Parkinson’s disease. Front Mol Neurosci. 2019;12:299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6906193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31866823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Follmer C, Coelho-Cerqueira E, Yatabe-Franco DY, Araujo GD, Pinheiro AS, Domont GB, Eliezer D. Oligomerization and membrane-binding properties of covalent adducts formed by the interaction of a-synuclein with the toxic dopamine metabolite 3,4-dihydroxyphenylacetaldehyde (DOPAL) J Biol Chem. 2015;290:27660–27679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4646016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26381411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaig C, Marti MJ, Ezquerra M, Rey MJ, Cardozo A, Tolosa E. G2019S LEUCINE RICH REPEAT KINASE-2 mutation causing Parkinson's disease without Lewy bodies. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:626–628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17210620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganguly U, Chakrabarti SS, Kaur U, Mukherjee A, Chakrabarti S. Alpha-synuclein proteotoxicity and Parkinson’s disease: search for neuroprotective therapy. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2018;16:1086–1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6120113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29189163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giasson BI, Covy JP, Bonini NM, Hurtig HI, Farrer MJ, Trojanowski JQ, Van Deerlin VM. Biochemical and pathological characterization of Lrrk2. Ann Neurol. 2006;59:315–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16437584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldstein DS. The “Sick-but-not-Dead” phenomenon applied to catecholamine deficiency in neurodegenerative diseases. Semin Neurol. 2020;40:502–514.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32906170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grünblatt E, Mandel S, Jacob-Hirsch J, Zeligson S, Amariglo N, Rechavi G, Li J, Ravid R, Roggendorf W, Riederer P, Youdim MB. Gene expression profiling of parkinsonian substantia nigra pars compacta; alterations in ubiquitin-proteasome heat shock protein iron and oxidative stress regulated proteins cell adhesion/cellular matrix and vesicle trafficking genes. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2004;111:1543–1573.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15455214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herrera A, Muñoz P, Steinbusch HWM, Segura-Aguilar J. Are dopamine oxidation metabolites involved in the loss of dopaminergic neurons in the nigrostriatal system in Parkinson’s disease. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2017;8:702–711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28233992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu ZL, Sun T, Lu M, Ding JH, Du RH, Hu G. Kir6.1/K-ATP channel on astrocytes protects against dopaminergic neurodegeneration in the MPTP mouse model of Parkinson's disease via promoting mitophagy. Brain Behav Immun. 2019;81:509–522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huenchuguala S, Muñoz P, Segura-Aguilar J. The importance of mitophagy in maintaining mitochondrial function in U373MG cells. Bafilomycin A1 restores aminochrome-induced mitochondrial damage. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2017;8:2247–2253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28763613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ioannou MS, Jackson J, Sheu SH, Chang CL, Weigel AV, Liu H, Pasolli HA, Xu CS, Pang S, Matthies D, Hess HF, Lippincott-Schwartz J, Liu Z. Neuron-astrocyte metabolic coupling protects against activity-induced fatty acid toxicity. Cell. 2019;177:1522–1535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31130380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jankovic J, Tan EK. Parkinson’s disease: etiopathogenesis and treatment. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91:795–808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jha MK, Morrison BM. Lactate transporters mediate glia-neuron metabolic crosstalk in homeostasis and disease. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:589582.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33132853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lafon-Cazal M, Adjali O, Galéotti N, Poncet J, Jouin P, Homburger V, Bockaert J, Marin P. Proteomic analysis of astrocytic secretion in the mouse. Comparison with the cerebrospinal fluid proteome. J Biol Chem. 2003;278:24438–24448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12709418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LaVoie MJ, Ostaszewski BL, Weihofen A, Schlossmacher MG, Selkoe DJ. Dopamine covalently modifies and functionally inactivates parkin. Nat Med. 2005;11:1214–1221.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16227987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee N, Sa M, Hong YR, Lee CJ, Koo J. Fatty acid increases cAMP-dependent lactate and MAO-B-dependent GABA production in mouse astrocytes by activating a Gαs protein-coupled receptor. Exp Neurobiol. 2018;27:365–376.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6221839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li T, Liu T, Chen X, Li L, Feng M, Zhang Y, Wan L, Zhang C, Yao W. Microglia induce the transformation of A1/A2 reactive astrocytes via the CXCR7/PI3K/Akt pathway in chronic post-surgical pain. J Neuroinflammation. 2020;17:211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7362409</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32665021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ling H, Kara E, Bandopadhyay R, Hardy J, Holton J, Xiromerisiou G, Lees A, Houlden H, Revesz T. TDP-43 pathology in a patient carrying G2019S leucine rich repeat kinase-2 mutation and a novel p.Q124E MAPT. Neurobiol Aging. 2013;34:2889.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23664753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu G, Yu J, Ding J, Xie C, Sun L, Rudenko I, Zheng W, Sastry N, Luo J, Rudow G, Troncoso JC, Cai H. Aldehyde dehydrogenase 1 defines and protects a nigrostriatal dopaminergic neuron subpopulation. J Clin Invest. 2014;124:3032–3046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4071380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24865427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margineanu MB, Sherwin E, Golubeva A, Peterson V, Hoban A, Fiumelli H, Rea K, Cryan JF, Magistretti PJ. Gut microbiota modulates expression of genes involved in the astrocyte-neuron lactate shuttle in the hippocampus. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2020;41:152–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33191074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinez-Vicente M, Vila M. Alpha-synuclein and protein degradation pathways in Parkinson’s disease: a pathological feed-back loop. Exp Neurol. 2013;13:88–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23499831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayorquin LC, Rodriguez AV, Sutachan JJ, Albarracín SL. Connexin-mediated functional and metabolic coupling between astrocytes and neurons. Front Mol Neurosci. 2018;11:118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5905222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGann JC, Mandel G. Neuronal activity induces glutathione metabolism gene expression in astrocytes. Glia. 2018;66:2024–2039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6185788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercado G, Castillo V, Soto P, Sidhu A. ER stress and Parkinson disease: pathological inputs that converge into the secretory pathway. Brain Res. 2016;16:30260–30268.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27103567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moors T, Paciotti S, Chiasserini D, Calabresi P, Parnetti L, Beccari T, van de Berg WD. Lysosomal dysfunction and α-synuclein aggregation in Parkinson’s disease. Diagnostic Links Mov Disord. 2016;6:791–801.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26923732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mor DE, Daniels MJ, Ischiropoulos H. The usual suspects, dopamine and alpha-synuclein, conspire to cause neurodegeneration. Mov Disord. 2019;34:167–179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6379109</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30633814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori H, Kondo T, Yokochi M, Matsumine H, Nakagawa-Hattori Y, Miyake T, Suda K, Mizuno Y. Pathologic and biochemical studies of juvenile parkinsonism linked to chromosome 6q. Neurology. 1998;51:890.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9748052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz P, Cardenas S, Huenchuguala S, Briceño A, Couve E, Paris I, Segura-Aguilar J. DT-diaphorase prevents aminochrome-induced alpha-synuclein oligomer formation and neurotoxicity. Toxicol Sci. 2015;145:37–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4833033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25634539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paris I, Muñoz P, Huenchuguala S, Couve E, Sanders LH, Greenamyre JT, Caviedes P, Segura-Aguilar J. Autophagy protects against aminochrome-induced cell death in substantia nigra-derived cell line. Toxicol Sci. 2011;121:376–388.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3145404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21427056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pezzella A, Crescenzi O, Natangelo A, Panzella L, Napolitano A, Navaratnam S, Edge R, Land EJ, Barone V, d’Ischia M. Chemical pulse radiolysis and density functional studies of a new labile 5,6-indolequinone and its semiquinone. J Org Chem. 2007;72:1595–1603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17266371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qi G, Mi Y, Shi X, Gu H, Brinton RD, Yin F. ApoE4 impairs neuron-astrocyte coupling of fatty acid metabolism. Cell Rep. 2021;34:108572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7837265</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33406436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajput A, Dickson DW, Robinson CA, Ross OA, Dachsel JC, Lincoln SJ, Cobb SA, Rajput ML, Farrer MJ. Parkinsonism, Leucine rich repeat kinase-2 G2019S, and tau neuropathology. Neurology. 2006;67:1506–1508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17060589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roos DS, Twisk JWR, Raijmakers PGHM, Doty RL, Berendse HW. Hyposmia as a marker of (non-) motor disease severity in Parkinson’s disease. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2019;126:1471–1478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31515655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ross JM, Olson L, Coppotelli G. Mitochondrial and ubiquitin proteasome system dysfunction in ageing and disease: two sides of the same coin. Int J Mol Sci. 2015;16:19458–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4581307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26287188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schousboe A. Astrocytic metabolism focusing on glutamate homeostasis: a short review dedicated to vittorio gallo. Neurochem Res. 2020;45:522–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31617053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag A, Horsfall L, Walters K, Noyce A, Petersen I. Prediagnostic presentations of Parkinson’s disease in primary care: a case-control study. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14:57–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25435387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segura-Aguilar J.  In: Clinical studies and therapies in Parkinson's disease: translations from preclinical models (Segura-Aguilar J, ed) Cambridge: Elsevier; 2021a. Dopamine oxidation to neuromelanin and neurotoxic metabolites; pp. 213–223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segura-Aguilar J.  In: Clinical studies and therapies in Parkinson's disease: translations from preclinical models (Segura-Aguilar J, ed) Cambridge: Elsevier; 2021b. Neuroprotective mechanisms against dopamine oxidationdependent neurotoxicity; pp. 229–237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tarczyluk MA, Nagel DA, O’Neil JD, Parri HR, Tse EH, Coleman MD, Hill EJ. Functional astrocyte-neuron lactate shuttle in a human stem cell-derived neuronal network. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2013;33:1386–1393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3764384</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23715062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor JM, Main BS, Crack PJ. Neuroinflammation and oxidative stress: Co-conspirators in the pathology of Parkinson’s disease. Neurochem Int. 2013;62:803–819.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23291248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torrez VR, Zimmer ER, Kalinine E, Haas CB, Zenki KC, Muller AP, Souza DO, Portela LV. Memantine mediates astrocytic activity in response to excitotoxicity induced by PP2A inhibition. Neurosci Lett. 2019;696:179–183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valdes R, Armijo A, Muñoz P, Hultenby K, Hagg A, Inzunza J, Nalvarte I, Varshney M, Mannervik B, Segura-Aguilar J. Cellular trafficking of glutathione transferase M2-2 between U373MG and SHSY-S7 cells is mediated by exosomes. Neurotox Res. 2021;39:182–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33555546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Laar VS, Mishizen AJ, Cascio M, Hastings TG. Proteomic identification of dopamine-conjugated proteins from isolated rat brain mitochondria and SH-SY5Y cells. Neurobiol Dis. 2009;34:487–500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2759724</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19332121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vargas MR, Pehar M, Cassina P, Beckman JS, Barbeito L. Increased glutathione biosynthesis by Nrf2 activation in astrocytes prevents p75NTR-dependent motor neuron apoptosis. J Neurochem. 2006;97:687–696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16524372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volpicelli-Daley L, Brundin P. Prion-like propagation of pathology in Parkinson disease. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;153:321–335.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6625652</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29887143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang XF, Cynader MS. Astrocytes provide cysteine to neurons by releasing glutathione. J Neurochem. 2000;74:1434–1442.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10737599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang XY, Han YY, Li G, Zhang B. Association between autonomic dysfunction and olfactory dysfunction in Parkinson’s disease in southern Chinese. BMC Neurol. 2019;19:17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6359856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welcome MO, Mastorakis NE. Emerging concepts in brain glucose metabolic functions: from glucose sensing to how the sweet taste of glucose regulates its own metabolism in astrocytes and neurons. Neuromolecular Med. 2018;20:281–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30022304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wey MC, Fernandez E, Martinez PA, Sullivan P, Goldstein DS, Strong R. Neurodegeneration and motor dysfunction in mice lacking cytosolic and mitochondrial aldehyde dehydrogenases: implications for Parkinson’s disease. PLoS One. 2012;7:e31522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3284575</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22384032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitehead RE, Ferrer JV, Javitch JA, Justice JB. Reaction of oxidized dopamine with endogenous cysteine residues in the human dopamine transporter. J Neurochem. 2001;76:1242–1251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11181843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams A. MPTP toxicity: clinical features. J Neural Transm Suppl. 1986;20:5–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3489070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiong R, Siegel D, Ross D. Quinone-induced protein handling changes: implications for major protein handling systems in quinone-mediated toxicity. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol. 2014;280:285–295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312139</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25151970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y, Stokes AH, Roskoski R Jr, Vrana KE. Dopamine in the presence of tyrosinase covalently modifies and inactivates tyrosine hydroxylase. J Neurosci Res. 1998;54:691–697.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9843160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang F, Li Y, Pan H, Wu K, Lu Y, Shi F. A novel LC-MS/MS method for quantification of unstable endogenous 3,4-dihydroxyphenylacetaldehyde in rat brain after chemical derivatization. J Pharm Biomed Anal. 2020;2020:113822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33358301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zafar KS, Inayat-Hussain SH, Siegel D, Bao A, Shieh B, Ross D. Overexpression of NQO1 protects human SK-N-MC neuroblastoma cells against dopamine-induced cell death. Toxicol Lett. 2006a;166:261–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16978807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaltieri M, Longhena F, Pizzi M, Missale C, Spano P, Bellucci A. Mitochondrial dysfunction and α-synuclein synaptic pathology in Parkinson’s disease: who’s on first. Parkinsons Dis. 2015;2015:108029.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4396726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25918668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
