<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35143049</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>530</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Spatial distribution of beta-klotho mRNA in the mouse hypothalamus, hippocampal region, subiculum, and amygdala.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1634</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1657</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1634-1657</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25306</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Beta-klotho (KLB) is a coreceptor required for endocrine fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 15/19 and FGF21 signaling in the brain. Klb is prominent within the hypothalamus, which is consistent with its metabolic functions, but diverse roles for Klb are now emerging. Central Klb expression is low but discrete and may govern FGF-targeted sites. However, given its low expression, it is unclear if Klb mRNA is more widespread. We performed in situ hybridization to label Klb mRNA to generate spatial maps capturing the distribution and levels of Klb within the mouse hypothalamus, hippocampal region, subiculum, and amygdala. Semiquantitative analysis revealed that Klb-labeled cells may express low, medium, or high levels of Klb mRNA. Hypothalamic Klb hybridization was heterogeneous and varied rostrocaudally within the same region. Most Klb-labeled cells were found in the lateral hypothalamic zone, but the periventricular hypothalamic region, including the suprachiasmatic nucleus, contained the greatest proportion of cells expressing medium or high Klb levels. We also found heterogeneous Klb hybridization in the amygdala and subiculum, where Klb was especially distinct within the central amygdalar nucleus and ventral subiculum, respectively. By contrast, Klb-labeled cells in the hippocampal region only expressed low levels of Klb and were typically found in the pyramidal layer of Ammon's horn or dentate gyrus. The Klb-labeled regions identified in this study are consistent with reported roles of Klb in metabolism, taste preference, and neuroprotection. However, additional identified sites, including within the hypothalamus and amygdala, may suggest novel roles for FGF15/19 or FGF21 signaling.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bono</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bianca S</ForeName>
            <Initials>BS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5078-9682</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Koziel Ly</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nikita K</ForeName>
            <Initials>NK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2889-9973</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Persephone A</ForeName>
            <Initials>PA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3997-6735</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Williams-Ikhenoba</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jesukhogie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1628-3071</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dumiaty</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yasmina</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1784-9361</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melissa J</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3815-9095</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000679" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amygdala</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002540" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral Cortex</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hippocampus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007031" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypothalamus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FGF15</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FGF19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FGF21</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FISH</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RRID:AB_221570</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RRID:AB_2536183</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RRID:SCR_016477</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amygdala</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta-klotho</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hippocampus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypothalamus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mouse</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143049</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25306</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abercrombie, M. (1946). Estimation of nuclear population from microtome sections. Anatomical Record, 94, 239-247. https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.1090940210</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrahao, K. P., Salinas, A. G., &amp; Lovinger, D. M. (2017). Alcohol and the brain: Neuronal molecular targets, synapses, and circuits. Neuron, 96(6), 1223-1238. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2017.10.032</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Advanced Cell Diagnostics. (2014). RNAscope manual solutions: Biomarker analysis by RNA in situ hybridization. Document 321245/081414/revA. Advanced Cell Diagnostics Inc.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Advanced Cell Diagnostics. (2017). A guide for RNAscope data analysis. Document MK 51-103. Advanced Cell Diagnostics Inc.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agoglia A. E., Herman M. A. (2018). The center of the emotional universe: Alcohol, stress, and CRF1 amygdala circuitry. Alcohol, 72, 61. -73. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.alcohol.2018.03.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen Institute for Brain Science. (2011). Technical white paper: Allen reference atlas, version 1 (2008) (PDF file). Allen Institute for Brain Science.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asada, M., Shinomiya, M., Suzuki, M., Honda, E., Sugimoto, R., Ikekita, M., &amp; Imamura, T. (2009). Glycosaminoglycan affinity of the complete fibroblast growth factor family. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta, 1790(1), 40-48. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbagen.2008.09.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badman, M. K., Pissios, P., Kennedy, A. R., Koukos, G., Flier, J. S., &amp; Maratos-Flier, E. (2007). Hepatic fibroblast growth factor 21 is regulated by PPARalpha and is a key mediator of hepatic lipid metabolism in ketotic states. Cell Metabolism, 5(6), 426-437. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2007.05.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bookout, A. L., De Groot, M. H. M., Owen, B. M., Lee, S., Gautron, L., Lawrence, H. L., Ding, X., Elmquist, J. K., Takahashi, J. S., Mangelsdorf, D. J., &amp; Kliewer, S. A. (2013). FGF21 regulates metabolism and circadian behavior by acting on the nervous system. Nature Medicine, 19(9), 1147-1152. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm.3249</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busch, S., Selcho, M., Ito, K., &amp; Tanimoto, H. (2009). A map of octopaminergic neurons in the Drosophila brain. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 513(6), 643-667. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21966</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canteras, N. S., &amp; Swanson, L. W. (1992). Projections of the ventral subiculum to the amygdala, septum, and hypothalamus: A PHAL anterograde tract-tracing study in the rat. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 324(2), 180-194. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903240204</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, S., Chen, S.-T., Sun, Y., Xu, Z., Wang, Y., Yao, S.-Y., Yao, W.-B., &amp; Gao, X.-D. (2019). Fibroblast growth factor 21 ameliorates neurodegeneration in rat and cellular models of Alzheimer's disease. Redox Biology, 22, 101133. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.redox.2019.101133</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Sousa Abreu, R., Penalva, L. O., Marcotte, E. M., &amp; Vogel, C. (2009). Global signatures of protein and mRNA expression levels. Molecular Biosystems, 5(12), 1512-1526. https://doi.org/10.1039/b908315d</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding, X., Boney-Montoya, J., Owen, B. M., Bookout, A. L., Coate, K. C., Mangelsdorf, D. J., &amp; Kliewer, S. A. (2012). betaKlotho is required for fibroblast growth factor 21 effects on growth and metabolism. Cell Metabolism, 16(3), 387-393. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2012.08.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong, H. W. (2008). The Allen reference atlas: A digital color brain atlas of the C57BL/6J male mouse. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Douris, N., Stevanovic, D. M., Fisher, F. M., Cisu, T. I., Chee, M. J., Nguyen, N. L., Zarebidaki, E., Adams, A. C., Kharitonenkov, A., Flier, J. S., Bartness, T. J., &amp; Maratos-Flier, E. (2015). Central fibroblast growth factor 21 browns white fat via sympathetic action in male mice. Endocrinology, 156(7), 2470-2481. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2014-2001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dushay, J. R., Toschi, E., Mitten, E. K., Fisher, F. M., Herman, M. A., &amp; Maratos-Flier, E. (2015). Fructose ingestion acutely stimulates circulating FGF21 levels in humans. Molecular Metabolism, 4(1), 51-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmet.2014.09.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flippo K. H., Trammell S. A. J., Gillum M. P., Aklan I., Perez M. B., Yavuz Y., Smith N. K., Jensen-Cody S. O., Zhou B., Claflin K. E., Beierschmitt A., Fink-Jensen A., Knop F. K., Palmour R. M., Grueter B. A., Atasoy D., Potthoff M. J. (2022). FGF21 suppresses alcohol consumption through an amygdalo-striatal circuit. Cell Metabolism, 34(2), 317-328. e6. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2021.12.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fon Tacer, K., Bookout, A. L., Ding, X., Kurosu, H., John, G. B., Wang, L., Goetz, R., Mohammadi, M., Kuro-O, M., Mangelsdorf, D. J., &amp; Kliewer, S. A. (2010). Research resource: Comprehensive expression atlas of the fibroblast growth factor system in adult mouse. Molecular Endocrinology, 24(10), 2050-2064. https://doi.org/10.1210/me.2010-0142</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilpin, N. W., Herman, M. A., &amp; Roberto, M. (2015). The central amygdala as an integrative hub for anxiety and alcohol use disorders. Biological Psychiatry, 77(10), 859-869. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2014.09.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goetz, R., Beenken, A., Ibrahimi, O. A., Kalinina, J., Olsen, S. K., Eliseenkova, A. V., Xu, C., Neubert, T. A., Zhang, F., Linhardt, R. J., Yu, X., White, K. E., Inagaki, T., Kliewer, S. A., Yamamoto, M., Kurosu, H., Ogawa, Y., Kuro-O, M., Lanske, B., … Mohammadi, M. (2007). Molecular insights into the klotho-dependent, endocrine mode of action of fibroblast growth factor 19 subfamily members. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 27(9), 3417-3428. https://doi.org/10.1128/MCB.02249-06</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez, A. M., Berry, M., Maher, P. A., Logan, A., &amp; Baird, A. (1995). A comprehensive analysis of the distribution of FGF-2 and FGFR1 in the rat brain. Brain Research, 701(1-2), 201-226. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(95)01002-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harmer, N. J., Pellegrini, L., Chirgadze, D., Fernandez-Recio, J., &amp; Blundell, T. L. (2004). The crystal structure of fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 19 reveals novel features of the FGF family and offers a structural basis for its unusual receptor affinity. Biochemistry, 43(3), 629-640. https://doi.org/10.1021/bi035320k</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill, C. M., Laeger, T., Dehner, M., Albarado, D. C., Clarke, B., Wanders, D., Burke, S. J., Collier, J. J., Qualls-Creekmore, E., Solon-Biet, S. M., Simpson, S. J., Berthoud, H.-R., Münzberg, H., &amp; Morrison, C. D. (2019). FGF21 signals protein status to the brain and adaptively regulates food choice and metabolism. Cell Reports, 27(10), 2934-2947.e3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2019.05.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoover, W. B., &amp; Vertes, R. P. (2007). Anatomical analysis of afferent projections to the medial prefrontal cortex in the rat. Brain Structure and Function, 212(2), 149-179. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00429-007-0150-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsuchou, H., Pan, W., &amp; Kastin, A. J. (2007). The fasting polypeptide FGF21 can enter brain from blood. Peptides, 28(12), 2382-2386. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.peptides.2007.10.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsuchou, H., Pan, W., &amp; Kastin, A. J. (2013). Fibroblast growth factor 19 entry into brain. Fluids Barriers CNS, 10(1), 32. https://doi.org/10.1186/2045-8118-10-32</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hultman, K., Scarlett, J. M., Baquero, A. F., Cornea, A., Zhang, Y., Salinas, C. B. G., Brown, J., Morton, G. J., Whalen, E. J., Grove, K. L., Koegler, F. H., Schwartz, M. W., &amp; Mercer, A. J. (2019). The central fibroblast growth factor receptor/beta klotho system: Comprehensive mapping in Mus musculus and comparisons to nonhuman primate and human samples using an automated in situ hybridization platform. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 527(12), 2069-2085. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24668</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inagaki, T., Dutchak, P., Zhao, G., Ding, X., Gautron, L., Parameswara, V., Li, Y., Goetz, R., Mohammadi, M., Esser, V., Elmquist, J. K., Gerard, R. D., Burgess, S. C., Hammer, R. E., Mangelsdorf, D. J., &amp; Kliewer, S. A. (2007). Endocrine regulation of the fasting response by PPARalpha-mediated induction of fibroblast growth factor 21. Cell Metabolism, 5(6), 415-425. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2007.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen-Cody, S. O., Flippo, K. H., Claflin, K. E., Yavuz, Y., Sapouckey, S. A., Walters, G. C., Usachev, Y. M., Atasoy, D., Gillum, M. P., &amp; Potthoff, M. J. (2020). FGF21 signals to glutamatergic neurons in the ventromedial hypothalamus to suppress carbohydrate intake. Cell Metabolism, 32(2), 273-286.e6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2020.06.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang, K., Xu, P., Wang, M., Chunyu, J., Sun, X., Ren, G., Xiao, W., &amp; Li, D. (2020). FGF21 attenuates neurodegeneration through modulating neuroinflammation and oxidant-stress. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy, 129, 110439. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110439</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kharitonenkov, A., Dunbar, J. D., Bina, H. A., Bright, S., Moyers, J. S., Zhang, C., Ding, L., Micanovic, R., Mehrbod, S. F., Knierman, M. D., Hale, J. E., Coskun, T., &amp; Shanafelt, A. B. (2008). FGF-21/FGF-21 receptor interaction and activation is determined by betaKlotho. Journal of Cellular Physiology, 215(1), 1-7. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcp.21357</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koob, G. F. (2009). Brain stress systems in the amygdala and addiction. Brain Research, 1293, 61-75. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2009.03.038</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koob, G. F., &amp; Volkow, N. D. (2016). Neurobiology of addiction: A neurocircuitry analysis. Lancet Psychiatry, 3(8), 760-773. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215-0366(16)00104-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurosu, H., Choi, M., Ogawa, Y., Dickson, A. S., Goetz, R., Eliseenkova, A. V., Mohammadi, M., Rosenblatt, K. P., Kliewer, S. A., &amp; Kuro-O, M. (2007). Tissue-specific expression of betaKlotho and fibroblast growth factor (FGF) receptor isoforms determines metabolic activity of FGF19 and FGF21. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 282(37), 26687-26695. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M704165200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lan, T., Morgan, D. A., Rahmouni, K., Sonoda, J., Fu, X., Burgess, S. C., Holland, W. L., Kliewer, S. A., &amp; Mangelsdorf, D. J. (2017). FGF19, FGF21, and an FGFR1/beta-klotho-activating antibody act on the nervous system to regulate body weight and glycemia. Cell Metabolism, 26(5), 709-718.e3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2017.09.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, Q., Zhong, L., Zhang, J., Wang, Y., Bornstein, S. R., Triggle, C. R., Ding, H., Lam, K. S. L., &amp; Xu, A. (2014). FGF21 maintains glucose homeostasis by mediating the cross talk between liver and brain during prolonged fasting. Diabetes, 63(12), 4064-4075. https://doi.org/10.2337/db14-0541</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, B. C., Wang, M., Blackmore, C., &amp; Desnoyers, L. R. (2007). Liver-specific activities of FGF19 require Klotho beta. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 282(37), 27277-27284. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M704244200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, V. B., Ballanyi, K., Colmers, W. F., &amp; Smith, P. A. (2007). Neuron type-specific effects of brain-derived neurotrophic factor in rat superficial dorsal horn and their relevance to ‘central sensitization’. Journal of Physiology, 584(Pt 2), 543-563. https://doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2007.141267</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marcelin, G., Jo, Y.-H., Li, X., Schwartz, G. J., Zhang, Y., Dun, N. J., Lyu, R.-M., Blouet, C., Chang, J. K., &amp; Chua, S. (2014). Central action of FGF19 reduces hypothalamic AGRP/NPY neuron activity and improves glucose metabolism. Molecular Metabolism, 3(1), 19-28. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmet.2013.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mickelsen, L. E., Bolisetty, M., Chimileski, B. R., Fujita, A., Beltrami, E. J., Costanzo, J. T., Naparstek, J. R., Robson, P., &amp; Jackson, A. C. (2019). Single-cell transcriptomic analysis of the lateral hypothalamic area reveals molecularly distinct populations of inhibitory and excitatory neurons. Nature Neuroscience, 22(4), 642-656. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41593-019-0349-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morton, G. J., Matsen, M. E., Bracy, D. P., Meek, T. H., Nguyen, H. T., Stefanovski, D., Bergman, R. N., Wasserman, D. H., &amp; Schwartz, M. W. (2013). FGF19 action in the brain induces insulin-independent glucose lowering. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 123(11), 4799-4808. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI70710</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morton, G. J., Kaiyala, K. J., Foster-Schubert, K. E., Cummings, D. E., &amp; Schwartz, M. W. (2014). Carbohydrate feeding dissociates the postprandial FGF19 response from circulating bile acid levels in humans. Journal of Clinical Endocrinology and Metabolism, 99(2), E241-E245. https://doi.org/10.1210/jc.2013-3129</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore, R. Y., Reppert, S. M., &amp; Klein, D. C. (1991). Suprachiasmatic nucleus: The mind's clock. Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mutsnaini, L., Kim, C.-S., Kim, J., Joe, Y., Chung, H. T., Choi, H.-S., Roh, E., Kim, M.-S., &amp; Yu, R. (2019). Fibroblast growth factor 21 deficiency aggravates obesity-induced hypothalamic inflammation and impairs thermogenic response. Inflammation Research, 68(5), 351-358. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00011-019-01222-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Negishi, K., Payant, M. A., Schumacker, K. S., Wittmann, G., Butler, R. M., Lechan, R. M., Steinbusch, H. W. M., Khan, A. M., &amp; Chee, M. J. (2020). Distributions of hypothalamic neuron populations coexpressing tyrosine hydroxylase and the vesicular GABA transporter in the mouse. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 528(11), 1833-1855. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24857</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogawa, Y., Kurosu, H., Yamamoto, M., Nandi, A., Rosenblatt, K. P., Goetz, R., Eliseenkova, A. V., Mohammadi, M., &amp; Kuro-O, M. (2007). BetaKlotho is required for metabolic activity of fibroblast growth factor 21. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 104(18), 7432-7437. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0701600104</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owen, B. M., Bookout, A. L., Ding, X., Lin, V. Y., Atkin, S. D., Gautron, L., Kliewer, S. A., &amp; Mangelsdorf, D. J. (2013). FGF21 contributes to neuroendocrine control of female reproduction. Nature Medicine, 19(9), 1153-1156. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm.3250</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owen, B. M., Ding, X., Morgan, D. A., Coate, K. C., Bookout, A. L., Rahmouni, K., Kliewer, S. A., &amp; Mangelsdorf, D. J. (2014). FGF21 acts centrally to induce sympathetic nerve activity, energy expenditure, and weight loss. Cell Metabolism, 20(4), 670-677. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2014.07.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parfitt, G. M., Nguyen, R., Bang, J. Y., Aqrabawi, A. J., Tran, M. M., Seo, D. K., Richards, B. A., &amp; Kim, J. C. (2017). Bidirectional control of anxiety-related behaviors in mice: Role of inputs arising from the ventral hippocampus to the lateral septum and medial prefrontal cortex. Neuropsychopharmacology, 42(8), 1715-1728. https://doi.org/10.1038/npp.2017.56</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perry, R. J., Lee, S., Ma, L., Zhang, D., Schlessinger, J., &amp; Shulman, G. I. (2015). FGF1 and FGF19 reverse diabetes by suppression of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis. Nature Communication, 6, 6980. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms7980</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitkänen, A., Pikkarainen, M., Nurminen, N., &amp; Ylinen, A. (2000). Reciprocal connections between the amygdala and the hippocampal formation, perirhinal cortex, and postrhinal cortex in rat. A review. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 911, 369-391. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2000.tb06738.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potthoff, M. J., Kliewer, S. A., &amp; Mangelsdorf, D. J. (2012). Endocrine fibroblast growth factors 15/19 and 21: From feast to famine. Genes &amp; Development, 26(4), 312-324. https://doi.org/10.1101/gad.184788.111</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radley, J. J., &amp; Sawchenko, P. E. (2015). Evidence for involvement of a limbic paraventricular hypothalamic inhibitory network in hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis adaptations to repeated stress. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 523(18), 2769-2787. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23815</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rapraeger, A. C., Krufka, A., &amp; Olwin, B. B. (1991). Requirement of heparan sulfate for bFGF-mediated fibroblast growth and myoblast differentiation. Science, 252(5013), 1705-1708. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1646484</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberto M., Kirson D., Khom S. (2021). The role of the central amygdala in alcohol dependence. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 11, (2), a039339. http://doi.org/10.1101/cshperspect.a039339</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan, K. K., Kohli, R., Gutierrez-Aguilar, R., Gaitonde, S. G., Woods, S. C., &amp; Seeley, R. J. (2013). Fibroblast growth factor-19 action in the brain reduces food intake and body weight and improves glucose tolerance in male rats. Endocrinology, 154(1), 9-15. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2012-1891</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan, K. K., Packard, A. E. B., Larson, K. R., Stout, J., Fourman, S. M., Thompson, A. M. K., Ludwick, K., Habegger, K. M., Stemmer, K., Itoh, N., Perez-Tilve, D., Tschöp, M. H., Seeley, R. J., &amp; Ulrich-Lai, Y. M. (2018). Dietary manipulations that induce ketosis activate the HPA axis in male rats and mice: A potential role for fibroblast growth factor-21. Endocrinology, 159(1), 400-413. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2017-00486 https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2017-00486</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sa-Nguanmoo, P., Tanajak, P., Kerdphoo, S., Satjaritanun, P., Wang, X., Liang, G., Li, X., Jiang, C., Pratchayasakul, W., Chattipakorn, N., &amp; Chattipakorn, S. C. (2016). FGF21 improves cognition by restored synaptic plasticity, dendritic spine density, brain mitochondrial function and cell apoptosis in obese-insulin resistant male rats. Hormones and Behavior, 85, 86-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yhbeh.2016.08.006 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yhbeh.2016.08.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santoso, P., Nakata, M., Shiizaki, K., Boyang, Z., Parmila, K., Otgon-Uul, Z., Hashimoto, K., Satoh, T., Mori, M., Kuro-O, M., &amp; Yada, T. (2017). Fibroblast growth factor 21, assisted by elevated glucose, activates paraventricular nucleus NUCB2/Nesfatin-1 neurons to produce satiety under fed states. Science Reports, 7, 45819. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep45819 https://doi.org/10.1038/srep45819</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarruf, D. A., Thaler, J. P., Morton, G. J., German, J., Fischer, J. D., Ogimoto, K., &amp; Schwartz, M. W. (2010). Fibroblast growth factor 21 action in the brain increases energy expenditure and insulin sensitivity in obese rats. Diabetes, 59(7), 1817-1824. https://doi.org/10.2337/db09-1878</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumann, G., Liu, C., O'reilly, P., Gao, H., Song, P., Xu, B., Ruggeri, B., Amin, N., Jia, T., Preis, S., Segura Lepe, M., Akira, S., Barbieri, C., Baumeister, S., Cauchi, S., Clarke, T.-K., Enroth, S., Fischer, K., Hällfors, J., …, &amp; Elliott, P. (2016). KLB is associated with alcohol drinking, and its gene product beta-Klotho is necessary for FGF21 regulation of alcohol preference. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 113(50), 14372-14377. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1611243113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shyu, A. B., Wilkinson, M. F., &amp; van Hoof, A. (2008). Messenger RNA regulation: To translate or to degrade. Embo Journal, 27(3), 471-481. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.emboj.7601977</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Søberg, S., Andersen, E. S., Dalsgaard, N. B., Jarlhelt, I., Hansen, N. L., Hoffmann, N., Vilsbøll, T., Chenchar, A., Jensen, M., Grevengoed, T. J., Trammell, S. A. J., Knop, F. K., &amp; Gillum, M. P. (2018). FGF21, a liver hormone that inhibits alcohol intake in mice, increases in human circulation after acute alcohol ingestion and sustained binge drinking at Oktoberfest. Molecular Metabolism, 11, 96-103. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molmet.2018.03.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, Z., Levin, B. E., McArdle, J. J., Bakhos, N., &amp; Routh, V. H. (2001). Convergence of pre- and postsynaptic influences on glucosensing neurons in the ventromedial hypothalamic nucleus. Diabetes, 50(12), 2673-2681. https://doi.org/10.2337/diabetes.50.12.2673</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonneveld, S., Verhagen, B. M. P., &amp; Tanenbaum, M. E. (2020). Heterogeneity in mRNA translation. Trends in Cell Biology, 30(8), 606-618. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tcb.2020.04.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stuber, G. D., &amp; Wise, R. A. (2016). Lateral hypothalamic circuits for feeding and reward. Nature Neuroscience, 19(2), 198-205. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4220</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki, M., Uehara, Y., Motomura-Matsuzaka, K., Oki, J., Koyama, Y., Kimura, M., Asada, M., Komi-Kuramochi, A., Oka, S., &amp; Toru, T. (2008). betaKlotho is required for fibroblast growth factor (FGF) 21 signaling through FGF receptor (FGFR) 1c and FGFR3c. Molecular Endocrinology, 22(4), 1006-1014. https://doi.org/10.1210/me.2007-0313</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talukdar, S., Owen, B. M., Song, P., Hernandez, G., Zhang, Y., Zhou, Y., Scott, W. T., Paratala, B., Turner, T., Smith, A., Bernardo, B., Müller, C. P., Tang, H., Mangelsdorf, D. J., Goodwin, B., &amp; Kliewer, S. A. (2016). FGF21 regulates sweet and alcohol preference. Cell Metabolism, 23(2), 344-349. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2015.12.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toda, C., Kim, J. D., Impellizzeri, D., Cuzzocrea, S., Liu, Z. W., &amp; Diano, S. (2016). UCP2 regulates mitochondrial fission and ventromedial nucleus control of glucose responsiveness. Cell, 164(5), 872-883. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2016.02.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong, X., Muchnik, M., Chen, Z., Patel, M., Wu, N., Joshi, S., Rui, L., Lazar, M. A., &amp; Yin, L. (2010). Transcriptional repressor E4-binding protein 4 (E4BP4) regulates metabolic hormone fibroblast growth factor 21 (FGF21) during circadian cycles and feeding. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 285(47), 36401-36409. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M110.172866</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Von Holstein-Rathlou, S., Bondurant, L. D., Peltekian, L., Naber, M. C., Yin, T. C., Claflin, K. E., Urizar, A. I., Madsen, A. N., Ratner, C., Holst, B., Karstoft, K., Vandenbeuch, A., Anderson, C. B., Cassell, M. D., Thompson, A. P., Solomon, T. P., Rahmouni, K., Kinnamon, S. C., Pieper, A. A., …, &amp; Potthoff, M. J. (2016). FGF21 mediates endocrine control of simple sugar intake and sweet taste preference by the liver. Cell Metabolism, 23(2), 335-343. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2015.12.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, D., Liu, F., Zhu, L., Lin, P., Han, F., Wang, X., Tan, X., Lin, L., &amp; Xiong, Y. (2020). FGF21 alleviates neuroinflammation following ischemic stroke by modulating the temporal and spatial dynamics of microglia/macrophages. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 17(1), 257. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-020-01921-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, F., Flanagan, J., Su, N., Wang, L.-C., Bui, S., Nielson, A., Wu, X., Vo, H.-T., Ma, X.-J., &amp; Luo, Y. (2012). RNAscope: A novel in situ RNA analysis platform for formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded tissues. Journal of Molecular Diagnostics, 14(1), 22-29. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmoldx.2011.08.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y., Zhang, Y., Shi, Z., Di, T., Yu, W., &amp; Chen, L. (2022). Exposure of male mice to perfluorooctanoic acid induces anxiety-like behaviors by increasing corticotropin-releasing factor in the basolateral amygdala complex. Chemosphere, 287(Pt 3), 132170. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2021.132170</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, C., Jin, C., Li, X., Wang, F., McKeehan, W. L., &amp; Luo, Y. (2012). Differential specificity of endocrine FGF19 and FGF21 to FGFR1 and FGFR4 in complex with KLB. PLoS One, 7(3), e33870. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0033870</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yayon, A., Klagsbrun, M., Esko, J. D., Leder, P., &amp; Ornitz, D. M. (1991). Cell surface, heparin-like molecules are required for binding of basic fibroblast growth factor to its high affinity receptor. Cell, 64(4), 841-848. https://doi.org/10.1016/0092-8674(91)90512-w</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yie, J., Hecht, R., Patel, J., Stevens, J., Wang, W., Hawkins, N., Steavenson, S., Smith, S., Winters, D., Fisher, S., Cai, L., Belouski, E., Chen, C., Michaels, M. L., Li, Y.-S., Lindberg, R., Wang, M., Véniant, M., &amp; Xu, J. (2009). FGF21 N- and C-termini play different roles in receptor interaction and activation. FEBS Letters, 583(1), 19-24. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.febslet.2008.11.023 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.febslet.2008.11.023</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
