<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35142871</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1459</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>269</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Bedside and laboratory diagnostic testing in myasthenia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>3372</StartPage>
          <EndPage>3384</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>3372-3384</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00415-022-10986-3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Myasthenia gravis (MG) and congenital myasthenic syndromes (CMS) are a group of disorders with a well characterised autoimmune or genetic and neurophysiological basis. We reviewed the literature from the last 20 years assessing the utility of various neurophysiological, immunological, provocative and genetic tests in MG and CMS. Diagnostic sensitivity of repetitive nerve stimulation test ranges between 14 and 94% and specificity between 73 and 100%; sensitivity of single-fibre EMG (SFEMG) test ranges between 64 and 100% and specificity between 22 and 100%; anti-acetylcholine receptor (AChR) antibody sensitivity ranges from 13 to 97% and specificity ranges from 95 to 100%. Overall, SFEMG has the highest sensitivity while positive anti-AChR antibodies have the highest specificity. Newer testing strategies that have been investigated over the last couple of decades include ocular vestibular-evoked myogenic potentials, otoacoustic emissions and disease-specific circulating miRNAs in serum for autoimmune myasthenia, as well as next-generation sequencing for genetic testing of CMS. While there has been significant progress in developing newer testing strategies for diagnosing MG and CMS over the last couple of decades, more research is needed to assess the utility of these newer tools regarding their sensitivity and specificity.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Yoganathan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katie</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2490-2941</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Oxford, UK and Oxford University Hospitals, Oxford, UK. katie.yoganathan@nhs.net.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital for Neurology and Neurosurgery, London, UK. katie.yoganathan@nhs.net.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Stevenson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexander</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Intensive Care, Royal Free Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tahir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Awais</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Acute Medicine, Addenbrooke's Hospital, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sadler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ross</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Oxford University Hospitals, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Radunovic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aleksandar</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Royal London Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Queen's Hospital, Romford, Essex, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Malek</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naveed</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Queen's Hospital, Romford, Essex, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0423161</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0340-5354</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011950">Receptors, Cholinergic</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004576" MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009157" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myasthenia Gravis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020294" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myasthenic Syndromes, Congenital</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011950" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Cholinergic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Congenital</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electromyography</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myasthenia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Repetitive nerve stimulation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35142871</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9119875</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-10986-3</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00415-022-10986-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verschuuren J, Strijbos E, Vincent A. Neuromuscular junction disorders. Handb Clin Neurol. 2016;133:447–466.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27112691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finsterer J. Congenital myasthenic syndromes. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2019;14(1):57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6390566</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richman DP. The future of research in myasthenia. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72(7):812–814.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26011044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saluja G, Samdani A, Bhatia P. Importance of clinical tests in ocular myasthenia. BMJ Case Rep. 2019;12(12):e231296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6904191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31818887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubis KC, Danesh-Meyer HV, Savino PJ, Sergott RC. The ice test versus the rest test in myasthenia gravis. Ophthalmology. 2000;107(11):1995–1998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11054320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marinos E, Buzzard K, Fraser CL, Reddel S. Evaluating the temperature effects of ice and heat tests on ptosis due to Myasthenia Gravis. Eye (Lond) 2018;32(8):1387–1391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6085283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29743585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kee HJ, Yang HK, Hwang JM, Park KS. Evaluation and validation of sustained upgaze combined with the ice-pack test for ocular myasthenia gravis in Asians. Neuromuscul Disord. 2019;29(4):296–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30704861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park JY, Yang HK, Hwang JM. Diagnostic value of repeated ice tests in the evaluation of ptosis in myasthenia gravis. PLoS One. 2017;12(5):e0177078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5451013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28562609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyka KV. Ptosis in myasthenia gravis: extended fatigue and recovery bedside test. Neurology. 2006;67(8):1524–1524.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17060601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leite MI, Jacob S, Viegas S, Cossins J, Clover L, Morgan BP, Beeson D, Willcox N, Vincent A. IgG1 antibodies to acetylcholine receptors in 'seronegative' myasthenia gravis. Brain. 2008;131(Pt 7):1940–1952.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2442426</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18515870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devic P, Petiot P, Simonet T, Stojkovic T, Delmont E, Franques J, Magot A, Vial C, Lagrange E, Nicot AS, Risson V, Eymard B, Schaeffer L. Antibodies to clustered acetylcholine receptor: expanding the phenotype. Eur J Neurol. 2014;21(1):130–134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24112557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodríguez Cruz PM, Al-Hajjar M, Huda S, Jacobson L, Woodhall M, Jayawant S, Buckley C, Hilton-Jones D, Beeson D, Vincent A, Leite MI, Palace J. Clinical features and diagnostic usefulness of antibodies to clustered acetylcholine receptors in the diagnosis of seronegative myasthenia gravis. JAMA Neurol. 2015;72(6):642–649.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6044422</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25894002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park KH, Waters P, Woodhall M, Lang B, Smith T, Sung JJ, Kim KK, Lim YM, Kim JE, Kim BJ, Park JS, Lim JG, Kim DS, Kwon O, Sohn EH, Bae JS, Yoon BN, Kim NH, Ahn SW, Oh J, Park HJ, Shin KJ, Hong YH. Myasthenia gravis seronegative for acetylcholine receptor antibodies in South Korea: autoantibody profiles and clinical features. PLoS ONE. 2018;13(3):e0193723.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5843234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29518096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trakas N, Tzartos SJ. Immunostick ELISA for rapid and easy diagnosis of myasthenia gravis. J Immunol Methods. 2018;460:107–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30056940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang SY, Oh JH, Song SK, Lee JS, Choi JC, Kang JH. Both binding and blocking antibodies correlate with disease severity in myasthenia gravis. Neurol Sci. 2015;36(7):1167–1171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25964166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haven TR, Astill ME, Pasi BM, Carper JB, Wu LL, Tebo AE, Hill HR. An algorithm for acetylcholine receptor antibody testing in patients with suspected myasthenia gravis. Clin Chem. 2010;56(6):1028–1029.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20360127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muppidi S, Wolfe GI. Muscle-specific receptor tyrosine kinase antibody-positive and seronegative myasthenia gravis. Front Neurol Neurosci. 2009;26:109–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19349708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pevzner A, Schoser B, Peters K, Cosma NC, Karakatsani A, Schalke B, Melms A, Kröger S. Anti-LRP4 autoantibodies in AChR- and MuSK-antibody-negative myasthenia gravis. J Neurol. 2012;259(3):427–435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21814823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoch W, McConville J, Helms S, Newsom-Davis J, Melms A, Vincent A. Auto-antibodies to the receptor tyrosine kinase MuSK in patients with myasthenia gravis without acetylcholine receptor antibodies. Nat Med. 2001;7(3):365–368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11231638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohta K, Shigemoto K, Kubo S, Maruyama N, Abe Y, Ueda N, Ohta M. MuSK antibodies in AChR Ab-seropositive MG vs AChR Ab-seronegative MG. Neurology. 2004;62(11):2132–2133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evoli A, Tonali PA, Padua L, Monaco ML, Scuderi F, Batocchi AP, Marino M, Bartoccioni E. Clinical correlates with anti-MuSK antibodies in generalized seronegative myasthenia gravis. Brain. 2003;126(10):2304–2311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsonis AI, Zisimopoulou P, Lazaridis K, Tzartos J, Matsigkou E, Zouvelou V, Mantegazza R, Antozzi C, Andreetta F, Evoli A, Deymeer F, Saruhan-Direskeneli G, Durmus H, Brenner T, Vaknin A, Berrih-Aknin S, Behin A, Sharshar T, De Baets M, Losen M, Martinez-Martinez P, Kleopa KA, Zamba-Papanicolaou E, Kyriakides T, Kostera-Pruszczyk A, Szczudlik P, Szyluk B, Lavrnic D, Basta I, Peric S, Tallaksen C, Maniaol A, Casasnovas Pons C, Pitha J, Jakubíkova M, Hanisch F, Tzartos SJ. MuSK autoantibodies in myasthenia gravis detected by cell based assay—a multinational study. J Neuroimmunol. 2015;284:10–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26025053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li M, Han J, Zhang Y, Lv J, Zhang J, Zhao X, Ren L, Fang H, Yang J, Zhang Y, Cui X, Zhang Q, Li Q, Du Y, Gao F. Clinical analysis of Chinese anti-low-density-lipoprotein-receptor-associated protein 4 antibodies in patients with myasthenia gravis. Eur J Neurol. 2019;26(10):1296–e84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31050101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang B, Tzartos JS, Belimezi M, Ragheb S, Bealmear B, Lewis RA, Xiong WC, Lisak RP, Tzartos SJ, Mei L. Autoantibodies to lipoprotein-related protein 4 in patients with double-seronegative myasthenia gravis. Arch Neurol. 2012;69(4):445–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikolic AV, Bojic SD, Rakocevic Stojanovic VM, Basta IZ, Lavrnic DV. Electrophysiological findings in patients with low density lipoprotein receptor related protein 4 positive myasthenia gravis. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23(11):1635–1641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27415961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzartos JS, Zisimopoulou P, Rentzos M, Karandreas N, Zouvelou V, Evangelakou P, Tsonis A, Thomaidis T, Lauria G, Andreetta F, Mantegazza R, Tzartos SJ. LRP4 antibodies in serum and CSF from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis patients. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2014;1(2):80–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4212481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lazaridis K, Tzartos SJ. Autoantibody specificities in myasthenia gravis; implications for improved diagnostics and therapeutics. Front Immunol. 2020;11:212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7033452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32117321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mygland A, Vincent A, Newsom-Davis J, Kaminski H, Zorzato F, Agius M, Gilhus NE, Aarli JA. Autoantibodies in thymoma-associated myasthenia gravis with myositis or neuromyotonia. Arch Neurol. 2000;57(4):527–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang WW, Hao HJ, Gao F. Detection of multiple antibodies in myasthenia gravis and its clinical significance. Chin Med J (Engl) 2010;123(18):2555–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21034627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patil SA, Bokoliya SC, Nagappa M, Taly AB. Diagnosis of myasthenia gravis: comparison of anti-nicotinic acetyl choline receptor antibodies, repetitive nerve stimulation and Neostigmine tests at a tertiary neuro care centre in India, a ten year study. J Neuroimmunol. 2016;292:81–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26943963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abraham A, Alabdali M, Alsulaiman A, Breiner A, Barnett C, Katzberg HD, Lovblom LE, Bril V. Repetitive nerve stimulation cut-off values for the diagnosis of myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2016;55:166–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27287989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abraham A, Alabdali M, Alsulaiman A, Breiner A, Barnett C, Katzberg HD, Lovblom LE, Bril V. Repetitive nerve stimulation cutoff values for the diagnosis of myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55(2):166–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27287989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee TH, Li Y. Consideration of repetitive nerve stimulation of the median nerve in patients being evaluated for myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60(6):658–661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31531870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witoonpanich R, Barakul S, Dejthevaporn C. Relative fatigability of muscles in response to repetitive nerve stimulation in myasthenia gravis. J Med Assoc Thai. 2006;89(12):2047–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17214055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niks EH, Badrising UA, Verschuuren JJ, Van Dijk JG. Decremental response of the nasalis and hypothenar muscles in myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2003;28(2):236–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12872330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bou Ali H, Salort-Campana E, Grapperon AM, Gallard J, Franques J, Sevy A, Delmont E, Verschueren A, Pouget J, Attarian S. New strategy for improving the diagnostic sensitivity of repetitive nerve stimulation in myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2017;55(4):532–538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27511866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misra UK, Kalita J, Srivastava A. A study of diagnostic yield, technical ease and patient discomfort of low rate repetitive nerve stimulation test in patients with myasthenia gravis. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 2006;46(6):337–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17147075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amandusson Å, Elf K, Grindlund ME, Punga AR. Diagnostic utility of repetitive nerve stimulation in a large cohort of patients with myasthenia gravis. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;34(5):400–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28872522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yildirim A, Adatepe T, Gunduz A, Yagiz O, Uzun N. Occipitalis muscle: using for repetitive facial nerve stimulation in myasthenia gravis. Acta Neurol Belg. 2020;120(3):609–613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29428994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abraham A, Alabdali M, Alsulaiman A, Breiner A, Barnett C, Katzberg HD, Bril V. Repetitive facial nerve stimulation in myasthenia gravis 1 min after muscle activation is inferior to testing a second muscle at rest. Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;127(10):3294–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27569990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Temuçin CM, Arsava EM, Nurlu G, Demirci M. Diagnostic value of double-step nerve stimulation test in patients with myasthenia gravis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2010;121(4):556–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20097122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh SJ, Jeong D, Lee I, Alsharabati M. Repetitive nerve stimulation test in myasthenic crisis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59(5):544–548.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30488463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jing F, Cui F, Chen Z, Yang F, Ling L, Huang X. Clinical and electrophysiological markers in myasthenia gravis patients. Eur Neurol. 2015;74(1–2):22–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26138989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stalberg E, Sanders DB, Kouyoumdjian JA. Pitfalls and errors in measuring jitter. Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;128(11):2233–2241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29017138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keesey JC. AAEE Minimonograph #33: electrodiagnostic approach to defects of neuromuscular transmission. Muscle Nerve. 1989;12(8):613–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2550820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srivastava A, Kalita J, Misra UK. A comparative study of single fiber electromyography and repetitive nerve stimulation in consecutive patients with myasthenia gravis. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 2007;47(2):93–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17479725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bromberg MB, Scott DM. Single fiber EMG reference values: reformatted in tabular form. AD HOC Committee of the AAEM Single Fiber Special Interest Group. Muscle Nerve. 1994;17(7):820–1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8008013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercelis R, Merckaert V. Diagnostic utility of stimulated single-fiber electromyography of the orbicularis oculi muscle in patients with suspected ocular myasthenia. Muscle Nerve. 2011;43(2):168–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21254079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morren JA, Levin KH, Shields RW. Diagnostic accuracy of single fiber electromyography for myasthenia gravis in patients followed longitudinally. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2016;33(5):469–474.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27749461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padua L, Caliandro P, Di Iasi G, Pazzaglia C, Ciaraffa F, Evoli A. Reliability of SFEMG in diagnosing myasthenia gravis: sensitivity and specificity calculated on 100 prospective cases. Clin Neurophysiol. 2014;125(6):1270–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24296278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giannoccaro MP, Di Stasi V, Zanesini C, Donadio V, Avoni P, Liguori R. Sensitivity and specificity of single-fibre EMG in the diagnosis of ocular myasthenia varies accordingly to clinical presentation. J Neurol. 2020;267(3):739–745.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31734908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rakocevic G, Moster M, Floeter MK. Single-fiber electromyography in the orbicularis oculi muscle in patients with ocular myasthenia gravis symptoms: does abnormal jitter predict response to treatment? BMC Neurol. 2017;17(1):108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5463377</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28592233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abraham A, Breiner A, Barnett C, Katzberg HD, Bril V. Recording fewer than 20 potential pairs with SFEMG may suffice for the diagnosis of myasthenia gravis. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2017;34(5):408–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28650411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanders DB, Massey JM. Does change in neuromuscular jitter predict or correlate with clinical change in MG? Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(1):45–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27759891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meriggioli MN, Rowin J. Single fiber EMG as an outcome measure in myasthenia gravis: results from a double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Neurophysiol. 2003;20(5):382–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14702000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zinman LH, O'Connor PW, Dadson KE, Leung RC, Ngo M, Bril V. Sensitivity of repetitive facial-nerve stimulation in patients with myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33(5):694–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16421884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Association of Electrodiagnostic Medicine (AAEM) Quality Assurance Committee (2001) Literature review of the usefulness of repetitive nerve stimulation and single fiber EMG in the electrodiagnostic evaluation of patients with suspected myasthenia gravis or Lambert–Eaton myasthenic syndrome. Muscle Nerve 24(9):1239–1247</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Ji F, Luo B. Jitter analysis with concentric needle electrodes in the extensor digitorum communis for the diagnosis of myasthenia gravis: a pilot study. Chin Med J (Engl) 2014;127(18):3209–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25266514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orhan EK, Deymeer F, Oflazer P, Parman Y, Baslo MB. Jitter analysis with concentric needle electrode in the masseter muscle for the diagnosis of generalised myasthenia gravis. Clin Neurophysiol. 2013;124(11):2277–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23849701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kouyoumdjian JA, Fanani AC, Stålberg EV. Concentric needle jitter on stimulated frontalis and extensor digitorum in 20 myasthenia gravis patients. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44(6):912–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22102462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benatar M, Hammad M, Doss-Riney H. Concentric-needle single-fiber electromyography for the diagnosis of myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;34(2):163–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16642500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machado FC, Kouyoumdjian JA, Marchiori PE. Diagnostic accuracy of concentric needle jitter in myasthenia: prospective study. Muscle Nerve. 2016;55:190–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27348087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verma S, Lin J. Stimulated jitter analysis for the evaluation of neuromuscular junction disorders in children. Muscle Nerve. 2016;53(3):471–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26663422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhatia S, Quinlan H, McCracken C, Price EW, Guglani L, Verma S. Serial stimulated jitter analysis in juvenile myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(5):729–732.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30106469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kouyoumdjian JA, Stålberg E. Stimulated jitter with concentric needle in 42 myasthenia gravis patients. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2013;71(4):237–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23588285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikolic A, Basta I, Stojanovic VR, Stevic Z, Lavrnic D. Electrophysiological profile of the patients with MuSK positive myasthenia gravis. Neurol Res. 2014;36(11):945–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24825477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padua L, Tonali P, Aprile I, Caliandro P, Bartoccioni E, Evoli A. Seronegative myasthenia gravis: comparison of neurophysiological picture in MuSK+ and MuSK− patients. Eur J Neurol. 2006;13(3):273–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16618345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemoto Y, Kuwabara S, Misawa S, Kawaguchi N, Hattori T, Takamori M, Vincent A. Patterns and severity of neuromuscular transmission failure in seronegative myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2005;76(5):714–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1739635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15834033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuwabara S, Nemoto Y, Misawa S, Takahashi H, Kawaguchi N, Hattori T. Anti-MuSK-positive myasthenia gravis: neuromuscular transmission failure in facial and limb muscles. Acta Neurol Scand. 2007;115(2):126–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17212617</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farrugia ME, Kennett RP, Newsom-Davis J, Hilton-Jones D, Vincent A. Single-fiber electromyography in limb and facial muscles in muscle-specific kinase antibody and acetylcholine receptor antibody myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2006;33(4):568–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16382443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh SJ, Hatanaka Y, Hemmi S, Young AM, Scheufele ML, Nations SP, Lu L, Claussen GC, Wolfe GI (2006) Repetitive nerve stimulation of facial muscles in MuSK antibody-positive myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve 33(4):500–504</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witoonpanich R, Dejthevaporn C, Sriphrapradang A, Pulkes T. Electrophysiological and immunological study in myasthenia gravis: diagnostic sensitivity and correlation. Clin Neurophysiol. 2011;122(9):1873–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21419697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo YL, Najjar RP, Teo KY, Tow SL, Loo JL, Milea D. A reappraisal of diagnostic tests for myasthenia gravis in a large Asian cohort. J Neurol Sci. 2017;376:153–158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28431604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sirin NG, Kocasoy Orhan E, Durmus H, Deymeer F, Baslo MB. Repetitive nerve stimulation and jitter measurement with disposable concentric needle electrode in newly diagnosed myasthenia gravis patients. Neurophysiol Clin. 2018;48(5):261–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29490884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katzberg HD, Bril V. A comparison of electrodiagnostic tests in ocular myasthenia gravis. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2005;6(3):109–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19078758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abraham A, Breiner A, Barnett C, Katzberg HD, Lovblom LE, Rt MN, Bril V. Electrophysiological testing is correlated with myasthenia gravis severity. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(3):445–448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28029691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aurangzeb S, Tariq M, Irshad M, Badshah M, Khan RS. Relationship between anti-acetylcholine receptor antibody titres and severity of myasthenia gravis, JPMA. J Pak Med Assoc. 2009;59(5):289–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19438131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daroff RB. The office tensilon test for ocular myasthenia gravis. Arch Neurol. 1986;43(8):843–844.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3729767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson GA, McLeod JG, Griffiths LR. Comparison of diagnostic tests in myasthenia gravis. Clin Exp Neurol. 1983;19:45–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6568927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sciacca G, Reggio E, Mostile G, Nicoletti A, Drago F, Salomone S, Zappia M. Clinical and CN-SFEMG evaluation of neostigmine test in myasthenia gravis. Neurol Sci. 2018;39(2):341–345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ing EB, Ing SY, Ing T, Ramocki JA. The complication rate of edrophonium testing for suspected myasthenia gravis. Can J Ophthalmol. 2000;35(3):141–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10812483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Natarajan B, Saifudheen K, Gafoor V, Jose J. Accuracy of the ice test in the diagnosis of myasthenic ptosis. Neurol India. 2016;64(6):1169–1172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27841180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutchinson EC, Matthews WB. The intra-arterial injection of neostigmine as a diagnostic test in myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1953;16(1):47–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC503114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13023440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tether JE. Intravenous neostigmine in diagnosis of myasthenia gravis. Ann Intern Med. 1948;29(6):1132–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18100411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pascuzzi RM. The edrophonium test. Semin Neurol. 2003;23(1):83–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12870109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naji A, Owens M (2022) Edrophonium. [Updated 2021 Jul 17]. In: StatPearls [Internet]. StatPearls Publishing, Treasure Island (FL). https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK554566/. Accessed 1 Aug 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valko Y, Rosengren SM, Jung HH, Straumann D, Landau K, Weber KP. Ocular vestibular evoked myogenic potentials as a test for myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2016;86(7):660–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26791146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi J, Kim NH, Park SH, Cho CG, Lee HJ, Kim SU, Park KS. Abnormalities of otoacoustic emissions in myasthenia gravis: association with serological and electrophysiological features. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6306561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30619074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Punga T, Le Panse R, Andersson M, Truffault F, Berrih-Aknin S, Punga AR. Circulating miRNAs in myasthenia gravis: miR-150-5p as a new potential biomarker. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2014;1(1):49–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4207504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25356381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tidswell T, Pitt MC. A new analytical method to diagnose congenital myasthenia with stimulated single-fiber electromyography. Muscle Nerve. 2007;35(1):107–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16941657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel AG, Shen XM, Selcen D, Sine SM. Congenital myasthenic syndromes: pathogenesis, diagnosis, and treatment. Lancet Neurol. 2015;14(4):420–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4520251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25792100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tay CG, Fong CY, Li L, Ganesan V, Teh CM, Gan CS, Thong MK. Congenital myasthenic syndrome with novel pathogenic variants in the COLQ gene associated with the presence of antibodies to acetylcholine receptors. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;72:468–471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31831253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zafeiriou DI, Pitt M, de Sousa C. Clinical and neurophysiological characteristics of congenital myasthenic syndromes presenting in early infancy. Brain Dev. 2004;26(1):47–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14729415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
