<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35156255</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0029</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>85</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Microscopy research and technique</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Microsc Res Tech</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Modified photoactivated methylene blue-incorporated quartz particles for dentin disinfection: A scanning electron microscope and spectroscopic analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2234</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2240</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2234-2240</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jemt.24080</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The aim of this study was to synthesize methylene blue-incorporated quartz particles (MB@QP) and to investigate its anti-bactericidal properties. Methylene blue was incorporated inside QP and characterized for morphology and chemical structure using scanning electron microscope (SEM) and Fourier transformed infrared spectroscopy (FTIR). Specimens were randomly divided into experimental and control groups (n = 9/groups). The dentin specimen infected with Enterococcus faecalis was treated using different treatment modalities: Control groups: treatment with 5.25% of sodium hypochlorite (NaOCl) for 60 s; MB: treatment with 1 ml MB solution and incubated for 60 s; MB-PDT (photodynamic therapy): treatment with 1 ml MB solution followed by irradiation using diode laser for 60 s; MB-QP-PDT: specimens treated with MB@QP and irradiated by the diode laser for 60s, and Er,Cr:YSGG laser alone. MB@PDT therapy showed the highest efficacy in reducing the survival rate of E. faecalis (0.49%) in comparison to control NaOCl (0.78%) and Er,Cr:YSGG laser treatment (2.17%). Encapsulating MB into QP followed by the PDT significantly improved the bactericidal capacity and significantly reduced the bacterial survival rate to 0.11% (p &lt; .05) compared to other groups. The combination of MB incorporated into QP and PDT could be an alternative treatment modality to conventional disinfection method for eliminating bacteria from the tooth dentin. RESEARCH HIGHLIGHTS: Quartz particles are potent in delivering the photosensitizer. Photoactivated MB@QP has a higher efficacy in eliminating bacteria from tooth dentin.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Al-Saleh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samar</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthetic Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Al Rifaiy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammed Q</ForeName>
            <Initials>MQ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthetic Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Binhasan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mashael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Restorative Dentistry, Division of Operative Dentistry, Collage of Dentistry, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alhamdan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mai M</ForeName>
            <Initials>MM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthetic Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vohra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fahim</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4682-3163</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthetic Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abduljabbar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tariq</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7266-5886</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Prosthetic Dental Sciences, College of Dentistry, King Saud University, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Microsc Res Tech</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9203012</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1059-910X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bactericidal</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dentinal tubule</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">methylene blue</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quartz</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35156255</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jemt.24080</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alhenaki, A. M., Attar, E. A., Alshahrani, A., Farooq, I., Vohra, F., &amp; Abduljabbar, T. (2021). Dentin bond integrity of filled and unfilled resin adhesive enhanced with silica nanoparticles-An SEM, EDX, micro-raman, FTIR and micro-tensile bond strength study. Polymers, 13(7), 1093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AlRefeai, M. H., AlHamdan, E. M., Al-Saleh, S., Alqahtani, A. S., Al-Rifaiy, M. Q., Alshiddi, I. F., Farooq, I., Vohra, F., &amp; Abduljabbar, T. (2021). Application of β-Tricalcium phosphate in adhesive dentin bonding. Polymers, 13(17), 2855.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Saleh, S., Alateeq, A., Alshaya, A. H., Al-Qahtani, A. S., Tulbah, H. I., Binhasan, M., Shabib, S., Farooq, I., Vohra, F., &amp; Abduljabbar, T. (2021). Influence of TiO2 and ZrO2 nanoparticles on adhesive bond strength and viscosity of dentin polymer: A physical and chemical evaluation. Polymers, 13(21), 3794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berutti, E., Marini, R., &amp; Angeretti, A. (1997). Penetration ability of different irrigants into dentinal tubules. Journal of Endodontics, 23(12), 725-727.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bystrom, A., &amp; Sundqvist, G. (1981). Bacteriologic evaluation of the efficacy of mechanical root canal instrumentation in endodontic therapy. European Journal of Oral Sciences, 89(4), 321-328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng, X., Guan, S., Lu, H., Zhao, C., Chen, X., Li, N., Bai, Q., Tian, Y., &amp; Yu, Q. (2012). Evaluation of the bactericidal effect of Nd:YAG, Er:YAG, Er, Cr:YSGG laser radiation, and antimicrobial photodynamic therapy (aPDT) in experimentally infected root canals. Lasers in Surgery and Medicine, 44(10), 824-831.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chivatxaranukul, P., Dashper, S. G., &amp; Messer, H. H. (2008). Dentinal tubule invasion and adherence by enterococcus faecalis. International Endodontic Journal, 41(10), 873-882.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, J., Nandakumar, R., &amp; Fouad, A. F. (2007). Molecular-and culture-based comparison of the effects of antimicrobial agents on bacterial survival in infected dentinal tubules. Journal of Endodontics, 33(6), 690-692.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fonseca, M. B., Júnior, P. O. T., Pallota, R. C., Filho, H. F., Denardin, O. V. P., Rapoport, A., Dedivitis, R. A., Veronezi, J. F., Genovese, W. J., &amp; Ricardo, A. L. F. (2008). Photodynamic therapy for root canals infected with enterococcus faecalis. Photomedicine and Laser Surgery, 26(3), 209-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomes, B. P., Pinheiro, E. T., Sousa, E. L., Jacinto, R. C., Zaia, A. A., Ferraz, C. C. R., &amp; de Souza-Filho, F. J. (2006). Enterococcus faecalis in dental root canals detected by culture and by polymerase chain reaction analysis. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology, Oral Radiology, and Endodontology, 102(2), 247-253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta, R., Rastogi, P. K., Srivastava, U., Ganesan, V., Sonkar, P. K., &amp; Yadav, D. K. (2016). Methylene blue incorporated mesoporous silica microsphere based sensing scaffold for the selective voltammetric determination of riboflavin. RSC Advances, 6(70), 65779-65788.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haapasalo, M., Udnaes, T., &amp; Endal, U. (2003). Persistent, recurrent, and acquired infection of the root canal system post-treatment. Endodontic Topics, 6(1), 29-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong, S., &amp; Choi, Y. (2018). Mesoporous silica-based nanoplatforms for the delivery of photodynamic therapy agents. Journal of Pharmaceutical Investigation, 48(1), 3-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karim, A. H., Jalil, A. A., Triwahyono, S., Sidik, S. M., Kamarudin, N. H. N., Jusoh, R., Jusoh, N. W. C., &amp; Hameed, B. H. (2012). Amino modified mesostructured silica nanoparticles for efficient adsorption of methylene blue. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science, 386(1), 307-314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura, Y., Wilder-Smith, P., &amp; Matsumoto, K. (2000). Lasers in endodontics: A review. International Endodontic Journal, 33(3), 173-185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konopka, K., &amp; Goslinski, T. (2007). Photodynamic therapy in dentistry. Journal of Dental Research, 86(8), 694-707.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuthati, Y., Kankala, R. K., Busa, P., Lin, S. X., Deng, J. P., Mou, C. Y., &amp; Lee, C. H. (2017). Phototherapeutic spectrum expansion through synergistic effect of mesoporous silica trio-nanohybrids against antibiotic-resistant gram-negative bacterium. Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology B: Biology, 169, 124-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Love, R. M., &amp; Jenkinson, H. F. (2002). Invasion of dentinal tubules by oral bacteria. Critical Reviews in Oral Biology &amp; Medicine, 13(2), 171-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lucky, S. S., Soo, K. C., &amp; Zhang, Y. (2015). Nanoparticles in photodynamic therapy. Chemical Reviews, 115(4), 1990-2042.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehrvarzfar, P., Saghiri, M. A., Asatourian, A., Fekrazad, R., Karamifar, K., Eslami, G., &amp; Dadresanfar, B. (2011). Additive effect of a diode laser on the antibacterial activity of 2.5% NaOCl, 2% CHX and MTAD against enterococcus faecalis contaminating root canals: An in vitro study. Journal of Oral Science, 53(3), 355-360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neelakantan, P., Cheng, C. Q., Mohanraj, R., Sriraman, P., Subbarao, C., &amp; Sharma, S. (2015). Antibiofilm activity of three irrigation protocols activated by ultrasonic, diode laser or Er: YAG laser in vitro. International Endodontic Journal, 48(6), 602-610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ovchinnikov, O. V., Chernykh, S. V., Smirnov, M. S., Alpatova, D. V., Vorob'Eva, R. P., Latyshev, A. N., Evlev, A. B., Utekhin, A. N., &amp; Lukin, A. N. (2007). Analysis of interaction between the organic dye methylene blue and the surface of AgCl (I) microcrystals. Journal of Applied Spectroscopy, 74(6), 809-816.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peciuliene, V., Balciuniene, I., Eriksen, H. M., &amp; Haapasalo, M. (2000). Isolation of enterococcus faecalis in previously root-filled canals in a Lithuanian population. Journal of Endodontics, 26(10), 593-595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peciuliene, V., Reynaud, A. H., Balciuniene, I., &amp; Haapasalo, M. (2001). Isolation of yeasts and enteric bacteria in root-filled teeth with chronic apical periodontitis. International Endodontic Journal, 34(6), 429-434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pradhan, A. C., Paul, A., &amp; Rao, G. R. (2017). Sol-gel-cum-hydrothermal synthesis of mesoporous co-Fe@Al2O3−MCM-41 for methylene blue remediation. Journal of Chemical Sciences, 129(3), 381-395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prażmo, E. J., Godlewska, R. A., &amp; Mielczarek, A. B. (2017). Effectiveness of repeated photodynamic therapy in the elimination of intracanal enterococcus faecalis biofilm: An in vitro study. Lasers in Medical Science, 32(3), 655-661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rios, A., He, J., Glickman, G. N., Spears, R., Schneiderman, E. D., &amp; Honeyman, A. L. (2011). Evaluation of photodynamic therapy using a light-emitting diode lamp against enterococcus faecalis in extracted human teeth. Journal of Endodontics, 37(6), 856-859.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen, Z., Zhou, H., Chen, H., Xu, H., Feng, C., &amp; Zhou, X. (2018). Synthesis of nano-zinc oxide loaded on mesoporous silica by coordination effect and its photocatalytic degradation property of methyl orange. Nanomaterials, 8(5), 317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrestha, A., Zhilong, S., Gee, N. K., &amp; Kishen, A. (2010). Nanoparticulates for antibiofilm treatment and effect of aging on its antibacterial activity. Journal of Endodontics, 36(6), 1030-1035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva, E. J., Coutinho-Filho, W. P., Andrade, A. O., Herrera, D. R., Coutinho-Filho, T. S., &amp; Krebs, R. L. (2014). Evaluation of photodynamic therapy using a diode laser and different photosensitizers against enterococcus faecalis. Acta Odontológica Latinoamericana, 27(2), 63-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stojicic, S., Amorim, H., Shen, Y., &amp; Haapasalo, M. (2013). Ex vivo killing of E nterococcus faecalis and mixed plaque bacteria in planktonic and biofilm culture by modified photoactivated disinfection. International Endodontic Journal, 46(7), 649-659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vohra, F., Akram, Z., Bukhari, I. A., Sheikh, S. A., &amp; Javed, F. (2018). Short-term effects of adjunctive antimicrobial photodynamic therapy in obese patients with chronic periodontitis: A randomized controlled clinical trial. Photodiagnosis and Photodynamic Therapy, 21, 10-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, M. K., Dummer, P. M. H., &amp; Wesselink, P. R. (2006). Consequences of and strategies to deal with residual post-treatment root canal infection. International Endodontic Journal, 39(5), 343-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
