<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35152448</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>48</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The S1PR2-CCL2-BDNF-TrkB pathway mediates neuroinflammation and motor incoordination in hyperammonaemia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e12799</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e12799</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12799</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Chronic hyperammonaemia and inflammation synergistically induce neurological impairment, including motor incoordination, in hepatic encephalopathy. Hyperammonaemic rats show neuroinflammation in the cerebellum which enhances GABAergic neurotransmission leading to motor incoordination. We aimed to identify underlying mechanisms. The aims were (1) to assess if S1PR2 is involved in microglial and astrocytic activation in the cerebellum of hyperammonaemic rats; (2) to identify pathways by which enhanced S1PR2 activation induces neuroinflammation and alters neurotransmission; (3) to assess if blocking S1PR2 reduces neuroinflammation and restores motor coordination in hyperammonaemic rats.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We performed ex vivo studies in cerebellar slices from control or hyperammonaemic rats to identify pathways by which neuroinflammation enhances GABAergic neurotransmission in hyperammonaemia. Neuroinflammation and neurotransmission were assessed by immunochemistry/immunofluorescence and western blot. S1PR2 was blocked by intracerebral treatment with JTE-013 using osmotic mini-pumps. Motor coordination was assessed by beam walking.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Chronic hyperammonaemia enhances S1PR2 activation in the cerebellum by increasing its membrane expression. This increases CCL2, especially in Purkinje neurons. CCL2 activates CCR2 in microglia, leading to microglial activation, increased P2X4 membrane expression and BDNF in microglia. BDNF enhances TrkB activation in neurons, increasing KCC2 membrane expression. This enhances GABAergic neurotransmission, leading to motor incoordination in hyperammonaemic rats. Blocking S1PR2 in hyperammonaemic rats by intracerebral administration of JTE-013 normalises the S1PR2-CCL2-CCR2-BDNF-TrkB-KCC2 pathway, reduces glial activation and restores motor coordination in hyperammonaemic rats.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Enhanced S1PR2-CCL2-BDNF-TrkB pathway activation mediates neuroinflammation and incoordination in hyperammonaemia. The data raise a promising therapy for patients with hepatic encephalopathy using compounds targeting this pathway.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arenas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yaiza M</ForeName>
            <Initials>YM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, Centro Investigación Príncipe Felipe, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Balzano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tiziano</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, Centro Investigación Príncipe Felipe, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ivaylova</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gergana</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, Centro Investigación Príncipe Felipe, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Llansola</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marta</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5565-5907</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, Centro Investigación Príncipe Felipe, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Felipo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vicente</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3145-9538</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Neurobiology, Centro Investigación Príncipe Felipe, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D019208">Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C111835">CCL2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C491766">Ccl2 protein, rat</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018932">Chemokine CCL2</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C477522">S1PR2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000081025">Sphingosine-1-Phosphate Receptors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D027981">Symporters</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001259" MajorTopicYN="N">Ataxia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019208" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain-Derived Neurotrophic Factor</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018932" MajorTopicYN="N">Chemokine CCL2</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006501" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hepatic Encephalopathy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D022124" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hyperammonemia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000090862" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroinflammatory Diseases</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017208" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Wistar</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000081025" MajorTopicYN="N">Sphingosine-1-Phosphate Receptors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D027981" MajorTopicYN="Y">Symporters</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CCL2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purkinje neurons</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">S1PR2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperammonaemia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroinflammation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35152448</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12799</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V. Hepatic encephalopathy: effects of liver failure on brain function. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14(12):851-858. doi:10.1038/nrn3587</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shawcross DL, Davies NA, Williams R, Jalan R. Systemic inflammatory response exacerbates the neuropsychological effects of induced hyperammonemia in cirrhosis. J Hepatol. 2004;40(2):247-254. doi:10.1016/j.jhep.2003.10.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V, Urios A, Montesinos E, et al. Contribution of hyperammonemia and inflammatory factors to cognitive impairment in minimal hepatic encephalopathy. Metab Brain Dis. 2012;27(1):51-58. doi:10.1007/s11011-011-9269-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mangas-Losada A, García-García R, Urios A, et al. Minimal hepatic encephalopathy is associated with expansion and activation of CD4+CD28-, Th22 and Tfh and B lymphocytes. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):6683 doi:10.1038/s41598-017-05938-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V, Urios A, Giménez-Garzó C, et al. Non invasive blood flow measurement in cerebellum detects minimal hepatic encephalopathy earlier than psychometric tests. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20(33):11815-11825. doi:10.3748/wjg.v20.i33.11815</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butz M, Timmermann L, Braun M, et al. Motor impairment in liver cirrhosis without and with minimal hepatic encephalopathy. Acta Neurol Scand. 2010;122(1):27-35. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0404.2009.01246.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V, Ordoño JF, Urios A, et al. Patients with minimal hepatic encephalopathy show impaired mismatch negativity correlating with reduced performance in attention tests. Hepatology. 2012;55(2):530-539. doi:10.1002/hep.24704</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giménez-Garzó C, Garcés JJ, Urios A, et al. The PHES battery does not detect all cirrhotic patients with early neurological deficits, which are different in different patients. PLoS One. 2017;12(2):e0171211 doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0171211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigo R, Cauli O, Gomez-Pinedo U, et al. Hyperammonemia induces neuroinflammation that contributes to cognitive impairment in rats with hepatic encephalopathy. Gastroenterology. 2010;139(2):675-684. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2010.03.040</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabrera-Pastor A, Llansola M, Montoliu C, et al. Peripheral inflammation induces neuroinflammation that alters neurotransmission and cognitive and motor function in hepatic encephalopathy: underlying mechanisms and therapeutic implications. Acta Physiol (Oxf). 2019;226(2):e13270. doi:10.1111/apha.13270</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balzano T, Dadsetan S, Forteza J, et al. Chronic hyperammonemia induces peripheral inflammation that leads to cognitive impairment in rats: reversed by anti-TNF-α treatment. J Hepatol. 2020;73(3):582-592. doi:10.1016/j.jhep.2019.01.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cauli O, Mansouri MT, Agusti A, Felipo V. Hyperammonemia increases GABAergic tone in the cerebellum but decreases it in the rat cortex. Gastroenterology. 2009;136(4):1359-e2. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2008.12.057</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Usano A, Cauli O, Agusti A, Felipo V. Pregnenolone sulfate restores the glutamate-nitric-oxide-cGMP pathway and extracellular GABA in cerebellum and learning and motor coordination in hyperammonemic rats. ACS Chem Nerosci. 2014;5(2):100-105. doi:10.1021/cn400168y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez-Rabaza V, Cabrera-Pastor A, Taoro-Gonzalez L, et al. Neuroinflammation increases GABAergic tone and impairs cognitive and motor function in hyperammonemia by increasing GAT-3 membrane expression. Reversal by sulforaphane by promoting M2 polarization of microglia. J Neuroinflammation. 2016;13(83):83. doi:10.1186/s12974-016-0549-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabrera-Pastor A, Balzano T, Hernández-Rabaza V, Malaguarnera M, Llansola M, Felipo V. Increasing extracellular cGMP in cerebellum in vivo reduces neuroinflammation, GABAergic tone and motor in-coordination in hyperammonemic rats. Brain Behav Immun. 2018;69:386-398. doi:10.1016/j.bbi.2017.12.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee JY, Jin HK, Bae JS. Sphingolipids in neuroinflammation: a potential target for diagnosis and therapy. BMB Rep. 2020;53(1):28-34. doi:10.5483/BMBRep.2020.53.1.278</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ji J, Wang J, Yang J, et al. The Intra-nuclear SphK2-S1P Axis Facilitates M1-to-M2 Shift of Microglia via Suppressing HDAC1-Mediated KLF4 Deacetylation. Front Immunol. 2019;10:1241. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2019.01241</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aytan N, Choi JK, Carreras I, et al. Fingolimod modulates multiple neuroinflammatory markers in a mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Sci Rep. 2016;6(1):24939. doi:10.1038/srep24939</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hunter SF, Bowen JD, Reder AT. The direct effects of fingolimod in the central nervous system: implications for relapsing multiple sclerosis. CNS Drugs. 2016;30(2):135-147. doi:10.1007/s40263-015-0297-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doolen S, Iannitti T, Donahue RR, Shaw BC, Grachen CM, Taylor BK. Fingolimod reduces neuropathic pain behaviors in a mouse model of multiple sclerosis by a sphingosine-1 phosphate receptor 1-dependent inhibition of central sensitization in the dorsal horn. Pain. 2018;159(2):224-238. doi:10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001106</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohan S, Lucassen E, Smoot K, Brink J, Chen C. Sphingosine-1-phosphate: its pharmacological regulation and the treatment of multiple sclerosis: a review article. Biomedicine. 2020;8:227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lucaciu A, Brunkhorst R, Pfeilschifter JM, Pfeilschifter W, Subburayalu J. The S1P-S1PR Axis in Neurological Disorders-Insights into Current and Future Therapeutic Perspectives. Cell. 2020;9(6):1515. doi:10.3390/cells9061515</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sapkota A, Gaire BP, Kang MG, Choi JW. S1P2 contributes to microglial activation and M1 polarization following cerebral ischemia through ERK1/2 and JNK. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):12106. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-48609-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMillin M, Frampton G, Grant S, et al. Bile Acid-Mediated Sphingosine-1-Phosphate Receptor 2 Signaling Promotes Neuroinflammation during Hepatic Encephalopathy in Mice. Front Cell Neurosci. 2017;11:191. doi:10.3389/fncel.2017.00191</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMillin M, Frampton G, Thompson M, et al. Neuronal CCL2 is upregulated during hepatic encephalopathy and contributes to microglia activation and neurological decline. J Neuroinflammation. 2014;11(1):121. doi:10.1186/1742-2094-11-121</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oskeritzian CA, Hait NC, Wedman P, et al. The sphingosine-1-phosphate/sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor 2 axis regulates early airway T-cell infiltration in murine mast cell-dependent acute allergic responses. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2015;135(4):1008-1018.e1. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2014.10.044</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Tan J, Jiang X, et al. Neuron-derived CCL2 contributes to microglia activation and neurological decline in hepatic encephalopathy. Biol Res. 2017;50(1):26. doi:10.1186/s40659-017-0130-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyomitsu E, Tsuda M, Yamashita T, Tozaki-Saitoh H, Tanaka Y, Inoue K. CCL2 promotes P2X4 receptor trafficking to the cell surface of microglia. Purinergic Signal. 2012;8(2):301-310. doi:10.1007/s11302-011-9288-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C, Zhang Y, Liu Q, et al. P2X4-receptor participates in EAAT3 regulation via BDNF-TrkB signaling in a model of trigeminal allodynia. Mol Pain. 2018:14. doi:10.1177/1744806918795930</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long T, He W, Pan Q, et al. Microglia P2X4R-BDNF signalling contributes to central sensitization in a recurrent nitroglycerin-induced chronic migraine model. J Headache Pain. 2020;21(1):4. doi:10.1186/s10194-019-1070-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrini F, De Koninck Y. Microglia control neuronal network excitability via BDNF signalling. Neural Plast 2013;2013:429815. doi:10.1155/2013/429815</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee-Hotta S, Uchiyama Y, Kametaka S. Role of the BDNF-TrkB pathway in KCC2 regulation and rehabilitation following neuronal injury: a mini review. Neurochem Int. 2019;128:32-38. doi:10.1016/j.neuint.2019.04.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V, Miñana MD, Grisolía S. Long-term ingestion of ammonium increases acetylglutamate and urea levels without affecting the amount of carbamoyl-phosphate synthase. Eur J Biochem. 1988;176(3):567-571. doi:10.1111/j.1432-1033.1988.tb14315.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taoro-Gonzalez L, Arenas YM, Cabrera-Pastor A, Felipo V. Hyperammonemia alters membrane expression of GluA1 and GluA2 subunits of AMPA receptors in hippocampus by enhancing activation of the IL-1 receptor: underlying mechanisms. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15(1):36. doi:10.1186/s12974-018-1082-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto S, Yako Y, Fujioka Y, et al. A role of the sphingosine-1-phosphate (S1P)-S1P receptor 2 pathway in epithelial defense against cancer (EDAC). Mol Biol Cell. 2016;27(3):491-499. doi:10.1091/mbc.e15-03-0161</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwiatkowski K, Piotrowska A, Rojewska E, Makuch W, Mika J. The RS504393 Influences the Level of Nociceptive Factors and Enhances Opioid Analgesic Potency in Neuropathic Rats. J Neuroimmune Pharmacol. 2017;12(3):402-419. doi:10.1007/s11481-017-9729-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cazorla M, Prémont J, Mann A, Girard N, Kellendonk C, Rognan D. Identification of a low-molecular weight TrkB antagonist with anxiolytic and antidepressant activity in mice. J Clin Invest. 2011;121(5):1846-1857. doi:10.1172/JCI43992</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montalbano A, Baj G, Papadia D, Tongiorgi E, Sciancalepore M. Blockade of BDNF signaling turns chemically-induced long-term potentiation into long-term depression. Hippocampus. 2013;23(10):879-889. doi:10.1002/hipo.22144</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King MD, Alleyne CH Jr, Dhandapani KM. TNF-alpha receptor antagonist, R-7050, improves neurological outcomes following intracerebral hemorrhage in mice. Neurosci Lett. 2013;542:92-96. doi:10.1016/j.neulet.2013.02.051</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V, Grau E, Miñana MD, Grisolía S. Ammonium injection induces an N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor-mediated proteolysis of the microtubule-associated protein MAP-2. J Neurochem. 1993;60(5):1626-1630. doi:10.1111/j.1471-4159.1993.tb13384.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabrera-Pastor A, Taoro L, Llansola M, Felipo V. Roles of the NMDA receptor and EAAC1 transporter in the modulation of extracellular glutamate by low and high affinity AMPA receptors in the cerebellum in vivo: differential alteration in chronic hyperammonemia. ACS Chem Nerosci. 2015;6(12):1913-1921. doi:10.1021/acschemneuro.5b00212</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rashad S, Niizuma K, Saigusa D, et al. Intracellular S1P Levels Dictate Fate of Different Regions of the Hippocampus following Transient Global Cerebral Ischemia. Neuroscience. 2018;384:188-202. doi:10.1016/j.neuroscience.2018.05.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimura A, Ohmori T, Kashiwakura Y, et al. Antagonism of sphingosine 1-phosphate receptor-2 enhances migration of neural progenitor cells toward an area of brain. Stroke. 2008;39(12):3411-3417. doi:10.1161/STROKEAHA.108.514612</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erceg S, Monfort P, Hernandez-Viadel M, Llansola M, Montoliu C, Felipo V. Restoration of learning ability in hyperammonemic rats by increasing extracellular cGMP in brain. Brain Res. 2005;1036(1-2):115-121. doi:10.1016/j.brainres.2004.12.045</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jover R, Rodrigo R, Felipo V, et al. Brain edema and inflammatory activation in bile duct ligated rats with diet-induced hyperammonemia: a model of hepatic encephalopathy in cirrhosis. Hepatology. 2006;43(6):1257-1266. doi:10.1002/hep.21180</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lucas EK, Reid CS, McMeekin LJ, Dougherty SE, Floyd CL, Cowell RM. Cerebellar transcriptional alterations with Purkinje cell dysfunction and loss in mice lacking PGC-1α. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;8:441. doi:10.3389/fncel.2014.00441</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zörner B, Filli L, Starkey ML, et al. Profiling locomotor recovery: comprehensive quantification of impairments after CNS damage in rodents. Nat Methods. 2010;7(9):701-708. doi:10.1038/nmeth.1484</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joly-Amado A, Hunter J, Quadri Z, et al. CCL2 Overexpression in the Brain Promotes Glial Activation and Accelerates Tau Pathology in a Mouse Model of Tauopathy. Front Immunol. 2020;11:997. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2020.00997</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang Y, Ko H, Cheung ZH, et al. Dual actions of brain-derived neurotrophic factor on GABAergic transmission in cerebellar Purkinje neurons. Exp Neurol. 2012;233(2):791-798. doi:10.1016/j.expneurol.2011.11.043</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buckley E, Mazzà C, McNeill A. A systematic review of the gait characteristics associated with Cerebellar Ataxia. Gait Posture. 2018;60:154-163. doi:10.1016/j.gaitpost.2017.11.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris ME, Iansek R, Matyas TA, Summers JJ. Stride length regulation in Parkinson's disease. Normalization Strategies and Underlying Mechanisms Brain. 1996;119(Pt 2):551-568. doi:10.1093/brain/119.2.551</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>San Martín-Valenzuela C, Borras-Barrachina A, Gallego JJ, et al. Motor and cognitive performance in patients with liver cirrhosis with minimal hepatic encephalopathy. J Clin Med. 2020;9(7):2154. doi:10.3390/jcm9072154</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaur C, Sivakumar V, Zou Z, Ling EA. Microglia-derived proinflammatory cytokines tumor necrosis factor-alpha and interleukin-1beta induce Purkinje neuronal apoptosis via their receptors in hypoxic neonatal rat brain. Brain Struct Funct. 2014;219(1):151-170. doi:10.1007/s00429-012-0491-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W, An J, Jawadi H, et al. Sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor-2 mediated NFκB activation contributes to tumor necrosis factor-α induced VCAM-1 and ICAM-1 expression in endothelial cells. Prostaglandins Other Lipid Mediat. 2013;106:62-71. doi:10.1016/j.prostaglandins.2013.06.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adada M, Canals D, Hannun YA, Obeid LM. Sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor 2. FEBS j. 2013;280(24):6354-6366. doi:10.1111/febs.12446</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kempf A, Tews B, Arzt ME, et al. The sphingolipid receptor S1PR2 is a receptor for Nogo-a repressing synaptic plasticity. PLoS Biol. 2014;12(1):e1001763. doi:10.1371/journal.pbio.1001763</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Dong H, Qian Q, et al. Astrocyte-derived CCL2 participates in surgery-induced cognitive dysfunction and neuroinflammation via evoking microglia activation. Behav Brain Res. 2017;332:145-153. doi:10.1016/j.bbr.2017.05.066</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang K, Wang H, Xu M, Frank JA, Luo J. Role of MCP-1 and CCR2 in ethanol-induced neuroinflammation and neurodegeneration in the developing brain. J Neuroinflammation. 2018;15(1):197. doi:10.1186/s12974-018-1241-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trang T, Beggs S, Wan X, Salter MW. P2X4-receptor-mediated synthesis and release of brain-derived neurotrophic factor in microglia is dependent on calcium and p38-mitogen-activated protein kinase activation. J Neurosci. 2009;29(11):3518-3528. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5714-08.2009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hurtado E, Cilleros V, Nadal L, et al. Muscle Contraction Regulates BDNF/TrkB Signaling to Modulate Synaptic Function through Presynaptic cPKCα and cPKCβI. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:147. doi:10.3389/fnmol.2017.00147</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomes JR, Costa JT, Melo CV, et al. Excitotoxicity downregulates TrkB.FL signaling and upregulates the neuroprotective truncated TrkB receptors in cultured hippocampal and striatal neurons. J Neurosci. 2012;32(13):4610-4622. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0374-12.2012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tejeda GS, Ayuso-Dolado S, Arbeteta R, Esteban-Ortega GM, Vidaurre OG, Díaz-Guerra M. Brain ischaemia induces shedding of a BDNF-scavenger ectodomain from TrkB receptors by excitotoxicity activation of metalloproteinases and γ-secretases. J Pathol. 2016;238(5):627-640. doi:10.1002/path.4684</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tejeda GS, Esteban-Ortega GM, San Antonio E, Vidaurre ÓG, Díaz-Guerra M. Prevention of excitotoxicity-induced processing of BDNF receptor TrkB-FL leads to stroke neuroprotection. EMBO Mol Med. 2019;11(7):e9950. doi:10.15252/emmm.201809950</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabrera-Pastor A, Taoro-Gonzalez L, Felipo V. Hyperammonemia alters glycinergic neurotransmission and modulation of the glutamate-nitric oxide-cGMP pathway by extracellular glycine in cerebellum in vivo. J Neurochem. 2016a;137(4):539-548. doi:10.1111/jnc.13579</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drake-Baumann R. Rapid modulation of inhibitory synaptic currents in cerebellar Purkinje cells by BDNF. Synapse. 2005;57(4):183-190. doi:10.1002/syn.20170</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng Q, Yeh HH. PLCgamma signaling underlies BDNF potentiation of Purkinje cell responses to GABA. J Neurosci Res. 2005;79(5):616-627. doi:10.1002/jnr.20397</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanaka C, Ohno K, Okabe A, et al. The differential expression patterns of messenger RNAs encoding K-Cl cotransporters (KCC1,2) and Na-K-2Cl cotransporter (NKCC1) in the rat nervous system. Neuroscience. 2001;104(4):933-946.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikawa S, Wang C, Shu F, Wang T, Fukuda A, Sato K. Developmental changes in KCC1, KCC2 and NKCC1 mRNAs in the rat cerebellum. Brain Res Dev Brain Res. 2002;136(2):93-100. doi:10.1016/S0165-3806(02)00345-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chamma I, Chevy Q, Poncer JC, Lévi S. Role of the neuronal K-Cl co-transporter KCC2 in inhibitory and excitatory neurotransmission. Front Cell Neurosci. 2012;6:5. doi:10.3389/fncel.2012.00005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tillman L, Zhang J. Crossing the chloride channel: the current and potential therapeutic value of the neuronal K+-Cl-cotransporter KCC2. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:12. doi:10.1155/2019/8941046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivera C, Voipio J, Kaila K. Two developmental switches in GABAergic signalling: the K+-Cl- cotransporter KCC2 and carbonic anhydrase CAVII. J Physiol. 2005;562(1):27-36. doi:10.1113/jphysiol.2004.077495</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granados-Rojas L, Jerónimo-Cruz K, Juárez-Zepeda TE, et al. Ketogenic Diet Provided During Three Months Increases KCC2 Expression but Not NKCC1 in the Rat Dentate Gyrus. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:673. doi:10.3389/fnins.2020.00673</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rangroo Thrane V, Thrane AS, Wang F, et al. Ammonia triggers neuronal disinhibition and seizures by impairing astrocyte potassium buffering. Nat Med. 2013;19(12):1643-1648. doi:10.1038/nm.3400</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayakumar AR, Liu M, Moriyama M, et al. Na-K-Cl Cotransporter-1 in the mechanism of ammonia-induced astrocyte swelling. J Biol Chem. 2008;283(49):33874-33882. doi:10.1074/jbc.M804016200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felipo V, Miñana MD, Azorín I, Grisolía S. Induction of rat brain tubulin following ammonium ingestion. J Neurochem. 1988;51(4):1041-1045. doi:10.1111/j.1471-4159.1988.tb03065.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Héja L, Barabás P, Nyitrai G, et al. Glutamate uptake triggers transporter-mediated GABA release from astrocytes. PLoS One. 2009;4(9):e7153. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0007153</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Z, Guo Z, Gearing M, Chen G. Tonic inhibition in dentate gyrus impairs long-term potentiation and memory in an Alzheimer's [corrected] disease model. Nat Commun. 2014;5(1):4159. doi:10.1038/ncomms5159</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khakh BS, Beaumont V, Cachope R, Munoz-Sanjuan I, Goldman SA, Grantyn R. Unravelling and Exploiting Astrocyte Dysfunction in Huntington's Disease. Trends Neurosci. 2017;40(7):422-437. doi:10.1016/j.tins.2017.05.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yue X, Jin H, Liu H, Rosenberg AJ, Klein RS, Tu Z. A potent and selective C-11 labeled PET tracer for imaging sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor 2 in the CNS demonstrates sexually dimorphic expression. Org Biomol Chem. 2015;13(29):7928-7939. doi:10.1039/C5OB00951K</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz-Orengo L, Daniels BP, Dorsey D, et al. Enhanced sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor 2 expression underlies female CNS autoimmunity susceptibility. J Clin Invest. 2014;124(6):2571-2584. doi:10.1172/JCI73408</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sfikakis A, Spyraki C, Sitaras N, Varonos D. Implication of the estrous cycle on conditioned avoidance behavior in the rat. Physiol Behav. 1978;21(3):441-446. doi:10.1016/0031-9384(78)90105-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz-Veliz G, Soto V, Dussaubat N, Mora S. Influence of the estrous cycle, ovariectomy and estradiol replacement upon the acquisition of conditioned avoidance responses in rats. Physiol Behav. 1989;46(3):397-401. doi:10.1016/0031-9384(89)90010-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gouveia A Jr, dos Santos UD, Felisbino FE, de Afonseca TL, Antunes G, Morato S. Influence of the estrous cycle on the behavior of rats in the elevated T-maze. Behav Processes. 2004;67(2):167-171. doi:10.1016/j.beproc.2004.03.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Llansola M, Montoliu C, Agusti A, et al. Interplay between glutamatergic and GABAergic neurotransmission alterations in cognitive and motor impairment in minimal hepatic encephalopathy. Neurochem Int. 2015;88:15-19. doi:10.1016/j.neuint.2014.10.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson M, Agusti A, Llansola M, et al. GR3027 antagonizes GABAA receptor-potentiating neurosteroids and restores spatial learning and motor coordination in rats with chronic hyperammonemia and hepatic encephalopathy. Am J Physiol Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 2015;309(5):G400-G409. doi:10.1152/ajpgi.00073.2015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blankenbach KV, Schwalm S, Pfeilschifter J, Heringdorf MZ, D. Sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor-2 antagonists: therapeutic potential and potential risks. Front Pharmacol. 2016;7(167). doi:10.3389/fphar.2016.00167</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seyedsadr MS, Weinmann O, Amorim A, et al. Inactivation of sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor 2 (S1PR2) decreases demyelination and enhances remyelination in animal models of multiple sclerosis. Neurobiol Dis. 2019;124:189-201. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2018.11.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim GS, Yang L, Zhang G, et al. Critical role of sphingosine-1-phosphate receptor-2 in the disruption of cerebrovascular integrity in experimental stroke. Nat Commun. 2015;6(1):7893. doi:10.1038/ncomms8893</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto N, Yamashita T, Shang J, et al. Up-regulation of sphingosine-1-phosphate receptors and sphingosine kinase 1 in the peri-ischemic area after transient middle cerebral artery occlusion in mice. Brain Res. 2020;1739:146831. doi:10.1016/j.brainres.2020.146831</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
