<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35150161</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2648</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>78</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of advanced nursing</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Nurs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Perceptions and help-seeking behaviours among community-dwelling older people with urinary incontinence: A systematic integrative review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1574</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1587</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1574-1587</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jan.15183</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To synthesize research evidence on perceptions and help-seeking behaviours in community-dwelling older people with urinary incontinence based on the Capability-Opportunity-Motivation-Behaviours model.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Urinary incontinence is highly prevalent in community-dwelling older people, yet only a small proportion seek help from health professionals. Untreated urinary incontinence has a detrimental impact on older people's quality of life and distresses their caregivers.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Systematic integrative review.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ten databases were searched systematically between 9 November 2020 and 17 December 2020 including Medline (PubMed), CINAHL, Ageline, Web of Science, Scopus, ProQuest, Psyclnfo, CNKI, Wanfang and Vip.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="REVIEW METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Quality appraisal was applied to assess the quality of selected articles. Data relevant to the review aim were extracted from included articles for analysis. Convergent qualitative synthesis was used to synthesize findings.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twenty articles were included and two main themes with six sub-themes were identified. Theme one described three common perceptions including urinary incontinence as a part of normal ageing, a stigma and a health problem. Each perception had a profound impact on older people's motivation to self-report the problem to health professionals. Theme two revealed three main help-seeking approaches comprising self-help, help from friends and help from health professionals. Of these, self-help was the dominant approach used to conceal urinary incontinence and contributed to social isolation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Improving urinary incontinence management in community-dwelling older people requires the development of their capability and motivation, and increased opportunities to access and gain help from skilled health professionals.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPACT" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Findings can facilitate resource development to improve health literacy for the general public pertinent to urinary incontinence and associated stigma. Moreover, findings can inform a user-friendly reporting and referral system for the problem. In addition, findings can inform education and skill training for health professionals, older people and their caregivers to effectively manage the problem.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fang</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Xiangya School of Nursing, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xiao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lily D</ForeName>
            <Initials>LD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4631-2443</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Nursing and Health Science, Adelaide, South Australia, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Keyi</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Xiangya School of Nursing, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zeen</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Xiangya School of Nursing, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Siyuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9940-5072</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Xiangya School of Nursing, Central South University, Changsha, Hunan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Adv Nurs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7609811</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0309-2402</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000066505" MajorTopicYN="Y">Help-Seeking Behavior</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057187" MajorTopicYN="N">Independent Living</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014549" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Incontinence</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour change</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caregivers</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">community-dwelling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health professionals</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">help-seeking behaviours</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">integrative review</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nurses</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">older people</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perceptions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urinary incontinence</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150161</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jan.15183</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai, X., Leung, D., Chi, I., Lai, C., &amp; Chong, A. (2016). Urinary incontinence, decline in social participation and negative in older adults. Gerontologist, 56(Suppl_3), 606-607. https://doi.org/10.1093/geront/gnw162.2449</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batmani, S., Jalali, R., Mohammadi, M., &amp; Bokaee, S. (2021). Prevalence and factors related to urinary incontinence in older adults women worldwide: A comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. BMC Geriatrics, 21(1), 17. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-021-02135-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blasco, P., Valdivia, M. I., Ona, M. R., Roset, M., Mora, A. M., &amp; Hernandez, M. (2016). Clinical characteristics, beliefs, and coping strategies among older patients with overactive bladder. Neurourology &amp; Urodynamics, 36(3), 774-779. https://doi.org/10.1002/nau.23022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bliss, D., Rolnick, C., Jackson, J., Arntson, C., Mullins, J., &amp; Hepburn, K. (2013). Health literacy needs related to incontinence and skin damage among family and friend caregivers of individuals with dementia. Journal of Wound Ostomy and Continence Nursing, 40(5), 515-523. https://doi.org/10.1097/WON.0b013e3182a3ff24</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bo, K., Frawley, H. C., Haylen, B. T., Abramov, Y., Almeida, F. G., Berghmans, B., Bortolini, M., Gomes, M., McClurg, D., Meijlink, J., Shelly, E., Trabuco, E., Walker, C., &amp; Wells, A. (2017). An international Urogynecological association (IUGA)/international continence society (ICS) joint report on the terminology for the conservative and nonpharmacological management of female pelvic floor dysfunction. International Urogynecology Journal, 28(2), 191-213. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-016-3123-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buckley, B. S., &amp; Lapitan, M. C. (2010). Prevalence of urinary incontinence in men, women, and children--current evidence: Findings of the Fourth International Consultation on Incontinence. Urology, 76(2), 265-270. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.urology.2009.11.078</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgio, K. L., Ives, D. G., Locher, J. L., Arena, V. C., &amp; Kuller, L. H. (1994). Treatment seeking for urinary incontinence in older adults. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 42(2), 208-212. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.1994.tb04954.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Büttner, P., &amp; Muller, R. (2015). Epidemiology (2nd ed.). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, L., Xiao, L. D., &amp; Chamberlain, D. (2020). An integrative review: Challenges and opportunities for stroke survivors and caregivers in hospital to home transition care. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 76(9), 2253-2265. https://doi.org/10.1111/jan.14446</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cini, B., Christina, A., Kalpa, K., Yehudit, B., Helen, C., Ann, L., … Kate, W. (2019). 'I've never drunk very much water and I still don't, and I see no reason to do so': A qualitative study of the views of community-dwelling older people and carers on hydration in later life. Age &amp; Ageing, 49(1), 111-118. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afz141</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colborne, M., &amp; Dahlke, S. (2017). Nurses' perceptions and Management of Urinary Incontinence in hospitalized older adults an integrative review. Journal of Gerontological Nursing, 43(10), 46-55. https://doi.org/10.3928/00989134-20170515-02</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Critical Appraisal Skills Programme. (2018). CASP qualitative checklist. https://casp-uk.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/CASP-Qualitative-Checklist-2018.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis, N. J., Parker, V. G., Lanham, J., Love, C. R., Christy, M. R., Poetzschke, E., &amp; Wyman, J. F. (2021). Burdens and educational needs of informal caregivers of older adults with urinary incontinence: An internet-based study. Rehabilitation Nursing, 46(3), 172-178. https://doi.org/10.1097/rnj.0000000000000317</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis, N. J., Wyman, J. F., Gubitosa, S., &amp; Pretty, L. (2020). Urinary incontinence in older adults. American Journal of Nursing, 120(1), 57-62. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.naj.0000652124.58511.24</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drennan, V. M., Cole, L., &amp; Iliffe, S. (2011). A taboo within a stigma? A qualitative study of managing incontinence with people with dementia living at home. BMC Geriatrics, 11, 75. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2318-11-75</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dugan, E., Roberts, C. P., Cohen, S. J., Preisser, J. S., Davis, C. C., Bland, D. R., &amp; Albertson, E. (2001). Why older community-dwelling adults do not discuss urinary incontinence with their primary care physicians. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 49(4), 462-465. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1532-5415.2001.49094.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenhandler, S. A. (1992). Social value of ‘physiological autonomy’: Urinary incontinence and continence in a sample of older women. Journal of Women and Aging, 4(3), 45-58. https://doi.org/10.1300/J074v04n03_04</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elenskaia, K., Haidvogel, K., Heidinger, C., Doerfler, D., Umek, W., &amp; Hanzal, E. (2011). The greatest taboo: Urinary incontinence as a source of shame and embarrassment. Wiener Klinische Wochenschrift, 123(19-20), 607-610. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00508-011-0013-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engberg, S. J., McDowell, B. J., Burgio, K. L., Watson, J. E., &amp; Belle, S. (1995). Self-care behaviors of older women with urinary incontinence. Journal of Gerontological Nursing, 21(8), 7-14. https://doi.org/10.3928/0098-9134-19950801-06</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Felde, G., Ebbesen, M. H., &amp; Hunskaar, S. (2017). Anxiety and depression associated with urinary incontinence. A 10-year follow-up study from the Norwegian HUNT study (EPINCONT). Neurourology &amp; Urodynamics, 36(2), 322-328. https://doi.org/10.1002/nau.22921</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flemming, K., Booth, A., Hannes, K., Cargo, M., &amp; Noyes, J. (2018). Cochrane qualitative and implementation methods group guidance series-paper 6: Reporting guidelines for qualitative, implementation, and process evaluation evidence syntheses. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 97, 79-85. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.10.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerst, K., Ray, L. A., Samper-Ternent, R., Espino, D. V., &amp; Markides, K. S. (2011). Self-reported urge urinary incontinence (UUI) among older Mexican American men: Risk factors and psycho-social consequences. Journal of Immigrant and Minority Health, 13(6), 1110-1115. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10903-010-9383-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herzog, A. R., Fultz, N. H., Normolle, D. P., Brock, B. M., &amp; Diokno, A. C. (1989). Methods used to manage urinary incontinence by older adults in the community. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society, 37(4), 339-347. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-5415.1989.tb05502.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horrocks, S., Somerset, M., Stoddart, H., &amp; Peters, T. J. (2004). What prevents older people from seeking treatment for urinary incontinence? A qualitative exploration of barriers to the use of community continence services. Family Practice, 21(6), 689-696. https://doi.org/10.1093/fampra/cmh622</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jatau, A. I., Peterson, G. M., Bereznicki, L., Dwan, C., Black, J. A., Bezabhe, W. M., &amp; Wimmer, B. C. (2019). Applying the capability, opportunity, and motivation behaviour model (COM-B) to guide the development of interventions to improve early detection of atrial fibrillation. Clinical Medicine Insights-Cardiology, 13, 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1177/1179546819885134</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>John, G., Bardini, C., Combescure, C., &amp; Dllenbach, P. (2016). Urinary incontinence as a predictor of death: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE, 11(7), e0158992. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0158992</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kataria, K., &amp; Ilsley, A. (2021). Urinary incontinence in older adults: What you need to know. British Journal of Hospital Medicine, 82(4), 1-8. https://doi.org/10.12968/hmed.2020.0518</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koch, L. H. (2006). Help seeking behaviors of women with urinary incontinence: An integrative literature review. Journal of Midwifery and Women's Health, 51(6), e39-e44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmwh.2006.06.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwak, Y., Kwon, H., &amp; Kim, Y. (2016). Health-related quality of life and mental health in older women with urinary incontinence. Aging and Mental Health, 20(7), 719-726. https://doi.org/10.1080/13607863.2015.1033682</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lane, G. I., Hagan, K., Erekson, E., Minassian, V. A., Grodstein, F., &amp; Bynum, J. (2021). Patient-provider discussions about urinary incontinence among older women. Journals of Gerontology Series a-Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences, 76(3), 463-469. https://doi.org/10.1093/gerona/glaa107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, B. A., Kim, S. J., Choi, D. K., Kwon, O., Na, H. R., &amp; Cho, S. T. (2017). Effects of pelvic floor muscle exercise on urinary incontinence in elderly women with cognitive impairment. International Neurourology Journal, 21(4), 295-301. https://doi.org/10.5213/inj.1734956.478</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, H. Y., Rhee, Y., &amp; Choi, K. S. (2021). Urinary incontinence and the association with depression, stress, and self-esteem in older Korean women. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 9054. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-88740-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, H. C., Chen, K. M., &amp; Hsu, H. F. (2019). Modelling factors of urinary incontinence in institutional older adults with dementia. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 28(23-24), 4504-4512. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.15039</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Y., Cai, X., Glance, L. G., &amp; Mukamel, D. B. (2007). Gender differences in healthcare-seeking behavior for urinary incontinence and the impact of socioeconomic status: A study of the Medicare managed care population. Medical Care, 45(11), 1116-1122. https://doi.org/10.1097/MLR.0b013e31812da820</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Livingston, J. D., &amp; Boyd, J. E. (2010). Correlates and consequences of internalized stigma for people living with mental illness: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Social Science &amp; Medicine, 71(12), 2150-2161. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2010.09.030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo, X., Chuang, C. C., Yang, E., Zou, K. H., Araiza, A. L., &amp; Bhagnani, T. (2015). Prevalence, management and outcomes of medically complex vulnerable elderly patients with urinary incontinence in the United States. International Journal of Clinical Practice, 69(12), 1517-1524. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijcp.12740</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKenzie, S., St John, W., Wallis, M., &amp; Griffiths, S. (2013). Men's management of urinary incontinence in daily living: Implications for practice. International Journal of Urological Nursing, 7(1), 43-52. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-771X.2012.01167.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michie, S., van Stralen, M. M., &amp; West, R. (2011). The behaviour change wheel: A new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implementation Science, 6, 42. https://doi.org/10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milne, A. (2010). The 'D' word: Reflections on the relationship between stigma, discrimination and dementia. Journal of Mental Health, 19(3), 227-233. https://doi.org/10.3109/09638231003728166</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milne, J. (2000). The impact of information on health behaviors of older adults with urinary incontinence. Clinical Nursing Research, 9(2), 161-176. https://doi.org/10.1177/105477380000900205</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitteness, L. S. (1987). The management of urinary incontinence by community-living elderly. The Gerontologist, 27(2), 185-193. https://doi.org/10.1093/geront/27.2.185</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher, D., Liberati, A., Tetzlaff, J., &amp; Altman, D. G. (2010). Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. International Journal of Surgery, 8(5), 336-341. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsu.2010.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy, C., Laine, C., &amp; Fader, M. (2020). Living at home with dementia and incontinence: A qualitative analysis of patient, family carer and health care professionals' perspectives. Alzheimer's &amp; Dementia, 16(58), e040896. https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.040896</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nazarko, L. (2015). Use of continence pads to manage urinary incontinence in older people. British Journal of Community Nursing, 20(8), 382-384. https://doi.org/10.12968/bjcn.2015.20.8.378</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orme, S., Morris, V., Gibson, W., &amp; Wagg, A. (2015). Managing urinary incontinence in patients with dementia: Pharmacological treatment options and considerations. Drugs &amp; Aging, 32(7), 559-567. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40266-015-0281-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostaszkiewicz, J. (2017). Reframing continence care in care-dependence. Geriatric Nursing, 38(6), 520-526. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gerinurse.2017.03.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostaszkiewicz, J., Dickson-Swift, V., Hutchinson, A., &amp; Wagg, A. (2020). A concept analysis of dignity-protective continence care for care dependent older people in long-term care settings. BMC Geriatrics, 20, 266. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12877-020-01673-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostaszkiewicz, J., O'Connell, B., &amp; Dunning, T. (2012). Residents' perspectives on urinary incontinence: A review of literature. Scandinavian Journal of Caring Sciences, 26(4), 761-772. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1471-6712.2011.00959.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostaszkiewicz, J., Tomlinson, E., &amp; Hunter, K. (2020). The effects of education about urinary incontinence on Nurses' and nursing Assistants' knowledge, attitudes, continence care practices, and patient outcomes A systematic review. Journal of Wound Ostomy and Continence Nursing, 47(4), 365-380. https://doi.org/10.1097/won.0000000000000651</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, S., Yeoum, S., Kim, Y., &amp; Kwon, H. J. (2017). Self-management experiences of older Korean women with urinary incontinence: A descriptive qualitative study using focus groups. Journal of Wound, Ostomy, and Continence Nursing, 44(6), 572-577. https://doi.org/10.1097/WON.0000000000000383</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Payne, D. (2018). Managing urinary incontinence in patients living with dementia. British Journal of Community Nursing, 23(1), 24-28. https://doi.org/10.12968/bjcn.2018.23.1.24</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters, T. J., Horrocks, S., Stoddart, H., &amp; Somerset, M. (2004). Factors associated with variations in older people's use of community-based continence services. Health and Social Care in the Community, 12(1), 53-62. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2524.2004.00468.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pluye, P., &amp; Hong, Q. N. (2014). Combining the power of stories and the power of numbers: Mixed methods research and mixed studies reviews. Annual Review of Public Health, 35(1), 29-45. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032013-182440</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Róin, Á., &amp; Nord, C. (2015). Urine incontinence in women aged sixty to sixty-five: Negotiating meaning and responsibility. Scandinavian Journal of Caring Sciences, 29(4), 625-632. https://doi.org/10.1111/scs.12190</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rickwood, D., Deane, F. P., Wilson, C. J., &amp; Ciarrochi, J. (2005). Young people's help seeking for mental health problems. Australian e-Journal for the Advancement of Mental Health, 4(3), 218-251. https://doi.org/10.5172/jamh.4.3.218</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santini, S., Andersson, G., &amp; Lamura, G. (2016). Impact of incontinence on the quality of life of caregivers of older persons with incontinence: A qualitative study in four European countries. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics, 63, 92-101. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.archger.2015.10.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlogl, M., &amp; Gordon, A. (2021). HEARTS, minds and souls-it is time for geriatricians to bring more to continence management. Age &amp; Ageing, 1-4, 1508-1511. https://doi.org/10.1093/ageing/afab088</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scholtz, N., Blank, M., Kruppa, J., Mueller-Werdan, U., &amp; Endres, A. S. (2018). Association of Urinary Tract Infections and Urinary Incontinence in old age. Zeitschrift Fur Gerontologie Und Geriatrie, 51, 138-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro, M., Setterlund, D., &amp; Cragg, C. (2003). Capturing the complexity of women's experiences: A mixed-method approach to studying incontinence in older women. Affilia, 18(1), 21-33. https://doi.org/10.1177/0886109902239094</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Southall, K., Tuazon, J. R., Djokhdem, A. H., van den Heuvel, E. A., Wittich, W., &amp; Jutai, J. W. (2017). Assessing the stigma content of urinary incontinence intervention outcome measures. Journal of Rehabilitation and Assistive Technologies Engineering, 4, 2055668317738943. https://doi.org/10.1177/2055668317738943</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>St John, W., Griffiths, S., Wallis, M., &amp; McKenzie, S. (2013). Women's Management of Urinary Incontinence in daily living. Journal of Wound Ostomy and Continence Nursing, 40(5), 524-532. https://doi.org/10.1097/WON.0b013e3182a2198a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stoddart, H., Donovan, J., Whitley, E., Sharp, D., &amp; Harvey, I. (2001). Urinary incontinence in older people in the community: A neglected problem? British Journal of General Practice, 51(468), 548-552. https://doi.org/10.3109/07853890109002092</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tannenbaum, C., van den Heuvel, E., Fritel, X., Southall, K., Jutai, J., Rajabali, S., &amp; Wagg, A. (2015). Continence across continents to upend stigma and dependency (CACTUS-D): Study protocol for a cluster randomized controlled trial. Trials, 16, 565. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13063-015-1099-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teunissen, D., &amp; Lagro-Janssen, T. (2004). Urinary incontinence in community dwelling elderly: Are there sex differences in help seeking behaviour? Scandinavian Journal of Primary Health Care, 22(4), 209-216. https://doi.org/10.1080/02813430410006666</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teunissen, D., van Weel, C., &amp; Lagro-Janssen, T. (2005). Urinary incontinence in older people living in the community: Examining help seeking behaviour. British Journal of General Practice, 55(519), 776-782.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teunissen, T. A. M., Bosch, W. J. H. M., van de Hoogen, H. J. M. V. D., &amp; Lagro-Janssen, A. L. M. (2004). Prevalence of urinary, fecal and double incontinence in the elderly living at home. International Urogynecology Journal, 15(1), 10-13. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-003-1047-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong, A., Flemming, K., McInnes, E., Oliver, S., &amp; Craig, J. (2012). Enhancing transparency in reporting the synthesis of qualitative research: ENTREQ. BMC Medical Research Methodology, 12(1), 181. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2288-12-181</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toye, F., &amp; Barker, K. L. (2020). A meta-ethnography to understand the experience of living with urinary incontinence: 'is it just part and parcel of life?'. BMC Urology, 20(1), 25. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12894-019-0555-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tseng, I. J., Chen, Y. T., Chen, M. T., Kou, H. Y., &amp; Tseng, S. F. (2000). Prevalence of urinary incontinence and intention to seek treatment in the elderly. Journal of the Formosan Medical Association, 99(10), 753-758. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0885-3924(00)00184-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Vuuren, A. J., van Rensburg, J. A., Jacobs, L., &amp; Hanekom, S. (2021). Exploring literature on knowledge, attitudes, beliefs and practices towards urinary incontinence management: A scoping review. International Urogynecology Journal, 32(3), 485-499. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00192-020-04628-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vethanayagam, N., Orrell, A., Dahlberg, L., McKee, K. J., Orme, S., Parker, S. G., &amp; Gilhooly, M. (2016). Understanding help seeking in older people with urinary incontinence: An interview study. Health and Social Care in the Community, 25(3), 1061-1069. https://doi.org/10.1111/hsc.12406</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wan, X., Wang, C., Xu, D., Guan, X., Sun, T., &amp; Wang, K. (2014). Disease stigma and its mediating effect on the relationship between symptom severity and quality of life among community-dwelling women with stress urinary incontinence: A study from a Chinese city. Journal of Clinical Nursing, 23(15-16), 2170-2180. https://doi.org/10.1111/jocn.12482</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, C. L., Wan, X. J., Wang, K. F., Li, J. J., Sun, T., &amp; Guan, X. M. (2014). Disease stigma and intentions to seek care for stress urinary incontinence among community-dwelling women. Maturitas, 77(4), 351-355. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.maturitas.2014.01.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y. (2020). A survey on the status of UI related stigma among older women in community and its correlation with their intention to seek medical treatment. Chinese General Practice Nursing, 18(13), 15-17. CNKI:SUN:JTHS.0.2020-13-006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whittal, A., Stork, S., Riegel, B., &amp; Herber, O. R. (2021). Applying the COM-B behaviour model to overcome barriers to heart failure self-care: A practical application of a conceptual framework for the development of complex interventions (ACHIEVE study). European Journal of Cardiovascular Nursing, 20(3), 261-267. https://doi.org/10.1177/1474515120957292</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. (2017). WHO Guidelines on Integrated Care for Older People (ICOPE). https://www.who.int/ageing/publications/guidelines-icope/en/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, C., Liu, Y., &amp; Wang, K. (2012). Analysis on confirmatory factors of revised social impact scale applied for female patients with urinary incontinent. Chinese Nursing Research, 26, 2680-2682.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yip, S. O., Dick, M. A., McPencow, A. M., Martin, D. K., Ciarleglio, M. M., &amp; Erekson, E. A. (2013). The association between urinary and fecal incontinence and social isolation in older women. American Journal of Obstetrics and Gynecology, 208(2), 7-146.e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajog.2012.11.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zachariou, A., Filiponi, M., Kaltsas, A., Dimitriadis, F., Champilomatis, I., Paliouras, A., Tsounapi, P., Mamoulakis, C., Takenaka, A., &amp; Sofikitis, N. (2021). Mirabegron alleviates the degree of burden experienced by caregivers of older females with mixed or urge incontinence: A prospective study. Clinical Interventions in Aging, 16, 291-299. https://doi.org/10.2147/cia.s283737</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
