<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35150389</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1559-0283</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>80</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cell biochemistry and biophysics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cell Biochem Biophys</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The Antitumor Activity of hAMSCs Secretome in HT-29 Colon Cancer Cells Through Downregulation of EGFR/c-Src/IRTKS Expression and p38/ERK1/2 Phosphorylation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>395</StartPage>
          <EndPage>402</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>395-402</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12013-022-01066-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Colon cancer is considered as one of the main causes of mortality worldwide. Identifying a novel and more effective platform with fewer side effects is still progress. In various cancer types, Epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) and c-Src (a key mediator in EGFR signaling pathway) are the key targets for cancer therapy. Moreover, insulin receptor tyrosine kinase substrate (IRTKS or BAI1-associated protein 2-like 1: BAIAP2L1) is a member of the subfamily of inverse BAR (I-BAR) domain proteins, which mediates cell morphology and movement through regulation of actin polymerization. In this study, we employed a co-culture system using Transwell six-well plates. After 72 h, hAMSCs-treated HT-29 cells, EGFR, c-Src, IRTKS, p38, and ERK1/2 expression were analyzed using quantitative real time PCR (qRT-PCR) and western blot methods. The significant reduction in tumor cell growth and motility through downregulation of EGFR/c-Src/IRTKS expression and p38/ERK1/2 phosphorylation in HT-29 cells was demonstrated based on 2D and 3D cell culture models. The induction of cellular apoptosis was also found. Our results support the idea that the hAMSCS secretome has therapeutic effects on cancer cells. However, further experiments will be required to identify the exact molecular mechanisms.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ebadi Zavieh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shamin</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biology, Faculty of Science, University of Guilan, Rasht, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Safari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0300-7665</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biology, Faculty of Science, University of Guilan, Rasht, Iran. fsafari@guilan.ac.ir.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cell Biochem Biophys</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9701934</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1085-9195</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C512478">EGFR protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D066246">ErbB Receptors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Colonic Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015536" MajorTopicYN="N">Down-Regulation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D066246" MajorTopicYN="N">ErbB Receptors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019073" MajorTopicYN="N">HT29 Cells</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020935" MajorTopicYN="Y">MAP Kinase Signaling System</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010766" MajorTopicYN="N">Phosphorylation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000089282" MajorTopicYN="N">Secretome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGFR/c-Src/IRTKS expression</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HT-29 colon cancer cells</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hAMSCs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">p38/ERK1/2 phosphorylation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150389</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12013-022-01066-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12013-022-01066-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Safari, F., &amp; Suetsugu, S. (2012). The bar domain superfamily proteins from subcellular structures to human diseases. Membrane, 2, 91–1170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/membranes2010091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, G., Li, T., Zhang, L., Yi, M., Chen, F., Wang, Z., &amp; Zhang, X. (2011). Src-stimulated IRTKS phosphorylation enhances cell migration. FEBS Letters, 585, 2972–2978.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.febslet.2011.08.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh, T. C., Ogawa, W., Danielsen, A. G., &amp; Roth, R. A. (1996). Characterization and cloning of a 58/53-kDa substrate of the insulin receptor tyro-sine kinase. Journal of Biology and Chemistry, 271, 2921–2928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.271.6.2921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scita, G., Confalonieri, S., Lappalainen, P., &amp; Suetsugu, S. (2008). IRSp53: crossing the road of membrane and actin dynamics in the formation of membrane protrusions. Trends in Cell Biology, 18, 52–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcb.2007.12.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu, R. M., Han, Z. G., Song, H. D., Peng, Y. D., Huang, Q. H., Ren, S. X., Gu, Y. J., Huang, C. H., Li, Y. B., Jiang, C. L., Fu, G., Zhang, Q. H., Gu, B. W., Dai, M., Mao, Y. F., Gao, G. F., Rong, R., Ye, M., Zhou, J., Xu, S. H., Gu, J., Shi, J. X., Jin, W. R., Zhang, C. K., Wu, T. M., Huang, G. Y., Chen, Z., Chen, M. D. &amp; &amp; Chen, J. L. (2000). Gene expression profiling in the human hypothalamus-pituitary-adrenal axis and full-length cDNA cloning. Proceedings of the National Academy of Science of the United States of America, 97, 9543–9548.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.160270997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y. P., Huang, L. Y., Sun, W. M., Zhang, Z. Z., Fang, J. Z., Wei, B. F., Wu, B. H. &amp; Han, Z. G. (2013). Insulin receptor tyrosine kinase substrate activates EGFR/ERK signalling pathway and promotes cell proliferation of hepatocellular carcinoma. Cancer Letters, 337, 96–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2013.05.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, K. S., Chen, G., Shen, H. L., Li, T. T., Chen, F., Wang, Q. W., Wang, Z. Q., Han, Z. G., &amp; Zhang, X. (2011). Insulin receptor tyrosine kinase substrate enhances low levels of MDM2-mediated p53 ubiquitination. PLoS One, 6, e23571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0023571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, S., Liu, Z., Ma, Y. M., Guan, X., Jiang, Z., Sun, P., Liu, E. R., Zhang, Y. K., Wang, H. Y., &amp; Wang, X. S. (2020). Upregulated insulin receptor tyrosine kinase substrate promotes the proliferation of colorectal cancer cells via the bFGF/AKT signaling pathway. Gastroenterology Reports, 9(2), 166–175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gastro/goaa032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas, S. M. &amp; Brugge, J. S. (1997). Cellular functions regulated by Src family kinases. Annual Review of Cell and Developmental Biology, 13, 513–609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.cellbio.13.1.513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maa, M. C., Leu, T. H., McCarley, D. J., Schatzman, R. C. &amp; Parson, S. J. (1995). Potentiation of epidermal growth factor receptor-mediated oncogenesis by c-Src: implications for the etiology of multiple human cancers. Proceedings of the National Academy of Science of the United States of America, 92, 6981–6985.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.92.15.6981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bray, F., Ferlay, J., Soerjomataram, I., Siegal, R. L., Torre, L. A., &amp; Jemal, A. (2018). Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA: a Cancer Journal for Clinicians, 68, 394–424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tjandra, J. J., &amp; Chan, M. K. (2007). Follow-up after curative resection of colorectal cancer: a meta-analysis. Diseases of the Colon &amp; Rectum, 50, 1783–1799.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10350-007-9030-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, C. L., Huang, T., Wu, B. L., He, W. X., &amp; Liu, D. (2017). Stem cells in cancer therapy: opportunities and challenges. Oncotarget, 8(43), 75756–75766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.20798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarukhan, A., Zanotti, L., &amp; Viola, A. (2015). Mesenchymal stem cells: myths and reality. Swiss Medical Weekly, 145, w14229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francois, S., Usunier, B., Forgue-Lafitte, M. E., Homme, B., Benderitter, M., Douay, L., Gorin, N. C., Larsen, A. K., &amp; Chapel, A. (2019). Mesenchymal stem cell administration attenuates colon cancer progression by modulating the immune component within the colorectal tumor microenvironment. Stem Cells Translational Medicines, 8(3), 285–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sctm.18-0117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahmani, Z., &amp; Safari, F. (2020). Evaluating the in vitro therapeutic effects of human amniotic mesenchymal stromal cells on MiaPaca2 pancreatic cancer cells using 2D and 3D cell culture model. Tissue Cell, 23(68), 101479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Safari, F., Shakery, T. &amp; Sayadamin, N. (2021). Evaluating the effect of secretome of human amniotic mesenchymal stromal cells on apoptosis induction and epithelial-mesenchymal transition inhibition in LNCaP prostate cancer cells based on 2D and 3D cell culture models. Cell Biochemistry &amp; Function, 39(6), 813–820.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbf.3654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz, O., &amp; Sakaraya, S. (2018). Is “Hanging Drop” a useful method to form spheroids of Jimt, Mcf-7, T-47d, Bt-474 that are breast cancer cell lines? Single Cell Biology 7, 1000170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lia, L., Liuc, H., Baxterb, S. S., Gu, N., Ji, M., &amp; Zhang, X. (2016). The SH3 domain distinguishes the role of I-BAR proteins IRTKS and MIM in chemotactic response to serum. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 479(4), 787–792.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2016.09.131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roskoski, Jr., R. (2014). The ErbB/HER family of protein-tyrosine kinases and cancer. Pharmaceutical Research, 79, 34–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2013.11.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talamonti, M. S., Roh, M. S., Curley, S. A., &amp; Gallick, G. E. (1993). Increase in activity and level of pp60c-src in progressive stages of human colorectal cancer. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 91, 53–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI116200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Termuhlen, P. M., Curley, S. A., Talamonti, M. S., Saboorian, M. H., &amp; Gallick, G. E. (1993). Site-specific differences in pp60c-src activity in human colorectal metastases. Journal of Surgical Research, 54, 293–298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jsre.1993.1046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, B., Zhang, H., Zeng, M., He, W., Li, M., Huang, X., Deng, D. Y., &amp; Wu, J. (2015). Bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells protect alveolar macrophages from lipopolysaccharide-induced apoptosis partially by inhibiting the Wnt/β-catenin pathway. Cell Biology International, 39, 192–200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cbin.10359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang, Y. L., Zhao, Q., Qin, X., Shen, L., Cheng, L., Ge, J. &amp; Phillips, M. I. (2005). Paracrine action enhances the effects of autologous mesenchymal stem cell transplantation on vascular regeneration in rat model of myocardial infarction. The Annals of Thoracic Surgery, 80, 229–236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.athoracsur.2005.02.072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, S., Ju, G. Q., Du, T., Zhu, Y. J., &amp; Liu, G. H. (2013). Microvesicles derived from human umbilical cord Wharton’s jelly mesenchymal stem cells attenuate bladder tumor cell growth in vitro and in vivo. PLoS One, 8, e61366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0061366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermudez, M. A., Sendon-Lago, J., Seoane, S., Eiro, N., Gonzalez, F., Saa, J., Vizoso, F. &amp; Perez-Fernandez, R. (2016). Anti-inflammatory effect of conditioned medium from human uterine cervical stem cells in uveitis. Experimental Eye Research, 149, 84–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exer.2016.06.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zagoura, D. S., Roubelakis, M. G., Bitsika, V., Trohatou, O., Pappa, K. I., Kapelouzou, A., Antsaklis, A., &amp; Anagnou, N. P. (2012). Therapeutic potential of a distinct population of human amniotic fluid mesenchymal stem cells and their secreted molecules in mice with acute hepatic failure. Gut, 61, 894–906.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gutjnl-2011-300908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cantinieaux, D., Quertainmont, R., Blacher, S., Rossi, L., Wanet, T., Noel, A., Brook, G., Schoenen, J., &amp; Franzen, R. (2013). Conditioned medium from bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells improves recovery after spinal cord injury in rats: An original strategy to avoid cell transplantation. PLoS One, 8, e69515.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0069515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, M. J., Kim, J., Lee, K. I., Shin, J. M., Chae, J. I., &amp; Chung, H. M. (2011). Enhancement of wound healing by secretory factors of endothelial precursor cells derived from human embryonic stem cells. Cytotherapy, 13, 165–178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/14653249.2010.512632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, C., Cui, X., Huang, L., Shang, X., Wu, B., Wang, N., He, K., &amp; Han, Z. (2019). IRTKS promotes insulin signaling transduction through inhibiting SHIP2 phosphatase activity. International Journal of Molecular Science, 20(11), 2834.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms20112834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahara, K., Ii, M., Inamoto, T., Komura, K., Ibuki, N., Minami, K., Uehara, H., Hirano, H., Nomi, H., Kiyama, S., Asahi, M., &amp; Azuma, H. (2014). Adipose-derived stromal cells inhibit prostate cancer cell proliferation inducing apoptosis. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 446, 1102–1107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2014.03.080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun, B., Roh, K. H., Park, J. R., Lee, S. R., Park, S. B., Jung, J. W., Kang, S. K., Lee, Y. S., &amp; Kang, K. S. (2009). Therapeutic potential of mesenchymal stromal cell s in a mouse breast cancer metastas is model. Cytotherapy, 11, 289–298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14653240902807026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chao, K. C., Yang, H. T., &amp; Chen, M. W. (2011). Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells suppress breast cancer tumourigenesis through direct cell-cell contact and internalization. Journal of Cell Molecular Medicine, 16, 1803–1815.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1582-4934.2011.01459.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, D., Liu, S., Ma, H., Liang, X., Ma, H., Yan, X., Yang, B., Wei, J., &amp; Liu, X. (2015). Paracrine factors from adipose-mesenchymal stem cells enhance metastatic capacity through Wnt signaling pathway in a colon cancer cell co-culture model. Cancer Cell International, 15, 42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-015-0198-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>So, K. A., Min, K. J., Hong, J. H., &amp; Lee, J. K. (2015). Interleukin-6 expression by interactions between gynecologic cancer cells and human mesenchymal stem cells promotes epithelial-mesenchymal transition. International Journal of Oncology, 47, 1451–145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijo.2015.3122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma, F., Chen, D., Chen, F., Chi, Y., Han, Z., Feng, X., Li, X., &amp; Han, Z. (2015). Human umbilical cord mesenchymal stem cells promote breast cancer metastasis by interleukin-8- and interleukin-6-dependent induction of CD44+/CD24− Cells. Cell Transplantation, 24, 2585–2599.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3727/096368915X687462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scherzad, A., Steber, M., Gehrke, T., Rak, K., Froelich, K., Schenddzielorz, P., Hagen, R., Kleinsasser, N., &amp; Hackenberg, S. (2015). Human mesenchymal stem cells enhance cancer cell proliferation via IL-6 secretion and activation of ERK1/2. International Journal of Oncology, 47, 391–397.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijo.2015.3009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadeghi, A., Roudi, R., Mirzaei, A., Zare Mirzaei, A., Madjd, Z., &amp; Abolhasani, M. (2019). CD44 epithelial isoform inversely associates with invasive characteristics of colorectal cancer. Biomarkers in Medicine, 13(6), 419–426.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/bmm-2018-0337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roudi, R., Barodabi, M., Madjd, Z., Roviello, G., Corona, S. P., &amp; Panahi, M. (2020). Expression patterns and clinical significance of the potential cancer stem cell markers OCT4 and NANOG in colorectal cancer patients. Molecular &amp; Cellular Oncology, 7(5), 1788366 https://doi.org/10.1080/23723556.2020.1788366 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23723556.2020.1788366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
