<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35150049</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4930</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>11</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cytometry. Part A : the journal of the International Society for Analytical Cytology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cytometry A</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Inherent bioelectrical parameters of hundreds of thousands of single leukocytes based on impedance flow cytometry.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cyto.a.24544</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>As label-free biomarkers, bioelectrical properties of single cells have been widely used in hematology analyzers for 3-part differential of leukocytes, in which, however, instrument dependent bioelectrical parameters (e.g., DC/AC impedance values) rather than inherent bioelectrical parameters (e.g., diameter D<sub>c</sub> , specific membrane capacitance C<sub>sm</sub> and cytoplasmic conductivity σ<sub>cy</sub> ) were used, leading to poor comparisons among different instruments. In order to address this issue, this study collected inherent bioelectrical parameters from hundreds of thousands of white blood cells based on a home-developed impedance flow cytometry with corresponding 3-part differential of leukocytes realized. More specifically, leukocytes were separated into three major subtypes of granulocytes, monocytes and lymphocytes based on density gradient centrifugation. Then these separated cells were aspirated through a constriction-microchannel based impedance flow cytometry where inherent bioelectrical parameters of D<sub>c</sub> , C<sub>sm</sub> and σ<sub>cy</sub> were quantified as 9.8 ± 0.7 μm, 2.06 ± 0.26 μF/cm<sup>2</sup> , and 0.34 ± 0.05 S/m for granulocytes (n<sub>cell</sub>  = 134,829); 10.4 ± 1.0 μm, 2.45 ± 0.48 μF/cm<sup>2</sup> , and 0.42 ± 0.08 S/m for monocytes (n<sub>cell</sub>  = 40,226); 8.0 ± 0.5 μm, 2.23 ± 0.34 μF/cm<sup>2</sup> , and 0.35 ± 0.08 S/m for lymphocytes (n<sub>cell</sub>  = 129,193). Based on these inherent bioelectrical parameters, neural pattern recognition was conducted, producing a high "classification accuracy" of 93.5% in classifying these three subtypes of leukocytes. These results indicate that as inherent bioelectrical parameters, D<sub>c</sub> , C<sub>sm</sub> , and σ<sub>cy</sub> can be used to electrically phenotype white blood cells in a label-free manner.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 International Society for Advancement of Cytometry.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huiwen</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Future Technology, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Minruihong</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Future Technology, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Electronic, Electrical and Communication Engineering, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xukun</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Electronic, Electrical and Communication Engineering, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deyong</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Future Technology, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Electronic, Electrical and Communication Engineering, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yueying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Genomic and Precision Medicine, Collaborative Innovation Center of Genetics and Development, Beijing Institute of Genomics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>China National Center for Bioinformation, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Min-Hsien</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Biochemical and Biomedical Engineering, Chang Gung University, Taoyuan City, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ke</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Electronic Engineering, Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junbo</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Future Technology, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Electronic, Electrical and Communication Engineering, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jian</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4612-3279</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Transducer Technology, Aerospace Information Research Institute, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Future Technology, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Electronic, Electrical and Communication Engineering, University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cytometry A</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101235694</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1552-4922</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">constriction microchannel</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impedance flow cytometry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inherent bioelectrical parameter</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leukocyte phenotyping</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">single cell analysis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150049</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cyto.a.24544</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y, Xie X, Duan Y, Wang L, Cheng Z, &amp; Cheng J. A review of impedance measurements of whole cells. Biosens Bioelectron. 2016;77(77):824-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petchakup C, Li KHH, Hou HW. Advances in single cell impedance cytometry for biomedical applications. Micromachines. 2017;8(3):87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang R-J, Fu L-M, Hou H-H. Review and perspectives on microfluidic flow cytometers. Sens Actuators B Chem. 2018;266:26-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adekanmbi EO, Srivastava SK. Dielectric characterization of bioparticles via electrokinetics: the past, present, and the future. Appl Phys Rev. 2019;6(4):041313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang H, Tan H, Chen D, Wang J, Chen J, &amp; Wu M. Single-cell impedance flow cytometry. In: Santra TS, Tseng F-G, editors. Handbook of single cell technologies. Singapore: Springer; 2019. p. 1-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honrado C, Bisegna P, Swami NS, &amp; Caselli F. Single-cell microfluidic impedance cytometry: from raw signals to cell phenotypes using data analytics. Lab Chip. 2021;21(1):22-54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Memmel S, Sukhorukov VL, Horing M, Westerling K, Fiedler V, &amp; Katzer A. Cell surface area and membrane folding in glioblastoma cell lines differing in PTEN and p53 status. PLoS One. 2014;9(1):e87052.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham KA, Mulhall HJ, Labeed FH, Lewis MP, Hoettges KF, &amp; Kalavrezos N. A dielectrophoretic method of discrimination between normal oral epithelium, and oral and oropharyngeal cancer in a clinical setting. Analyst. 2015;140(15):5198-204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lannin T, Su WW, Gruber C, Cardle I, Huang C, &amp; Thege F. Automated electrorotation shows electrokinetic separation of pancreatic cancer cells is robust to acquired chemotherapy resistance, serum starvation, and EMT. Biomicrofluidics. 2016;10(6):064109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar R, Liu S, Minna JD, &amp; Prasad S. Monitoring drug induced apoptosis and treatment sensitivity in non-small cell lung carcinoma using dielectrophoresis. Biochim Biophys Acta Biomembr. 2016;1860(9):1877-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang W, Zhao Y, Liu L, Wang Y, Li WJ, &amp; Lee G-B. Determination of cell membrane capacitance and conductance via optically induced electrokinetics. Biophys J. 2017;113(7):1531-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Wang K, Chen D, Fan B, Xu Y, &amp; Ye Y. Development of microfluidic impedance cytometry enabling the quantification of specific membrane capacitance and cytoplasm conductivity from 100,000 single cells. Biosens Bioelectron. 2018;111:138-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Liang H, Tan H, Chen D, Wang Y, &amp; Xu Y. Development of microfluidic platform to high-throughput quantify single-cell intrinsic bioelectrical markers of tumor cell lines, subtypes and patient tumor cells. Sens. Actuators B Chem. 2020;317:128231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ziervogel H, Glaser R, Schadow D, &amp; Heymann S. Electrorotation of lymphocytes--the influence of membrane events and nucleus. Biosci Rep. 1986;6(11):973-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu X, Arnold WM, Zimmermann U. Alterations in the electrical properties of T and B lymphocyte membranes induced by mitogenic stimulation. Activation monitored by electro-rotation of single cells. Biochim Biophys Acta Biomembr. 1990;1021(2):191-200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang J, Huang Y, Wang X-B, Wang X, Becker FF, &amp; Gascoyne PRC. Dielectric properties of human leukocyte subpopulations determined by electrorotation as a cell separation criterion. Biophys J. 1999;76(6):3307-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vykoukal DM, Gascoyne PR, Vykoukal J. Dielectric characterization of complete mononuclear and polymorphonuclear blood cell subpopulations for label-free discrimination. Integr Biol. 2009;1(7):477-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sancho M, Martinez G, Munoz S, Sebastian JL, &amp; Pethig R. Interaction between cells in dielectrophoresis and electrorotation experiments. Biomicrofluidics. 2010;4(2):022802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang K, Chang CC, Chiu TK, Zhao X, Chen D, &amp; Chou W. Membrane capacitance of thousands of single white blood cells. J R Soc Interface. 2017;14(137):20170717.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labeed FH, Lu J, Mulhall HJ, Marchenko SA, Hoettges KF, &amp; Estrada LC. Biophysical characteristics reveal neural stem cell differentiation potential. PLoS One. 2011;6(9):e25458.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velugotla S, Pells S, Mjoseng HK, Duffy CR, Smith S, &amp; Sousa P. Dielectrophoresis based discrimination of human embryonic stem cells from differentiating derivatives. Biomicrofluidics. 2012;6(4):44113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams TNG, Turner PA, Janorkar AV, Zhao F, &amp; Minerick AR. Characterizing the dielectric properties of human mesenchymal stem cells and the effects of charged elastin-like polypeptide copolymer treatment. Biomicrofluidics. 2014;8(5):054109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ismail A, Hughes MP, Mulhall HJ, Oreffo RO, &amp; Labeed FH. Characterization of human skeletal stem and bone cell populations using dielectrophoresis. Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2015;9(2):162-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Liu Q, Sun H, Chen D, Li Z, &amp; Fan B. Electrical property characterization of neural stem cells in differentiation. PLoS One. 2016;11(6):e0158044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buttarello M, Plebani M. Automated blood cell counts: state of the art. Am J Clin Pathol. 2008;130(1):104-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeNicola DB. Advances in hematology analyzers. Top Companion Anim M. 2011;26(2):52-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chabot-Richards DS, George TI. White blood cell counts: reference methodology. Clin Lab Med. 2015;35(1):11-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goater AD, Pethig R. Electrorotation and dielectrophoresis. Parasitology. 1998;117(7):S177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coley HM, Labeed FH, Thomas H, &amp; Hughes MP. Biophysical characterization of MDR breast cancer cell lines reveals the cytoplasm is critical in determining drug sensitivity. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2007;1770(4):601-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Chen D, Li H, Luo Y, Deng B, &amp; Huang SB. A microfluidic system enabling continuous characterization of specific membrane capacitance and cytoplasm conductivity of single cells in suspension. Biosens Bioelectron. 2013;43:304-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Chen D, Luo Y, Li H, Deng B, &amp; Huang SB. A microfluidic system for cell type classification based on cellular size-independent electrical properties. Lab Chip. 2013;13(12):2272-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhamare D, Suryawanshi P. Review on reliable pattern recognition with machine learning techniques. J Intell Fuzzy Syst. 2019;10(3):362-77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A, Harrison PJ, Wieslander H, Pielawski N, Kartasalo K, &amp; Partel G. Deep learning in image cytometry: a review. Cytometry A. 2019;95(4):366-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riordon J, Sovilj D, Sanner S, Sinton D, &amp; Young EWK. Deep learning with microfluidics for biotechnology. Trends Biotechnol. 2019;37(3):310-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honrado C, Mcgrath JS, Reale R, Bisegna P, Swami NS, &amp; Caselli F. A neural network approach for real-time particle/cell characterization in microfluidic impedance cytometry. Anal Bioanal Chem. 2020;412(16):3835-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kutlu H, Avci E, Ozyurt F. White blood cells detection and classification based on regional convolutional neural networks. Med Hypotheses. 2020;135:109472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng Y, Cheng Z, Chai H, He W, Huang L, &amp; Wang W. Neural network-enhanced real-time impedance flow cytometry for single-cell intrinsic characterization. Lab Chip. 2022;22(2):240-249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Z, Wang S, Chen G, &amp; Su X. Deep learning based label-free small extracellular vesicles analyzer with light-sheet illumination differentiates normal and cancer liver cells. Sens Actuators B Chem. 2021;347:130612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegde RB, Prasad K, Hebbar H, Sandhya I. Peripheral blood smear analysis using image processing approach for diagnostic purposes: a review. Biocybern Biomed Eng. 2018;38(3):467-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang M, Wang X, Zhao X, Teng Y, Chen J, &amp; Wang J. Classification of tumor subtypes leveraging constriction-channel based impedance flow cytometry and optical imaging. Cytometry A. 2021;99(11):1114-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
