<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35150142</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2665</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>45</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of inherited metabolic disease</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Inherit Metab Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>No effect of oral ketone ester supplementation on exercise capacity in patients with McArdle disease and healthy controls: A randomized placebo-controlled cross-over study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>502</StartPage>
          <EndPage>516</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>502-516</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jimd.12484</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Patients with glycogen storage disease type V (GSDV), also known as McArdle disease, have blocked glycogen breakdown due to myophosphorylase deficiency, leading to exercise intolerance, muscle pain, and risk of muscle damage. Blood-derived ketone bodies (KBs) constitute an alternative energy source that could fuel the muscle independent of glycogenolysis. However, except for long-time fasting or ketogenic dieting, KBs are present in low quantities. This led us to explore the effects of a drink containing exogenously produced KBs in the form of D-β-hydroxybutyrate esters (KE) on exercise capacity and metabolism in patients with GSDV. Eight GSDV patients and four healthy controls (HC) were included in this placebo-controlled, cross-over study where subjects were randomized to receive a KE drink with 395 mgKE/kg or placebo drink on two separate days 25 min before a submaximal cycle exercise test. The primary outcome was exercise capacity as indicated by heart rate response (HR) to exercise. Secondary outcomes included perceived exertion (PE) and measures of KB, carbohydrate, and fat metabolism during exercise. In GSDV, the KE drink vs. placebo increased plasma KBs and KB oxidation (p ≤ 0.0001) but did not improve exercise capacity as judged from HR (p = 0.120) and PE (p = 0.109). In addition, the KE drink lowered plasma glucose, free fatty acids, and lowered lipolytic rate and glucose rate of appearance compared with placebo. Similar results were found in the HC group. The present study indicates that an increase in KB oxidation by oral KE supplementation does not improve exercise capacity in GSDV possibly because of KB-induced inhibition of lipolysis and liver glucose output. Thus, oral KE supplementation alone cannot be recommended as a treatment option for patients with GSDV.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Journal of Inherited Metabolic Disease published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of SSIEM.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Løkken</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicoline</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5494-8484</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Storgaard</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jesper H</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Revsbech</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karoline L</ForeName>
            <Initials>KL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Voermans</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicol C</ForeName>
            <Initials>NC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Department of Neurology, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, Radboud University Nijmegen Medical Centre, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Van Hall</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gerrit</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Metabolomics Core Facility, Clinical Biochemistry, Copenhagen University Hospital, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, Faculty of Health &amp; Medical Sciences, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vissing</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Medicine, University of Copenhagen, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ørngreen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mette C</ForeName>
            <Initials>MC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Copenhagen Neuromuscular Center, Copenhagen University Hospital - Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Inherit Metab Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7910918</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0141-8955</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D004952">Esters</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007657">Ketone Bodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007659">Ketones</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>IY9XDZ35W2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005947">Glucose</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018592" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Over Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019587" MajorTopicYN="N">Dietary Supplements</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004952" MajorTopicYN="N">Esters</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017079" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Tolerance</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005947" MajorTopicYN="N">Glucose</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006012" MajorTopicYN="Y">Glycogen Storage Disease Type V</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007657" MajorTopicYN="N">Ketone Bodies</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007659" MajorTopicYN="N">Ketones</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">McArdle disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise capacity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exogenous ketone bodies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glycogen storage disease type V</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ketone ester</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35150142</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jimd.12484</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oldfors A, DiMauro S. New insights in the field of muscle glycogenoses. Curr Opin Neurol. 2013;26(5):544-553.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Mauro S. Muscle glycogenoses: an overview. Acta Myol. 2007;26(1):35-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang W-C, Nishino I. State of the art in muscle lipid diseases. Acta Myol. 2010;29(2):351-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orngreen MC, Jeppesen TD, Andersen ST, et al. Fat metabolism during exercise in patients with McArdle disease. Neurology. 2009;72(8):718-724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersen ST, Haller RG, Vissing J. Effect of oral sucrose shortly before exercise on work capacity in McArdle disease. Arch Neurol. 2008;65(6):786-789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vissing J, Haller RG. The effect of oral sucrose on exercise tolerance in patients with McArdle's disease. N Engl J Med. 2003;349(26):2503-2509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madsen KL, Laforêt P, Buch AE, et al. No effect of triheptanoin on exercise performance in McArdle disease. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2019;6(10):1949-1960.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikkelsen KH, Seifert T, Secher NH, Grøndal T, van Hall G. Systemic, cerebral and skeletal muscle ketone body and energy metabolism during acute hyper-D-β-Hydroxybutyratemia in post-absorptive healthy males. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2015;100(2):636-643.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukao T, Mitchell G, Sass JO, Hori T, Orii K, Aoyama Y. Ketone body metabolism and its defects. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2014;37(4):541-551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukao T, Lopaschuk GD, Mitchell GA. Pathways and control of ketone body metabolism: on the fringe of lipid biochemistry. Prostaglandins Leukot Essent Fatty Acids. 2004;70(3):243-251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owen OE, Felig P, Morgan AP, Wahren J, Cahill GF Jr. Liver and kidney metabolism during prolonged starvation. J Clin Invest. 1969;48(3):574-583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Løkken N, Hansen KK, Storgaard JH, Ørngreen MC, Quinlivan R, Vissing J. Titrating a modified ketogenic diet for patients with McArdle disease: a pilot study. J Inherit Metab Dis. 2020;43(4):778-786.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox PJ, Kirk T, Ashmore T, et al. Nutritional ketosis alters fuel preference and thereby endurance performance in athletes. Cell Metab. 2016;24(2):256-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stubbs BJ, Cox PJ, Evans RD, et al. On the metabolism of exogenous ketones in humans. Front Physiol. 2017;8:848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CJDC H, Schofield GM, Williden M. The use of nutritional supplements to induce ketosis and reduce symptoms associated with keto-induction: a narrative review. PeerJ. 2018;6:e4488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myette-Côté É, Neudorf H, Rafiei H, Clarke K, Little JP. Prior ingestion of exogenous ketone monoester attenuates the glycaemic response to an oral glucose tolerance test in healthy young individuals: ketone monoester and glycaemic response. J Physiol. 2018;596(8):1385-1395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vissing J, Haller RG. A diagnostic cycle test for McArdle's disease. Ann Neurol. 2003;54(4):539-542.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliot DL, Buist NR, Goldberg L, et al. Metabolic myopathies: evaluation by graded exercise testing. Medicine. 1989;68(3):163-172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14(5):377-381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hall G. Correction factors for 13C-labelled substrate oxidation at whole-body and muscle level. Proc Nutr Soc. 1999;58(4):979-986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leckey JJ, Ross ML, Quod M, Hawley JA, Burke LM. Ketone diester ingestion impairs time-trial performance in professional cyclists. Front Physiol. 2017;8:806.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodger S, Plews D, Laursen P, Driller M. The effects of an oral β-hydroxybutyrate supplement on exercise metabolism and cycling performance. J Sci Cycl. 2017;6(1):26-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans M, Patchett E, Nally R, Kearns R, Larney M, Egan B. Effect of acute ingestion of β-hydroxybutyrate salts on the response to graded exercise in trained cyclists. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018;18(3):376-386.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dearlove DJ, Faull OK, Rolls E, Clarke K, Cox PJ. Nutritional ketoacidosis during incremental exercise in healthy athletes. Front Physiol. 2019;10:290.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taggart AKP, Kero J, Gan X, et al. (d)-β-Hydroxybutyrate inhibits adipocyte lipolysis via the nicotinic acid receptor PUMA-G. J Biol Chem. 2005;280(29):26649-26652.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stubbs BJ, Koutnik AP, Poff AM, Ford KM, D'Agostino DP. Commentary: ketone diester ingestion impairs time-trial performance in professional cyclists. Front Physiol. 2018;9:279.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans M, Cogan KE, Egan B. Metabolism of ketone bodies during exercise and training: physiological basis for exogenous supplementation. J Physiol. 2017;595(9):2857-2871.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hall G, van der Vusse GJ, Söderlund K, Wagenmakers AJ. Deamination of amino acids as a source for ammonia production in human skeletal muscle during prolonged exercise. J Physiol. 1995;489(1):251-261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hall G, Saltin B, van der Vusse G, Söderlund K, Saris WHM, Wagenmakers AJM. Deamination of amino acids: a source of muscle ammonia production during exercise. Clin Nutr. 1993;12:62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagenmakers AJ, Coakley JH, Edwards RH. Metabolism of branched-chain amino acids and ammonia during exercise: clues from McArdle's disease. Int J Sports Med. 1990;11(Suppl 2):S101-S113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacLean D, Vissing J, Vissing SF, Haller RG. Oral branched-chain amino acids do not improve exercise capacity in McArdle disease. Neurology. 1998;51(5):1456-1459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
