<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35168463</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparing the use of mathematical calculation to a measuring wheel to determine distance walked in three different course configurations of the 6 minute Walk Test in healthy adults.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>591</StartPage>
          <EndPage>598</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>591-598</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2022.2041209</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A recent clinical practice guideline set forth recommendations for the administration of the 6 Minute Walk Test, including course set-up and using mathematical calculation to obtain the distance walked. In clinical practice and research, however, deviations from these protocols exist.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess for differences in total distance walked between use of mathematical calculation and a measuring wheel during three different course configurations of the 6 Minute Walk Test.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifty healthy adults (18 males, 32 females) completed this study. The mean age was 37.04 (13.76) years ranging from 23 to 61 years. Each participant completed three course configurations of the 6 Minute Walk Test: a 12-meter straight walkway representing the Academy of Neurologic Physical Therapy Core Set of Outcome Measures Clinical Practice Guideline protocol, a 30-meter straight walkway, representing the American Thoracic Society's recommended protocol, and a 1.2-meter by 12-meter rectangular walkway, of which the Core Set of Outcome Measures Clinical Practice Guideline was derived. For mathematical calculation, the total number of laps counted, and this total number was multiplied by the distance of one lap with any partial lap added. Additionally, a research assistant followed behind each participant with a measuring wheel to capture distance walked.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">For all configurations, there were statistically significant differences between mathematical calculation and a measuring wheel, with mathematical calculation producing significantly less total distance. Additionally, there were statistically significant differences between all course configurations, despite the method of measurement.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Adhering to 6 Minute Walk Test protocols, including the method of measuring the distance, is imperative to accurately interpret results and compare to existing data.Key messagesDespite recommendations for standardized administration of the 6 Minute Walk Test, deviations exist, including the method of which to obtain the total distance walked; either by use of mathematical calculation or a measuring wheel.In three different 6 minute walk test course configurations, including the American Thoracic Society's recommended protocol and the Academy of Neurologic Physical Therapy recommended protocol, the measuring wheel resulted in significantly larger distances than use of the mathematical calculation.Despite the measuring wheel able to account for the turns during the 6 Minute Walk Test, it is imperative for clinicians to utilize standardized procedures such as using mathematical calculation, in order to accurately track progress and compare to existing data, of which mathematical calculation was used to derive.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>O'Neal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Suzanne K</ForeName>
            <Initials>SK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0127-5132</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eikenberry</LastName>
            <ForeName>Megan C</ForeName>
            <Initials>MC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bocchi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexander</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Carroll</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kyle</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fettig</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michelle</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Folliard</LastName>
            <ForeName>Parker</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martinez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Clara</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Doctor of Physical Therapy Program, Midwestern University, Glendale, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005080" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Test</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017063" MajorTopicYN="Y">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000070857" MajorTopicYN="N">Walk Test</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking capacity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gait</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">outcome measures</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">walking test</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>In accordance with Taylor &amp; Francis policy and my ethical obligation as a researcher, I am reporting that Megan Eikenberry, PT, DPT is a member of the Academy of Neurologic Physical Therapy’s Core Set of Outcome Measures Knowledge Translation Task Force. The purpose of this Task Force is to help assist clinicians in applying the Core Set of Outcome Measures Clinical Practice Guidelines into practice. Potential benefit of this research study is increased exposure and recognition of this Task Force and the Clinical Practice Guideline itself. No potential conflict of was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35168463</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8856093</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2041209</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Thoracic Society . ATS statement: guidelines for the six-minute walk test. Am J Resp Crit Care. 2002;166:111–117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steffen T, Seney M.. 
Test-retest reliability and minimal detectable change on balance and ambulation tests, the 36-item short-form health survey, and the unified Parkinson disease rating scale in people with Parkinsonism. Phys Ther. 2008;88(6):733–746.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18356292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam T, Noonan VK, Eng JJ, SCIRE Research Team. 
A systematic review of functional ambulation outcome measures in spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2008;46(4):246–254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3095631</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17923844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ries JD, Echternach JL, Nof L, et al. . 
Test-retest reliability and minimal detectable change scores for the timed “up &amp; go” test, the six-minute walk test, and gait speed in people with Alzheimer disease. Phys Ther. 2009;89(6):569–579.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19389792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fulk GD, He Y.. 
Minimal clinically important difference of the 6-Minute walk test in people with stroke. Phys Ther. 2008;42:235–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holland AE, Spruit MA, Troosters T, et al. . 
An official European Respiratory Society/American Thoracic Society technical standard: field walking tests in chronic respiratory disease. Eur Respir J. 2014;44(6):1428–1446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25359355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn A, Marsden DL, Nugent E, et al. . 
Protocol variations and six-minute walk test performance in stroke survivors: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Stroke Res Treat. 2015;2015:484813.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4320847</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25685596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore JL, Potter K, Blankshain K, et al. . 
A core set of outcome measures for adults with neurologic conditions undergoing rehabilitation: a clinical practice guideline. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2018;42(3):174–220.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6023606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29901487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quinn L, Khalil H, Dawes H, Outcome Measures Subgroup of the European Huntington's Disease Network, et al.. 
Reliability and minimal detectable change of physical performance measures in individuals with pre-manifest and manifest Huntington disease. Phys Ther. 2013;93(7):942–956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23520147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bean JF, Kiely DK, Leveille SG, et al. . 
The 6-Minute walk test in mobility-limited elders: what is being measured?
J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2002;57(11):M751–M756.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12403805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geiger R, Strasak A, Treml B, et al. . 
Six-minute walk test in children and adolescents. J Pediatr. 2007;150(4):395–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17382117</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox PD, Frengopoulos CA, Hunter SW, et al. . 
Impact of course configuration on 6-minute walk test performance of people with lower extremity amputations. Physiother Can. 2017;69(3):197–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5963553</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30275635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng SS, Tsang WW, Cheung TH, et al. . 
Walkway length, but not turning direction, determines six-minute walk test distance in individuals with stroke. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2011;92(5):806–811.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21530729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng SS, Yu PC, To FP, et al. . 
Effect of walkway length and turning direction on the distance covered in the 6-minute walk test among adults over 50 years of age: a cross-sectional study. Physiother. 2013;99(1):63–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23219645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sciurba F, Criner GJ, Lee SM, et al. . 
Six-minute walk test distance in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2003;167(11):1522–1527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12615634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauchenzauner M, Schneider J, Colleselli V, et al. . 
Comparing modalities of conducting the six-minute walk test in healthy children and adolescents. Minerva Pediatr. 2019;71(3):229–234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31017381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuseppe P.
StaTips part IV: Selection, interpretation and reporting of the intraclass correlation coefficient. South Eur J Orthod Dentofac Res. 2018;5:3–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J.
A power primer. Pyschol Bull. 1992;112(1):155–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flansbjer UB, Holmback AM, Downham D, et al. . 
Reliability of gait performance tests in men and women with hemiparesis after stroke. J Rehabil Med. 2005;37(2):75–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15788341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harada ND, Chiu V, Stewart AL.. 
Mobility-related function in older adults: assessment with a 6-minute walk test. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1999;80(7):837–841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10414771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kennedy DM, Stratford PW, Wessel J, et al. . 
Assessing stability and change of four performance measures: a longitudinal study evaluation outcome following total hip arthroplasty. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2005;6(1):1–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC549207</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15679884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scivoletto G, Tamburella F, Laurenza L, et al. . 
Validity and reliability of the 10-m walk test and the 6-min walk test in spinal cord injury patients. Spinal Cord. 2011;49(6):736–740.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21221120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cederberg KLJ, Sikes EM, Bartolucci AA, et al. . 
Walking endurance in multiple sclerosis: meta-analysis of six-minute walk test performance. Gait Posture. 2019;73:147–153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31326830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
