<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35167127</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-1594</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Artificial organs</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Artif Organs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Factors influencing the functional status of aortic valve in ovine models supported by continuous-flow left ventricular assist device.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/aor.14207</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">An acute animal experiment was performed to observe factors influencing the functional status of the aortic valve functional status after continuous-flow left ventricular assist device (CF-LVAD) implantation in an ovine model, and a physiologic predictive model was established.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A CF-LVAD model was established in Small Tail Han sheep. The initial heart rate (HR) was set to 60 beats/min, and grouping was performed at an interval of 20 beats/min. In all groups, the pump speed was started from 2000 rpm and was gradually increased by 50-100 rpm. A multi-channel physiological recorder recorded the HR, aortic pressure, central venous pressure, and left ventricular systolic pressure (LVSP). A double-channel ultrasonic flowmeter was used to obtain real-time artificial vascular blood flow (ABF). A color Doppler ultrasound device was applied to assess the aortic valve functional status. Multivariate dichotomous logistic regression was used to screen significant variables for predicting the functional status of the aortic valve.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Observational studies showed that ABF and the risk of aortic valve closure (AVC) were positively correlated with pump speed at the same HR. Meanwhile, the mean arterial pressure (MAP) was unaltered or slightly increased with increased pump speed. When the pump speed was constant, an increase in HR was associated with a decrease in the size of the aortic valve opening. This phenomenon was accompanied by an initial transient increase in the ABF and MAP, which subsequently decreased. Statistical analysis showed that the AVC was associated with increased pump speed (OR = 1.02, 95% CI = 1.01-1.04, p = 0.001), decreased LVSP (OR = 0.95, 95% CI = 0.91-0.98, p = 0.003), and decreased pulse pressure (OR = 0.82, 95% CI = 0.68-0.96, p = 0.026). ABF or MAP was negatively associated with the risk of AVC (OR &lt; 1). The prediction model of AVC after CF-LVAD implantation exhibited good differentiation (AUC = 0.973, 95% CI = 0.978-0.995) and calibration performance (Hosmer-Lemeshow χ<sup>2</sup>  = 9.834, p = 0.277 &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The pump speed, LVSP, ABF, MAP, and pulse pressure are significant predictors of the risk of AVC. Predictive models built from these predictors yielded good performance in differentiating aortic valve opening and closure after CF-LVAD implantation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Artificial Organs published by International Center for Artificial Organ and Transplantation (ICAOT) and Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xin-Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>XY</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3118-4407</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, TEDA International Cardiovascular Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Graduate School of Peking Union Medical College, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jian-Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>JW</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6890-5795</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, TEDA International Cardiovascular Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Graduate School of Peking Union Medical College, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi-Rui</ForeName>
            <Initials>YR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2328-570X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, TEDA International Cardiovascular Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Graduate School of Peking Union Medical College, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie-Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory Animal Center, TEDA International Cardiovascular Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Graduate School of Peking Union Medical College, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhi-Gang</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascular Surgery, TEDA International Cardiovascular Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Graduate School of Peking Union Medical College, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Artif Organs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7802778</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0160-564X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LVAD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">aortic valve</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">influencing factors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nomogram</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">predictive model</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35167127</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aor.14207</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molina EJ, Shah P, Kiernan MS, Cornwell WK 3rd, Copeland H, Takeda K, et al. The society of thoracic surgeons Intermacs 2020 annual report. Ann Thorac Surg. 2021;111(3):778-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teuteberg JJ, Cleveland JC Jr, Cowger J, Higgins RS, Goldstein DJ, Keebler M, et al. The society of thoracic surgeons Intermacs 2019 annual report: the changing landscape of devices and indications. Ann Thorac Surg. 2020;109(3):649-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>John R, Mantz K, Eckman P, Rose A, May-Newman K. Aortic valve pathophysiology during left ventricular assist device support. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2010;29(12):1321-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuzun E, Pennings K, van Tuijl S, de Hart J, Stijnen M, van de Vosse F, et al. Assessment of aortic valve pressure overload and leaflet functions in an ex vivo beating heart loaded with a continuous flow cardiac assist device. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2014;45(2):377-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Truby LK, Garan AR, Givens RC, Wayda B, Takeda K, Yuzefpolskaya M, et al. Aortic insufficiency during contemporary left ventricular assist device support: analysis of the INTERMACS registry. JACC Heart Fail. 2018;6(11):951-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Merwe J, Paul E, Rosenfeldt FL. Early gastrointestinal complications from ventricular assist devices is increased by non-pulsatile flow. Heart Lung Circ. 2020;29(2):295-300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>John R, Boyle A, Pagani F, Miller L. Physiologic and pathologic changes in patients with continuous-flow ventricular assist devices. J Cardiovasc Transl Res. 2009;2(2):154-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wever-Pinzon O, Selzman CH, Drakos SG, Saidi A, Stoddard GJ, Gilbert EM, et al. Pulsatility and the risk of nonsurgical bleeding in patients supported with the continuous-flow left ventricular assist device HeartMate II. Circ Heart Fail. 2013;6(3):517-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuzun E, Rutten M, Dat M, van de Vosse F, Kadipasaoglu C, de Mol B. Continuous-flow cardiac assistance: effects on aortic valve function in a mock loop. J Surg Res. 2011;171(2):443-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bozkurt S, van de Vosse FN, Rutten MC. Aortic valve function under support of a left ventricular assist device: continuous vs. dynamic speed support. Ann Biomed Eng. 2015;43(8):1727-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Liu X, Liu Z, Li Y, Han Z, Xu J, et al. In vivo evaluation of magnetic and hydrodynamic suspension centrifugal ventricular assist device. Zhonghua Yi Xue Za Zhi. 2014;94(22):1740-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iizuka K, Nishinaka T, Ichihara Y, Miyamoto T, Yamazaki K. Outflow graft anastomosis site design could be correlated to aortic valve regurgitation under left ventricular assist device support. J Artif Organs. 2018;21(2):150-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhagra S, Bhagra C, Ozalp F, Butt T, Ramesh BC, Parry G, et al. Development of de novo aortic valve incompetence in patients with the continuous-flow HeartWare ventricular assist device. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2016;35(3):312-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schaefer JJ, Sajgalik P, Kushwaha SS, Olson LJ, Stulak JM, Johnson BD, et al. Left ventricle assist device pulsatility index at the time of implantation is associated with follow-up pulmonary hemodynamics. Int J Artif Organs. 2020;43(7):452-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeile C, Rauwolf T, Schmeisser A, Mizerski JK, Braun-Dullaeus RC, Sager S. An intra-cycle optimal control framework for ventricular assist devices based on atrioventricular plane displacement modeling. Ann Biomed Eng. 2021;49(12):3508-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent F, Rauch A, Loobuyck V, Robin E, Nix C, Vincentelli A, et al. Arterial pulsatility and circulating von Willebrand factor in patients on mechanical circulatory support. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018;71(19):2106-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rt BK, Pressure S. Flow rate and operating speed characteristics of a continuous flow left ventricular assist device during varying speed support. IEEE Access. 2020;8:129830-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobarro D, Urban M, Booth K, Wrightson N, Castrodeza J, Jungschleger J, et al. Impact of aortic valve closure on adverse events and outcomes with the HeartWare ventricular assist device. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2017;36(1):42-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frazier OH, Myers TJ, Gregoric ID, Khan T, Delgado R, Croitoru M, et al. Initial clinical experience with the Jarvik 2000 implantable axial-flow left ventricular assist system. Circulation. 2002;105(24):2855-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuzun E, Gregoric ID, Conger JL, Golden K, Jarvik R, Frazier OH, et al. The effect of intermittent low speed mode upon aortic valve opening in calves supported with a Jarvik 2000 axial flow device. ASAIO J. 2005;51(2):139-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ooi HL, Ng SC, Lim E, Salamonsen RF, Avolio AP, Lovell NH. Robust aortic valve non-opening detection for different cardiac conditions. Artif Organs. 2014;38(3):E57-67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granegger M, Schima H, Zimpfer D, Moscato F. Assessment of aortic valve opening during rotary blood pump support using pump signals. Artif Organs. 2014;38(4):290-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun P, Bozkurt S, Sorguven E. Computational analyses of aortic blood flow under varying speed CF-LVAD support. Comput Biol Med. 2020;127:104058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akimoto T, Yamazaki K, Litwak P, Litwak KN, Tagusari O, Mori T, et al. Rotary blood pump flow spontaneously increases during exercise under constant pump speed: results of a chronic study. Artif Organs. 1999;23(8):797-801.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muthiah K, Gupta S, Otton J, Robson D, Walker R, Tay A, et al. Body position and activity, but not heart rate, affect pump flows in patients with continuous-flow left ventricular assist devices. JACC Heart Fail. 2014;2(4):323-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imamura T, Kinugawa K, Fujino T, Inaba T, Maki H, Hatano M, et al. Aortic insufficiency in patients with sustained left ventricular systolic dysfunction after axial flow assist device implantation. Circ J. 2015;79(1):104-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>da Rocha ESJG, Meyer AL, Eifert S, Garbade J, Mohr FW, Strueber M. Influence of aortic valve opening in patients with aortic insufficiency after left ventricular assist device implantation. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2016;49(3):784-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodwin ML, Bobba CM, Mokadam NA, Whitson BA, Essandoh M, Hasan A, et al. Continuous-flow left ventricular assist devices and the aortic valve: interactions, issues, and surgical therapy. Curr Heart Fail Rep. 2020;17(4):97-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayward CS, Salamonsen R, Keogh AM, Woodard J, Ayre P, Prichard R, et al. Effect of alteration in pump speed on pump output and left ventricular filling with continuous-flow left ventricular assist device. ASAIO J. 2011;57(6):495-500.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myers TJ, Bolmers M, Gregoric ID, Kar B, Frazier OH. Assessment of arterial blood pressure during support with an axial flow left ventricular assist device. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2009;28(5):423-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohno H, Matsumiya G, Sawa Y, Fukushima N, Saiki Y, Shiose A, et al. Can the intermittent low-speed function of left ventricular assist device prevent aortic insufficiency? J Artif Organs. 2021;24(2):191-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saeed D, Westenfeld R, Maxhera B, Keymel S, Sherif A, Sadat N, et al. Prevalence of de novo aortic valve insufficiency in patients after HeartWare VAD implantation with an intermittent low-speed algorithm. ASAIO J. 2016;62(5):565-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imamura T, Nguyen A, Kim G, Raikhelkar J, Sarswat N, Kalantari S, et al. Optimal haemodynamics during left ventricular assist device support are associated with reduced haemocompatibility-related adverse events. Eur J Heart Fail. 2019;21(5):655-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cowger J, Rao V, Massey T, Sun B, May-Newman K, Jorde U, et al. Comprehensive review and suggested strategies for the detection and management of aortic insufficiency in patients with a continuous-flow left ventricular assist device. J Heart Lung Transplant. 2015;34(2):149-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
