<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35171884</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1533-0311</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>44</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The American Journal of dermatopathology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Dermatopathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Diagnostic Value of Plasmacytoid Dendritic Cells in Differentiating Pityriasis Lichenoides et Varioliformis Acuta From Lymphomatoid Papulosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>174</StartPage>
          <EndPage>178</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>174-178</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/DAD.0000000000002063</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pityriasis lichenoides et varioliformis acuta (PLEVA) and lymphomatoid papulosis (LyP) can often demonstrate clinical and histopathologic overlap. A recent study demonstrated significant plasmacytoid dendritic cell (pDC) recruitment in lesions of PLEVA, whereas another study reported minimal pDC recruitment in lesions of LyP. To confirm the possible diagnostic value of pDCs in differentiating PLEVA and LyP, we compared the presence and distribution of pDCs and myxovirus protein A (MxA) expression (an indirect assessment of pDC activity). In total, 19 cases of PLEVA (16 patients) and 14 cases of LyP (11 patients) were examined using immunohistochemical stains for anti-blood-derived dendritic cell antigen-2 and MxA. Individual semiquantitative scoring systems were used to assess the immunohistochemical results, and a Mann-Whitney test with a subsequent 2-tailed P test was performed for statistical analysis. No statistically significant difference in the number of pDCs in both groups was found. However, most PLEVA cases (84%) demonstrated intense and diffuse MxA expression, whereas LyP cases (71%) demonstrated weak patchy staining (P &lt; 0.007). Our study suggests that although additional studies may be needed to determine whether pDCs are more relevant to the pathogenesis of PLEVA or LyP, pDC activity through MxA staining may play a role in differentiating PLEVA from LyP and may serve as a platform for additional studies.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brem</LastName>
            <ForeName>Candice E</ForeName>
            <Initials>CE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6183-8833</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Dermatopathology, Department of Dermatology, Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, MA; and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abbas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ossama</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Department, American University of Beirut Medical Center, Beirut, Lebanon.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bhawan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jag</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Section of Dermatopathology, Department of Dermatology, Boston University School of Medicine, Boston, MA; and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Dermatopathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7911005</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0193-1091</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003713" MajorTopicYN="N">Dendritic Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017731" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphomatoid Papulosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017514" MajorTopicYN="N">Pityriasis Lichenoides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35171884</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DAD.0000000000002063</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00000372-202203000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charles J, Chaperot L, Salameire D, et al. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells and dermatological disorders: focus on their role in autoimmunity and cancer. Eur J Dermatol. 2010;20:16–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vermi W, Soncini M, Melocchi L, et al. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells and cancer. J Leukoc Biol. 2011;90:681–690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holzinger D, Jorns C, Stertz S, et al. Induction of MxA gene expression by influenza A virus requires type I or type III interferon signaling. J Virol. 2007;81:7776–7785.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haller O, Kochs G. Human MxA protein: an interferon-induced dynamin-like GTPase with broad antiviral activity. J Interferon Cytokine Res. 2011;31:79–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vermi W, Vescovi R, Facchetti F. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells in cutaneous disorders. Curr Derm Rep. 2013;2:1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saadeh D, Kurban M, Abbas O. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells and type I interferon in the immunological response against warts. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2017;42:857–862.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vermi W, Fisogni S, Salogni L, et al. Spontaneous regression of highly immunogenic molluscum contagiosum virus (MCV)-induced skin lesions is associated with plasmacytoid dendritic cells and IFN-DC infiltration. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:426–434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saadeh D, Kurban M, Kibbi AG, et al. Involvement of plasmacytoid dendritic cells in the immunological response against Orf infection. JAMA Dermatol. 2014;150:1112–1113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson-Huang LM, McNutt NS, Krueger JG, et al. Cytokine-producing dendritic cells in the pathogenesis of inflammatory skin diseases. J Clin Immunol. 2009;29:247–256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiel A, Kesselring R, Pries R, et al. Plasmacytoid dendritic cell subpopulations in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Oncol Rep. 2011;26:615–620.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sleiman R, Kurban M, Abbas O. Evaluation of the diagnostic value of plasmacytoid dendritic cells in differentiating the lymphocytic cicatricial alopecias. Dermatology. 2015;231:158–163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen SJT, Tse JY, Harms PW, et al. Utility of CD123 immunohistochemistry in differentiating lupus erythematosus from cutaneous T cell lymphoma. Histopathology. 2019;74:908–916.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsh NM, Lai J, Hanly JG, et al. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells in hypertrophic discoid lupus erythematosus: an objective evaluation of their diagnostic value. J Cutan Pathol. 2015;42:32–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Y, Jia J, Tian Q, et al. Lymphomatoid papulosis misdiagnosed as pityriasis lichenoides et varioliformis acuta: two case reports and a literature review. Exp Ther Med. 2014;8:1927–1933.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kempf W, Kazakov DV, Palmedo G, et al. Pityriasis lichenoides et varioliformis acuta with numerous CD30(+) cells: a variant mimicking lymphomatoid papulosis and other cutaneous lymphomas. A clinicopathologic, immunohistochemical, and molecular biological study of 13 cases. Am J Surg Pathol. 2012;36:1021–1029.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karouni M, Rahal JA, Kurban M, et al. Possible role of plasmacytoid dendritic cells in pityriasis lichenoides. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2018;43:404–409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza A, Tinguely M, Burghart DR, et al. Characterization of the tumor microenvironment in primary cutaneous CD30-positive lymphoproliferative disorders: a predominance of CD163-positive M2 macrophages. J Cutan Pathol. 2016;43:579–588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khachemoune A, Blyumin ML. Pityriasis lichenoides. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2007;8:29–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menzinger S, Frassati-Biaggi A, Leclerc-Mercier S, et al. Pityriasis lichenoides: a large histopathological case series with a focus on adnexotropism. Am J Dermatopathol. 2020;42:1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinez-Cabriales SA, Walsh S, Sade S, et al. Lymphomatoid papulosis: an update and review. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34:59–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fitzgerald-Bocarsly P, Dai J, Singh S. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells and type I IFN: 50 years of convergent history. Cytokine Growth Factor Rev. 2008;19:3–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wenzel J, Scheler M, Proelss J, et al. Type I interferon-associated cytotoxic inflammation in lichen planus. J Cutan Pathol. 2006;33:672–678.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomasini D, Tomasini CF, Cerri A, et al. Pityriasis lichenoides: a cytotoxic T-cell-mediated skin disorder. Evidence of human parvovirus B19 DNA in nine cases. J Cutan Pathol. 2004;31:531–538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghoreishi M, Vera Kellet C, Dutz JP. Type 1 IFN-induced protein MxA and plasmacytoid dendritic cells in lesions of morphea. Exp Dermatol. 2012;21:417–419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambers WM, Diercks GFH, Homan FM, et al. Myxovirus resistance protein A is a useful additional histological marker in suspected cutaneous lupus erythematosus. Acta Derm Venereol. 2020;100:adv00234.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vermi W, Lonardi S, Morassi M, et al. Cutaneous distribution of plasmacytoid dendritic cells in lupus erythematosus. Selective tropism at the site of epithelial apoptotic damage. Immunobiology. 2009;214:877–886.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saadeh D, Kurban M, Abbas O. Update on the role of plasmacytoid dendritic cells in inflammatory/autoimmune skin diseases. Exp Dermatol. 2016;25:415–421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badr D, Abadi R, Kurban M, et al. Plasmacytoid dendritic cells and type I interferon signature in lichen striatus. Pediatr Dermatol. 2016;33:301–306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saadeh D, Kurban M, Abbas O. Plasmacytoid dendritic cell role in cutaneous malignancies. J Dermatol Sci. 2016;83:3–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwingshackl P, Obermoser G, Nguyen VA, et al. Distribution and maturation of skin dendritic cell subsets in two forms of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma: mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome. Acta Derm Venereol. 2012;92:269–275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes PS. Treatment of lymphomatoid papulosis with imiquimod 5% cream. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2006;54:546–547.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanna E, Abadi R, Abbas O. Imiquimod in dermatology: an overview. Int J Dermatol. 2016;55:831–844.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bilgiç Temel A, Unal B, Erdi Şanlı H, et al. A severe case of lymphomatoid papulosis type E successfully treated with interferon-alfa 2a. Case Rep Dermatol Med. 2017;2017:3194738.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmuth M, Topar G, Illersperger B, et al. Therapeutic use of interferon-alpha for lymphomatoid papulosis. Cancer. 2000;89:1603–1610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
