<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35171539</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-3083</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology : JEADV</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>No evidence of Borrelia in cutaneous infiltrates of B-cell lymphomas with a highly sensitive, semi-nested real-time polymerase chain reaction targeting the 5S-23S intergenic spacer region.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>836</StartPage>
          <EndPage>845</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>836-845</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jdv.18003</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The role of Borrelia in the development of skin lymphomas has been under discussion for decades. A similar association has been shown for Helicobacter pylori and gastric lymphomas (MALT type). Nevertheless, few molecular studies investigated Borrelia in skin lymphomas and the results are controversial.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We analysed 46 formalin-fixed, paraffin-embedded skin specimens of clincopathologically confirmed B-cell lymphomas (15 marginal zone lymphomas; 20 follicular lymphomas; three diffuse large B-cell lymphomas; eight secondary cutaneous infiltrates) taken from 36 patients from Northern Germany, an endemic area for Borrelia. Fifteen pseudolymphomatous lesions of cutaneous Borreliosis served as the control. Both groups were examined with a real-time (rt) PCR and a semi-nested PCR targeting the 5S-23S intergenic spacer region (IGS). A multiplex PCR was used to investigate B-cell clonality in all lymphomatous infiltrates (Biomed Primers).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">With both assays no Borrelia burgdorferi-specific DNA was identified in any of the B-cell lymphomas, while all 15 Borreliosis specimens gave a positive PCR result in the semi-nested PCR protocol, 12 were also positive in the rt PCR (P &lt; 0.01). All B-cell lymphomas showed monoclonal IgH-Rearrangement. Analysis of cutaneous B-cell lymphomas from available studies including ours (n = 334) reveals an odds ratio &lt;1.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">While some previous studies suggested an association between B. burgdorferi and the development of cutaneous B-cell lymphomas in endemic areas, we were unable to confirm this in our patients, despite a highly sensitive Borrelia PCR assay. Our results including meta-analysis of previous studies question the need for antibiotic therapy in patients with cutaneous B-cell lymphomas.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Papadopoulou</LastName>
            <ForeName>K</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1429-5159</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatologikum Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Falk</LastName>
            <ForeName>T M</ForeName>
            <Initials>TM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatologikum Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Metze</LastName>
            <ForeName>D</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Münster University, Münster, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Böer-Auer</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatologikum Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Münster University, Münster, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9216037</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0926-9959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D004269">DNA, Bacterial</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D021901">DNA, Intergenic</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001898" MajorTopicYN="Y">Borrelia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001899" MajorTopicYN="Y">Borrelia Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004269" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA, Bacterial</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D021901" MajorTopicYN="N">DNA, Intergenic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016393" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymphoma, B-Cell</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D060888" MajorTopicYN="N">Real-Time Polymerase Chain Reaction</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012878" MajorTopicYN="Y">Skin Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35171539</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.18003</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senff NJ, Noordijk EM, Kim YH et al. European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer and International Society for cutaneous lymphoma Consensus recommendations for the management of cutaneous B-cell lymphomas. Blood 2008; 112: 1600-1609.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinzerling L, Hartmann A, Hund M. Kutane lymphome. In: Medikamentöse Tumortherapie in der Dermato-Onkologie. Springer Berlin Heidelberg, Berlin, Heidelberg, 2019: 135-190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilcox RA. Cutaneous B-cell lymphomas: 2019 update on diagnosis, risk stratification, and management. Am J Hematol 2018; 93: 1427-1430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dippel E, Assaf C, Becker JC et al. S2k - Leitlinie - Kutane Lymphome (ICD10 C82-C86). AWMF Online 2021; 12: 6-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lukowsky A, Marchwat M, Sterry W, Gellrich S. Evaluation of B-cell clonality in archival skin biopsy samples of cutaneous B-cell lymphoma by immunoglobulin heavy chain gene polymerase chain reaction. Leuk Lymphoma 2006; 47: 487-493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suarez F, Lortholary O, Hermine O, Lecuit M. Infection-associated lymphomas derived from marginal zone B cells: a model of antigen-driven lymphoproliferation. Blood 2006; 107: 3034-3044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodlad JR, Davidson MM, Hollowood K et al. Primary cutaneous B-cell lymphoma and Borrelia burgdorferi infection in patients from the highlands of Scotland. Am J Surg Pathol 2000; 24: 1279-1285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerroni L, Zöchling N, Pütz B, Kerl H. Infection by Borrelia burgdorferi and cutaneous B-cell lymphoma. J Cutan Pathol 1997; 24: 457-461. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0560.1997.tb01318.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kutting B, Bonsmann G, Metze D et al. Borrelia burgdorferi-associated primary cutaneous B cell lymphoma: Complete clearing of skin lesions after antibiotic pulse therapy or intralesional injection of interferon alfa-2a. J Am Acad Dermatol 1997; 36: 311-314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roggero E, Zucca E, Mainetti C et al. Eradication of Borrelia burgdorferi infection in primary marginal zone B-cell lymphoma of the skin. Hum Pathol 2000; 31: 263-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li C, Inagaki H, Kuo TT et al. Primary cutaneous marginal zone B-cell lymphoma: a molecular and clinicopathologic study of 24 Asian cases. Am J Surg Pathol 2003; 27: 1061-1069.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ponzoni M, Ferreri AJM, Mappa S et al. Prevalence of Borrelia burgdorferi infection in a series of 98 primary cutaneous lymphomas. Oncologist 2011; 16: 1582-1588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood GS, Kamath NV, Guitart J et al. Absence of Borrelia burgdorferi DNA in cutaneous B-cell lymphomas from the United States. J Cutan Pathol 2001; 28: 502-507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanek G. Lyme borreliosis, ticks and Borrelia species. Wien Klin Wochenschr 2018; 130: 459-462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strnad M, Hönig V, Růžek D et al. Europe-wide meta-analysis of Borrelia burgdorferi sensu lato prevalence in questing Ixodes ricinus ticks. Appl Environ Microbiol 2017; 83. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.00609-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerroni L, Kerl H. Diagnostic immunohistology: cutaneous lymphomas and pseudolymphomas. Semin Cutan Med Surg 1999; 18: 64-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Böer A, Tirumalae R, Bresch M, Falk T. Pseudoclonality in cutaneous pseudolymphomas: a pitfall in interpretation of rearrangement studies. Br J Dermatol 2008; 159: 394-402.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Podbicanin-Ziburt A, Falk T, Metze D, Böer-Auer A. Diagnosis of Lyme borreliosis with a novel, semi-nested real time Polymerase chain reaction targeting the 5S-23S intergenic spacer region: clinical features, histopathology and immunophenotype in 44 patients. Am J Dermatopathol 2021.43(12):</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willemze R, Cerroni L, Kempf W et al. The 2018 update of the WHO-EORTC classification for primary cutaneous lymphomas. Blood 2019; 133: 1703-1714.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strube C, Montenegro V, Epe C et al. Establishment of a minor groove binder-probe based quantitative real time PCR to detect Borrelia burgdorferi sensu lato and differentiation of Borrelia spielmanii by ospA-specific conventional PCR. Parasit Vectors 2010; 3: 69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Dongen J, Langerak A, Brüggemann M et al. Design and standardization of PCR primers and protocols for detection of clonal immunoglobulin and T-cell receptor gene recombinations in suspect lymphoproliferations: report of the BIOMED-2 Concerted Action BMH4-CT98-3936. Leukemia 2003; 17: 2257-2317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruxton GD, Neuhäuser M. Review of alternative approaches to calculation of a confidence interval for the odds ratio of a 2 × 2 contingency table. Methods Ecol Evol 2013; 4: 9-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calculate Odds Ratio with 95% Confidence Intervals [WWW Document]. URL https://www.scalestatistics.com/odds-ratio.html (last accessed: 5 October 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jelic S, Filipović-Lješković I. Positive serology for Lyme disease borrelias in primary cutaneous B-cell lymphoma: a study in 22 patients; is it a fortuitous finding? Hematol Oncol 1999; 17: 107-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garbe C, Stein H, Dienemann D, Orfanos CE. Borrelia burgdorferi-associated cutaneous B cell lymphoma: clinical and immunohistologic characterization of four cases. J Am Acad Dermatol 1991; 24: 584-590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takino H, Li C, Hu S et al. Primary cutaneous marginal zone B-cell lymphoma: a molecular and clinicopathological study of cases from Asia, Germany, and the United States. Mod Pathol 2008; 21: 1517-1526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de la Fouchardiere A, Vandenesch F, Berger F. Borrelia-associated primary cutaneous MALT lymphoma in a nonendemic region. Am J Surg Pathol 2003; 27: 702-703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goteri G, Ranaldi R, Simonetti O et al. Clinicopathological features of primary cutaneous B-cell lymphomas from an academic regional hospital in central Italy: no evidence of Borrelia burgdorferi association. Leuk Lymphoma 2007; 48: 2184-2188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Travaglino A, Varricchio S, Pace M et al. Borrelia burgdorferi in primary cutaneous lymphomas: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Dtsch Dermatol Ges 2020; 18: 1379-1384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreri AJM, Govi S, Ponzoni M. Marginal zone lymphomas and infectious agents. Semin. Cancer Biol 2013; 23: 431-440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ponzoni M, Ferreri AJM. Bacteria associated with marginal zone lymphomas. Best Pract Res Clin Haematol 2017; 30: 32-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Violeta Filip P, Cuciureanu D, Sorina Diaconu L et al. MALT lymphoma: epidemiology, clinical diagnosis and treatment. J Med Life 2018; 11: 187-193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schutzer S, Body B, Boyle J et al. Direct diagnostic tests for lyme disease. Clin Infect Dis 2019; 68: 1052-1057.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergman R. Pseudolymphoma and cutaneous lymphoma: facts and controversies. Clin Dermatol 2010; 28: 568-574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerroni LKH. Diagnostic immunohistology: cutaneous lymphomas and pseudolymphomas. Semin Cutan Med Surg 1999; 18: 64-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grange F, Wechsler J, Guillaume J et al. Borrelia burgdorferi-associated lymphocytoma cutis simulating a primary cutaneous large B-cell lymphoma. J Am Acad Dermatol 2002; 47: 530-534.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koens L, Zoutman WH, Ngarmlertsirichai P et al. Nuclear factor-κB pathway-activating gene aberrancies in primary cutaneous large B-cell lymphoma, leg type. J Invest Dermatol 2014; 134: 290-292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou XA, Yang J, Ringbloom KG et al. Genomic landscape of cutaneous follicular lymphomas reveals 2 subgroups with clinically predictive molecular features. Blood Adv 2021; 5: 649-661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurus K, Appenzeller S, Roth S et al. Panel sequencing shows recurrent genetic FAS alterations in primary cutaneous marginal zone lymphoma. J Invest Dermatol 2018; 138: 1573-1581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caskey JR, Hasenkampf NR, Martin DS et al. The functional and molecular effects of doxycycline treatment on Borrelia burgdorferi phenotype. Front Microbiol 2019; 10. https://doi.org/10.3389/FMICB.2019.00690</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng J, Auwaerter PG, Zhang Y. Drug combinations against Borrelia burgdorferi persisters in vitro: eradication achieved by using daptomycin, cefoperazone and doxycycline. PLoS One 2015; 10: e0117207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
