<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35178733</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-765X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>74</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Letters in applied microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lett Appl Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antibacterial activity and mechanism of essential oils in combination with medium-chain fatty acids against predominant bovine mastitis pathogens.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>959</StartPage>
          <EndPage>969</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>959-969</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/lam.13675</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Bovine mastitis has become a significant economic importance for the dairy industry. Concerns regarding poor milk quality and emergence of bacterial resistance have necessitated to develop an alternative therapeutic approach to antibiotics for the treatment of mastitis. Saturated medium-chain fatty acids (MCFAs) and essential oils (EOs) are known natural antimicrobials, but their combined effect has not been investigated extensively. The objective of the present investigation was to examine the bactericidal effect of various combined treatments of eight EOs and three saturated MCFAs to inactivate predominant mastitis pathogens, including Staphylococcus aureus ATCC 29213; Escherichia coli ATCC 25922; Klebsiella pneumoniae ATCC 27736 and Streptococcus agalactiae ATCC 27956. The minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) values confirmed that all the tested pathogens were variably susceptible to both EOs and saturated MCFAs. Among essential oils, carvacrol (CAR), trans-cinnamaldehyde (TC) and thymol (TM) showed the highest inhibitory activity at concentration 0·38-1·32 mg/mL. Carvacrol exhibited effective additive antibacterial activity in combined treatment with octanoic acid (OA) in terms of its fractional inhibitory index (0·63-0·88) and time-kill effect in reducing about 6 log CFU/mL bacterial cells in less than 5 min. The effort was also made to elucidate the mechanism of antibacterial action of CAR and OA against selected mastitis pathogens by observing changes in cell microstructure, permeability and integrity of cell membrane and their membrane potential. After adding CAR and OA at MIC level, there were obvious changes in cell morphology, leakage of small electrolytes and macromolecules at the initial few hours of treatment i.e. within 1-2 h were observed. Our results indicated that CAR and OA could be evaluated as alternatives or adjuncts to antibiotics as intramammary infusion or topical application to treat bovine mastitis, significantly improving the microbiological safety of milk.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Society for Applied Microbiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sapna</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Synbiotic Functional Food and Bioremediation Research Laboratory, Dairy Microbiology Division, ICAR- National Dairy Research Institute (Deemed University), Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Verma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sunita</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Synbiotic Functional Food and Bioremediation Research Laboratory, Dairy Microbiology Division, ICAR- National Dairy Research Institute (Deemed University), Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Singh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hemlata</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Synbiotic Functional Food and Bioremediation Research Laboratory, Dairy Microbiology Division, ICAR- National Dairy Research Institute (Deemed University), Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ram</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chand</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0597-3536</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Synbiotic Functional Food and Bioremediation Research Laboratory, Dairy Microbiology Division, ICAR- National Dairy Research Institute (Deemed University), Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Lett Appl Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8510094</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0266-8254</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005227">Fatty Acids</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D009822">Oils, Volatile</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002417" MajorTopicYN="N">Cattle</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005227" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatty Acids</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008414" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mastitis, Bovine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008826" MajorTopicYN="N">Microbial Sensitivity Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009822" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oils, Volatile</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibacterial activity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibacterial mechanism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">essential oils</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mastitis pathogens</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medium-chain fatty acids</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>54</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35178733</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/lam.13675</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdalhamed, A.M., Zeedan, G.S.G. and Abou Zeina, H.A.A. (2018) Isolation and identification of bacteria causing mastitis in small ruminants and their susceptibility to antibiotics, honey, essential oils, and plant extracts. Vet World 11, 355-362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adwan, G., Abu-Shanab, B. and Adwan, K. (2010) Antibacterial activities of some plant extracts alone and in combination with different antimicrobials against multidrug-resistant Pseudomonas aeruginosa strains. Asian Pac J Trop Med 3, 266-269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad, A., Khan, A., Manzoor, N. and Khan, L.A. (2010) Evolution of ergosterol biosynthesis inhibitors as fungicidal against Candida. Microb Pathog 48, 35-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad, A. and Viljoen, A. (2015) The in vitro antimicrobial activity of Cymbopogon essential oil (lemon grass) and its interaction with silver ions. Phytomedicine 22, 657-665.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Hafi, M., El Beyrouthy, M., Ouaini, N., Stien, D., Rutledge, D. and Chaillou, S. (2016) Chemical composition and antimicrobial activity of Origanum libanoticum, Origanum ehrenbergii, and Origanum syriacum growing wild in Lebanon. Chem Biodivers 13, 555-560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bae, Y.S. and Rhee, M.S. (2019) Short-term antifungal treatments of caprylic acid with carvacrol or thymol induce synergistic 6-log reduction of pathogenic Candida albicans by cell membrane disruption and efflux pump inhibition. Cell Physiol Biochem 53, 285-300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baskaran, S.A., Kazmer, G.W., Hinckley, L., Andrew, S.M. and Venkitanarayanan, K. (2009) Antibacterial effect of plant-derived antimicrobials on major bacterial mastitis pathogens in vitro. J Dairy Sci 92, 1423-1429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batovska, D.I., Todorova, T., Tsvetkova, V. and Najdenski, H.M. (2009) Antibacterial study of the medium chain fatty acids and their 1-monoglycerides: individual effects and synergistic relationships. Pol J Microbiol 58, 43-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benbelkacema, I., Sellesc, S.M.A., Aissia, M., Khaldib, F. and Ghazib, K. (2019) In vitro assessment of antifungal and antistaphylococcal activities of Cinnamomum aromaticum essential oil against subclinical mastitis pathogens. Veterinaria 68, 31-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berenbaum, M.C. (1978) A method for testing for synergy with any number of agents. J Infect Dis 137, 122-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borges, A., Ferreira, C., Saavedra, M.J. and Simoes, M. (2013) Antibacterial activity and mode of action of ferulic and gallic acids against pathogenic bacteria. Microb Drug Resist 19, 256-265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradford, M.M. (1976) A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation of microgram quantities of protein utilizing the principle of protein-dye binding. Anal Biochem 72, 248-254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campion, A., Morrissey, R., Field, D., Cotter, P.D., Hill, C. and Ross, R.P. (2017) Use of enhanced nisin derivatives in combination with food-grade oils or citric acid to control Cronobacter sakazakii and Escherichia coli O157: H7. Food Microbial 65, 254-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Churchward, C.P., Alany, R.G. and Snyder, L.A. (2018) Alternative antimicrobials: the properties of fatty acids and monoglycerides. Crit Rev Microbiol 44, 561-570.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CLSI. (2012) Methods for dilution antimicrobial susceptibility tests for bacteria that grow aerobically; approved standard. CLSI document M07-A9. Clinical and Laboratory Standards Institute Wayne, PA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cristani, M., D’Arrigo, M., Mandalari, G., Castelli, F., Sarpietro, M.G., Micieli, D., Venuti, V., Bisignano, G. et al. (2007) Interaction of four monoterpenes contained in essential oils with model membranes: implications for their antibacterial activity. J Agric Food Chem 55, 6300-6308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhanabalan, R. (2008) In vitro phytochemical screening and antibacterial activity of aqueous and methanolic leaf extracts of Tridax procumbens against bovine mastitis isolated Staphylococcus aureus. Ethnobot Leaf 2008, 144-149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espina, L., Somolinos, M., Lorán, S., Conchello, P., García, D. and Pagán, R. (2011) Chemical composition of commercial citrus fruit essential oils and evaluation of their antimicrobial activity acting alone or in combined processes. Food Control 22, 896-902.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaare, M., Grover, C.R. and Suman, R. (2017) Combination of trans-cinnamaldehyde or eugenol with nisin for inactivation of L. monocytogenes. Indian J Dairy Sci 70, 379-385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giri, S.S., Sen, S.S., Chi, C., Kim, H.J., Yun, S., Park, S.C. and Sukumaran, V. (2015) Effect of guava leaves on the growth performance and cytokine gene expression of Labeo rohita and its susceptibility to Aeromonas hydrophila infection. Fish Shellfish Immunol 46, 217-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta, A., Cheepurupalli, L., Vigneswaran, S., Singh Rathore, S., Suma Mohan, S. and Ramakrishnan, J. (2020) In vitro and in silico investigation of caprylic acid effect on multi drug resistant (MDR) Klebsiella pneumoniae biofilm. J Biomol Struct Dyn 38, 616-624.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helander, I.M., Alakomi, H.L., Latva-Kala, K., Mattila-Sandholm, T., Pol, I., Smid, E.J., Gorris, L.G. and von Wright, A. (1998) Characterization of the action of selected essential oil components on Gram-negative bacteria. J Agric Food Chem 46, 3590-3595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyldgaard, M., Mygind, T. and Meyer, R.L. (2012) Essential oils in food preservation: mode of action, synergies, and interactions with food matrix components. Front Microbiol 3, 12-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iseppi, R., Camellini, S., Sabia, C. and Messi, P. (2020) Combined antimicrobial use of essential oils and bacteriocin bacLP17 as seafood biopreservative to control Listeria monocytogenes both in planktonic and in sessile forms. Res Microbiol 171, 351-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, S.A. and Rhee, M.S. (2016) Highly enhanced bactericidal effects of medium chain fatty acids (caprylic, capric, and lauric acid) combined with edible plant essential oils (carvacrol, eugenol, β-resorcylic acid, trans-cinnamaldehyde, thymol, and vanillin) against Escherichia coli O157: H7. Food Control 60, 447-454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamar, R.V. (1911) Chemo-immunological studies on localized infections: second paper: lysis of the Pneumococcus and hemolysis by certain fatty acids and their alkali soaps. J Exp Med 13, 380-387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert, R.J.W., Skandamis, P.N., Coote, P.J. and Nychas, G.J. (2001) A study of the minimum inhibitory concentration and mode of action of oregano essential oil, thymol and carvacrol. J Appl Microbiol 91, 453-462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Romero, J.C., Gonzalez-Rios, H., Borges, A. and Simoes, M. (2015) Antibacterial effects and mode of action of selected essential oils components against Escherichia coli and Staphylococcus aureus. Evid Based Complementary Altern Med 2015, 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Memar, M.Y., Raei, P., Alizadeh, N., Aghdam, M.A. and Kafil, H.S. (2017) Carvacrol and thymol: strong antimicrobial agents against resistant isolates. Rev Med Microbiol 28, 63-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monk, J.D., Beuchat, L.R. and Hathcox, A.K. (1996) Inhibitory effects of sucrose monolaurate, alone and in combination with organic acids, on Listeria monocytogenes and Staphylococcus aureus. J Appl Bacteriol 81, 7-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nair, M.K.M., Joy, J., Vasudevan, P., Hinckley, L., Hoagland, T.A. and Venkitanarayanan, K.S. (2005) Antibacterial effect of caprylic acid and monocaprylin on major bacterial mastitis pathogens. J Dairy Sci 88, 3488-3495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nohynek, L.J., Alakomi, H.L., Kahkonen, M.P., Heinonen, M., Helander, I.M., Oksman-Caldentey, K.M. and Puupponen-Pimia, R.H. (2006) Berry phenolics: antimicrobial properties and mechanisms of action against severe human pathogens. Nutr Cancer 54, 18-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parsons, J.B., Yao, J., Frank, M.W., Jackson, P. and Rock, C.O. (2012) Membrane disruption by antimicrobial fatty acids releases low-molecular-weight proteins from Staphylococcus aureus. J Bacteriol 194, 5294-5304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pateiro, M., Munekata, P.E.S., Sant'Ana, A.S., Domínguez, R., Rodríguez-Lázaro, D. and Lorenzo, J.M. (2020) Application of essential oils as antimicrobial agents against spoilage and pathogenic microorganisms in meat products. Int J Food Microbiol 337, 108966.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersson-Wolfe, C.S., Mullarky, I.K. and Jones, G.M. (2010) Staphylococcus aureus mastitis: cause, detection, and control. Verginia Tech 1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rani, S., Singh, H. and Ram, C. (2021) Efficacy and mechanism of carvacrol with octanoic acid against mastitis causing multi-drug-resistant pathogens. Braz J Microbiol 53, 385-399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rota, C., Carraminana, J.J., Burillo, J. and Herrera, A. (2004) In vitro antimicrobial activity of essential oils from aromatic plants against selected foodborne pathogens. J Food Prot 67, 1252-1256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlievert, P.M. and Peterson, M.L. (2012) Glycerol monolaurate antibacterial activity in broth and biofilm cultures. PLoS One 7, e40350.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeder, J. (2012) Bovine Mastitis and Milking Management. Fargo, ND: North Dakota State University.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi, C., Zhang, X., Zhao, X., Meng, R., Liu, Z., Chen, X. and Guo, N. (2017) Synergistic interactions of nisin in combination with cinnamaldehyde against Staphylococcus aureus in pasteurized milk. Food Control 71, 10-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Standards, N.C.C.L. and Barry, A.L. (1999) Methods for determining bactericidal activity of antimicrobial agents: Approved guideline. National Committee for Clinical Laboratory Standards, Wayne, PA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Vuuren, S. and Viljoen, A. (2011) Plant-based antimicrobial studies-methods and approaches to study the interaction between natural products. Planta Med 77, 1168-1182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, B.A., Garud, N.R., Feder, A.F., Assaf, Z.J. and Pennings, P.S. (2016) The population genetics of drug resistance evolution in natural populations of viral, bacterial and eukaryotic pathogens. Mol Ecol 25, 42-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Y., Liu, X., Wang, Y., Jiang, P. and Quek, S. (2016) Antibacterial activity and mechanism of cinnamon essential oil against Escherichia coli and Staphylococcus aureus. Food Control 59, 282-289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, F., Ji, B., Zhang, H., Jiang, H.U.I., Yang, Z., Li, J., Li, J. and Yan, W. (2007) The antibacterial effect of cinnamaldehyde, thymol, carvacrol and their combinations against the foodborne pathogen Salmonella typhimurium. J Food Saf 27, 124-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, J., Velliou, E. and Hong, S.H. (2020) Investigating the effects of nisin and free fatty acid combined treatment on Listeria monocytogenes inactivation. LWT 133, 110115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
