<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35171128</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-4521</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>49</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Sexually transmitted diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sex Transm Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Chlamydia trachomatis Variants Escaping Detection in the Aptima Combo 2 Assay in the United States.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>448</StartPage>
          <EndPage>452</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>448-452</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/OLQ.0000000000001617</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The Aptima Combo 2 (AC2) assay manufactured by Hologic, Inc., detects Neisseria gonorrhoeae and/or Chlamydia trachomatis (CT) in urogenital and extragenital specimens by targeting either a 16S rRNA (N. gonorrhoeae) or 23S rRNA (CT) region. In 2019, a mutation (C1515T) in the 23S rRNA region was reported to cause false-negative/equivocal results in specimens collected in Finland. Specimens containing this variant (Fl-nvCT) were also discovered internationally. Working with specimens submitted to a large commercial laboratory, we sought to determine if this variant was also present in the United States.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A subset (n = 401) of specimens tested with the AC2 assay collected during a 5-week period in late 2019/early 2020 were evaluated using an updated AC2 assay.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Although the FI-nvCT variant was not detected within this specimen panel, 2 CT variants containing 23S rRNA mutations (A1518G, G1526A) were identified. The updated AC2 assay targeting an additional region of the 23S rRNA detected both of these variants. A retrospective study of &gt;18 million AC2 results tested between 2018 and 2019 did not display a decrease in CT positivity.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although we did not detect the Fl-nvCT variant among US specimens, we show evidence that the low occurrence of similar diagnostic-escape mutants can be detected with an updated AC2 assay using multiple 23S rRNA targets.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 American Sexually Transmitted Diseases Association. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Katz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samantha S</ForeName>
            <Initials>SS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Danavall</LastName>
            <ForeName>Damien C</ForeName>
            <Initials>DC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morris</LastName>
            <ForeName>Monica R</ForeName>
            <Initials>MR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Herrod</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bridgett P</ForeName>
            <Initials>BP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dale</LastName>
            <ForeName>Suzanne E</ForeName>
            <Initials>SE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Esoteric Testing, Laboratory Corporation of America, Holdings, Burlington, NC.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melinda B</ForeName>
            <Initials>MB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Esoteric Testing, Laboratory Corporation of America, Holdings, Burlington, NC.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kersh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ellen N</ForeName>
            <Initials>EN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kirkcaldy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert D</ForeName>
            <Initials>RD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Raphael</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brian H</ForeName>
            <Initials>BH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Division of STD Prevention, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Sex Transm Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7705941</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-5717</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest and Sources of Funding: None of the authors have conflicts of interest to disclose. This publication was funded by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35171128</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/OLQ.0000000000001617</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00007435-202206000-00009</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Sexually Transmitted Disease Surveillance 2019. Atlanta, GA: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oakeshott P, Kerry S, Aghaizu A, et al. Randomised controlled trial of screening for Chlamydia trachomatis to prevent pelvic inflammatory disease: the POPI (Prevention of Pelvic Infection) trial. BMJ 2010; 340:c1642.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westrom L, Joesoef R, Reynolds G, et al. Pelvic inflammatory disease and fertility. A cohort study of 1,844 women with laparoscopically verified disease and 657 control women with normal laparoscopic results. Sex Transm Dis 1992; 19:185–192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Recommendations for the laboratory-based detection of Chlamydia trachomatis and Neisseria gonorrhoeae—2014. MMWR Recomm Rep 2014; 63:1–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rantakokko-Jalava K, Hokynar K, Hieta N, et al. Chlamydia trachomatis samples testing falsely negative in the Aptima Combo 2 test in Finland, 2019. Euro Surveill 2019; 24:1900298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hokynar K, Rantakokko-Jalava K, Hakanen A, et al. The Finnish new variant of Chlamydia trachomatis with a single nucleotide polymorphism in the 23S rRNA target escapes detection by the Aptima Combo 2 Test. Microorganisms 2019; 7:227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unemo M, Hansen M, Hadad R, et al. Finnish new variant of Chlamydia trachomatis escaping detection in the Aptima Combo 2 assay also present in Orebro County, Sweden, May 2019. Euro Surveill 2019; 24:1900370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadad R, Jensen JS, Westh H, et al. A Chlamydia trachomatis 23S rRNA G1523A variant escaping detection in the Aptima Combo 2 assay (Hologic) was widespread across Denmark in July–September 2019. APMIS 2020; 128:440–444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansen TB, Klovstad H, Rykkvin R, et al. The ‘Finnish new variant of Chlamydia trachomatis’ escaping detection in the Aptima Combo 2 assay is widespread across Norway, June to August 2019. Euro Surveill 2019; 24:1900592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts DJ, Davis GS, Cole MJ, et al. Prevalence of new variants of Chlamydia trachomatis escaping detection by the Aptima Combo 2 assay, England, June to August 2019. Euro Surveill 2019; 24:1900557.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cole MJ, Davis GS, Fifer H, et al. No widespread dissemination of Chlamydia trachomatis diagnostic-escape variants and the impact of Neisseria gonorrhoeae positivity on the Aptima Combo 2 assay. Sex Transm Infect 2021; sextrans-2021-054988. doi: 10.1136/sextrans-2021-054988.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/sextrans-2021-054988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unemo M, Hansen M, Hadad R, et al. Sensitivity, specificity, inclusivity and exclusivity of the updated Aptima Combo 2 assay, which provides detection coverage of the new diagnostic-escape Chlamydia trachomatis variants. BMC Infect Dis 2020; 20:419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Team RC. The R Project for Statistical Computing. R version 4.1.2. 2019. Available at: https://www.R-project.org/.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodson EN, Katz SS, Mosley SS, et al. Use of real-time PCR as an alternative to conventional genotyping methods for the laboratory detection of lymphogranuloma venereum (LGV). Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis 2021; 101:115532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ripa T, Nilsson P. A variant of Chlamydia trachomatis with deletion in cryptic plasmid: implications for use of PCR diagnostic tests. Euro Surveill 2006; 11:E061109.2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soderblom T, Blaxhult A, Fredlund H, et al. Impact of a genetic variant of Chlamydia trachomatis on national detection rates in Sweden. Euro Surveill 2006; 11:E061207.1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Won H, Ramachandran P, Steece R, et al. Is there evidence of the new variant Chlamydia trachomatis in the United States?Sex Transm Dis 2013; 40:352–353.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
