<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35183232</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Trials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effect of Tai Chi combined with Kinesio taping on posture control of football players with FAI: protocol for a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>162</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>162</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">162</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-022-06083-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Functional ankle instability (FAI) of college football players is an important risk factor affecting their training and competition. Physical therapy and appropriate sports intervention can improve the stability of FAI patients. Previous studies have shown that Tai Chi (TC) and Kinesio taping (KT) can improve the posture control ability of FAI patients. However, whether Tai Chi combined with Kinesio taping effect patch can be used as an effective exercise for rehabilitation of college football players with FAI is not yet proven.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS/DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Fifty-three FAI college football players were randomly assigned to 3 groups: TC+KT (n = 20); TC+KTp (placebo Kinesio taping, KTp, placebo) (n = 17), and KT (n = 16). The TC+KT group received TC and KT functional correction technical intervention, the TC+KTp group received TC and placebo KT technical intervention, and the KT group received KT functional correction technical intervention. Each of the three groups received 30 min each time, 3 times a week, for a total of 6 weeks of intervention training. Star Excursion Balance Test (SEBT) and UniPedal Stance Test (UST) at baseline (before), 4 weeks after intervention (middle), and 6 weeks after intervention (after) and Toe Touch Test (TTT) were evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">For the first time in this trial, the impact will be evaluated. If the results are the same as expected, they will provide evidence that Tai Chi combined with Kinesio taping sticking intervention can promote the posture control of college football players with FAI.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry ChiCTR1900027253 . Registered on 6 November 2019.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Youhua</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xingyue</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Capital University of Physical Education And Sports, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Luo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiwen</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Sport, School of Teacher Education, Taizhou University, Taizhou, Zhejiang, China. 83391901@qq.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chunjie</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beijing Sport University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn">
          <RefSource>Trials. 2022 Apr 25;23(1):351</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">35468864</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055052" MajorTopicYN="Y">Athletic Tape</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005538" MajorTopicYN="Y">Football</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007593" MajorTopicYN="Y">Joint Instability</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004856" MajorTopicYN="N">Postural Balance</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D026302" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tai Ji</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ankle joint</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Balance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Functional ankle instability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kinesio taping</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Posture control</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tai Chi</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>26</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35183232</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8858540</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-022-06083-5</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-022-06083-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hägglund M, Waldén M, Ekstrand J. Injuries among male and female elite football Players. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;19:819–827.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18980604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noya JS, Gómez-Carmona PM, Moliner-Urdiales D. An examination of injuries in Spanish professional soccer league. J Sports Med Phys fitness. 2014;54:765–771.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25350033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dvorak J, Junge A. Football injuries and physical symptoms: a review of the literature. Am J Sports Med. 2000;28:3–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11032101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain TK, Wauneka CN, Liu W. The effect of balance training on ankle proprioception in patients with functional ankle instability. J Foot Ankle Res. 2014;7:A37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walls RJ, Ross KA, Fraser EJ, Hodgkins CW, Smyth NA, Egan CJ, Kennedy JG. Football injuries of the ankle: a review of injury mechanisms, diagnosis and management. World J Orthop. 2016;7:8–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716575</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26807351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>BeBeynnon BD, MurPhy DF, Alosa DM. Predictive factors for lateral ankle sprains: a literature review. J Athl Train. 2002;37:376–380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164368</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hale SA, Hertel J. Reliability and sensitivity of the foot and ankle disability index in subjects with chronic ankle instability. J Athl Training. 2005;40:35–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1088343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15902322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayala F, Calderón-López A, Delgado-Gosálbez JC, et al.  Acute effects of three neuromuscular warm- up strategies on several Physical Performance measures in football Players. Plos ONE. 2017;12:e0169660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5218464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28060927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steib S, Pfeifer K. Sensorimotor deficits in functional ankle instability. Z fur Orthopadie und Unfallchirurgie. 2015;153:253–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26008756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grooms DR, Palmer T, Onate JA, et al.  Soccer-specific warm up and lower extremity injury rates in collegiate male soccer players. J Athl Train. 2013;48:782–789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3867089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23848519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rössler R, Donath L, Bizzini M, et al.  A new injury prevention programme for children’s football - FIFA 11+ kids - can improve motor performance: a cluster- randomised controlled trial. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:549–556.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26508531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang PY, Jankaew A, Lin CF. Effects of plyometric and balance training on neuromuscular control of recreational athletes with functional ankle instability: a randomized controlled laboratory study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18:5269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8156931</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34063454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elshemy SA, Battecha KH. Kinesio taping versus proprioceptive training on dynamic position sense of the ankle and eversion to inversion strength ratios in children with functional ankle instability. Med J Cairo Univ. 2013;81:61–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanci E, Sekir U, Gur H, et al.  Eccentric training improves ankle evertor and dorsiflexor strength and proprioception in functionally unstable ankles. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2016;95:448–458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26745222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ha SY, Han JH, Sung YH. Effects of ankle strengthening exercise program on an unstable supporting surface on proprioception and balance in adults with functional ankle instability. J Exerc Rehabil. 2018;14:301–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5931169</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz-Diaz D, Lomas-Vega R, Osuna-Perez MC, Contreras FH, Martinez-Amat A. Effects of 6 weeks of balance training on chronic ankle instability in athletes: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Sports Med. 2015;36:754–760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim KJ. Impact of combined muscle strength and proprioceptive exercises on functional ankle instability. J Int Acad phys Ther Res. 2013;2013(4):600–604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed AF. Effect of sensorimotor training on joint proprioception and isokinetic strength ratios in subjects with unilateral functional ankle instability. Bull Faculty Phys Ther. 2010;15:25–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ho YH, Lin CF, Chang CH. Effect of ankle Kinesio taping on vertical jump with run-up and countermovement jump in athletes with ankle functional instability. J Physic Ther Sci. 2015;27:2087–2090.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26311931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilic BB, Yildiz S, Sahinkaya T. The effects of Kinesio tape application on functional performance measurements in young female basketball players with chronic ankle instability. J Sports Sci. 2017;5:206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim H. The effect of prolonged use of ankle Kinesio taping on dynamic balance and functional performance tests in people with chronic ankle instability. Master's Thesis at The University of Nebraska at Omaha. 2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Fu W, Pan J, Wang L, Xia R, Liu Y. Acute effects of Kinesio taping on muscle strength and fatigue in the forearm of tennis Players. J Sci Med Sport / Sports Med Aust. 2016;19:459–464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26229044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magalhaes I, Bottaro M, Freitas JR, Carmo J, Matheus JP, Carregaro R. L:Prolonged use of Kinesio taping does not enhance functional performance and joint proprioception in healthy young males: randomized controlled trial. Braz J Phys Ther. 2016;20:213–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4946837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27437712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen CH, Huang TS, Chai HM, Jan MH, Lin J. Two stretching treatments for the hamstrings: proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation versus Kinesio taping. J Sport Rehabil. 2013;22:59–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23069636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Almeida Lins CA, Neto FL, de Amorim ABC, de Brito Macedo L, Brasileiro J. S: Kinesio Taping® does not alter neuromuscular performance of femoral quadriceps or lower limb function in healthy subjects: randomized, blind, controlled, clinical trial. Man Ther. 2013;18:41–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22796389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ly K, Michaud L, Lajoie Y. The effects of Kinesiology tape on static postural control in individuals with functional ankle instability. Phys Ther Sport. 2021;48:146–153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33486407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu D. Effect of tai chi exercise on proprioception of ankle and knee joints in old People. Br J Sports Med. 2004;38:50–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1724726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14751946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li F, Harmer P, Fisher KJ, et al.  Tai Chi and fall reductions in older adults: a randomized controlled trial. J Erontology. 2005;60:187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15814861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fong SM, Ng GY. The effects on sensorimotor performance and balance with Tai Chi training. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2006;87:80–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16401443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jun-Hong Y, Wan-Jie G, Jian S. Efficacy of Tai Chi on pain, stiffness and function in patients with osteoarthritis: A Meta-Analysis. Plos ONE. 2013;8:e61672.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23620778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G* Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175–191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delahunt E, Coughlan GF, Caulfield B, et al.  Inclusion criteria when investigating insufficiencies in chronic ankle instability. Med Sci SPort Exer. 2010;42:2106–2121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kase K, Wallis J, Kase T. Clinical therapeutic applications of the Kinesio taping method. Albuquerque: Kinesio Taping Asso; 2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Iglesias J, Fernandez-de-Las-Penas C, Cleland JA, Huijbregts P, Del Rosario Gutierrez-Vega M. Short-term effects of cervical Kinesio taping on pain and cervical range of motion in patients with acute whiplash injury: a randomized clinical trial. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2009;39:515–521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19574662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bravi R, Cohen EJ, Quarta E, Martinelli A, Minciacchi D. Effect of direction and tension of Kinesio taping application on sensorimotor coordination. Int J Sports Med. 2016;37:909–914.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27454132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konradsen L, Voigt M, Hojsgaard C. Ankle inversion injuries. The role of the dynamic defense mechanism. Am J Sports Med. 1997;25:54–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9006692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawood RS, Kattabei OM, Nasef SA, Battarjee KA, Abdelraouf O. R: Effectiveness of Kinesio taping versus cervical traction on mechanical neck dysfunction. Int J Rehabil Res. 2013;2:1–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu D. 24-style Taijiquan introduction and improvement. Taiyuan: Shanxi Science and Technology Press; 2001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Q, Huang L, Xie W, Lin W, Zhang Y, Min F. Effects of tai ji quan training on gait kinematics in older Chinese women with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. J Sport Health Sci. 2016;5:297–303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6188600</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30356529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kinzey SJ, Armstrong C. W: The reliability of the star-excursion test in assessing dynamic balance. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 1998;27:356–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9580895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olmsted LC, Carcia CR, Hertel J. Efficacy of the Star Excursion Balance Tests in detecting reach deficits in subjects with chronic ankle instability. J Athl Train. 2003;37:501–506.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC164384</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12937574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plisky PJ, Rauh MJ, Kaminski TW, Underwood FB. Star excursion balance test as a Predictor of lower extremity injury in high school basketball Players. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2006;36:911–919.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17193868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Springer BA, Marin R, Cyhan T, Roberts H, Gill NW. Normative values for the unipedal stance test with eyes open and closed. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2007;30:8–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19839175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayala F, Sainz de Baranda P, De Ste Croix M, Santonja F. Absolute reliability of five clinical tests for assessing hamstring flexibility in Professional futsal Players. J Sci Med SPort / SPorts Med Aust. 2012;15:142–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22104651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J.  Statistical Power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Academic Press: Routledge; 2013. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qaseem A, Wilt TJ, McLean RM. Noninvasive treatments for acute, subacute, and chronic low back pain:a clinical practice guideline from the American College of Physicians. Ann Intern Med. 2017;166:514–530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28192789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Guideline Centre (UK). Low Back Pain and Sciatica in Over 16s: Assessment and Management. London: National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE); 2016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27929617</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stochkendahl MJ, Kjaer P, Hartvigsen J. National Clinical Guidelines for non-surgical treatment of patients with recent onset low back pain or lumbar radiculopathy. Eur Spine J. 2018;27:60–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28429142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C, Schmid CH, Rones R. A randomized trial of Tai Chi for fibromyalgia. New Engl J Med. 2010;363:743–754.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20818876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li F, Harmer P, Fitzgerald K. Tai Chi and postural stability in patients with Parkinson’s disease. New Engl J Med. 2012;366:511–519.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3285459</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22316445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung PH, Lin GL, Liu C. The effects of Tai Chi Chuan combined with vibration training on balance control and lower extremity muscle power. J Sports Sci Med. 2013;12:19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3761759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24149721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hallisy KM. Tai Chi beyond balance and fall prevention: health benefits and its potential role in combatting social isolation in the aging population. Curr Geriatr Rep. 2018;7:1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen EW, Fu AS, Chan KM. The effects of Tai Chi on the balance control of elderly persons with visual impairment: a randomized clinical trial. Age Ageing. 2012;41:254–263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22180415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz-Díaz D, Kim KM, Hita-Contreras F. Effects of a twelve-week Tai Chi intervention in patients with chronic ankle instability: a randomized controlled trial. J Sport Rehabil. 2019;29:1–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30747567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kase K, Wallis J, Kase T.  Clinical therapeutic applications of the Kinesio taping method. 2. Tokyo, JaPan: Ken Ikai Co. Ltd; 2003. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inglés M, Serra-Añó P, Méndez ÀG, Zarzoso M, Aguilar-Rodríguez M, Suso-Martí L, Cuenca-Martínez F, Gemma V. EsPí-LóPez: Effect of Kinesio taping and balance exercises on postural control in amateur soccer players: a randomised control trial. J Sports Sci. 2019;37:2853–2862.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31613172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kodesh E, Dar G. The effect of Kinesio tape on dynamic balance following muscle fatigue in individuals with chronic ankle instability. Res Sports Med (print) 2015;23:367–378.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26279271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen CH, Huang TS, Chai HM. Two stretching treatments for the hamstrings: proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation versus Kinesio taping. J Sport Rehabil. 2013;22:59–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23069636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang H-Y, Chou K-Y, Lin J-J, Lin C-F, Wang C-H. Immediate effect of forearm Kinesio taping on maximal grip strength and force sense in healthy collegiate athletes. Phys Ther Sport. 2010;11(4):122–127.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21055705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosik KB, Mccann RS, Terada M. Therapeutic interventions for improving self-reported unction in patients with chronic ankle instability: a systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2017;51:105–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27806951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
