<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35180045</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1087-2981</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medical education online</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Med Educ Online</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Student video production within health professions education: A scoping review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2040349</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2040349</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2040349</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/10872981.2022.2040349</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recent technological developments have influenced a shift in the use of videos in Health Professions Education (HPE). Rather than casting students in the role of observers of videos, educators have been asking students to produce videos as a learning activity. The assumption is that video production is often an active and collaborative exercise, therefore could engage students and enhance learning. However, applications of this emerging pedagogical approach vary, and there has not been a knowledge synthesis to guide future research and practice.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">With a view to mapping existing knowledge, identifying avenues for further research, and informing practice, we conducted a scoping review to establish current understanding of video production in HPE. We undertook a literature search of seven databases and identified thirty-six studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The findings showed considerable variation in purposes and implementation approaches, consequences and challenges associated with video production. In particular, the assumption that creating a video automatically promotes student engagement was not well supported, especially when the intended learning was not made apparent to students.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Overall, the review suggests that despite the increasing adoption of video production in HPE, the purposes are often unclear; pedagogical considerations underlying project design are limited, which risks undermining the intended learning. To optimise educational benefits, future video production projects should be explicit in their intention and approach, draw upon pedagogical theories, anticipate and address implementation issues, and be robust in their formative and summative assessment processes. Future research should more explicitly show the relationship between the intended learning and the underlying pedagogy and thoroughly evaluate the effectiveness and feasibility of video production projects.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1412-0615</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Higher Education Development Centre, University of Otago, Dunedin, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Geertshuis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Susan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9417-572X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Management and International Business, University of Auckland, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gladman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tehmina</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5112-3460</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Education Unit, University of Otago, Wellington, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Grainger</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9201-8678</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Education Unit, University of Otago, Wellington, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Med Educ Online</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9806550</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1087-2981</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006281" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Occupations</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007858" MajorTopicYN="Y">Learning</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Student</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">creation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health professions education</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">production</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scoping review</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">video</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35180045</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8865118</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10872981.2022.2040349</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colonnello V, Mattarozzi K, Agostini A, et al. Emotionally salient patient information enhances the educational value of surgical videos. Adv Health Sci Educ. 2020;25:1–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31960188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karic B, Moino V, Nolin A, et al. Evaluation of surgical educational videos available for third year medical students. Med Educ Online. 2020;25(1):1714197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6968551</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31920174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valdez CA, Paulsen S.. 
Design and implementation of a video-based clinical examination. Med Educ Online. 2007;12(1):4468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28253097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snelson C. Video production in content-area pedagogy: a scoping study of the research literature. Learn Media Technol. 2018;43(3):294–306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omar H, Khan SA, Toh CG. Structured Student-generated videos for first-year students at a dental school in Malaysia. J Dent Educ. 2013;77(5):640–647.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23658411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearney M, Schuck S. Spotlight on authentic learning: student developed digital video projects. Aust J Educat Technol. 2006;22(2). DOI:10.14742/ajet.1298</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14742/ajet.1298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jorm C, Roberts C, Gordon C, et al. Time for university educators to embrace student videography. Cambridge J Educat. 2019;49:673–693.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shuldman M, Tajik M. The role of media/video production in non-media disciplines: the case of health promotion. Learn Media Technol. 2010;35(3):357–362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McQueen S, McKinnon V, VanderBeek L, et al. Video-based assessment in surgical education: a scoping review. J Surg Educ. 2019;76(6):1645–1654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwan K, Wu C, Duffy D, et al. Lights, camera, surgery: a novel pilot project to engage medical students in the development of pediatric surgical learning resources. J Pediatr Surg. 2011;46(5):962–965.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21616261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Gagne JC, Kim SS, Schoen ER, et al. Assessing the impact of video-based assignments on health professions students’ social presence on web: case study. JMIR Med Educ. 2018;4(2):e11390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6288589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30478027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro D, Tomasa L, Koff NA. Patients as teachers, medical students as filmmakers: the video slam, a pilot study. Acad Med. 2009;84(9):1235–1243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19707063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniel M, Gordon M, Patricio M, et al. An update on developments in medical education in response to the COVID-19 pandemic: a BEME scoping review: BEME guide no. 64. Med Teach. 2021;43(3):253–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33496628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi B, Jegatheeswaran L, Minocha A, et al. The impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on final year medical students in the UK: a national survey. BMC Med Educ. 2020;20(1):1–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323883</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32600460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas A, Lubarsky S, Durning SJ, et al. Knowledge syntheses in medical education: demystifying scoping reviews. Acad Med. 2017;92(2):161–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27782918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munn Z, Peters MD, Stern C, et al. Systematic review or scoping review? Guidance for authors when choosing between a systematic or scoping review approach. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6245623</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30453902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arksey H, O’Malley L. Scoping studies: towards a methodological framework. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2005;8(1):19–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levac D, Colquhoun H, O’Brien KK. Scoping studies: advancing the methodology. Implement Sci. 2010;5(1):69.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954944</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med. 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tricco AC, Lillie E, Zarin W, et al. PRISMA extension for scoping reviews (PRISMA-ScR): checklist and explanation. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(7):467–473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouzzani M, Hammady H, Fedorowicz Z, et al. Rayyan—a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2016;5(1):210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5139140</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeBourgh GA, Prion SK. Student-directed video validation of psychomotor skills performance: a strategy to facilitate deliberate practice, peer review, and team skill sets. Int J Nurs Educ Scholarsh. 2017;14(1):22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28343165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decloedt EH, van Schalkwyk S. Students shooting videos to learn pharmacology. Clin Teach. 2019;16(5):490–496.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarabi N. Nursing students’ experiences from two methods of teaching: film preparation and demonstration of physical examinations. Int J Pharm Phytopharmacological Res. 2019;9(2):14–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frenzel JE, Skoy ET, Eukel HN. Using student produced videos to increase knowledge of self-care topics and nonprescription medications. Curr Pharm Teach Learn. 2013;5(1):44–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green B, Hope A. Promoting clinical competence using social media. Nurse Educ. 2010;35(3):127–129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20410751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terregino CA, and Saks NS. Creative group performances to assess core competencies in a first-year patient-centered medicine course. Med Educ Online. 2010;15(1):1–4. doi:10.3402/meo.v15i0.4879.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3402/meo.v15i0.4879</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2824498</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20174597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smallheer BA, Stone E, Hicks J, et al. Use of video recording to facilitate peer-to-peer learning in a prelicensure nursing program. Teach Learn Nurs. 2017;12(2):158–160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hinck G, Bergmann T. Video capture on student-owned mobile devices to facilitate psychomotor skills acquisition: a feasibility study. J Chiropr Educ. 2013;27(2):158–162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3791909</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23957324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ericsson KA, Krampe RT, Tesch-Römer C. The role of deliberate practice in the acquisition of expert performance. Psychol Rev. 1993;100(3):363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sterling-Fox C, Smith JP, Gariando O, et al. Nursing skills video selfies: an innovative teaching and learning strategy for undergraduate nursing students to master psychomotor skills. Sage Open Nurs. 2020;6:2377960820934090.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7774365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33415287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira J, Echeazarra L, Sanz-Santamaría S, et al. Student-generated online videos to develop cross-curricular and curricular competencies in Nursing studies. Comput Hum Behav. 2014;31:580–590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nascimento GP, Moreira DC, Welker AF. A controlled study on an instrument that couples active learning with technology: student video creation. F1000Res. 2019;8(1107):1107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bilge A, Palabiyik O. The effect of short films about mental health and disorders on preventing stigmatization in nursing education. Arch Psychiatr Nurs. 2017;31(1):88–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28104066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lockeman KS, Lanning SK, Dow AW, et al. Outcomes of introducing early learners to interprofessional competencies in a classroom setting. Teach Learn Med. 2017;29(4):433–443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28281832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unterseher L. Social marketing campaigns as a teaching strategy for health promotion. Nurs Educ Perspect. 2018;40(6):381–383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29994893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haines SL, Van Amburgh JA. A vidcasting project to promote the pharmacist’s role in public health. Am J Pharm Educ. 2010;74(6):97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21045939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krull H. Video project brings new life to community engagement. J Nurs Educ. 2013;52(8):480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23909565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jorm C, Nisbet G, Roberts C, et al. Using complexity theory to develop a student-directed interprofessional learning activity for 1220 healthcare students. BMC Med Educ. 2016;16:199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4977619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27502773</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhardt SJ, Clark JE, Kelly WN, et al. Active-learning strategies for legal topics and substance abuse in a pharmacy curriculum. Am J Pharm Educ. 2017;81(1):4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5339590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green CA, Kim EH, O’Sullivan PS, et al. Using technological advances to improve surgery curriculum: experience with a mobile application. J Surg Educ. 2018;75(4):1087–1095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29397357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green CA, Vaughn CJ, Wyles SM, et al. Evaluation of a surgery-based adjunct course for senior medical students entering surgical residencies. J Surg Educ. 2016;73(4):631–638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27168383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McIntosh C, Patterson J, Miller S. First year midwifery students’ experience with self-recorded and assessed video of selected midwifery practice skills at Otago polytechnic in New Zealand. Nurse Educ Pract. 2018;28:54–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28950150</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sorenson DS, Dieter C. From beginning to end: video-based introductory, instructional, and evaluation applications. Nurse Educ. 2005;30(1):40–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15685025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenkoetter MM, Smith D, Stachura ME, et al. Video analysis tool system: implementation and evaluation of use with clinical nursing assessments of older adults. Nurs Adm Q. 2014;38(4):E11–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25208159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baharav E. Students’ use of video clip technology in clinical education. Top Lang Disord. 2008;28(3):286–298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gill P, Kitney L, Kozan D, et al. Online learning in paediatrics: a student-led web-based learning modality. Clin Teach. 2010;7(1):53–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21134144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos-Rincón JM, Belinchón-Romero I, Sánchez-Ferrer F, et al. The reach of Spanish-language YouTube videos on physical examinations made by undergraduate medical students. J Educ Eval Health Prof. 2017;14:31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5801321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29278903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wever GS, Elliott I, McCaul J, et al. Viewership footprint for a low-resource, student-centred collaborative video platform to teach orthopaedics in Southern Africa. SAMJ S Afr Med J. 2020;110(6):532–536.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodríguez-Almagro J, MdC P-L, Hernández-Martínez A, et al. The impact on nursing students of creating audiovisual material through digital storytelling as a teaching method. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(2):694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7831018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33467398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maloney S, Paynter S, Storr M, et al. Implementing student self‐video of performance. Clin Teach. 2013;10(5):323–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24015739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein I, Bertram M. Using students’ smartphones to learn a nursing skill: students’ perspectives. J Nurs Educ Pract. 2019;9(5):24–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallace H, VanderMolen J. Teaching health education through the development of student centered video assignment. Front Public Health. 2019;7:312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6839524</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31737592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weathers E. A creative teaching method for research and evidence-based practice. Nurs Educ Perspect. 2021;42(1):53–55. doi:10.1097/01.NEP.0000000000000539.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.NEP.0000000000000539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31306358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans C, Kandiko Howson C, Forsythe A. Making sense of learning gain in higher education. Higher Educ Pedagog. 2018;3(1):1–45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogrinc G, Armstrong GE, Dolansky MA, et al. SQUIRE-EDU (Standards for quality improvement reporting excellence in education): publication guidelines for educational improvement. Acad Med. 2019;94(10):1461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6760810</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30998575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clandinin DJ. Personal practical knowledge: a study of teachers’ classroom images. Curric Inq. 1985;15(4):361–385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips AC, Lewis LK, McEvoy MP, et al. Development and validation of the guideline for reporting evidence-based practice educational interventions and teaching (GREET). BMC Med Educ. 2016;16(1):1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5011880</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27599967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Jong T. Cognitive load theory, educational research, and instructional design: some food for thought. Instructional Sci. 2010;38(2):105–134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggs J. Enhancing teaching through constructive alignment. Higher Educ. 1996;32(3):347–364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bates R. A critical analysis of evaluation practice: the Kirkpatrick model and the principle of beneficence. Eval Program Plann. 2004;27(3):341–347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gladman T, Gallagher S, and Ali A. MUSIC® for medical students: confirming the reliability and validity of a multi-factorial measure of academic motivation for medical education. Teach Learn Med. 2020;32(5):495–507. doi:10.1080/10401334.2020.1758704.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10401334.2020.1758704</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32369397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harland T, McLean A, Wass R, et al. An assessment arms race and its fallout: high-stakes grading and the case for slow scholarship. Assess Eval Higher Educ. 2015;40(4):528–541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
