<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35187695</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2230</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>20</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical and experimental dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor-associated cutaneous eruptions: a retrospective observational study.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ced.15144</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Dipeptidyl peptidase (DPP)-4 plays a complex role in immune regulation and its inhibition can have effects on the pathogenesis of various skin diseases. Studies have shown that DPP-4 inhibitors are associated with an increased risk of bullous pemphigoid (BP).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To analyse the clinical and histopathological features of cutaneous adverse events in patients on DPP-4 inhibitors.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We performed a retrospective review of patients with suspected DPP-4 inhibitor-associated cutaneous adverse events, at a tertiary teaching hospital from 1 January 2017 to 31 December 2020. Exclusion criteria included previous history of chronic skin disease and lack of histopathological reports or follow-up records. The clinical characteristics, latency period, Naranjo Adverse Drug Reaction Probability Scale and clinical outcomes were evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In total, 18 patients (10 men, 8 women; mean age 68.6 years, range 38-89 years) were included. The DPP-4 inhibitors used were teneligliptin (n = 6), vildagliptin (n = 6), sitagliptin (n = 4), linagliptin (n = 1) and saxagliptin (n = 1). The mean interval between therapy initiation and lesion onset was 8.8 months (range 1-24 months). The dermatoses noted were BP (n = 12; 66.6%), lichenoid dermatitis (n = 4; 22.2%), psoriasiform dermatitis (n = 1; 5.6%) and spongiotic dermatitis (n = 1; 5.6%). Eight patients (44.4%) had necrotic keratinocytes as one of the distinct histological features. Causality assessment using the Naranjo scale rated the causative role of DPP-4 inhibitors as 'possible' in all patients. Of the 18 patients, 11 (61.1%) noted improvement in their condition following discontinuation of DPP-4 inhibitors, with 5 having complete remission within 6 months of stopping the drug.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">DPP-4 inhibitor-associated dermatoses are not necessarily limited to BP. It is necessary to recognize the possibility of other dermatoses in patients on DPP-4 inhibitors as drug substitution/cessation may improve disease morbidity.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 British Association of Dermatologists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Duraisamy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Prasanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8133-8799</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Amrita Institute of Medical Sciences, Kochi, Kerala, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jagadeesan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Soumya</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Amrita Institute of Medical Sciences, Kochi, Kerala, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eapen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Malini</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Amrita Institute of Medical Sciences, Kochi, Kerala, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thomas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jacob</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Amrita Institute of Medical Sciences, Kochi, Kerala, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Exp Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7606847</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0307-6938</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35187695</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ced.15144</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deacon CF. Physiology and pharmacology of DPP-4 in glucose homeostasis and the treatment of type 2 diabetes. Front Endocrinol 2019; 10: 80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel PM, Jones VA, Kridin K et al. The role of dipeptidyl peptidase-4 in cutaneous disease. Exp Dermatol 2021; 30: 304-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang W, Cai X, Zhang S et al. Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor treatment and the risk of bullous pemphigoid and skin-related adverse events: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 2021; 37: e3391.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffmann P, Bentley P, Sahota P et al. Vascular origin of vildagliptin-induced skin effects in Cynomolgus monkeys: pathomechanistic role of peripheral sympathetic system and neuropeptide Y. Toxicol Pathol 2014; 42: 684-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mas-Vidal A, Santos-Juanes J, Esteve-Martinez A et al. Psoriasiform eruption triggered by a dipeptidyl peptidase IV inhibitor. Australas J Dermatol 2012; 53: 70-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yıldız İ, Gen R, Batmaz L et al. Localized painful rash induced by linagliptin in a patient with type 2 diabetes. İstanbul Med J 2019; 20: 253-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stricklin SM, Stoecker WV, Rader RK et al. Persistent edematous-plaque photosensitivity observed with sitagliptin phosphate (Januvia®). Dermatol Online J 2012; 18: 9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka K, Ogawa Y, Shimada S. Drug eruption caused by sitagliptin, a dipeptidyl peptidase-IV inhibitor. J Dermatol 2012; 39: 726-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtani A, Takenaka Y, Ishiguro N et al. Case of lichen planus induced by sitagliptin phosphate hydrate. J Dermatol 2017; 44: 1081-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Someili A, Azzam K, Hilal MA. Linagliptin-associated alopecia and bullous pemphigoid. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med 2019; 6: 1207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sankar P, Jagadeesan S, Ahmed WN. Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor (vildagliptin) induced oral mucositis: a case report. Diabetes Metab Syndr 2021; 15: 509-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SG, Lee HJ, Yoon MS et al. Association of dipeptidyl peptidase 4 inhibitor use with risk of bullous pemphigoid in patients with diabetes. JAMA Dermatol 2019; 155: 172-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kridin K, Cohen AD. Dipeptidyl-peptidase IV inhibitor-associated bullous pemphigoid: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Acad Dermatol 2021; 85: 501-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chijiwa C, Takeoka S, Kamata M et al. Decrease in eosinophils infiltrating into the skin of patients with dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor-related bullous pemphigoid. J Dermatol 2018; 45: 596-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Izumi K, Nishie W, Mai Y et al. Autoantibody profile differentiates between inflammatory and noninflammatory bullous pemphigoid. J Invest Dermatol 2016; 136: 2201-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plaquevent M, Tétart F, Fardet L et al. Higher frequency of dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor intake in bullous pemphigoid patients than in the French general population. J Invest Dermatol 2019; 139: 835-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patsatsi A, Kyriakou A, Meltzanidou P et al. Βullous pemphigoid in patients with DPP-4 inhibitors at the onset of disease: does this differ from common bullous pemphigoid? Eur J Dermatol 2018; 28: 711-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarro-Triviño FJ, Lopez Gomez J, Pleguezuelos RFM et al. Pemphigoid lichen planus consequential to vildagliptin: a rare variant of bullous pemphigoid? Int J Dermatol 2020; 59: e1-e3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weyers W, Metze D. Histopathology of drug eruptions - general criteria, common patterns, and differential diagnosis. Dermatol Pract Concept 2011; 1: 33-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hussein MR. Drug-induced skin reactions: a pathologist viewpoint. Cutan Ocul Toxicol 2016; 35: 67-79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerl K. Histopathological patterns indicative of distinct adverse drug reactions. Adverse Cutan Drug Erupt 2012; 97: 61-78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
