<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35194860</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1360-0443</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>22</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Addiction (Abingdon, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Addiction</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparative efficacy and safety of pharmacotherapies for alcohol withdrawal: a systematic review and network meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/add.15853</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">There have been few head-to-head clinical trials of pharmacotherapies for alcohol withdrawal (AW). We, therefore, aimed to evaluate the comparative performance of pharmacotherapies for AW.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Six databases were searched for randomized clinical trials through November 2021. Trials were included after a blinded review by two independent reviewers. Outcomes included incident seizures, delirium tremens, AW severity scores, adverse events, dropouts, dropouts from adverse events, length of hospital stay, use of additional medications, total benzodiazepine requirements, and death. Effect sizes were pooled using frequentist random-effects network meta-analysis models to generate summary ORs and Cohen's d standardized mean differences (SMDs).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Across the 149 trials, there were 10 692 participants (76% male, median 43.5 years old). AW severity spanned mild (n = 32), moderate (n = 51), and severe (n = 66). Fixed-schedule chlormethiazole (OR, 0.16; 95% CI, 0.04-0.65), fixed-schedule diazepam (OR, 0.16; 95% CI, 0.04-0.59), fixed-schedule lorazepam (OR = 0.19; 95% CI, 0.08-0.45), fixed-schedule chlordiazepoxide (OR = 0.21; 95% CI, 0.08-0.53), and divalproex (OR = 0.22; 95% CI, 0.05-0.86) were superior to placebo at reducing incident AW seizures. However, only fixed-schedule diazepam (OR, 0.19; 95% CI, 0.05-0.76) reduced incident delirium tremens. Oxcarbazepine (d = -3.69; 95% CI, -6.21 to -1.17), carbamazepine (d = -2.76; 95% CI, -4.13 to -1.40), fixed-schedule oxazepam (d = -2.55; 95% CI, -4.26 to -0.83), and γ-hydroxybutyrate (d = -1.80; 95% CI, -3.35 to -0.26) improved endpoint Clinical Institute Withdrawal Assessment for Alcohol-Revised scores over placebo. Promazine and carbamazepine were the only agents significantly associated with greater dropouts because of adverse events. The quality of evidence was downgraded because of the substantial risk of bias, heterogeneity, inconsistency, and imprecision.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Although some pharmacotherapeutic modalities, particularly benzodiazepines, appear to be safe and efficacious for reducing some measures of alcohol withdrawal, methodological issues and a high risk of bias prevent a consistent estimate of their comparative performance.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Society for the Study of Addiction.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bahji</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anees</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3490-314X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>British Columbia Centre for Substance Use, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bach</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paxton</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2413-9133</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>British Columbia Centre for Substance Use, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Danilewitz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marlon</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ontario Shores Centre for Mental Health Sciences, Whitby, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Crockford</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>El-Guebaly</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nady</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Devoe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName>
            <Initials>DJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Saitz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Richard</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2535-1427</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, School of Public Health, Boston University School of Public Health, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Boston University School of Medicine and Boston Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Translational Science Institute, Boston University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Addiction</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9304118</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0965-2140</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alcohol use disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">comparative effectiveness</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">withdrawal</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>37</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194860</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.15853</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahman A, Paul M. Delirium Tremens. In: StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2020 [cited 2021 Jan 6]. Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK482134/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKeon A, Frye MA, Delanty N. The alcohol withdrawal syndrome. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79(8):854-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caetano R, Clark CL, Greenfield TK. Prevalence, trends, and incidence of alcohol withdrawal symptoms: Analysis of general population and clinical samples. Alcohol Health Res World. 1998;22(1):73-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soyka M, Kranzler HR, Berglund M, Gorelick D, Hesselbrock V, Johnson BA, et al. World Federation of Societies of biological psychiatry (WFSBP) guidelines for biological treatment of substance use and related disorders, part 1: Alcoholism. World J Biol Psychiatry. 2008;9(1):6-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kattimani S, Bharadwaj B. Clinical management of alcohol withdrawal: A systematic review. Ind Psychiatry J. 2013;22(2):100-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaw JM, Kolesar GS, Sellers EM, Kaplan HL, Sandor P. Development of optimal treatment tactics for alcohol withdrawal. I. Assessment and effectiveness of supportive care. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 1981;1(6):382-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitfield CL, Thompson G, Lamb A, Spencer V, Pfeifer M, Browning-Ferrando M. Detoxification of 1,024 alcoholic patients without psychoactive drugs. Jama. 1978;239(14):1409-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller WR. Retire the concept of “relapse.”. Subst Use Misuse. 2015;50(8-9):976-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrons R, Roberts N. The role of carbamazepine and oxcarbazepine in alcohol withdrawal syndrome. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2010;35(2):153-67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berglund M, Thelander S, Salaspuro M, Franck J, Andréasson S, Öjehagen A. Treatment of alcohol abuse: An evidence-based review. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2003;27(10):1645-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charlet K, Heinz A. Harm reduction-A systematic review on effects of alcohol reduction on physical and mental symptoms. Addict Biol. 2017;22(5):1119-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dixit D, Endicott J, Burry L, Ramos L, Yeung SYA, Devabhakthuni S, et al. Management of Acute Alcohol Withdrawal Syndrome in critically ill patients. Pharmacother J Hum Pharmacol Drug Ther. 2016;36(7):797-822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayo-Smith MF, Beecher LH, Fischer TL, Gorelick DA, Guillaume JL, Hill A, et al. Management of alcohol withdrawal delirium. An evidence-based practice guideline. Arch Intern Med. 2004;164(13):1405-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moskowitz G, Chalmers TC, Sacks HS, Fagerstrom RM, Smith H. Deficiencies of clinical trials of alcohol withdrawal. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 1983;7(1):42-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miura T, Noma H, Furukawa TA, Mitsuyasu H, Tanaka S, Stockton S, et al. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of pharmacological treatments in the maintenance treatment of bipolar disorder: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2014;1(5):351-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yildiz A, Vieta E, Correll CU, Nikodem M, Baldessarini RJ. Critical issues on the use of network meta-analysis in psychiatry. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2014;22(6):367-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cipriani A, Furukawa TA, Salanti G, Chaimani A, Atkinson LZ, Ogawa Y, et al. Comparative efficacy and acceptability of 21 antidepressant drugs for the acute treatment of adults with major depressive disorder: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Lond Engl. 2018;391(10128):1357-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salanti G. Indirect and mixed-treatment comparison, network, or multiple-treatments meta-analysis: Many names, many benefits, many concerns for the next generation evidence synthesis tool. Res Synth Methods. 2012;3(2):80-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Ermacora D, Stephenson C, Hawken ER, Vazquez G. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of pharmacological treatments for the treatment of acute bipolar depression: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2020;269:154-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Ermacora D, Stephenson C, Hawken ER, Vazquez G. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of adjunctive pharmacotherapies for acute bipolar depression: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Can J Psychiatry Rev Can Psychiatr. 2021;66(3):274-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Vazquez GH, Zarate CA. Comparative efficacy of racemic ketamine and esketamine for depression: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2021;278:542-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, Chaimani A, Schmid CH, Cameron C, et al. The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: Checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayo-Smith MF. Pharmacological Management of Alcohol Withdrawal: A meta-analysis and evidence-based practice guideline. Jama. 1997;278(2):144-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holbrook AM, Crowther R, Lotter A, Cheng C, King D. Meta-analysis of benzodiazepine use in the treatment of acute alcohol withdrawal. CMAJ Can Med Assoc J. 1999;160(5):649-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Addolorato G, Caputo F, Capristo E, Janiri L, Bernardi M, Agabio R, et al. Rapid suppression of alcohol withdrawal syndrome by baclofen. Am J Med. 2002;112(3):226-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Addolorato G, Leggio L, Abenavoli L, Caputo F, Gasbarrini G. Baclofen for outpatient treatment of alcohol withdrawal syndrome. J Fam Pract. 2005;54(1):24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ait-Daoud N, Malcolm RJ, Johnson BA. An overview of medications for the treatment of alcohol withdrawal and alcohol dependence with an emphasis on the use of older and newer anticonvulsants. Addict Behav. 2006;31(9):1628-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lum E, Gorman SK, Slavik RS. Valproic acid management of acute alcohol withdrawal. Ann Pharmacother. 2006;40(3):441-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillman MA, Lichtigfeld F, Young T. Psychotropic analgesic nitrous oxide for alcoholic withdrawal states. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2007 [cited 2021 Jan 26];(2). Available from: http://www.cochranelibrary.com/cdsr/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD005190.pub2/full</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Connor AB, Lang VJ. Baclofen not comparable to diazepam for alcohol withdrawal. Am J Med. 2007;120(6):e5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saitz R. Baclofen for alcohol withdrawal: Not comparable to the gold standard (benzodiazepines). Am J Med. 2007;120(6):e9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amato L, Minozzi S, Vecchi S, Davoli M. Benzodiazepines for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Drugs and Alcohol Group, editor. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2010 Mar 17 [cited 2021 Feb 6]; Available from: http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/14651858.CD005063.pub3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leone MA, Vigna-Taglianti F, Avanzi G, Brambilla R, Faggiano F. Gamma-hydroxybutyrate (GHB) for treatment of alcohol withdrawal and prevention of relapses. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2010 [cited 2021 Jan 26];(2). Available from: http://www.cochranelibrary.com/cdsr/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD006266.pub2/full</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minozzi S, Amato L, Vecchi S, Davoli M. Anticonvulsants for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet] 2010 [cited 2020 Sep 22];(3). Available from: https://www.readcube.com/articles/10.1002%2F14651858.CD005064.pub3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amato L, Minozzi S, Davoli M. Efficacy and safety of pharmacological interventions for the treatment of the alcohol withdrawal syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;6:CD008537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jakob SM, Ruokonen E, Grounds RM, Sarapohja T, Garratt C, Pocock SJ, et al. Dexmedetomidine vs midazolam or propofol for sedation during prolonged mechanical ventilation: Two randomized controlled trials. Jama. 2012;307(11):1151-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazanikov M, Udd M, Kylänpää L, Mustonen H, Lindström O, Halttunen J, et al. Dexmedetomidine impairs success of patient-controlled sedation in alcoholics during ERCP: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Surg Endosc. 2013;27(6):2163-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ungur LA, Neuner B, John S, Wernecke K, Spies C. Prevention and therapy of alcohol withdrawal on intensive care units: Systematic review of controlled trials. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2013;37(4):675-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goodson CM, Clark BJ, Douglas IS. Predictors of severe alcohol withdrawal syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2014;38(10):2664-77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keating GM. Sodium oxybate: A review of its use in alcohol withdrawal syndrome and in the maintenance of abstinence in alcohol dependence. Clin Drug Investig. 2014;34(1):63-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zindel LR, Kranzler HR. Pharmacotherapy of alcohol use disorders: Seventy-five years of Progress. J Stud Alcohol Drugs Suppl. 2014;75(Suppl 17):79-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keating GM. Dexmedetomidine: A review of its use for sedation in the intensive care setting. Drugs. 2015;75(10):1119-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leung JG, Hall-Flavin D, Nelson S, Schmidt KA, Schak KM. The role of gabapentin in the management of alcohol withdrawal and dependence. Ann Pharmacother. 2015;49(8):897-906.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods AD, Giometti R, Weeks SM. The use of dexmedetomidine as an adjuvant to benzodiazepine-based therapy to decrease the severity of delirium in alcohol withdrawal in adult intensive care unit patients: A systematic review. JBI Database System Rev Implement Rep. 2015;13(1):224-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Wang L. Baclofen for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;2017(8):CD008502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mannucci C, Pichini S, Spagnolo EV, Calapai F, Gangemi S, Navarra M, et al. Sodium Oxybate therapy for alcohol withdrawal syndrome and keeping of alcohol abstinence. Curr Drug Metab. 2018;19(13):1056-64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed S, Stanciu CN, Kotapati PV, Ahmed R, Bhivandkar S, Khan AM, et al. Effectiveness of gabapentin in reducing cravings and withdrawal in alcohol use disorder: A meta-analytic review. Prim Care Companion CNS Disord. 2019;21(4):0-0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Beaurepaire R, Sinclair JMA, Heydtmann M, Addolorato G, Aubin H-J, Beraha EM, et al. The use of baclofen as a treatment for alcohol use disorder: A clinical practice perspective. Front Psychiatry [Internet] 2019 Jan 4 [cited 2021 Feb 6];9. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6328471/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holleck JL, Merchant N, Gunderson CG. Symptom-triggered therapy for alcohol withdrawal syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Gen Intern Med. 2019;34(6):1018-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latifi S, Messer T. The efficacy of Tiapride and carbamazepine combination therapy in reducing alcohol withdrawal symptoms: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Pharmacopsychiatry. 2019;52(05):209-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Wang L-N. Baclofen for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2019 [cited 2021 Nov 9];(11). Available from: https://www.readcube.com/articles/10.1002%2F14651858.CD008502.pub6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Society of Addiction Medicine. The ASAM clinical practice guideline on alcohol withdrawal management. J Addict Med. 2020;14(3S):1-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makram J, Ismail A, Sotello Aviles D, Mallah H, Karim A, Iwuji K, et al. The Safety and Efficacy of Dexmedetomidine in Alcohol Withdrawal: A Meta-Analysis and Systematic Review. In: D23 WHAT'S NEW IN NON-PULMONARY CRITICAL CARE? [Internet]. American Thoracic Society; 2020 [cited 2020 Sep 22]. p. A6322-A6322. Available from: https://www.atsjournals.org/doi/10.1164/ajrccm-conference.2020.201.1_MeetingAbstracts.A6322</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai J-Y, Kalk N, Roberts E. The effectiveness and tolerability of anti-seizure medication in alcohol withdrawal syndrome: A systematic review, meta-analysis and GRADE of the evidence. Addiction. 2021;117(1):5-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steel TL, Afshar M, Edwards S, Jolley SE, Timko C, Clark BJ, et al. Research needs for inpatient Management of Severe Alcohol Withdrawal Syndrome: An official American Thoracic Society research statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;204(7):e61-87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media. Zotero [Internet]. Fairfax, Virginia, USA: George Mason University; 2018. Available from: www.zotero.org</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veritas Health Innovation. Covidence systematic review software. Australia: Melbourne; 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, Gøtzsche PC, Jüni P, Moher D, Oxman AD, et al. The Cochrane Collaboration's tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Hillsdale, N.J: L. Erlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipsey MW, Wilson DB. Practical meta-analysis [Internet]. Thousand Oaks, Calif: Sage Publications; 2001 [cited 2021 Jan 12]. Available from: http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;scope=site&amp;db=nlebk&amp;db=nlabk&amp;AN=63274</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A. The effectiveness of naltrexone for opioid use disorder among inmates: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Adv Justice. 2019;2(1):71-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Mazhar MN, Hudson CC, Nadkarni P, MacNeil BA, Hawken E. Prevalence of substance use disorder comorbidity among individuals with eating disorders: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2019;273:58-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Cheng B, Gray S, Stuart H. Reduction in mortality risk with opioid agonist therapy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2019;140(4):313-339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Cheng B, Gray S, Stuart H. Mortality among people with opioid use disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Addict Med. 2020;14(4):e118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Stephenson C, Tyo R, Hawken ER, Seitz DP. Prevalence of Cannabis Withdrawal Symptoms Among People With Regular or Dependent Use of Cannabinoids. JAMA Netw Open [Internet] 2020 Apr 9 [cited 2021 Jun 11];3(4). Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7146100/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Pierce M, Wong J, Roberge JN, Ortega I, Patten S. Comparative efficacy and acceptability of psychotherapies for self-harm and suicidal behavior among children and adolescents: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(4):e216614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahji A, Meyyappan AC, Hawken ER, Tibbo PG. Pharmacotherapies for cannabis use disorder: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Int J Drug Policy. 2021;97:103295.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palpacuer C, Duprez R, Huneau A, Locher C, Boussageon R, Laviolle B, et al. Pharmacologically controlled drinking in the treatment of alcohol dependence or alcohol use disorders: A systematic review with direct and network meta-analyses on nalmefene, naltrexone, acamprosate, baclofen and topiramate. Addiction. 2018;113(2):220-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salanti G, Higgins JPT, Ades AE, Ioannidis JPA. Evaluation of networks of randomized trials. Stat Methods Med Res. 2008;17(3):279-301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huhn M, Nikolakopoulou A, Schneider-Thoma J, Krause M, Samara M, Peter N, et al. Comparative efficacy and tolerability of 32 oral antipsychotics for the acute treatment of adults with multi-episode schizophrenia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Lancet Lond Engl. 2019;394(10202):939-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saitz R, Mayo-Smith M, Roberts M, Redmond H, Bernard D, Calkins D. Individualized treatment for alcohol withdrawal. A randomized double-blind controlled trial. Jama. 1994;272(7):519-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner RC, Lichstein PR, Peden JG, Busher JT, Waivers LE. Alcohol withdrawal syndromes: A review of pathophysiology, clinical presentation, and treatment. J Gen Intern Med. 1989;4(5):432-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashton C. Benzodiazepines: How They Work &amp; How to Withdraw [Internet]. Benzodiazepines: How They Work &amp; How to Withdraw. 2002 [cited 2021 Jan 6]. Available from: https://www.benzo.org.uk/manual/bzsched.htm</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rücker G, Schwarzer G. Ranking treatments in frequentist network meta-analysis works without resampling methods. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2015;15(58):1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rouse B, Chaimani A, Li T. Network meta-analysis: An introduction for clinicians. Intern Emerg Med. 2017;12(1):103-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG. Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ. 2003;327(7414):557-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JPT, Rothstein HR. A basic introduction to fixed-effect and random-effects models for meta-analysis. Res Synth Methods. 2010;1(2):97-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sedgwick P, Marston L. How to read a funnel plot in a meta-analysis. BMJ. 2015;351:h4718.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egger M, Davey Smith G, Schneider M, Minder C. Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ. 1997;315(7109):629-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Wang L. Baclofen for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2019 Nov 6 [cited 2021 Jan 26];2019(11). Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6831488/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasselbalch E, Timm S, Nordentoft M, Roesen A, Keiding S, Hemmingsen R. Delirium tremens and physical alcohol withdrawal: A double-blind comparison of phenobarbital and barbital treatment. Nord J Psychiatry. 1994;48(2):121-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hendey GW, Dery RA, Barnes RL, Snowden B, Mentler P. A prospective, randomized, trial of phenobarbital versus benzodiazepines for acute alcohol withdrawal. Am J Emerg Med. 2011;29(4):382-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mariani JJ, Rosenthal RN, Tross S, Singh P, Anand OP. A randomized, open-label, controlled trial of gabapentin and phenobarbital in the treatment of alcohol withdrawal. Am J Addict. 2006;15(1):76-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenson J, Clements C, Simon B, Vieaux J, Graffman S, Vahidnia F, et al. Phenobarbital for acute alcohol withdrawal: A prospective randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study. J Emerg Med. 2013;44(3):592-598.e2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenthal RN, Perkel C, Singh P, Anand O, Miner CR. A pilot open randomized trial of valproate and phenobarbital in the treatment of acute alcohol withdrawal. Am J Addict. 1998;7(3):189-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polycarpou A, Papanikolau P, Ioannidis JP, Ioannidis DC. Anticonvulsants for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2005 [cited 2020 Sep 22];(3). Available from: http://www.cochranelibrary.com/cdsr/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD005064.pub2/full</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sychla H, Gründer G, Lammertz SE. Comparison of Clomethiazole and diazepam in the treatment of alcohol withdrawal syndrome in clinical practice. Eur Addict Res. 2017;23(4):211-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly TM. Physiological dependence on, and symptoms of withdrawal from. Chlormethiazole Br J Psychiatry. 1976;128(4):375-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Wang L. Baclofen for alcohol withdrawal. Cochrane Database Syst Rev [Internet]. 2010 [cited 2021 Feb 6];(5). Available from: https://www.cochranelibrary.com/cdsr/doi/10.1002/14651858.CD008502/full</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saitz R. Baclofen for alcohol withdrawal: Not comparable to the gold standard (benzodiazepines). Am J Med. 2007;120(6):e9. author reply e11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tufanaru C, Munn Z, Stephenson M, Aromataris E. Fixed or random effects meta-analysis? Common methodological issues in systematic reviews of effectiveness. JBI Evid Implement. 2015;13(3):196-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
