<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35192238</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1526-4998</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>78</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pest management science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pest Manag Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The gut commensal bacterium Enterococcus faecalis LX10 contributes to defending against Nosema bombycis infection in Bombyx mori.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2215</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2227</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2215-2227</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ps.6846</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Microsporidia, a group of obligate intracellular fungal-related parasites, have been used as efficient biocontrol agents for agriculture and forestry pests due to their host specificity and transovarial transmission. They mainly infect insect pests through the intestinal tract, but the interactions between microsporidia and the gut microbiota of the host have not been well demonstrated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Based on the microsporidia-Bombyx mori model, we report that the susceptibility of silkworms to exposure to the microsporidium Nosema bombycis was both dose and time dependent. Comparative analyses of the silkworm gut microbiome revealed substantially increased abundance of Enterococcus belonging to Firmicutes after N. bombycis infection. Furthermore, a bacterial strain (LX10) was obtained from the gut of B. mori and identified as Enterococcus faecalis based on 16S rRNA sequence analysis. E. faecalis LX10 reduced the N. bombycis spore germination rate and the infection efficiency in vitro and in vivo, as confirmed by bioassay tests and histopathological analyses. In addition, after simultaneous oral feeding with E. faecalis LX10 and N. bombycis, gene (Akirin, Cecropin A, Mesh, Ssk, DUOX and NOS) expression, hydrogen peroxide and nitric oxide levels, and glutathione S-transferase (GST) activity showed different degrees of recovery and correction compared with those under N. bombycis infection alone. Finally, the enterococcin LX protein was identified from sterile LX10 fermentation liquid based on liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS) analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Altogether, the results revealed that E. faecalis LX10 with anti-N. bombycis activity might play an important role in protecting silkworms from microsporidia. Removal of these specific commensal bacteria with antibiotics and utilization of transgenic symbiotic systems may effectively improve the biocontrol value of microsporidia. © 2022 The Authors. Pest Management Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society of Chemical Industry.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Pest Management Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of Society of Chemical Industry.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiancui</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8412-964X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Feng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huihui</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jintao</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xili</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nan</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yongqi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fan</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3281-6325</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Animal Resistance Biology of Shandong Province, College of Life Science, Shandong Normal University, Jinan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xingmeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Sericulture and Apiculture, College of Animal Sciences, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pest Manag Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100898744</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1526-498X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D012336">RNA, Ribosomal, 16S</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Organism" UI="C000678946">Nosema bombycis</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012831" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bombyx</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002853" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromatography, Liquid</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013293" MajorTopicYN="N">Enterococcus faecalis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016818" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nosema</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012336" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Ribosomal, 16S</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053719" MajorTopicYN="N">Tandem Mass Spectrometry</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bombyx mori</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Enterococcus faecalis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-Nosema bombycis activity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microsporidia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35192238</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ps.6846</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xia Q, Zhou Z, Lu C, Cheng D, Dai F, Li B et al., A draft sequence for the genome of the domesticated silkworm (Bombyx mori). Science 306:1937-1940 (2004).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Didier ESDP, Snowden KF and Shadduck JA, Microsporidiosis in mammals. Microbes Infect 2:709-720 (2000).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhat SA, Bashir I and Kamili AS, Microsporidiosis of silkworm, Bombyx mori L. (Lepidoptera-bombycidae): a review. Afr J Agric Res 4:1519-1523 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z, Wang Y, Wang L and Zhou Z, Molecular and biochemical responses in the midgut of the silkworm, Bombyx mori, infected with Nosema bombycis. Parasit Vectors 11:147 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bjornson SOD, Microsporidia biological control agents and pathogens of beneficial insects, in Microsporidia Biological Control Agents and Pathogens of Beneficial Insects[M]. John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nattoh G, Maina T, Makhulu EE, Mbaisi L, Mararo E, Otieno FG et al., Horizontal transmission of the symbiont microsporidia MB in anopheles arabiensis. Front Microbiol 12:647183 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Down RE, Bell HA, Kirkbride-Smith AE and Edwards JP, The pathogenicity of Vairimorpha necatrix (Microspora: Microsporidia) against the tomato moth, Lacanobia oleracea (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae) and its potential use for the control of lepidopteran glasshouse pests. Pest Manag Sci 60:755-764 (2004).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bardi C, Mariottini Y, Plischuk S and Lange CE, Status of the alien pathogen Paranosema locustae(microsporidia) in grasshoppers (Orthoptera: Acridoidea) of the Argentine Pampas. Biocontrol Sci Technol 22:497-512 (2012).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang-Peng S, Zheng X, Jia WT, Li AM, Camara I, Chen HX et al., Horizontal transmission of Paranosema locustae (microsporidia) in grasshopper populations via predatory natural enemies. Pest Manag Sci 74:2589-2593 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lange CE and Azzaro FG, New case of long-term persistence of Paranosema locustae (microsporidia) in melanopline grasshoppers (Orthoptera: Acrididae: Melanoplinae) of Argentina. J Invertebr Pathol 99:357-359 (2008).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miao J, Guo Y and Shi W, The persistence of Paranosema locustae after application in Qinghai plateau, China. Biocontrol Sci Technol 22:733-735 (2012).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng S, Huang Y, Huang H, Yu B, Zhou N, Wei J et al., The role of NbTMP1, a surface protein of sporoplasm, in Nosema bombycis infection. Parasit Vectors 14:81 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinz E, Hacker C, Dean P, Mifsud J, Goldberg AV, Williams TA et al., Plasma membrane-located purine nucleotide transport proteins are key components for host exploitation by microsporidian intracellular parasites. PLoS Pathog 10:e1004547 (2014).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han B and Weiss LM, Microsporidia: obligate intracellular pathogens within the fungal kingdom. Microbiol Spectr 5:2 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han B, Takvorian PM and Weiss LM, Invasion of host cells by microsporidia. Front Microbiol 11:172 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang X, Sun C, Chen B, Du K, Yu T, Luang-In V et al., Insect symbionts as valuable grist for the biotechnological mill: an alkaliphilic silkworm gut bacterium for efficient lactic acid production. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol 102:4951-4962 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Q, Ren M, Liu X, Xia H and Chen K, Identification and characterization of novel short-type BmPGRP-S4 from the silkworm, Bombyx mori, involved in innate immunity. Z Naturforsch C J Biosci 75:13-21 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun YX, Chen C, Xu WJ, Abbas MN, Mu FF, Ding WJ et al., Functions of Bombyx mori cathepsin L-like in innate immune response and anti-microbial autophagy. Deve Comp Immunol 116:103927 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Q, Wang J, Ren M, Ma S, Liu X, Chen K et al., Peptidoglycan recognition protein-S1 acts as a receptor to activate AMP expression through the IMD pathway in the silkworm Bombyx mori. Deve Comp Immunol 115:103903 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xin ZZ, Liu QN, Liu Y, Zhang DZ, Wang ZF, Zhang HB et al., Transcriptome-wide identification of differentially expressed genes in Chinese oak silkworm Antheraea pernyi in response to Lead challenge. J Agric Food Chem 65:9305-9314 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Z, Li C, Pan G, Li Z, Han B, Xu J et al., Genome-wide transcriptional response of silkworm (Bombyx mori) to infection by the microsporidian Nosema bombycis. PLoS One 8:e84137 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen B, Zhang N, Xie S, Zhang X, He J, Muhammad A et al., Gut bacteria of the silkworm Bombyx mori facilitate host resistance against the toxic effects of organophosphate insecticides. Environ Int 143:105886 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar D, Sun Z, Cao G, Xue R, Hu X and CJJoA-PE G, Study of gut bacterial diversity of Bombyx mandarina and Bombyx mori through 16S rRNA gene sequencing. J Asia Pac Entomol 22:522-530 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang D, Dong Z, Zhang Y, Guo K, Guo P, Zhao P et al., Proteomics provides insight into the interaction between mulberry and silkworm. J Proteome Res 16:2472-2480 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brummel T, Ching A, Seroude L, Simon AF and Benzer S, Drosophila lifespan enhancement by exogenous bacteria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 101:12974-12979 (2004).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu H, Chen B, Hu S, Liang X, Lu X and Shao Y, Quantitative proteomic analysis of germination of Nosema bombycis spores under extremely alkaline conditions. Front Microbiol 7:1459 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peralta-Sanchez JM, Martin-Platero AM, Ariza-Romero JJ, Rabelo-Ruiz M, Zurita-Gonzalez MJ, Banos A et al., Egg production in poultry farming is improved by probiotic bacteria. Front Microbiol 10:1042 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eveno M, Savard P, Belguesmia Y, Bazinet L, Gancel F, Drider D et al., Compatibility, cytotoxicity, and gastrointestinal tenacity of bacteriocin-producing bacteria selected for a consortium probiotic formulation to be used in livestock feed. Probiotics Antimicrob Proteins 13:208-217 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nairz M, Dichtl S, Schroll A, Haschka D, Tymoszuk P, Theurl I et al., Iron and innate antimicrobial immunity-depriving the pathogen, defending the host. J Trace Elem Med Biol 48:118-133 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xi Z, Ramirez JL and Dimopoulos G, The Aedes aegypti toll pathway controls dengue virus infection. PLoS Pathog 4:e1000098 (2008).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang F, Yang C, Zhang X, Zhu H, Zhao D and Huang Y, Isolation of an anti-entomopathogenic fungal protein secreted from Pseudomonas aeruginosa BGf-2: an intestinal bacteriam of Blattella germanica (L.). J Invertebr Pathol 173:107371 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shao Y, Chen B, Sun C, Ishida K, Hertweck C and Boland W, Symbiont-derived antimicrobials contribute to the control of the lepidopteran gut microbiota. Cell Chem Biol 24:66-75 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang F, Lu X, Kumar VS, Zhu H, Chen H, Chen Z et al., Effects of a novel anti-exospore monoclonal antibody on microsporidial Nosema bombycis germination and reproduction in vitro. Parasitology 134:1551-1558 (2007).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu Z, He X, Cai S, Liu H, He X, Li M et al., Quantitative PCR for detection of Nosema bombycis in single silkworm eggs and newly hatched larvae. J Microbiol Methods 120:72-78 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen B, Du K, Sun C, Vimalanathan A, Liang X, Li Y et al., Gut bacterial and fungal communities of the domesticated silkworm (Bombyx mori) and wild mulberry-feeding relatives. ISME J 12:2252-2262 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He J, Zhang N, Muhammad A, Shen X, Sun C, Li Q et al., From surviving to thriving, the assembly processes of microbial communities in stone biodeterioration: a case study of the West Lake UNESCO World Heritage area in China. Sci Total Environ 805:150395 (2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Callahan BJ, McMurdie PJ, Rosen MJ, Han AW, Johnson AJ and Holmes SP, DADA2: high-resolution sample inference from Illumina amplicon data. Nat Methods 13:581-583 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schloss PD, Westcott SL, Ryabin T, Hall JR, Hartmann M, Hollister EB et al., Introducing mothur: open-source, platform-independent, community-supported software for describing and comparing microbial communities. Appl Environ Microbiol 75:7537-7541 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMurdie PJ and Holmes S, Phyloseq: an R package for reproducible interactive analysis and graphics of microbiome census data. PLoS One 8:e61217 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastian M, Heyman S and Jacomy M, An Open Source Software for Exploring and Manipulating Networks, Vol. 17. AAI Publications, San Jose, CA, p. 20 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Douglas GMBR and Langille MGI, Predicting the functional potential of the microbiome from marker genes using PICRUS. Methods Mol Biol 1849:169-177 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinai L, Rosenberg A, Smith Y, Segev E and Ben-Yehuda S, The molecular timeline of a reviving bacterial spore. Mol Cell 57:695-707 (2015).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kermani N, Abu-Hassan ZA, Dieng H, Ismail NF, Attia M and Abd Ghani I, Pathogenicity of Nosema sp. (microsporidia) in the diamondback moth, Plutella xylostella (Lepidoptera: Plutellidae). PLoS One 8:e62884 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubanov A, Russell KA, Rothman JA, Nieh JC and McFrederick QS, Intensity of Nosema ceranae infection is associated with specific honey bee gut bacteria and weakly associated with gut microbiome structure. Sci Rep 9:3820 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osterman J, Wintermantel D, Locke B, Jonsson O, Semberg E, Onorati P et al., Clothianidin seed-treatment has no detectable negative impact on honeybee colonies and their pathogens. Nat Commun 10:692 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li T, Fang Z, He Q, Wang C, Meng X, Yu B et al., Characterizing the Xenoma of Vairimorpha necatrix provides insights into the Most efficient mode of microsporidian proliferation. Front Cell Infect Microbiol 11:699239 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta SK, Hossain Z, Nanu MM and Mondal K, Impact of microsporidian infection on growth and development of silkworm Bombyx mori L (Lepidoptera: Bombycidae). Agri Nat Resour 50:388-395 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He Q, Luo J, Xu JZ, Wang CX, Meng XZ, Pan GQ et al., Morphology and transcriptome analysis of Nosema bombycis Sporoplasm and insights into the initial infection of microsporidia. mSphere 5:1 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Z, Zheng N, Hu C, Deng B, Fang W, Wu Q et al., Nosema bombycis microRNA-like RNA 8 (Nb-milR8) increases fungal pathogenicity by modulating BmPEX16 gene expression in its hos, Bombyx mori. Microbiol Spectr 9:e0104821 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin L, Du Y, Song J, Wang W and Yang C, Imaging commensal microbiota and pathogenic bacteria in the gut. Acc Chem Res 54:2076-2087 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang PV, Chemical mechanisms of colonization resistance by the gut microbial metabolome. ACS Chem Biol 15:1119-1126 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schirmer M, Denson L, Vlamakis H, Franzosa EA, Thomas S, Gotman NM et al., Compositional and temporal changes in the gut microbiome of pediatric ulcerative colitis patients are linked to disease course. Cell Host Microbe 24:600-610 e604 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang HLM, Zhao Y, Zhao LP, Zhang YH and Huang YP, Bacterial community in midguts of the silkworm larvae estimated by PCR/DGGE and 16S rDNA gene library analysis. Acta Entomologica Sinica 50:222-233 (2007).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Z, Lu Y, Zhang H, Kumar D, Liu B, Gong Y et al., Effects of BmCPV infection on silkworm Bombyx mori intestinal bacteria. PLoS One 11:e0146313 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres C, Alonso CA, Ruiz-Ripa L, Leon-Sampedro R, Del Campo R and Coque TM, Antimicrobial resistance in enterococcus spp. of animal origin. Microbiol Spectr 6:4 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du Y, Luo S and Zhou X, Enterococcus faecium regulates honey bee developmental genes. Int J Mol Sci 22:12105 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa Sousa N, Couto MVS, Abe HA, Paixão PEG, Cordeiro CAM, Monteiro Lopes E et al., Effects of an Enterococcus faecium-based probiotic on growth performance and health of Pirarucu, Arapaima gigas. Aquac Res 50:3720-3728 (2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suraporn S and Terenius O, Supplementation of Lactobacillus casei reduces the mortality of Bombyx mori larvae challenged by Nosema bombycis. BMC Res Notes 14:398 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garsin DA and Lorenz MC, Candida albicans and Enterococcus faecalis in the gut: synergy in commensalism? Gut Microbes 4:409-415 (2013).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonchar NVSA, Maryshev VP, Sorokina TM, Churkova TV and Kharit SM, Probiotics, nutritional status and resistance to respiratory infections in infants. Eksp Klin Gastroenterol 1:48-54 (2015).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mead LJ, Khachatourians GG and Jones GA, Microbial ecology of the gut in laboratory stocks of the migratory grasshopper, Melanoplus sanguinipes (Fab.) (Orthoptera: Acrididae). Appl Environ Microbiol 54:1174-1181 (1988).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh TBM and Khan MA, Microsporidiosis in the silkworm, Bombyx mori L (Lepidoptera: Bombycidae). Pertanika J Trop Agric Sci 35:387-406 (2012).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham CE, Cruz MR, Garsin DA and Lorenz MC, Enterococcus faecalis bacteriocin EntV inhibits hyphal morphogenesis, biofilm formation, and virulence of Candida albicans. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 114:4507-4512 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffin ME, Espinosa J, Becker JL, Luo JD, Carroll TS, Jha JK et al., Enterococcus peptidoglycan remodeling promotes checkpoint inhibitor cancer immunotherapy. Science 373:1040-1046 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng MY, Cisalpino D, Varadarajan S, Hellman J, Warren HS, Cascalho M et al., Gut microbiota-induced immunoglobulin G controls systemic infection by symbiotic bacteria and pathogens. Immunity 44:647-658 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazmanian SK, Liu CH, Tzianabos AO and Kasper DL, An immunomodulatory molecule of symbiotic bacteria directs maturation of the host immune system. Cell 122:107-118 (2005).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edelman SM and Kasper DL, Symbiotic commensal bacteria direct maturation of the host immune system. Curr Opin Gastroenterol 24:720-724 (2008).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermudez-Brito M, Plaza-Diaz J, Munoz-Quezada S, Gomez-Llorente C and Gil A, Probiotic mechanisms of action. Ann Nutr Metab 61:160-174 (2012).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishida S, Ono Y and Sekimizu K, Lactic acid bacteria activating innate immunity improve survival in bacterial infection model of silkworm. Drug Discov Ther 10:49-56 (2016).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He X, Fu Z, Li M, Liu H, Cai S, Man N et al., Nosema bombycis (Microsporidia) suppresses apoptosis in BmN cells (Bombyx mori). Acta Biochim Biophys Sin (Shanghai) 47:696-702 (2015).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antúnez K, Martín-Hernández R, Prieto L, Meana A, Zunino P and MJEM H, immune suppression in the honey bee (Apis mellifera) following infection by Nosema ceranae (Microsporidia). Environ Microbiol 11:2284-2290 (2009).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen HJ, Li Q, Nirala NK and Ip YT, The snakeskin-mesh complex of smooth septate junction restricts Yorkie to regulate intestinal homeostasis in drosophila. Stem Cell Reports 14:828-844 (2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Liu C, Jin R, Wang Y, Cai T, Ren Z et al., Dual oxidase-dependent reactive oxygen species are involved in the regulation of UGT overexpression-mediated clothianidin resistance in the brown planthopper, Nilaparvata lugens. Pest Manag Sci 77:4159-4167 (2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durvasula RV, Gumbs A, Panackal A, Kruglov O, Aksoy S, Merrifield RB et al., Prevention of insect-borne disease: an approach using transgenic symbiotic bacteria. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 94:3274-3278 (1997).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang S, Dos-Santos AL, Huang W, Liu KC, Oshaghi MA, Wei G et al., Driving mosquito refractoriness to Plasmodium falciparum with engineered symbiotic bacteria. Science 357:1399-1402 (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang F, Sun XX, Zhang XC, Zhang S, Lu J, Xia YM et al., The interactions between gut microbiota and entomopathogenic fungi: a potential approach for biological control of Blattella germanica (L.). Pest Manag Sci 74:438-447 (2018).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
