<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35192737</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2796</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>291</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of internal medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Intern Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparison of effectiveness and safety for low versus full dose of apixaban during extended phase oral anticoagulation in patients with venous thromboembolism.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>877</StartPage>
          <EndPage>885</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>877-885</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/joim.13462</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The optimal dose of apixaban therapy to prevent asecondary venous thromboembolism (VTE) event remains unconfirmed. To investigate the effects of extended phase use of apixaban (2.5 vs. 5 mg twice daily) beyond 6 months of initial treatment on the risk of recurrent VTE and major bleeding events among patients with a history of VTE.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective cohort analysis of two large national insurance claims databases was conducted for patients diagnosed with VTE. Cox proportional hazard models after propensity score matching were used to compare the risk of recurrent VTE and major bleeding.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There were no detected differences in recurrent VTE or major bleeding events between patients prescribed low versus full dose apixaban.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides evidence that apixaban 2.5 mg twice daily is an alternative option for extended phase therapy for risk reduction of VTE recurrence compared to apixaban 5 mg twice daily.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Association for the Publication of the Journal of Internal Medicine.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>DeRemer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christina E</ForeName>
            <Initials>CE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacotherapy and Translational Research, College of Pharmacy, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dietrich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eric A</ForeName>
            <Initials>EA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacotherapy and Translational Research, College of Pharmacy, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hye-Rim</ForeName>
            <Initials>HR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Outcomes and Policy, College of Pharmacy, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pei-Lin</ForeName>
            <Initials>PL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Outcomes and Policy, College of Pharmacy, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lo-Ciganic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei-Hsuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>WH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Outcomes and Policy, College of Pharmacy, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Drug Evaluation and Safety, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Park</LastName>
            <ForeName>Haesuk</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3299-8111</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Outcomes and Policy, College of Pharmacy, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Drug Evaluation and Safety, University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Intern Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8904841</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0954-6820</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011720">Pyrazoles</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011728">Pyridones</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>3Z9Y7UWC1J</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C522181">apixaban</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>5Q7ZVV76EI</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014859">Warfarin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011720" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyrazoles</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011728" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyridones</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054556" MajorTopicYN="Y">Venous Thromboembolism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014859" MajorTopicYN="N">Warfarin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anticoagulants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apixaban</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extended phase anticoagulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">major bleeding</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">venous thromboembolism</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35192737</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joim.13462</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Akl EA, Comerota AJ, Prandoni P, Bounameaux H, Goldhaber SZ, et al. Antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: antithrombotic therapy and prevention of thrombosis, 9th ed: American College of Chest Physicians Evidence-Based Clinical Practice Guidelines. Chest 2012;141(2):e419S-96S.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Akl EA, Ornelas J. Antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest 2016; 149(2):315-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Gent M, Hirsh J. A comparison of three months of anti-coagulation with extended anticoagulation for a first episode of idiopathic venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 1999; 340(12):901-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ageno W, Farjat A, Haas S, Weitz JI, Goldhaber SZ, Turpie AGG, et al. Provoked versus unprovoked venous thromboembolism: findings from GARFIELD-VTE. Res Pract Thromb Haemost. 2021;5(2):326-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albertsen Ida E, Piazza G, Goldhaber SZ. Let's stop dichotomizing venous thromboembolism as provoked or unprovoked. Circulation 2018;138(23):2591-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klok FA, Huisman MV. How I assess and manage the risk of bleeding in patients treated for venous thromboembolism. Blood 2020;135(10):724-34. PMID: 31951652</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitworth MM, Haase KK, Fike DS, Bharadwaj RM, Young RB, MacLaughlin EJ. Utilization and prescribing patterns of direct oral anticoagulants. Int J Gen Med. 2017;10:87-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ageno W, Samperiz A, Caballero R, Dentali F, Di Micco P, Prandoni P, et al. Duration of anticoagulation after venous thromboembolism in real world clinical practice. Thromb Res. 2015;135(4):666-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haas S, Ageno W, Weitz JI, Goldhaber SZ, Turpie AGG, Goto S, et al. Anticoagulation therapy patterns for acute treatment of venous thromboembolism in GARFIELD-VTE patients. J Thromb Haemost. 2019;17(10):1694-706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kearon C, Ageno W, Cannegieter SC, Cosmi B, Geersing GJ, Kyrle PA. Subcommittees on control of anticoagulation, and predictive and diagnostic variables in thrombotic disease. Categorization of patients as having provoked or unprovoked venous thromboembolism: guidance from the SSC of ISTH. J Thromb Haemost. 2016;14:1480-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couturaud F, Sanchez O, Pernod G, Mismetti P, Jego P, Duhamel E, et al. Six months vs extended oral anticoagulation after a first episode of pulmonary embolism: the PADIS-PE randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2015;314(1):31-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iorio A, Kearon C, Filippucci E, Marcucci M, Macura A, Pengo V, et al. Risk of recurrence after a first episode of symptomatic venous thromboembolism provoked by a transient risk factor: a systematic review. Arch Intern Med. 2010;170(19):1710-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens SM, Woller SC, Baumann Kreuziger L, Bounameaux H, Doerschug K, Geersing G-J, et al. Executive summary: antithrombotic therapy for VTE disease: second update of the CHEST guideline and expert panel report. Chest 2021;160(6):2247-59. PMID: 34352279</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandes CJ, Calderaro D, Piloto B, Hoette S, Jardim CVP, Souza R. Extended anticoagulation after venous thromboembolism: should it be done? Ther Adv Respir Dis. 2019;13. https://doi.org/10.1177/1753466619878556</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Buller HR, Cohen A, Curto M, Gallus AS, Johnson M, et al. Apixaban for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013; 368:699-708.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heit JA, Spencer FA, White RH. The epidemiology of venous thromboembolism. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2016;41(1):3-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agnelli G, Buller HR, Cohen A, Curto M, Gallus AS, Johnson M, et al. Oral apixaban for the treatment of acute venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2013; 369:799-808.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alotaibi GS, Wu C, Senthilselvan A, McMurtry MS. The validity of ICD codes coupled with imaging procedure codes for identifying acute venous thromboembolism using administrative data. Vasc Med. 2015;20(4):364-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White RH, Garcia M, Sadeghi B, Tancredi DJ, Zrelak P, Cuny J, et al. Evaluation of the predictive value of ICD-9-CM coded administrative data for venous thromboembolism in the United States. Thromb Res. 2010;126(1):61-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu S, Ross C, Raebel MA, Shetterly S, Blanchette C, Smith D. Use of stabilized inverse propensity scores as weights to directly estimate relative risk and its confidence intervals. Value Health. 2010;13(2):273-77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Austin PC, Stuart EA. The performance of inverse probability of treatment weighting and full matching on the propensity score in the presence of model misspecification when estimating the effect of treatment on survival outcomes. Stat Methods Med Res. 2017;26(4):1654-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trujillo-Santos J, Di Micco P, Dentali F, Douketis J, Díaz-Peromingo JA, Núñez MJ, et al.; RIETE investigators. Real-life treatment of venous thromboembolism with direct oral anticoagulants: the influence of recommended dosing and regimens. Thromb Haemost. 2017;117(2):382-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konstantinides SV, Meyer G, Becattini C, Bueno H, Geersing G-J, Harjola V-P, et al. 2019 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism developed in collaboration with the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Heart J. 2020;41(4):543-603.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortel TL, Neumann I, Ageno W, Beyth R, Clark NP, Cuker A, et al. American Society of Hematology 2020 guidelines for management of venous thromboembolism: treatment of deep vein thrombosis and pulmonary embolism. Blood Adv. 2020;4(19):4693-738.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gollamudi J, Al-Kindi S, Martin P, Nayak L. Safety of apixaban in patients with CKD stage V and ESRD with venous thromboembolism. Blood 2018;132(1):2523.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
