<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35199098</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-2421</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>IBRO neuroscience reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>IBRO Neurosci Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Functional connectivity of intercalated nucleus with medial amygdala: A circuit relevant for chemosignal processing.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>170</StartPage>
          <EndPage>181</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>170-181</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ibneur.2022.01.005</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Medial amygdala processes social/reproductive chemosensory input, and its projections to preoptic and hypothalamic areas evoke appropriate behavioral and physiological responses. We and others have shown that different chemosensory signals elicit differential responses in medial amygdala subregions and in adjacent main intercalated nucleus (mICN). The largely GABAergic mICN receives no direct chemosensory input but, as we show, mICN has functional circuit connections with medial amygdala that could be responsible both for mICN chemosensitivity and for a feedforward inhibitory effect on posterior medial amygdala; which, in turn would affect chemosignal response. mICN is subject to inhibition by dopamine and is probably regulated by neuropeptides and input from frontal cortex. Thus, mICN is in position to modify chemosensory processing in medial amygdala and behavioral responses to social signals, according to internal brain state. Patch-clamp recordings from neurons in each relevant nucleus in horizontal brain-slices, with electrical stimulation in adjacent nuclei, reveal multiple functional connections between medial amygdala subregions and mICN. We highlight a triangular circuit which may underlie mICN chemosensitivity and its potential for modifying chemosensory information transmitted to basal forebrain. Anterior medial amygdala, which receives most of the chemosensory input, connects to posterior medial amygdala directly and both areas send information on to basal forebrain. Anterior medial amygdala can also modulate posterior medial amygdala indirectly via the mICN side-loop, which also provides a pathway for modulation by cortical input or, when inhibited by dopamine, could allow a more automatic response - as proposed for other amygdala circuits with similar ICN side loops.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Biggs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lindsey M</ForeName>
            <Initials>LM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Program in Neuroscience and Dept. Biological Science, Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL 32306, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meredith</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Program in Neuroscience and Dept. Biological Science, Florida State University, Tallahassee, FL 32306, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>IBRO Neurosci Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101775148</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2667-2421</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electrical stimulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GABA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glutamate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Male Hamster</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Whole-cell slice-recording</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35199098</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8850325</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ibneur.2022.01.005</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-2421(22)00005-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adolphs R. What does the amygdala contribute to social cognition? Ann. NY Acad. Sci. 2010;1191:42–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2871162</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20392275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amano T., Unal C.T., Paré D. Synaptic correlates of fear extinction in the amygdala. Nat. Neurosci. 2010;13:489–494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2847017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20208529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amir A., Amano T., Pare D. Physiological identification and infralimbic responsiveness of rat intercalated amygdala neurons. J. Neurophysiol. 2011;105:3054–3066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118749</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471396</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asede D., Bosch D., Lüthi A., Ferraguti F., Ehrlich I. Sensory inputs to intercalated cells provide fear-learning modulated inhibition to the basolateral amygdala. Neuron. 2015;86:541–554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25843406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Been L.E., Petrulis A. Chemosensory and hormone information are relayed directly between the medial amygdala, posterior bed nucleus of the stria terminalis, and medial preoptic area in male Syrian hamsters. Hormon. Behav. 2011;59:536–548.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3081384</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21316366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergan J.F., Ben-Shaul Y., Dulac C. Sex-specific processing of social cues in the medial amygdala. ELife. 2014:3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4038839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24894465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggs L.M., Meredith M. Activation of calcium binding protein-ir neurons in medial amygdala during chemosignal processing. Chem. Sens. 2020;45:439–448.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32386197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Billing A., Henrique Correia M., Kelly D.A., Li G.-L., Bergan J.F. Synaptic connections of aromatase circuits in the medial amygdala are sex specific. ENeuro. 2020;7(3):2020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7322293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32471845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cádiz-Moretti B., Otero-García M., Martínez-García F., Lanuza E. Afferent projections to the different medial amygdala subdivisions: a retrograde tracing study in the mouse. Brain Struct. Funct. 2016;221:1033–1065.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25503449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho V.M., de A., Nakahara T.S., Souza M.A., de A., Cardozo L.M., Trintinalia G.Z., Pissinato L.G., Venancio J.O., Stowers L., Papes F. Representation of olfactory information in organized active neural ensembles in the hypothalamus. Cell Rep. 2020;32</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho V.M.A., Nakahara T.S., Cardozo L.M., Souza M.A.A., Camargo A.P., Trintinalia G.Z., Ferraz E., Papes F. Lack of spatial segregation in the representation of pheromones and kairomones in the mouse medial amygdala. Front. Neurosci. 2015:9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4531233</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26321906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coolen L.M., Wood R.I. Bidirectional connections of the medial amygdaloid nucleus in the Syrian hamster brain: simultaneous anterograde and retrograde tract tracing. J. Comp. Neurol. 1998;399:189–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9721903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demir E., Li K., Bobrowski-Khoury N., Sanders J.I., Beynon R.J., Hurst J.L., Kepecs A., Axel R. The pheromone darcin drives a circuit for innate and reinforced behaviours. Nature. 2020;578:137–141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31996852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duvarci S., Pare D. Amygdala microcircuits controlling learned fear. Neuron. 2014;82:966–980.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4103014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24908482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorelova N., Seamans J.K., Yang C.R. Mechanisms of dopamine activation of fast-spiking interneurons that exert inhibition in rat prefrontal cortex. J. Neurophysiol. 2002;88:3150–3166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12466437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregoriou G.C., Kissiwaa S.A., Patel S.D., Bagley E.E. Dopamine and opioids inhibit synaptic outputs of the main island of the intercalated neurons of the amygdala. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2019;50:2065–2074.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30099803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hagihara K.M., Bukalo O., Zeller M., Aksoy-Aksel A., Karalis N., Limoges A., Rigg T., Campbell T., Mendez A., Weinholtz C., et al.  Intercalated amygdala clusters orchestrate a switch in fear state. Nature. 2021;594:403–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8402941</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34040259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hermel E.E.S., Faccioni-Heuser M.C., Marcuzzo S., Rasia-Filho A.A., Achaval M. Ultrastructural features of neurons and synaptic contacts in the posterodorsal medial amygdala of adult male rats. J. Anat. 2006;208:565–575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2100224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16637879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu H., Jonas P. A supercritical density of Na(+) channels ensures fast signaling in GABAergic interneuron axons. Nat. Neurosci. 2014;17:686–693.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4286295</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24657965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang N., Baum M.J., Cherry J.A. A direct main olfactory bulb projection to the “vomeronasal” amygdala in female mice selectively responds to volatile pheromones from males. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2009;29:624–634.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2669936</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19187265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang N., McCarthy E.A., Cherry J.A., Baum M.J. A sex comparison of the anatomy and function of the main olfactory bulb-medial amygdala projection in mice. Neuroscience. 2011;172:196–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3010476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21070839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang N., Baum M.J., Cherry J.A. Different profiles of main and accessory olfactory bulb mitral/tufted cell projections revealed in mice using an anterograde tracer and a whole-mount, flattened cortex preparation. Chem. Sens. 2011;36:251–260.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3038272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21177285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keshavarzi S., Sullivan R.K.P., Ianno D.J., Sah P. Functional properties and projections of neurons in the medial amygdala. J. Neurosci. 2014;34:8699–8715.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6608208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24966371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondo Y., Arai Y. Functional association between the medial amygdala and the medial preoptic area in regulation of mating behavior in the male rat. Physiol. Behav. 1995;57:69–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7878127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuerbitz J., Arnett M., Ehrman S., Williams M.T., Vorhees C.V., Fisher S.E., Garratt A.N., Muglia L.J., Waclaw R.R., Campbell K. Loss of intercalated cells (ITCs) in the mouse amygdala of tshz1 mutants correlates with fear, depression, and social interaction phenotypes. J. Neurosci. 2018;38:1160–1177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5792476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29255003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lehman M.N., Winans S.S. Vomeronasal and olfactory pathways to the amygdala controlling male hamster sexual behavior: Autoradiographic and behavioral analyses. Brain Res. 1982;240:27–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7093718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Likhtik E., Popa D., Apergis-Schoute J., Fidacaro G.A., Pare D. Amygdala intercalated neurons are required for expression of fear extinction. Nature. 2008;454:642–645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2528060</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18615014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H., Müller-Bardorff M., Gathmann B., Brieke J., Mothes-Lasch M., Bruchmann M., Miltner W.H.R., Straube T. Stimulus arousal drives amygdalar responses to emotional expressions across sensory modalities. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:1898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mańko M., Geracitano R., Capogna M. Functional connectivity of the main intercalated nucleus of the mouse amygdala. J. Physiol. 2011;589:1911–1925.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090594</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21224220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maras P.M., Petrulis A. Chemosensory and steroid-responsive regions of the medial amygdala regulate distinct aspects of the opposite-sex odor preference in male syrian hamsters. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2006;24:3541–3552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maras P.M., Petrulis A. The anterior medial amygdala transmits sexual odor information to the posterior medial amygdala and related forebrain nuclei. Eur. J. Neurosci. 2010;32:469–482.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20704594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maras P.M., Petrulis A. Anatomical connections between the anterior and posterodorsal sub-regions of the medial amygdala: integration of odor and hormone signals. Neuroscience. 2010;170:610–622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2936916</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20620195</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maras P.M., Petrulis A. Lesions that functionally disconnect the anterior and posterodorsal sub-regions of the medial amygdala eliminate opposite-sex odor preference in male Syrian hamsters (Mesocricetus auratus) Neuroscience. 2010;165:1052–1062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2814983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19931356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marowsky A., Yanagawa Y., Obata K., Vogt K.E. A specialized subclass of interneurons mediates dopaminergic facilitation of amygdala function. Neuron. 2005;48:1025–1037.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16364905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meredith M., Westberry J.M. Distinctive responses in the medial amygdala to same-species and different-species pheromones. J. Neurosci. 2004;24:5719–5725.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6729222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15215294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minami S., Kiyokawa Y., Takeuchi Y. The lateral intercalated cell mass of the amygdala is activated during social buffering of conditioned fear responses in male rats. Behav. Brain Res. 2019;372</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31260719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman S.W. The medial extended amygdala in male reproductive behavior a node in the mammalian social behavior network. Ann. NY Acad. Sci. 1999;877:242–257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10415653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paré D., Smith Y. The intercalated cell masses project to the central and medial nuclei of the amygdala in cats. Neuroscience. 1993;57:1077–1090.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8309544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrulis A. Chemosignals and hormones in the neural control of mammalian sexual behavior. Front. Neuroendocrinol. 2013;34:255–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23911848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rattay F., Bassereh H., Fellner A. Impact of electrode position on the elicitation of sodium spikes in retinal bipolar cells. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:17590.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5730545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29242502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Root C.M., Denny C.A., Hen R., Axel R. The participation of cortical amygdala in innate, odour-driven behaviour. Nature. 2014;515:269–273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4231015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuelsen C.L., Meredith M. Categorization of biologically relevant chemical signals in the medial amygdala. Brain Res. 2009;1263:33–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2798152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19368822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuelsen C.L., Meredith M. Oxytocin antagonist disrupts male mouse medial amygdala response to chemical-communication signals. Neuroscience. 2011;180:96–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3093756</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21333718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt-Hieber C., Bischofberger J. Fast sodium channel gating supports localized and efficient axonal action potential initiation. J. Neurosci. 2010;30:10233–10242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6633381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20668206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sosulski D.L., Lissitsyna Bloom M., Cutforth T., Axel R., Datta S.R. Distinct representations of olfactory information in different cortical centres. Nature. 2011;472:213–216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3354569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21451525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strobel C., Sullivan R.K.P., Stratton P., Sah P. Calcium signalling in medial intercalated cell dendrites and spines. J. Physiol. 2017;595:5653–5669.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5556156</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28594440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson J.M., Neugebauer V. Amygdala plasticity and pain. Pain Res. Manag. 2017;2017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5742506</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29302197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson J.A., Salcedo E., Restrepo D., Finger T.E. Second-order input to the medial amygdala from olfactory sensory neurons expressing the transduction channel TRPM5. J. Comp. Neurol. 2012;520:1819–1830.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3716388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22120520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y., He Z., Zhao C., Li L. Medial amygdala lesions modify aggressive behavior and immediate early gene expression in oxytocin and vasopressin neurons during intermale exposure. Behav. Brain Res. 2013;245:42–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23403283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westberry J.M., Meredith M. GABAergic mechanisms contributing to categorical amygdala responses to chemosensory signals. Neuroscience. 2016;331:186–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4955787</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27329335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westberry J.M., Meredith M. Characteristic response to chemosensory signals in gabaergic cells of medial amygdala is not driven by main olfactory input. Chem. Senses. 2017;42:13–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5155562</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27651427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winters B.L., Gregoriou G.C., Kissiwaa S.A., Wells O.A., Medagoda D.I., Hermes S.M., Burford N.T., Alt A., Aicher S.A., Bagley E.E. Endogenous opioids regulate moment-to-moment neuronal communication and excitability. Nat. Commun. 2017;8:14611.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5364458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28327612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood R.I., Coolen L.M. Integration of chemosensory and hormonal cues is essential for sexual behaviour in the male syrian hamster: role of the medial amygdaloid nucleus. Neuroscience. 1997;78:1027–1035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9174071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao S., Bergan J., Lanjuin A., Dulac C. Oxytocin signaling in the medial amygdala is required for sex discrimination of social cues. ELife. 2017;6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5768418</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29231812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zald D.H. The human amygdala and the emotional evaluation of sensory stimuli. Brain Res. Rev. 2003;41:88–123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12505650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zikopoulos B., Höistad M., John Y., Barbas H. Posterior orbitofrontal and anterior cingulate pathways to the amygdala target inhibitory and excitatory systems with opposite functions. J. Neurosci. 2017;37:5051–5064.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5444191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28411274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
