<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35194977</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2055-5822</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>ESC heart failure</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>ESC Heart Fail</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A comparison of drug-eluting stent and coronary artery bypass grafting in mildly to moderately ischemic heart failure.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1749</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1755</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1749-1755</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ehf2.13852</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The best revascularization strategy for patients with ischaemic heart failure (IHF) remains unclear. Current evidence and guidelines mainly focus on patients with severe ischaemic heart failure (ejection fraction [EF] &lt; 35%). There are limited data comparing clinical outcomes of coronary artery bypass grafting (CABG) with implantation of drug-eluting stents (DESs) in patients with mild to moderate ischaemic heart failure (EF 35-50%). It is therefore unknown whether percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) with DES implantation can provide comparable outcomes to CABG in these patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">From January 2016 to December 2017, we enrolled patients with mildly to moderately reduced EF (35-50%) who had undergone PCI with DESs or CABG. Patients with a history of CABG, presented with acute ST-elevation myocardial infarction (MI) or acute heart failure, and patients who had undergone CABG concomitant valvular or aortic surgery were excluded. Propensity score-matching analysis was performed between the two groups. Kaplan-Meier analysis and multivariate Cox proportional hazard regression were applied to assess all-cause mortality and individual end points. A total of 2050 patients (1330 PCIs and 720 CABGs) were included, and median follow-up was 45 months (interquartile range 40 to 54). There were significant differences in all-cause death between the two groups: 77 patients in the PCI group and 27 in the CABG group (DES vs. CABG: 5.8% vs. 3.8%, P = 0.045). After propensity score matching for the entire population, 601 matched pairs were obtained. The long-term cumulative rate of all-cause death was significantly different between the two groups (DES vs. CABG: 5.8% vs. 2.7%, P = 0.006). No differences were found in the rates of cardiac death (DES vs. CABG: 4.8% vs. 3.0%, P = 0.096), recurrent MI (DES vs. CABG: 4.0% vs. 2.8%, P = 0.234), and stroke (DES vs. CABG: 6.8% vs. 5.2%, P = 0.163). The rate of repeat coronary revascularization was significantly higher in the PCI group than in the CABG group (12.1% vs. 6.0%, P = 0.000).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Considering the higher long-term survival rate and lower repeat-revascularization rate, CABG may be superior to DES implantation in patients with mildly to moderately reduced EF (35-50%) and significant CAD.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. ESC Heart Failure published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of European Society of Cardiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kun</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Tianjin Medical University Graduate School, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Le</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hongliang</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jingxia</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuecheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yingyi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rui</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wenyu</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Qi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Tianjin Chest Hospital, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>ESC Heart Fail</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101669191</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2055-5822</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001026" MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary Artery Bypass</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054855" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug-Eluting Stents</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006333" MajorTopicYN="Y">Heart Failure</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062645" MajorTopicYN="Y">Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013318" MajorTopicYN="N">Stroke Volume</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronary artery bypass grafting</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug-eluting stent implantation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ischaemic heart failure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Revascularization</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35194977</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065860</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ehf2.13852</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hunt SA, Baker DW, Chin MH, Cinquegrani MP, Feldman AM, Francis GS, Ganiats TG, Goldstein S, Gregoratos G, Jessup ML, Noble RJ, Packer M, Silver MA, Stevenson LW, Gibbons RJ, Antman EM, Alpert JS, Faxon DP, Fuster V, Jacobs AK, Hiratzka LF, Russell RO, Smith SC Jr, 
American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association
. ACC/AHA guidelines for the evaluation and management of chronic heart failure in the adult: A report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association task force on practice guidelines (committee to revise the 1995 guidelines for the evaluation and Management of Heart Failure). J Am Coll Cardiol
2001; 38: 2101–2113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Velazquez EJ, Lee KL, Jones RH, Al‐Khalidi HR, Hill JA, Panza JA, Michler RE, Bonow RO, Doenst T, Petrie MC, Oh JK, She L, Moore VL, Desvigne‐Nickens P, Sopko G, Rouleau JL, 
STICHES Investigators
. Coronary‐artery bypass surgery in patients with ischemic cardiomyopathy. N Engl J Med
2016; 374: 1511–1520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4938005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27040723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wolff G, Dimitroulis D, Andreotti F, Kolodziejczak M, Jung C, Scicchitano P, Devito F, Zito A, Occhipinti M, Castiglioni B, Calveri G, Maisano F, Ciccone MM, De Servi S, Navarese EP. Survival benefits of invasive versus conservative strategies in heart failure in patients with reduced ejection fraction and coronary artery disease: A meta‐analysis. Circ Heart Fail
2017; 10: e003255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28087687</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wrobel K, Stevens SR, Jones RH, Selzman CH, Lamy A, Beaver TM, Djokovic LT, Wang N, Velazquez EJ, Sopko G, Kron IL, DiMaio JM, Michler RE, Lee KL, Yii M, Leng CY, Zembala M, Rouleau JL, Daly RC, Al‐Khalidi HR. Influence of baseline characteristics, operative conduct, and postoperative course on 30‐day outcomes of coronary artery bypass grafting among patients with left ventricular dysfunction: Results from the surgical treatment for ischemic heart failure (STICH) trial. Circulation
2015; 132: 720–730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4551105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26304663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nagendran J, Bozso SJ, Norris CM, McAlister FA, Appoo JJ, Moon MC, Freed DH, Nagendran J. Coronary artery bypass surgery improves outcomes in patients with diabetes and left ventricular dysfunction. J Am Coll Cardiol
2018; 71: 819–827.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29471931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yancy CW, Jessup M, Bozkurt B, Butler J, Casey DE Jr, Drazner MH, Fonarow GC, Geraci SA, Horwich T, Januzzi JL, Johnson MR, Kasper EK, Levy WC, Masoudi FA, McBride PE, McMurray JJV, Mitchell JE, Peterson PN, Riegel B, Sam F, Stevenson LW, Tang WHW, Tsai EJ, Wilkoff BL. 2013 ACCF/AHA guideline for the management of heart failure: Executive summary. A report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association task force on practice guidelines. Circulation
2017; 128: 1810–1852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fihn SD, Gardin JM, Abrams J, Berra K, Blankenship JC, Dallas AP, Douglas PS, Foody JM, Gerber TC, Hinderliter AL, King SB 3rd, Kligfield PD, Krumholz HM, Kwong RY, Lim MJ, Linderbaum JA, Mack MJ, Munger MA, Prager RL, Sabik JF, Shaw LJ, Sikkema JD, Smith CR Jr, Smith SC Jr, Spertus JA, Williams SV, 
American College of Cardiology Foundation
, 
American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines
, 
American College of Physicians
, 
American Association for Thoracic Surgery
, 
Preventive Cardiovascular Nurses Association
, 
Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions
, 
Society of Thoracic Surgeons
. 2017 ACCF/AHA/ACP/AATS/PCNA/SCAI/STS guideline for the diagnosis and management of patients with stable ischemic heart disease: A report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association task force on practice guidelines, and the American College of Physicians, American Association for Thoracic Surgery, preventive cardiovascular nurses association, Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions, and Society of Thoracic Surgeons. J Am Coll Cardiol
2017; 60: e44–e164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Neumann FJ, Sousa‐Uva M, Ahlsson A, Alfonso F, Banning AP, Benedetto U, Byrne RA, Collet JP, Falk V, Head SJ, Jüni P, Kastrati A, Koller A, Kristensen SD, Niebauer J, Richter DJ, Seferović PM, Sibbing D, Stefanini GG, Windecker S, Yadav R, Zembala MO, 
ESC Scientific Document Group
, Wijns W, Glineur D, Aboyans V, Achenbach S, Agewall S, Andreotti F, Barbato E, Baumbach A, Brophy J, Bueno H, Calvert PA, Capodanno D, Davierwala PM, Delgado V, Dudek D, Freemantle N, Funck‐Brentano C, Gaemperli O, Gielen S, Gilard M, Gorenek B, Haasenritter J, Haude M, Ibanez B, Iung B, Jeppsson A, Katritsis D, Knuuti J, Kolh P, Leite‐Moreira A, Lund LH, Maisano F, Mehilli J, Metzler B, Montalescot G, Pagano D, Petronio AS, Piepoli MF, Popescu BA, Sádaba R, Shlyakhto E, Silber S, Simpson IA, Sparv D, Tavilla G, Thiele H, Tousek P, van Belle E, Vranckx P, Witkowski A, Zamorano JL, Roffi M, Windecker S, Aboyans V, Agewall S, Barbato E, Bueno H, Coca A, Collet JP, Coman IM, Dean V, Delgado V, Fitzsimons D, Gaemperli O, Hindricks G, Iung B, Jüni P, Katus HA, Knuuti J, Lancellotti P, Leclercq C, McDonagh TA, Piepoli MF, Ponikowski P, Richter DJ, Roffi M, Shlyakhto E, Sousa‐Uva M, Simpson IA, Zamorano JL, Pagano D, Freemantle N, Sousa‐Uva M, Chettibi M, Sisakian H, Metzler B, İbrahimov F, Stelmashok VI, Postadzhiyan A, Skoric B, Eftychiou C, Kala P, Terkelsen CJ, Magdy A, Eha J, Niemelä M, Kedev S, Motreff P, Aladashvili A, Mehilli J, Kanakakis IG, Becker D, Gudnason T, Peace A, Romeo F, Bajraktari G, Kerimkulova A, Rudzītis A, Ghazzal Z, Kibarskis A, Pereira B, Xuereb RG, Hofma SH, Steigen TK, Witkowski A, de Oliveira EI, Mot S, Duplyakov D, Zavatta M, Beleslin B, Kovar F, Bunc M, Ojeda S, Witt N, Jeger R, Addad F, Akdemir R, Parkhomenko A, Henderson R. ESC scientific document group. 2018 ESC/EACTS guidelines on myocardial revascularization. Eur Heart J
2019; 40: 87–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mohr FW, Morice MC, Kappetein AP, Feldman TE, Stahle E, Colombo A, Mack MJ, Holmes DR, Morel MA, Van Dyck N, Houle VM, Dawkins KD, Serruys PW. Coronary artery bypass graft surgery versus percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with three‐vessel disease and left main coronary disease: 5‐year follow‐up of the randomised, clinical SYNTAX trial. Lancet
2013; 381: 629–638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23439102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Coles JG, Del Campo C, Ahmed SN, Corpus R, MacDonald AC, Goldbach MM, Coles JC. Improved long‐term survival following myocardial revascularization in patients with severe left ventricular dysfunction. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg
1981; 81: 846–850.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6971965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zubiate P, Kay JH, Mendez AM. Myocardial revascularization for the patient with drastic impairment of function of the left ventricle. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg
1977; 73: 84–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">831011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Islamoglu F, Apaydin AZ, Posacioglu H, Ozbaran M, Hamulu A, Buket S, Telli A, Durmaz I. Coronary artery bypass grafting in patients with poor left ventricular function. Jpn Heart J
2002; 43: 343–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12227710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nagendran J, Norris CM, Graham MM, Ross DB, Macarthur RG, Kieser TM, Maitland AM, Southern D, Meyer SR. Coronary revascularization for patients with severe left ventricular dysfunction. Ann Thorac Surg
2013; 96: 2038–2044.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23968761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Caines AE, Massad MG, Kpodonu J, Rebeiz AG, Evans A, Geha AS. Outcomes of coronary artery bypass grafting versus percutaneous coronary intervention and medical therapy for multivessel disease with and without left ventricular dysfunction. Cardiology
2004; 101: 21–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14988623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Paolini G, Zuccari M, Mariani MA, Di Credico G, Pocar M, Galli L, Grossi A. Myocardial revascularization in patients with severe ischaemic left ventricular dysfunction: A clinical experience. Cardiovasc Surg
1994; 2: 88–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8049933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mickleborough LL, Maruyama H, Takagi Y, Mohamed S, Sun Z, Ebisuzaki L. Results of revascularization in patients with severe left ventricular dysfunction. Circulation
1995; 92: 73–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Louagie Y, Jamart J, Buche M, Eucher P, Haxhe JP, Lhommel R, Schoevaerdts D, Gonzalez M, Marchandise B, Schoevaerdts JC. Myocardial revascularization for severe left ventricular dysfunction: Factors influencing early and late survival. Cardiovasc Surg
1996; 4: 607–616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8909818</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bouchart F, Tabley A, Litzler PY, Haas‐Hubscher C, Bessou JP, Soyer R. Myocardial revascularization in patients with severe ischemic left ventricular dysfunction: Long term follow‐up in 141 patients. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg
2001; 20: 1157–1162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11717021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kappetein AP, Head SJ, Morice MC, Banning AP, Serruys PW, Mohr FW, Dawkins KD, Mack MJ, 
SYNTAX Investigators
. Treatment of complex coronary artery disease in patients with diabetes: 5‐year results comparing outcomes of bypass surgery and percutaneous coronary intervention in the SYNTAX trial. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg
2013; 43: 1006–1013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23413014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lee SE, Lee H‐Y, Cho H, Choe WS, Kim H, Choi JO, Jeon ES, Kim MS, Hwang KK, Chae SC, Baek SH, Kang SM, Choi DJ, Yoo BS, Kim KH, Cho MC, Kim JJ, Oh BH. Coronary artery bypass graft versus percutaneous coronary intervention in acute heart failure. Heart
2020; 106: 50–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6952823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Iribarne A, DiScipio AW, Leavitt BJ, Baribeau YR, McCullough JN, Weldner PW, Huang YL, Robich MP, Clough RA, Sardella GL, Olmstead EM, Malenka DJ. Comparative effectiveness of coronary artery bypass grafting versus percutaneous coronary intervention in a real‐world surgical treatment for ischemic heart failure trial population. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg
2018; 156: 1410–1421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29961592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bangalore S, Guo Y, Samadashvili Z, Blecker S, Hannan EL. Revascularization in patients with multivessel coronary artery disease and severe left ventricular systolic dysfunction: Everolimus‐eluting stents versus coronary artery bypass graft surgery. Circulation
2016; 133: 2132–2214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6330114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27151532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Park SJ, Ahn JM, Kim YH, Park DW, Yun SC, Lee JY, Kang SJ, Lee SW, Lee CW, Park SW, Choo SJ, Chung CH, Lee JW, Cohen DJ, Yeung AC, Hur SH, Seung KB, Ahn TH, Kwon HM, Lim DS, Rha SW, Jeong MH, Lee BK, Tresukosol D, Fu GS, Ong TK, 
BEST Trial Investigators
. Trial of everolimus‐eluting stents or bypass surgery for coronary disease. N Engl J Med
2015; 372: 1204–1212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25774645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Head SJ, Milojevic M, Daemen J, Ahn JM, Boersma E, Christiansen EH, Domanski MJ, Farkouh ME, Flather M, Fuster V, Hlatky MA, Holm NR, Hueb WA, Kamalesh M, Kim YH, Makikallio T, Mohr FW, Papageorgiou G, Park SJ, Rodriguez AE, Sabik JF III, Stables RH, Stone GW, Serruys PW, Kappetein AP. Mortality after coronary artery bypass grafting versus percutaneous coronary intervention with stenting for coronary artery disease: A pooled analysis of individual patient data. Lancet
2018; 391: 939–948.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chang M, Ahn JM, Lee CW, Cavalcante R, Sotomi Y, Onuma Y, Tenekecioglu E, Han M, Park DW, Kang SJ, Lee SW, Kim YH, Park SW, Serruys PW, Park SJ. Long‐term mortality after coronary revascularization in nondiabetic patients with multivessel disease. J Am Coll Cardiol
2016; 68: 29–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27364047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
