<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35213059</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1528-1167</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>63</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Epilepsia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Epilepsia</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Novel lissencephaly-associated DCX variants in the C-terminal DCX domain affect microtubule binding and dynamics.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1253</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1265</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1253-1265</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/epi.17198</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Pathogenic variants in DCX on the X chromosome lead to lissencephaly and subcortical band heterotopia (SBH), brain malformations caused by neuronal migration defects. Its product doublecortin (DCX) binds to microtubules to modulate microtubule polymerization. How pathogenic DCX variants affect these activities remains not fully investigated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">DCX variants were identified using whole exome and Sanger sequencing from six families with lissencephaly/SBH. We examined how these variants affect DCX functions using microtubule binding, regrowth, and colocalization assays.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We found novel DCX variants p.Val177AlafsTer31 and p.Gly188Trp, as well as reported variants p.Arg196His, p.Lys202Met, and p.Thr203Ala. Incidentally, all of the missense variants were clustered on the C-terminal DCX domain. The microtubule binding ability was significantly decreased in p.Val177AlafsTer31, p.Gly188Trp, p.Lys202Met, and previously reported p.Asp262Gly variants. Furthermore, expression of p.Val177AlafsTer31, p.Gly188Trp, p.Arg196His, p.Lys202Met, and p.Asp262Gly variants hindered microtubule growth in cells. There were also decreases in the colocalization of p.Val177AlafsTer31, p.Thr203Ala, and p.Asp262Gly variants to microtubules.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results indicate that these variants in the C-terminal DCX domain altered microtubule binding and dynamics, which may underlie neuronal migration defects during brain development.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 International League Against Epilepsy.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun-Ru</ForeName>
            <Initials>JR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, College of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ju-Fang</ForeName>
            <Initials>JF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Neurology, Changhua Christian Hospital, Changhua, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yo-Tsen</ForeName>
            <Initials>YT</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5902-3870</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, College of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, College of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Epilepsy, Neurological Institute, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Brain Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hsu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ting-Rong</ForeName>
            <Initials>TR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, College of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kao-Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>KM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatric Neurology, Chiayi Christian Hospital, Chiayi, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Functional Neurosurgery, Xiamen Humanity Hospital, Xiamen, Fujian, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chien</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, College of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Epilepsy, Neurological Institute, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chia-Ling</ForeName>
            <Initials>CL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Chiayi Christian Hospital, Chiayi, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Meng-Han</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4570-5712</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, Chang Gung University, Taoyuan, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kaohsiung Chang Gung Memorial Hospital and Chang Gung University College of Medicine, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jin-Wu</ForeName>
            <Initials>JW</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0135-759X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Brain Science, College of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Brain Research Center, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biological Science and Technology, College of Biological Science and Technology, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Epilepsia</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>2983306R</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0013-9580</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000089622">Doublecortin Domain Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000089662">Doublecortin Protein</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D008869">Microtubule-Associated Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D009479">Neuropeptides</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054221" MajorTopicYN="Y">Classical Lissencephalies and Subcortical Band Heterotopias</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000089622" MajorTopicYN="N">Doublecortin Domain Proteins</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000089662" MajorTopicYN="N">Doublecortin Protein</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lissencephaly</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008869" MajorTopicYN="N">Microtubule-Associated Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008870" MajorTopicYN="N">Microtubules</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009479" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuropeptides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DCX</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">doublecortin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epilepsy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lissencephaly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microtubule binding protein</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuronal migration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subcortical band heterotopia</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35213059</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.17198</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Portes VD, Pinard JM, Billuart P, Vinet MC, Koulakoff A, Carrié A, et al. A novel CNS gene required for neuronal migration and involved in X-linked subcortical laminar heterotopia and lissencephaly syndrome. Cell. 1998;92(1):51-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francis F, Koulakoff A, Boucher D, Chafey P, Schaar B, Vinet M-C, et al. Doublecortin is a developmentally regulated, microtubule-associated protein expressed in migrating and differentiating neurons. Neuron. 1999;23:247-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pilz DT, Kuc J, Matsumoto N, Bodurtha J, Bernadi B, Tassinari CA, et al. Subcortical band heterotopia in rare affected males can be caused by missense mutations in DCX (XLIS) or LIS1. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8(9):1757-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haverfield EV, Whited AJ, Petras KS, Dobyns WB, Das S. Intragenic deletions and duplications of the LIS1 and DCX genes: a major disease-causing mechanism in lissencephaly and subcortical band heterotopia. Eur J Hum Genet. 2009;17(7):911-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavone L, Rizzo R, Dobyns WB. Clinical manifestations and evaluation of isolated lissencephaly. Childs Nerv Syst. 1993;9:387-90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buchsbaum IY, Cappello S. Neuronal migration in the CNS during development and disease: insights from in vivo and in vitro models. Development. 2019;146:dev163766.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto N, Leventer RJ, Kuc JA, Mewborn SK, Dudlicek LL, Ramocki MB, et al. Mutation analysis of the DCX gene and genotype/phenotype correlation in subcortical band heterotopia. Eur J Hum Genet. 2001;9:5-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai M-H, Kuo P-W, Myers CT, Li S-W, Lin W-C, Fu T-Y, et al. A novel DCX missense mutation in a family with X-linked lissencephaly and subcortical band heterotopia syndrome inherited from a low-level somatic mosaic mother: genetic and functional studies. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2016;20:788-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim MH, Cierpicki T, Derewenda U, Krowarsch D, Feng Y, Devedjiev Y, et al. The DCX-domain tandems of doublecortin and doublecortin-like kinase. Nat Struct Biol. 2003;10:324-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sapir T, Horesh D, Caspi M, Atlas R, Burgess HA, Wolf SG, et al. Doublecortin mutations cluster in evolutionarily conserved functional domains. Hum Mol Genet. 2000;9(5):703-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai MH, Chan CK, Chang YC, Yu YT, Chuang ST, Fan WL, et al. DEPDC5 mutations in familial and sporadic focal epilepsy. Clin Genet. 2017;92:397-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang WJ, Tay HG, Soni R, Perumal GS, Goll MG, Macaluso FP, et al. CEP162 is an axoneme-recognition protein promoting ciliary transition zone assembly at the cilia base. Nat Cell Biol. 2013;15(6):591-601.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang HY, Cheng HY, Tsao AN, Liu C, Tsai JW. Multiple functions of KBP in neural development underlie brain anomalies in Goldberg-Shprintzen syndrome. Front Mol Neurosci. 2019;12:265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demelas L, Serra G, Conti M, Achene A, Mastropaolo C, Matsumoto N, et al. Incomplete penetrance with normal MRI in a woman with germline mutation of the DCX gene. Neurology. 2001;57(2):327-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng J-F, Ou Y-H, Lio M-L, Yang R-C, Chang T-M, Chang M-Y, et al. Identifying a novel DCX mutation in a Taiwanese boy with lissencephaly: a case report the Changhua. J Med. 2020;18:134-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gleeson JG, Lin PT, Flanagan LA, Walsh CA. Doublecortin is a microtubule-associated protein and is expressed widely by migrating neurons. Neuron. 1999;23(2):257-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horesh D, Sapir T, Francis F, Wolf SG, Caspi M, Elbaum M, et al. Doublecortin, a stabilizer of microtubules. Hum Mol Genet. 1999;8(9):1599-610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sholl DA. Dendritic organization in the neurons of the visual and motor cortices of the cat. J Anat. 1953;87:387-406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leventer RJ. Genotype-phenotype correlation in lissencephaly and subcortical band heterotopia: the key questions answered. J Child Neurol. 2005;20:307-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahi-Buisson N, Souville I, Fourniol FJ, Toussaint A, Moores CA, Houdusse A, et al. New insights into genotype-phenotype correlations for the doublecortin-related lissencephaly spectrum. Brain. 2013;136:223-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aigner L, Uyanik G, Couillard-Despres S, Ploetz S, Wolff G, Morris-Rosendahl D, et al. Somatic mosaicism and variable penetrance in doublecortin-associated migration disorders. Neurology. 2003;60(2):329-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gleeson JG, Minnerath S, Kuzniecky RI, Dobyns WB, Young ID, Ross ME, et al. Somatic and germline mosaic mutations in the doublecortin gene are associated with variable phenotypes. Am J Hum Genet. 2000;67(3):574-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aiken J, Moore JK, Bates EA. TUBA1A mutations identified in lissencephaly patients dominantly disrupt neuronal migration and impair dynein activity. Hum Mol Genet. 2019;15(28):1227-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belvindrah R, Natarajan K, Shabajee P, Bruel-Jungerman E, Bernard J, Goutierre M, et al. Mutation of the alpha-tubulin Tuba1a leads to straighter microtubules and perturbs neuronal migration. J Cell Biol. 2017;216(8):2443-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos SI, Makeyev EV, Salierno M, Kodama T, Kawakami Y, Sahara S. Tuba8 drives differentiation of cortical radial glia into apical intermediate progenitors by tuning modifications of tubulin C termini. Dev Cell. 2020;24(52):477-91.e8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun A, Breuss M, Salzer MC, Flint J, Cowan NJ, Keays DA. Tuba8 is expressed at low levels in the developing mouse and human brain. Am J Hum Genet. 2010;86:819-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breuss M, Morandell J, Nimpf S, Gstrein T, Lauwers M, Hochstoeger T, et al. The expression of Tubb2b undergoes a developmental transition in murine cortical neurons. J Comp Neurol. 2015;523:2161-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oegema R, Barkovich AJ, Mancini GMS, Guerrini R, Dobyns WB. Subcortical heterotopic gray matter brain malformations: classification study of 107 individuals. Neurology. 2019;93(14):e1360-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dentici ML, Maglione V, Agolini E, Catena G, Capolino R, Lanari V, et al. TUBB3 E410K syndrome: case report and review of the clinical spectrum of TUBB3 mutations. Am J Med Genet A. 2020;182:1977-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
