<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35212003</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>65</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Explanatory factors of dynamic balance impairment in myotonic dystrophy type 1.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>683</StartPage>
          <EndPage>687</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>683-687</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27527</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Myotonic dystrophy type 1 (DM1) is a neuromuscular disease affecting many systems and for which muscle weakness is one of the cardinal symptoms. People with DM1 also present with balance-related impairments and high fall risk. The aim of this study was to explore explanatory factors of dynamic balance impairment in the DM1 population.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A secondary analysis of data collected as part of a larger study was performed. The Mini Balance Evaluation System Test (Mini-BESTest) was used to assess dynamic balance. Age, sex, and CTG repeat length in blood were retrieved from medical records and research files. The maximal isometric muscle strength of five lower limb muscle groups (hip flexors and extensors, knee flexors and extensors, and ankle dorsiflexors) was quantitatively assessed as well as fatigue. Standard multiple regression analysis was used.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifty-two individuals (31 men) aged between 24 and 81 years were included. The final model explains 65.9% of the balance score; ankle dorsiflexor muscle strength was the strongest explanatory factor, followed by CTG repeat length, age and fatigue to a lesser extent.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Dynamic balance is impaired in people with DM1. Results of this study suggest that rehabilitation interventions aimed at improving strength of the ankle dorsiflexors and managing fatigue could help to improve dynamic balance in this specific population.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bélair</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unité d'enseignement en physiothérapie, Département des sciences de la santé, Université du Québec à Chicoutimi, Chicoutimi, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Côté</LastName>
            <ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Groupe de recherche interdisciplinaire sur les maladies neuromusculaires (GRIMN), Centre intégré universitaire de santé et de services sociaux du Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean, Hôpital de Jonquière, Jonquière, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gagnon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cynthia</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Groupe de recherche interdisciplinaire sur les maladies neuromusculaires (GRIMN), Centre intégré universitaire de santé et de services sociaux du Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean, Hôpital de Jonquière, Jonquière, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre de recherche du Centre hospitalier universitaire de Sherbrooke (CR-CHUS), Sherbrooke, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculté de médecine et des sciences de la santé, Université de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre intersectoriel en santé durable (CISD), Université du Québec à Chicoutimi, Chicoutimi, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mathieu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Groupe de recherche interdisciplinaire sur les maladies neuromusculaires (GRIMN), Centre intégré universitaire de santé et de services sociaux du Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean, Hôpital de Jonquière, Jonquière, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculté de médecine et des sciences de la santé, Université de Sherbrooke, Sherbrooke, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Duchesne</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elise</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9953-8315</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unité d'enseignement en physiothérapie, Département des sciences de la santé, Université du Québec à Chicoutimi, Chicoutimi, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Groupe de recherche interdisciplinaire sur les maladies neuromusculaires (GRIMN), Centre intégré universitaire de santé et de services sociaux du Saguenay-Lac-Saint-Jean, Hôpital de Jonquière, Jonquière, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre intersectoriel en santé durable (CISD), Université du Québec à Chicoutimi, Chicoutimi, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre de recherche Charles-Le Moyne (CRCLM), Sherbrooke, Québec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053580" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Strength</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018908" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle Weakness</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009223" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myotonic Dystrophy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">balance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">explanatory factors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quantitative muscle testing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35212003</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27527</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petitclerc E, Hébert LJ, Mathieu J, Desrosiers J, Gagnon C. Lower limb muscle strength impairment in late-onset and adult myotonic dystrophy type 1 phenotypes. Muscle Nerve. 2017;56(1):57-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagnon C, Petitclerc É, Kierkegaard M, Mathieu J, Duchesne É, Hébert LJ. A 9-year follow-up study of quantitative muscle strength changes in myotonic dystrophy type 1. J Neurol. 2018;265(7):1698-1705.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammaren E et al. Factors of importance for dynamic balance impairment and frequency of falls in individuals with myotonic dystrophy type 1 - a cross-sectional study - including reference values of timed up &amp; go, 10m walk and step test. Neuromuscul Disord. 2014;24(3):207-215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petitclerc E, Hébert LJ, Mathieu J, Desrosiers J, Gagnon C. Relationships between lower limb muscle strength impairments and physical limitations in DM1. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;5(2):215-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berends J, Tieleman AA, Horlings CGC, et al. High incidence of falls in patients with myotonic dystrophy type 1 and 2: a prospective study. Neuromuscul Disord. 2019;29(10):758-765.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagnon C, Heatwole C, Hébert LJ, et al. Report of the third outcome measures in myotonic dystrophy type 1 (OMMYD-3) international workshop Paris, France, June 8, 2015. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;5(4):523-537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duchesne E, Hébert LJ, Mathieu J, Côté I, Roussel MP, Gagnon C. Validity of the mini-BESTest in adults with myotonic dystrophy type 1. Muscle Nerve. 2020;62(1):95-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tremblay M, Muslemani S, Côté I, Gagnon C, Fortin J, Gallais B. Accomplishment of instrumental activities of daily living and its relationship with cognitive functions in adults with myotonic dystrophy type 1 childhood phenotype: an exploratory study. BMC Psychol. 2021;9(1):56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Heugten C et al. Participation and the role of neuropsychological functioning in Myotonic dystrophy type 1. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;5(2):205-214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujino H, Shingaki H, Suwazono S, et al. Cognitive impairment and quality of life in patients with myotonic dystrophy type 1. Muscle Nerve. 2018;57(5):742-748.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallais B, Gagnon C, Mathieu J, Richer L. Cognitive decline over time in adults with myotonic dystrophy type 1: a 9-year longitudinal study. Neuromuscul Disord. 2017;27(1):61-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winblad S, Samuelsson L, Lindberg C, Meola G. Cognition in myotonic dystrophy type 1: a 5-year follow-up study. Eur J Neurol. 2016;23:1471-1476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallais B, Montreuil M, Gargiulo M, Eymard B, Gagnon C, Laberge L. Prevalence and correlates of apathy in myotonic dystrophy type 1. BMC Neurol. 2015;15:148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laberge L, Gagnon C, Dauvilliers Y. Daytime sleepiness and myotonic dystrophy. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2013;13(4):340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raymond K, Levasseur M, Mathieu J, Gagnon C. Progressive decline in daily and social activities: a 9-year longitudinal study of participation in myotonic dystrophy type 1. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2019;100(9):1629-1639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raymond K, Levasseur M, Mathieu J, Desrosiers J, Gagnon C. A 9-year follow-up study of the natural progression of upper limb performance in myotonic dystrophy type 1: a similar decline for phenotypes but not for gender. Neuromuscul Disord. 2017;27(7):673-682.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogan C, de Antonio M, Hamroun D, et al. Gender as a modifying factor influencing Myotonic dystrophy type 1 phenotype severity and mortality: a Nationwide multiple databases cross-sectional observational study. PLoS One. 2016;11(2):e0148264.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu YH, Pizzuti A, Fenwick RG Jr, et al. An unstable triplet repeat in a gene related to myotonic muscular dystrophy. Science. 1992;255(5049):1256-1258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathieu J, Boivin H, Meunier D, Gaudreault M, Begin P. Assessment of a disease-specific muscular impairment rating scale in myotonic dystrophy. Neurology. 2001;56(3):336-340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindeman E, Leffers P, Reulen J, Spaans F, Drukker J. Quadriceps strength and timed motor performances in myotonic dystrophy, Charcot-Marie-tooth disease, and healthy subjects. Clin Rehabil. 1998;12(2):127-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiles CM et al. Falls and stumbles in myotonic dystrophy. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2006;77(3):393-396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hebert LJ et al. Isometric muscle strength in youth assessed by hand-held dynamometry: a feasibility, reliability, and validity study. Pediatr Phys Ther. 2011;23(3):289-299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roussel MP, Fiset MM, Gauthier L, et al. Assessment of muscular strength and functional capacity in the juvenile and adult myotonic dystrophy type 1 population: a 3-year follow-up study. J Neurol. 2021;268:4221-4237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roussel MP, Hébert LJ, Duchesne E. Strength-training effectively alleviates skeletal muscle impairments in myotonic dystrophy type 1. Neuromuscul Disord. 2020;30(4):283-293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roussel MP, Hébert LJ, Duchesne E. Intra-rater reliability and concurrent validity of quantified muscle testing for maximal knee extensors strength in men with Myotonic dystrophy type 1. J Neuromuscul Dis. 2019;6(2):233-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimoto M, Hsu WL, Woollacott MH, Chou LS. Ankle dorsiflexor strength relates to the ability to restore balance during a backward support surface translation. Gait Posture. 2013;38(4):812-817.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mateos-Aierdi AJ et al. Muscle wasting in myotonic dystrophies: a model of premature aging. Front Aging Neurosci. 2015;7:125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salzman B. Gait and balance disorders in older adults. Am Fam Physician. 2010;82(1):61-68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thornton CA. Myotonic dystrophy. Neurol Clin. 2014;32(3):705-719. viii.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Antonio M et al. Unravelling the myotonic dystrophy type 1 clinical spectrum: a systematic registry-based study with implications for disease classification. Rev Neurol (Paris). 2016;172(10):572-580.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagnon C, Mathieu J, Jean S, et al. Predictors of disrupted social participation in myotonic dystrophy type 1. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2008;89(7):1246-1255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veenhuizen Y, Satink T, Graff MJL, et al. Mixed methods evaluation of a self-management group programme for patients with neuromuscular disease and chronic fatigue. BMJ Open. 2021;11(8):e048890.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
