<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35218176</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1437-4331</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>60</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical chemistry and laboratory medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Chem Lab Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The value proposition of integrative diagnostics for (early) detection of cancer. On behalf of the EFLM interdisciplinary Task and Finish Group "CNAPS/CTC for early detection of cancer".</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>821</StartPage>
          <EndPage>829</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>821-829</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/cclm-2022-0129</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Disruptive imaging and laboratory technologies can improve clinical decision processes and outcomes in oncology. However, certain obstacles must be overcome before these technologies can be fully implemented as part of the standard for care. An integrative diagnostic approach represents a unique opportunity to unleash the full diagnostic potential and paves the way towards personalized cancer diagnostics. To meet this demand, an interdisciplinary Task Force of the EFLM was initiated as a consequence of an EFLM/ESR during the CELME 2019 meeting in order to evaluate the clinical value of CNAPS/CTC (circulating nucleic acids in plasma and serum/circulating tumor cells) in early detection of cancer. Here, an overview of current disruptive techniques, their clinical implications and potential value of an integrative diagnostic approach is provided. Furthermore, requirements such as the establishment of diagnostic tumor boards, development of adequate software solutions and a change of mindset towards a new generation of diagnosticians providing actionable health information are presented. This development has the potential to elevate the position and clinical recognition of diagnosticians.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Walter de Gruyter GmbH, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Froelich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Matthias F</ForeName>
            <Initials>MF</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8501-2147</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Nuclear Medicine, University Medicine Mannheim, Medical Faculty Mannheim of the University of Heidelberg, Mannheim, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Capoluongo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ettore</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine and Medical Biotechnologies, University of Naples Federico II, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CEINGE-Biotecnologie Avanzate, Napoli, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kovacs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zsolt</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Clinical County Emergency Hospital, Targu-Mures, Romania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Patton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simon J</ForeName>
            <Initials>SJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>EMQN CIC, Manchester Science Park, Manchester, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lianidou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Evi S</ForeName>
            <Initials>ES</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Analysis of Circulating Tumor Cells Lab, Laboratory of Analytical Chemistry, University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Haselmann</LastName>
            <ForeName>Verena</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8380-6581</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Faculty Mannheim of the University of Heidelberg, Institute of Clinical Chemistry, University Hospital Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Chem Lab Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9806306</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1434-6621</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014408">Biomarkers, Tumor</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014408" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers, Tumor</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055088" MajorTopicYN="Y">Early Detection of Cancer</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009360" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplastic Cells, Circulating</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">circulating tumor cells (CTC)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">colorectal cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">ctDNA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">integrative diagnostics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">liquid biopsy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35218176</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/cclm-2022-0129</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">cclm-2022-0129</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siegel, RL, Miller, KD, Jemal, A. Cancer statistics, 2020. CA Cancer J Clin 2020;70:7–30. https://doi.org/10.3322/caac.21590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alix-Panabieres, C, Pantel, K. Liquid biopsy: from discovery to clinical application. Cancer Discov 2021;11:858–73. https://doi.org/10.1158/2159-8290.cd-20-1311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tie, J, Wang, Y, Tomasetti, C, Li, L, Springer, S, Kinde, I, et al.. Circulating tumor DNA analysis detects minimal residual disease and predicts recurrence in patients with stage II colon cancer. Sci Transl Med 2016;8:346ra92. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.aaf6219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, G, Peng, J, Xiao, Q, Wu, HX, Wu, X, Wang, F, et al.. Postoperative circulating tumor DNA as markers of recurrence risk in stages II to III colorectal cancer. J Hematol Oncol 2021;14:80. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13045-021-01089-z.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taniguchi, H, Nakamura, Y, Kotani, D, Yukami, H, Mishima, S, Sawada, K, et al.. CIRCULATE-Japan: circulating tumor DNA-guided adaptive platform trials to refine adjuvant therapy for colorectal cancer. Cancer Sci 2021;112:2915–20. https://doi.org/10.1111/cas.14926.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haselmann, V, Gebhardt, C, Brechtel, I, Duda, A, Czerwinski, C, Sucker, A, et al.. Liquid profiling of circulating tumor DNA in plasma of melanoma patients for companion diagnostics and monitoring of BRAF inhibitor therapy. Clin Chem 2018;64:830–42. https://doi.org/10.1373/clinchem.2017.281543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reinert, T, Scholer, LV, Thomsen, R, Tobiasen, H, Vang, S, Nordentoft, I, et al.. Analysis of circulating tumour DNA to monitor disease burden following colorectal cancer surgery. Gut 2016;65:625–34. https://doi.org/10.1136/gutjnl-2014-308859.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montagut, C, Dalmases, A, Bellosillo, B, Crespo, M, Pairet, S, Iglesias, M, et al.. Identification of a mutation in the extracellular domain of the epidermal growth factor receptor conferring cetuximab resistance in colorectal cancer. Nat Med 2012;18:221–3. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm.2609.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonanno, L, Pavan, A, Ferro, A, Calvetti, L, Frega, S, Pasello, G, et al.. Clinical impact of plasma and tissue next-generation sequencing in advanced non-small cell lung cancer: a real-world experience. Oncologist 2020;25:e1996–2005. https://doi.org/10.1634/theoncologist.2020-0148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jee, J, Lebow, ES, Murciano-Goroff, YR, Jayakumaran, G, Shen, R, Brannon, AR, et al.. Overall survival with circulating tumor DNA-guided therapy in advanced non-small cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol 2021;39:9009. https://doi.org/10.1200/jco.2021.39.15_suppl.9009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parseghian, CM, Loree, JM, Morris, VK, Liu, X, Clifton, KK, Napolitano, S, et al.. Anti-EGFR-resistant clones decay exponentially after progression: implications for anti-EGFR re-challenge. Ann Oncol 2019;30:243–9. https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mdy509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal, C, Thompson, JC, Black, TA, Katz, SI, Fan, R, Yee, SS, et al.. Clinical implications of plasma-based genotyping with the delivery of personalized therapy in metastatic non-small cell lung cancer. JAMA Oncol 2019;5:173–80. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2018.4305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldberg, SB, Narayan, A, Kole, AJ, Decker, RH, Teysir, J, Carriero, NJ, et al.. Early assessment of lung cancer immunotherapy response via circulating tumor DNA. Clin Cancer Res 2018;24:1872–80. https://doi.org/10.1158/1078-0432.ccr-17-1341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scherer, F, Kurtz, DM, Newman, AM, Stehr, H, Craig, AF, Esfahani, MS, et al.. Distinct biological subtypes and patterns of genome evolution in lymphoma revealed by circulating tumor DNA. Sci Transl Med 2016;8:364ra155. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.aai8545.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fugger, K, Hewitt, G, West, SC, Boulton, SJ. Tackling PARP inhibitor resistance. Trends Cancer 2021;7:1102–18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trecan.2021.08.007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoon, JH, Lee, JM, Chang, W, Kang, HJ, Bandos, A, Lim, HJ, et al.. Initial M staging of rectal cancer: FDG PET/MRI with a hepatocyte-specific contrast agent vs. contrast-enhanced CT. Radiology 2020;294:310–9. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2019190794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margel, D, Bernstine, H, Groshar, D, Ber, Y, Nezrit, O, Segal, N, et al.. Diagnostic performance of (68)Ga prostate-specific membrane antigen PET/MRI compared with multiparametric MRI for detecting clinically significant prostate cancer. Radiology 2021;301:379–86. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2021204093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belmouhand, M, Lofgren, J, Johannesen, HH, Baeksgaard, L, Gutte, H, Tariq, K, et al.. Early response evaluation of neoadjuvant therapy with PET/MRI to predict resectability in patients with adenocarcinoma of the esophagogastric junction. Abdom Radiol 2019;44:836–44. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00261-018-1841-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IJzerman, MJ, de Boer, J, Azad, A, Degeling, K, Geoghegan, J, Hewitt, C, et al.. Towards routine implementation of liquid biopsies in cancer management: it is always too early, until suddenly it is too late. Diagnostics 2021;11:103. https://doi.org/10.3390/diagnostics11010103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nero, C, Ciccarone, F, Boldrini, L, Lenkowicz, J, Paris, I, Capoluongo, ED, et al.. Germline BRCA 1-2 status prediction through ovarian ultrasound images radiogenomics: a hypothesis generating study (PROBE study). Sci Rep 2020;10:16511. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-73505-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diehl, F, Li, M, He, Y, Kinzler, KW, Vogelstein, B, Dressman, D. BEAMing: single-molecule PCR on microparticles in water-in-oil emulsions. Nat Methods 2006;3:551–9. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth898.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo, A, Incorvaia, L, Del Re, M, Malapelle, U, Capoluongo, E, Gristina, V, et al.. The molecular profiling of solid tumors by liquid biopsy: a position paper of the AIOM-SIAPEC-IAP-SIBioC-SIC-SIF Italian Scientific Societies. ESMO Open 2021;6:100164. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esmoop.2021.100164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siravegna, G, Mussolin, B, Buscarino, M, Corti, G, Cassingena, A, Crisafulli, G, et al.. Clonal evolution and resistance to EGFR blockade in the blood of colorectal cancer patients. Nat Med 2015;21:827. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm0715-827b.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedtke, M, Pessoa Rejas, R, Froelich, MF, Ast, V, Duda, A, Mirbach, L, et al.. Liquid profiling of circulating tumor DNA in colorectal cancer: steps needed to achieve its full clinical value as standard care. Mol Oncol 2021. https://doi.org/10.1002/1878-0261.13156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Z, Duan, J, Cai, S, Han, M, Dong, H, Zhao, J, et al.. Assessment of blood tumor mutational burden as a potential biomarker for immunotherapy in patients with non-small cell lung cancer with use of a next-generation sequencing cancer gene panel. JAMA Oncol 2019;5:696–702. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaoncol.2018.7098.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzanikou, E, Lianidou, E. The potential of ctDNA analysis in breast cancer. Crit Rev Clin Lab Sci 2020;57:54–72. https://doi.org/10.1080/10408363.2019.1670615.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strati, A, Zavridou, M, Kallergi, G, Politaki, E, Kuske, A, Gorges, TM, et al.. A comprehensive molecular analysis of in vivo isolated EpCAM-positive circulating tumor cells in breast cancer. Clin Chem 2021;67:1395–405. https://doi.org/10.1093/clinchem/hvab099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keup, C, Suryaprakash, V, Storbeck, M, Hoffmann, O, Kimmig, R, Kasimir-Bauer, S. Longitudinal multi-parametric liquid biopsy approach identifies unique features of circulating tumor cell, extracellular vesicle, and cell-free DNA characterization for disease monitoring in metastatic breast cancer patients. Cells 2021;10:212. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells10020212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maillet, D, Allioli, N, Peron, J, Plesa, A, Decaussin-Petrucci, M, Tartas, S, et al.. Improved androgen receptor splice variant 7 detection using a highly sensitive assay to predict resistance to abiraterone or enzalutamide in metastatic prostate cancer patients. Eur Urol Oncol 2021;4:609–17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.euo.2019.08.010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neumann, MHD, Bender, S, Krahn, T, Schlange, T. ctDNA and CTCs in liquid biopsy – current status and where we need to progress. Comput Struct Biotechnol J 2018;16:190–5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.csbj.2018.05.002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele, JA, Bethel, K, Kralickova, M, Kuhn, P. Circulating tumor cells: fluid surrogates of solid tumors. Annu Rev Pathol 2017;12:419–47. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-pathol-052016-100256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham, TJ, Box, G, Tunariu, N, Crespo, M, Spinks, TJ, Miranda, S, et al.. Preclinical evaluation of imaging biomarkers for prostate cancer bone metastasis and response to cabozantinib. J Natl Cancer Inst 2014;106:dju033. https://doi.org/10.1093/jnci/dju033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tudorica, A, Oh, KY, Chui, SY, Roy, N, Troxell, ML, Naik, A, et al.. Early prediction and evaluation of breast cancer response to neoadjuvant chemotherapy using quantitative DCE-MRI. Transl Oncol 2016;9:8–17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tranon.2015.11.016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ehman, EC, Johnson, GB, Villanueva-Meyer, JE, Cha, S, Leynes, AP, Larson, PEZ, et al.. PET/MRI: where might it replace PET/CT? J Magn Reson Imag 2017;46:1247–62. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmri.25711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenhauer, EA, Therasse, P, Bogaerts, J, Schwartz, LH, Sargent, D, Ford, R, et al.. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur J Cancer 2009;45:228–47. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerwing, M, Herrmann, K, Helfen, A, Schliemann, C, Berdel, WE, Eisenblatter, M, et al.. The beginning of the end for conventional RECIST – novel therapies require novel imaging approaches. Nat Rev Clin Oncol 2019;16:442–58. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41571-019-0169-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui, S, Ming, S, Lin, Y, Chen, F, Shen, Q, Li, H, et al.. Development and clinical application of deep learning model for lung nodules screening on CT images. Sci Rep 2020;10:13657. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-70629-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillies, RJ, Kinahan, PE, Hricak, H. Radiomics: images are more than pictures, they are data. Radiology 2016;278:563–77. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2015151169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trebeschi, S, Drago, SG, Birkbak, NJ, Kurilova, I, Calin, AM, Delli Pizzi, A, et al.. Predicting response to cancer immunotherapy using noninvasive radiomic biomarkers. Ann Oncol 2019;30:998–1004. https://doi.org/10.1093/annonc/mdz108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kratz, A, Lee, SH, Zini, G, Riedl, JA, Hur, M, Machin, S, et al.. Digital morphology analyzers in hematology: ICSH review and recommendations. Int J Lab Hematol 2019;41:437–47. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijlh.13042.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walter, W, Haferlach, C, Nadarajah, N, Schmidts, I, Kuhn, C, Kern, W, et al.. How artificial intelligence might disrupt diagnostics in hematology in the near future. Oncogene 2021;40:4271–80. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41388-021-01861-y.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grossmann, P, Stringfield, O, El-Hachem, N, Bui, MM, Rios Velazquez, E, Parmar, C, et al.. Defining the biological basis of radiomic phenotypes in lung cancer. Elife 2017;6:e23421. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.23421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gill, AB, Rundo, L, Wan, JCM, Lau, D, Zawaideh, JP, Woitek, R, et al.. Correlating radiomic features of heterogeneity on CT with circulating tumor DNA in metastatic melanoma. Cancers 2020;12:3493. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers12123493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lafata, KJ, Corradetti, MN, Gao, J, Jacobs, CD, Weng, J, Chang, Y, et al.. Radiogenomic analysis of locally advanced lung cancer based on CT imaging and intratreatment changes in cell-free DNA. Radiol Imag Cancer 2021;3:e200157. https://doi.org/10.1148/rycan.2021200157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siravegna, G, Lazzari, L, Crisafulli, G, Sartore-Bianchi, A, Mussolin, B, Cassingena, A, et al.. Radiologic and genomic evolution of individual metastases during HER2 blockade in colorectal cancer. Cancer Cell 2018;34:148–62 e7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccell.2018.06.004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magbanua, MJM, Swigart, LB, Wu, HT, Hirst, GL, Yau, C, Wolf, DM, et al.. Circulating tumor DNA in neoadjuvant-treated breast cancer reflects response and survival. Ann Oncol 2021;32:229–39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.annonc.2020.11.007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gombos, A, Venet, D, Ameye, L, Vuylsteke, P, Neven, P, Richard, V, et al.. FDG positron emission tomography imaging and ctDNA detection as an early dynamic biomarker of everolimus efficacy in advanced luminal breast cancer. NPJ Breast Cancer 2021;7:125. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41523-021-00331-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yousefi, B, LaRiviere, MJ, Cohen, EA, Buckingham, TH, Yee, SS, Black, TA, et al.. Combining radiomic phenotypes of non-small cell lung cancer with liquid biopsy data may improve prediction of response to EGFR inhibitors. Sci Rep 2021;11:9984. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-88239-y.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen, JD, Li, L, Wang, Y, Thoburn, C, Afsari, B, Danilova, L, et al.. Detection and localization of surgically resectable cancers with a multi-analyte blood test. Science 2018;359:926–30. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aar3247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y, Li, L, Douville, C, Cohen, JD, Yen, TT, Kinde, I, et al.. Evaluation of liquid from the Papanicolaou test and other liquid biopsies for the detection of endometrial and ovarian cancers. Sci Transl Med 2018;10:eaap8793. https://doi.org/10.1126/scitranslmed.aap8793.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alunni-Fabbroni, M, Weber, S, Ocal, O, Seidensticker, M, Mayerle, J, Malfertheiner, P, et al.. Circulating cell-free DNA combined to magnetic resonance imaging for early detection of HCC in patients with liver cirrhosis. Cancers 2021;13:521. https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers13030521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon, AM, Buchanan, AH, Kinde, I, Warren, A, Honushefsky, A, Cohain, AT, et al.. Feasibility of blood testing combined with PET-CT to screen for cancer and guide intervention. Science 2020;369:eabb9601. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.abb9601.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo, A, Incorvaia, L, Capoluongo, E, Tagliaferri, P, Galvano, A, Del Re, M, et al.. The challenge of the molecular tumor board empowerment in clinical oncology practice: a position paper on behalf of the AIOM-SIAPEC/IAP-SIBioC-SIC-SIF-SIGU-SIRM Italian Scientific Societies. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol 2022;169:103567. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.critrevonc.2021.103567.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lippi, G, Plebani, M. Integrated diagnostics: the future of laboratory medicine? Biochem Med 2020;30:010501. https://doi.org/10.11613/BM.2020.010501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plebani, M, Laposata, M, Lippi, G. A manifesto for the future of laboratory medicine professionals. Clin Chim Acta 2019;489:49–52. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cca.2018.11.021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
