<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35218052</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>65</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Validation of myasthenia gravis diagnosis in the older Medicare population.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>676</StartPage>
          <EndPage>682</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>676-682</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27526</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Administrative health data has been increasingly used to study the epidemiology of myasthenia gravis (MG) but a case ascertainment algorithm is lacking. We aimed to develop a valid algorithm for identifying MG patients in the older population with Medicare coverage.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Local older patients (age ≥65) who received healthcare at the Cleveland Clinic and possessed Medicare coverage in 2014 and 2015 were selected. Potential MG patients were identified by using a combination of ICD9 or ICD10 codes for MG and MG-related text-word search. Diagnosis was categorized as "definite MG", "possible MG" or "non-MG" after review of clinical summaries by 5 neuromuscular specialists. Performances of various algorithms were tested by use of the definite MG cohort as a reference standard, and calculation of sensitivity, specificity, and predictive values.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 118 988 local older patients with Medicare coverage were identified. Usage of MG ICD codes and text-word search resulted in 125 patients with definite and 67 with possible MG. A total of 45 algorithms involving ICD usage, medication prescription, and specialty visit were tested. The best performing algorithm was identified as 2 office visits using MG ICD codes separated by at least 4 weeks or 1 hospital discharge and 1 office visit each using MG ICD codes separated by at least 4 weeks within the two-year period, resulting in a sensitivity and positive predictive value of 80% for identifying definite MG patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Algorithms using ICD codes can reliably identify patients with MG with a high degree of accuracy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ikjae</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Neurological Institute of New York, Columbia University, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schold</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jesse D</ForeName>
            <Initials>JD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Quantitative Health Sciences, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hehir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael K</ForeName>
            <Initials>MK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurological Sciences, University of Vermont Larner College of Medicine, Burlington, Vermont, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Claytor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neurological Institute, Clevelnd Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Silvestri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7931-0930</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Jacobs School of Medicine and Biomedical Sciences, University at Buffalo/SUNY, Buffalo, New York, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuebing</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4248-8927</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neurological Institute, Clevelnd Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016208" MajorTopicYN="N">Databases, Factual</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D038801" MajorTopicYN="N">International Classification of Diseases</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006278" MajorTopicYN="Y">Medicare</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009157" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myasthenia Gravis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011237" MajorTopicYN="N">Predictive Value of Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">algorithm</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">incidence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myasthenia gravis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevalence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sensitivity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">specificity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35218052</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27526</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aragones JM, Bolibar I, Bonfill X, et al. Myasthenia gravis: a higher than expected incidence in the elderly. Neurology. 2003;60(6):1024-1026.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuda M, Dohi-Iijima N, Nakamura A, et al. Increase in incidence of elderly-onset patients with myasthenia gravis in Nagano prefecture. Japan Intern Med. 2005;44(6):572-577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Somnier FE. Increasing incidence of late-onset anti-AChR antibody-seropositive myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2005;65(6):928-930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casetta I, Groppo E, De Gennaro R, et al. Myasthenia gravis: a changing pattern of incidence. J Neurol. 2010;257(12):2015-2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pakzad Z, Aziz T, Oger J. Increasing incidence of myasthenia gravis among elderly in British Columbia, Canada. Neurology. 2011;76(17):1526-1528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pallaver F, Riviera AP, Piffer S, et al. Change in myasthenia gravis epidemiology in Trento, Italy, after twenty years. Neuroepidemiology. 2011;36(4):282-287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park SY, Lee JY, Lim NG, Hong YH. Incidence and prevalence of myasthenia gravis in Korea: a population-based study using the National Health Insurance Claims Database. J Clin Neurol. 2016;12(3):340-344.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinka I, Fulova M, Spalekova M, Spalek P. Epidemiology of myasthenia gravis in Slovakia in the years 1977-2015. Neuroepidemiology. 2018;50(3-4):153-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maddison P, Ambrose PA, Sadalage G, Vincent A. A prospective study of the incidence of myasthenia gravis in the east midlands of England. Neuroepidemiology. 2019;53(1-2):93-99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai CH, Tseng HF. Nationwide population-based epidemiological study of myasthenia gravis in Taiwan. Neuroepidemiology. 2010;35(1):66-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gattellari M, Goumas C, Worthington JM. A national epidemiological study of myasthenia gravis in Australia. Eur J Neurol. 2012;19(11):1413-1420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel-Nitz NM, Boscoe A, Wolbeck R, Johnson J, Silvestri NJ. Burden of illness in patients with treatment refractory myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2018;58(1):99-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersen JB, Engeland A, Owe JF, Gilhus NE. Myasthenia gravis requiring pyridostigmine treatment in a national population cohort. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17(12):1445-1450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breiner A, Young J, Green D, et al. Canadian administrative health data can identify patients with myasthenia gravis. Neuroepidemiology. 2015;44(2):108-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kassardjian CD, Widdifield J, Paterson JM, et al. Serious infections in patients with myasthenia gravis: population-based cohort study. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27(4):702-708.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breiner A, Widdifield J, Katzberg HD, Barnett C, Bril V, Tu K. Epidemiology of myasthenia gravis in Ontario, Canada. Neuromuscul Disord. 2016;26(1):41-46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mues KE, Liede A, Liu J, et al. Use of the Medicare database in epidemiologic and health services research: a valuable source of real-world evidence on the older and disabled populations in the US. Clin Epidemiol. 2017;9:267-277.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pope GC, Urato CJ, Kulas ED, Kronick R, Gilmer T. Prevalence, expenditures, utilization, and payment for persons with MS in insured populations. Neurology. 2002;58(1):37-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams JR, Fitzhenry D, Grant L, Martyn D, Kerr DA. Diagnosis pathway for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: retrospective analysis of the US Medicare longitudinal claims database. BMC Neurol. 2013;13:160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirson NY, Desai U, Ristovska L, et al. Assessing the economic burden of Alzheimer's disease patients first diagnosed by specialists. BMC Geriatr. 2016;16:138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terman SW, Reeves MJ, Skolarus LE, Burke JF. Association between early outpatient visits and readmissions after ischemic stroke. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2018;11(4):e004024.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh JA, Cleveland JD. Gout and the risk of Parkinson's disease in older adults: a study of U.S. Medicare data. BMC Neurol. 2019;19(1):4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>United States Census Bureau. www.census.gov.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tonelli M, Wiebe N, Fortin M, et al. Methods for identifying 30 chronic conditions: application to administrative data. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2015;15:31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barthold D, Joyce G, Wharton W, Kehoe P, Zissimopoulos J. The association of multiple anti-hypertensive medication classes with Alzheimer's disease incidence across sex, race, and ethnicity. PLoS One. 2018;13(11):e0206705.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butt DA, Tu K, Young J, et al. A validation study of administrative data algorithms to identify patients with parkinsonism with prevalence and incidence trends. Neuroepidemiology. 2014;43(1):28-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Culpepper WJ, Marrie RA, Langer-Gould A, et al. United States multiple sclerosis prevalence W. validation of an algorithm for identifying MS cases in administrative health claims datasets. Neurology. 2019;92(10):e1016-e1028.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mbizvo GK, Schnier C, Simpson CR, Duncan SE, Chin RFM. Validating the accuracy of administrative healthcare data identifying epilepsy in deceased adults: a Scottish data linkage study. Epilepsy Res. 2020;167:106462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aragones JM, Roura-Poch P, Hernandez-Ocampo EM, et al. Myasthenia gravis: a disease of the very old. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2014;62(1):196-197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
