<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35228757</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1213-8118</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>166</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Biomedical papers of the Medical Faculty of the University Palacky, Olomouc, Czechoslovakia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Pap Med Fac Univ Palacky Olomouc Czech Repub</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Warfarin involvement, in comparison to NOACs, in the development of systemic atherosclerosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>150</StartPage>
          <EndPage>154</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>150-154</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5507/bp.2022.008</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Adverse effects of drugs are one of the objective criteria used for choosing the most appropriate anticoagulant. It is worrying that warfarin may be involved in the progression of systemic atherosclerosis, as more and more articles suggest. Warfarin has been widely used in the past and has greater efficacy compared to dabigatran in patients with mechanical heart valves; there is an antidote to it and it is cheap. Unfortunately, warfarin inhibits the synthesis and activity of Matrix-Gla-Protein, which is the major vitamin K-dependent inhibitor of arterial calcification - an active process associated with atherosclerosis, stimulated by inflammatory mechanisms. Vitamin K antagonizes the NF-κB signaling mechanism and contributes to the prevention of arterial calcifications. Warfarin given in experimental animal models of atherosclerosis contributed to the occurrence of an increased number of aortic calcifications. Warfarin treatment used in clinical trials was associated with the progressive increase of coronary atheroma calcification. Younger patients are more sensitive to warfarin-related arterial calcifications compared to older patients, due to warfarin-induced cellular senescence changes. Non-vitamin K antagonist direct oral anticoagulants do not interact with vitamin K. Edoxaban reduces the inflammatory process in the vascular walls and the proliferation of smooth vascular muscle cells, so it is involved in the prevention of vascular maladaptive remodeling process. Apixaban is able to stabilize the coronary atherosclerotic process. Randomized clinical trials are needed to evaluate the impact of warfarin on plaque stability and cardiovascular evolution of patients.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mihaila</LastName>
            <ForeName>Romeo Gabriel</ForeName>
            <Initials>RG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, "Lucian Blaga" University of Sibiu, Romania.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Czech Republic</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Biomed Pap Med Fac Univ Palacky Olomouc Czech Repub</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101140142</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1213-8118</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000925">Anticoagulants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>12001-79-5</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014812">Vitamin K</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>5Q7ZVV76EI</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014859">Warfarin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000284" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Oral</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000925" MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D050197" MajorTopicYN="Y">Atherosclerosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001281" MajorTopicYN="Y">Atrial Fibrillation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014812" MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin K</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014859" MajorTopicYN="N">Warfarin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atherosclerosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">direct oral anticoagulants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thrombosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular calcification</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">warfarin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>57</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35228757</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5507/bp.2022.008</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weitz JI, Chan NC. Novel antithrombotic strategies for treatment of venous thromboembolism. Blood 2020;135(5):351-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31917385</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2019000919</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaffer IH, Fredenburgh JC, Stafford A, Whitlock RP, Weitz JI. Rivaroxaban and Dabigatran for Suppression of Mechanical Heart Valve-Induced Thrombin Generation. Ann Thorac Surg 2020;110(2):582-90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.athoracsur.2019.10.091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shioi A, Morioka T, Shoji T, Emoto M. The Inhibitory Roles of Vitamin K in Progression of Vascular Calcification. Nutrients 2020;12(2):583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32102248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12020583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siltari A, Vapaatalo H. Vascular Calcification, Vitamin K and Warfarin Therapy - Possible or Plausible Connection? Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol 2018;122(1):19-24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcpt.12834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Win TT, Nakanishi R, Osawa K, Li D, Susaria SS, Jayawardena E, Hamal S, Kim M, Broersen A, Kitslaar PH, Dailing C, Budoff MJ. Apixaban versus warfarin in evaluation of progression of atherosclerotic and calcified plaques (prospective randomized trial). Am Heart J 2019;212:129-33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31002997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2019.02.014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J, Nakanishi R, Li D, Shaikh K, Shekar C, Osawa K, Nezarat N, Jayawardena E, Blanco M, Chen M, Sieckert M, Nelson E, Billingsley D, Hamal S, Budoff MJ. Randomized trial of rivaroxaban versus warfarin in the evaluation of progression of coronary atherosclerosis. Am Heart J 2018;206:127-30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30227941</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2018.08.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rattazzi M, Faggin E, Bertacco E, Nardin C, Pagliani L, Plebani M, Cinetto F, Guidolin D, Puato M, Pauletto P. Warfarin, but not rivaroxaban, promotes the calcification of the aortic valve in ApoE-/- mice. Cardiovasc Ther 2018;36(4):e12438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29847020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1755-5922.12438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Millenaar D, Bachmann P, Böhm M, Custodis F, Schirmer SH. Effects of edoxaban and warfarin on vascular remodeling: Atherosclerotic plaque progression and collateral artery growth. Vascul Pharmacol 2020;127:106661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32081687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vph.2020.106661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osawa K, Nakanishi R, Win TT, Li D, Rahmani S, Nezarat N, Sheidaee N, Budoff MJ. Rationale and design of a randomized trial of apixaban vs warfarin to evaluate atherosclerotic calcification and vulnerable plaque progression. Clin Cardiol 2017;40(10):807-13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28703931</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/clc.22746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrews J, Psaltis PJ, Bartolo BAD, Nicholls SJ, Puri R. Coronary arterial calcification: A review of mechanisms, promoters and imaging. Trends Cardiovasc Med 2018;28(8):491-501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tcm.2018.04.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li M, Wang Z, Shao J, Li S, Xia H, Yu L, Hu Z. Captopril Attenuates the Upregulated Connexin 43 Expression in Artery Calcification. Arch Med Res 2020;51(3):215-23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32111501</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arcmed.2020.02.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seime T, Akbulut AC, Liljeqvist ML, Siika A, Jin H, Winski G, van Gorp RH, Karlöf E, Lengquist M, Buckler AJ, Kronqvist M, Waring OJ, Lindeman JHN, Biessen EAL, Maegdefessel L, Razuvaev A, Schurgers LJ, Hedin U, Matic L. Proteoglycan 4 Modulates Osteogenic Smooth Muscle Cell Differentiation during Vascular Remodeling and Intimal Calcification. Cells 2021;10(6):1276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34063989</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10061276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florea A, Sigl JP, Morgenroth A, Vogg A, Sahnoun S, Winz OH, Bucerius J, Schurgers LJ, Mottaghy FM. Sodium [18F]Fluoride PET Can Efficiently Monitor In Vivo Atherosclerotic Plaque Calcification Progression and Treatment. Cells 2021;10(2):275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cells10020275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrews J, Psaltis PJ, Bayturan O, Shao M, Stegman B, Elshazly M, Kapadia SR, Tuzcu EM, Nissen SE, Nicholls SJ, Puri R. Warfarin Use Is Associated With Progressive Coronary Arterial Calcification: Insights From Serial Intravascular Ultrasound. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging 2018;11(9):1315-23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28734922</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcmg.2017.04.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uto K, Yoshizawa S, Aoki C, Nishikawa T, Oda H. Inhibition of extracellular matrix integrity attenuates the early phase of aortic medial calcification in a rodent model. Atherosclerosis 2021;319:10-20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2020.12.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin JF, Fan LL, Li BW, Zhao RR, Jiang LG, Zhang BC, Lu YS, Shao JW. A study to evaluate herb-drug interaction underlying mechanisms: An investigation of ginsenosides attenuating the effect of warfarin on cardiovascular diseases. Eur J Pharm Sci 2020;142:105100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31669385</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejps.2019.105100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan NC, Eikelboom JW. How I manage anticoagulant therapy in older individuals with atrial fibrillation or venous thromboembolism. Blood 2019;133(21):2269-78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2019-01-846048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Namba S, Yamaoka-Tojo M, Kakizaki R, Nemoto T, Fujiyoshi K, Hashikata T, Kitasato L, Hashimoto T, Kameda R, Meguro K, Shimohama T, Tojo T, Ako J. Erratum to: Effects on bone metabolism markers and arterial stiffness by switching to rivaroxaban from warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. Heart Vessels 2017;32(8):983.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00380-017-0966-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santiago MB, Paz A. Acute Peripheral and/or Cutaneous Ischemic Syndrome: What Rheumatologists Should Know. J Clin Rheumatol 2021;27(2):73-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315786</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RHU.0000000000001609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Caterina R, Ageno W, Agnelli G, Chan NC, Diener HC, Hylek E, Raskob GE, Siegal DM, Verheugt FWA, Lip GYH, Weitz JI. The Non-Vitamin K Antagonist Oral Anticoagulants in Heart Disease: Section V-Special Situations. Thromb Haemost 2019;119(1):14-38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30597497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0038-1675816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cappato R, Chiarito M, Giustozzi M, Briani M, Ali H, Riva L, Bonitta G, Lodigiani C, Furlanello F, Balla C, Lupo P, Stefanini G. Lower dose direct oral anticoagulants and improved survival: A combined analysis in patients with established atherosclerosis. Eur J Intern Med 2021;83:14-20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33158720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejim.2020.09.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feuring M, Schulman S, Eriksson H, Kakkar AJ, Schellong S, Hantel S, Schueler E, Kreuzer J, Goldhaber SZ. Net clinical benefit of dabigatran vs. warfarin in venous thromboembolism: analyses from RE-COVER®, RE-COVER™ II, and RE-MEDY™. J Thromb Thrombolysis 2017;43(4):484-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28210989</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11239-017-1479-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldhaber SZ, Eriksson H, Kakkar A, Schellong S, Feuring M, Fraessdorf M, Kreuzer J, Schueler E, Schulman S. Efficacy of dabigatran versus warfarin in patients with acute venous thromboembolism in the presence of thrombophilia: Findings from RE-COVER®, RE-COVER™ II, and RE-MEDY™. Vasc Med 2016;21(6):506-14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27807306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1358863X16668588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei N, Lu L, Zhang H, Gao M, Ghosh S, Liu Z, Qi J, Wang J, Chen J, Huang H. Warfarin Accelerates Aortic Calcification by Upregulating Senescence-Associated Secretory Phenotype Maker Expression. Oxid Med Cell Longev 2020;2020:2043762.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/2043762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Gorp RH, Dijkgraaf I, Bröker V, Bauwens M, Leenders P, Jennen D, Dweck MR, Bucerius J, Briedé JJ, van Ryn J, Brandenburg V, Mottaghy F, Spronk HMH, Reutelingsperger CP, Schurgers LJ. Off-target effects of oral anticoagulants - vascular effects of vitamin K antagonist and non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulant dabigatran etexilate. J Thromb Haemost 2021;19(5):1348-63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33687782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jth.15289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
