<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35223662</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2287-3651</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>11</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical and experimental vaccine research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Exp Vaccine Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Expression of full and fragment-B of diphtheria toxin genes in <i>Escherichia coli</i> for generating of recombinant diphtheria vaccines.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>12</StartPage>
          <EndPage>29</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>12-29</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7774/cevr.2022.11.1.12</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In the present study, whole diphtheria toxin (dt) and fragment B (dtb) genes from <i>Corynebacterium diphtheriae</i> Park William were cloned into <i>Escherichia coli</i>, the purified expressed proteins were evaluated for ultimately using as a candidate vaccine.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The dt and dtb genes were isolated from bacterial strain ATCC (American Type Culture Collection) no. 13812. Plasmid pET29a+ was extracted by DNA-spin TM plasmid purification kit where genes were inserted using BamHI and HindIII-HF. Cloned pET29a+dt and pET29a+dtb plasmids were transformed into <i>E. coli</i> BL21(DE3)PlysS as expression host. The identity of the sequences was validated by blasting the sequence (BLASTn) against all the reported nucleotide sequences in the NCBI (National Center for Biotechnology Information) GenBank. Production of proteins in high yield by different types and parameters of fermentation to determine optimal conditions. Lastly, the purified concentrated rdtx and rdtb were injected to BALB/c mice and antibody titers were detected.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The genetic transformation of <i>E. coli</i> DH5α and <i>E. coli</i> BL21 with the pET-29a(+) carrying the dt and dtb genes was confirmed by colony polymerase chain reaction assay and were positive to grow on Luria-Bertani/kanamycin medium. The open reading frame of dt and dtb sequences consisted of 1,600 bp and 1,000 bp, were found to be 100% identical to dt and dtb sequence of <i>C. diphtheriae</i> (accession number KX702999.1 and KX702993.1) respectively. The optimal condition for high cell density is fed-batch fermentation production to express the rdtx and rdtb at 280 and 240 Lf/mL, dissolved oxygen was about 24% and 22% and the dry cell weight of bacteria was 2.41 g/L and 2.18 g/L, respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study concluded with success in preparing genetically modified two strains for the production of a diphtheria vaccine, and to reach ideal production conditions to achieve the highest productivity.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© Korean Vaccine Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abulmagd</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shaimaa</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4201-0587</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Research and Development, VACSERA, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Khattab</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abd El-Nasser A</ForeName>
            <Initials>AEA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1553-477X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Genetics and Cytology Department, National Research Centre, Giza, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zedan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hamdallah</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5238-0584</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Microbiology and Immunology Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, Cairo University, Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Exp Vaccine Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101592344</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2287-3651</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Corynebacterium diphtheriae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diphtheria toxin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fermentation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gene expression</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunogenicity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest relevant to this article was reported.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35223662</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8844665</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7774/cevr.2022.11.1.12</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner KS, Stickings P, White JM, et al.  A review of the international issues surrounding the availability and demand for diphtheria antitoxin for therapeutic use. Vaccine. 2009;28:14–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19818425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tchorbanov AI, Dimitrov JD, Vassilev TL. Molecular composition of diphtheria toxoid produced using semi-synthetic and meat extract-based broths. World J Microbiol Biotechnol. 2004;20:211–217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mueller JH, Miller PA. Production of diphtheric toxin of high potency (100 Lf) on a reproducible medium. J Immunol. 1941;40:21–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Immunization coverage fact sheet [Internet] Geneva: World Health Organization; 2017.  [cited 2021 Jun 30].  Available from:  http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs378/en/
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaur J, Kumar A, Kaur J. Strategies for optimization of heterologous protein expression in E. coli: roadblocks and reinforcements. Int J Biol Macromol. 2018;106:803–822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28830778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gundinger T, Spadiut O. A comparative approach to re combinantly produce the plant enzyme horseradish peroxidase in Escherichia coli. J Biotechnol. 2017;248:15–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5453243</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28288816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang CJ, Lin H, Yang X. Industrial production of recombinant therapeutics in Escherichia coli and its recent advancements. J Ind Microbiol Biotechnol. 2012;39:383–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22252444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan JS, Ramanan RN, Ling TC, Shuhaimi M, Ariff AB. Enhanced production of periplasmic interferon alpha-2b by Escherichia coli using ion-exchange resin for in situ removal of acetate in the culture. Biochem Eng J. 2011;58:124–132.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menzella HG. Comparison of two codon optimization strategies to enhance recombinant protein production in Escherichia coli. Microb Cell Fact. 2011;10:15. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056764</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21371320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sohoni SV, Nelapati D, Sathe S, Javadekar-Subhedar V, Gaikaiwari RP, Wangikar PP. Optimization of high cell density fermentation process for recombinant nitrilase production in E. coli. Bioresour Technol. 2015;188:202–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25739996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins JH, Young EM. Genetic engineering of host organisms for pharmaceutical synthesis. Curr Opin Biotechnol. 2018;53:191–200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29471209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uhoraningoga A, Kinsella GK, Henehan GT, Ryan BJ. The Goldilocks approach: a review of employing design of experiments in prokaryotic recombinant protein production. Bioengineering (Basel) 2018;5:89 </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6316313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30347746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira C, Domingues L. Guidelines to reach high-quality purified recombinant proteins. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2018;102:81–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu M, Feng X, Ding Y, Zhao G, Liu H, Xian M. Metabolic engineering of Escherichia coli to improve recombinant protein production. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2015;99:10367–10377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26399416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stainer DW, Corkill JM, Scholte MJ. Preparation and properties of diphtheria toxoids in submerged culture. 3. Development of a new semisynthetic medium. Can J Microbiol. 1968;14:1155–1160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5681528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freiherr von Roman M, Koller A, von Ruden D, Berensmeier S. Improved extracellular expression and purification of recombinant Staphylococcus aureus protein A. Protein Expr Purif. 2014;93:87–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glazyrina J, Krause M, Junne S, Glauche F, Storm D, Neubauer P. Glucose-limited high cell density cultivations from small to pilot plant scale using an enzyme-controlled glucose delivery system. N Biotechnol. 2012;29:235–242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22100433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Packiam K, Ramanan RN, Ooi CW, Krishnaswamy L, Tey BT. Stepwise optimization of recombinant protein production in Escherichia coli utilizing computational and experimental approaches. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol. 2020;104:3253–3266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32076772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abulmagd S, Emara M, Aziz S, El-Domany R. Evaluation and characterisation of A and B fragments of Corynebacterium diphtheriae toxin towards recombinant diphtheria vaccine. Indian J Med Microbiol. 2013;31:3–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23508421</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sambrook J, Russell DW.  Molecular cloning: a laboratory manual. 3rd ed. Cold Spring Harbor (NY): Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press; </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohammadi N, Mojgan B, Pakzad P, Besharat M. Cloning and expression of Corynebacterium diphtheriae toxin gene. Afr J Microbiol Res. 2011;5:3018–3023.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nascimento DV, Lemes EM, Queiroz JL, et al.  Expression and purification of the immunogenically active fragment B of the Park Williams 8 Corynebacterium diphtheriae strain toxin. Braz J Med Biol Res. 2010;43:460–466.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20490433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Englard S, Seifter S. Precipitation techniques. Methods Enzymol. 1990;182:285–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2314242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung YJ, Lee JA, Jung MY, et al.  Optimization of diphtheria toxin production by Corynebacterium diphtheriae using a casein-based medium in a fermenter. Biotechnol Bioprocess Eng. 2016;21:537–543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayakawa S, Uchida T, Mekada E, Moynihan MR, Okada Y. Monoclonal antibody against diphtheria toxin: effect on toxin binding and entry into cells. J Biol Chem. 1983;258:4311–4317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6187735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson N, Pickett MA, Watt PJ, Clarke IN, Heckels JE. Construction of an epitope vector utilising the diphtheria toxin B-subunit. FEMS Microbiol Lett. 1997;146:91–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8997711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engvall E, Perlmann P. Enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, ELISA. 3. Quantitation of specific antibodies by enzyme-labeled anti-immunoglobulin in antigen-coated tubes. J Immunol. 1972;109:129–135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4113792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romaniuk SI, Kolybo DV, Komisarenko SV. Recombinant diphtheria toxin derivatives: perspectives of application. Russ J Bioorg Chem. 2012;38:565–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23547467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urieto JO, Liu T, Black JH, et al.  Expression and purification of the recombinant diphtheria fusion toxin DT388IL3 for phase I clinical trials. Protein Expr Purif. 2004;33:123–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14680969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wahby AI, El-kady E, Hamdi M. Determination of antibodies to the fragments A and B of diphtheria toxin. Egypt J Immunol. 1998;6:41–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preneta-Blanc R, Rigsby P, Wilhelmsen ES, Tierney R, Brierley M, Sesardic D. Calibration of replacement international standards of diphtheria and tetanus toxoids for use in flocculation test. Biologicals. 2008;36:315–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18676158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sundaran B, Rao YU, Boopathy R. Process optimization for enhanced production of diphtheria toxin by submerged cultivation. J Biosci Bioeng. 2001;91:123–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16232962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefan A, Conti M, Rubboli D, Ravagli L, Presta E, Hochkoeppler A. Overexpression and purification of the recombinant diphtheria toxin variant CRM197 in Escherichia coli. J Biotechnol. 2011;156:245–252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21889551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metz B, Jiskoot W, Mekkes D, et al.  Quality control of routine, experimental and real-time aged diphtheria toxoids by in vitro analytical techniques. Vaccine. 2007;25:6863–6871.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17707558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan JS, Ramanan RN, Azaman SN, Ling TC, Shuhaimi M, Ariff AB. Enhanced interferon-α2b production in periplasmic space of Escherichia coli through medium optimization using response surface method. Open Biotechnol J. 2009;3:117–124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Volonte F, Marinelli F, Gastaldo L, et al.  Optimization of glutaryl-7-aminocephalosporanic acid acylase expression in E. coli. Protein Expr Purif. 2008;61:131–137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18586517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yari K, Fatemi SS, Tavallaei M. High level expression of recombinant BoNT/A-Hc by high cell density cultivation of Escherichia coli. Bioprocess Biosyst Eng. 2012;35:407–414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21833619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad I, Nawaz N, Darwesh NM, et al.  Overcoming challenges for amplified expression of recombinant proteins using Escherichia coli. Protein Expr Purif. 2018;144:12–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29180019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Usuwanthim K, Pootong A, Chaisri U, et al.  Murine monoclonal antibodies neutralizing the cytotoxic activity of diphtheria toxin. Asian Pac J Allergy Immunol. 2008;26:47–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18595529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNeela EA, Jabbal-Gill I, Illum L, et al.  Intranasal immunization with genetically detoxified diphtheria toxin induces T cell responses in humans: enhancement of Th2 responses and toxin-neutralizing antibodies by formulation with chitosan. Vaccine. 2004;22:909–914.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15161067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clements CJ, Griffiths E. The global impact of vaccines containing aluminium adjuvants. Vaccine. 2002;20 Suppl 3:S24–S33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12184361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bazaral M, Goscienski PJ, Hamburger RN. Characteristics of human antibody to diphtheria toxin. Infect Immun. 1973;7:130–136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC422649</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4633288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabiaux V, Phalipon A, Wattiez R, Falmagne P, Ruysschaert JM, Kaczorek M. Expression of a biologically active diphtheria toxin fragment B in Escherichia coli. Mol Microbiol. 1988;2:339–346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3135463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
