<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35228636</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>28</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Scientific reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Measurement of the mass-flow-rate characterization parameters of high-pressure pneumatic servo slide valves.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>3273</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>3273</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3273</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-022-07377-z</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The mass-flow-rate characteristics of high-pressure pneumatic servo valves (HPSVs) have an important effect on the dynamic performance of high-pressure servo systems. However, these characteristics are difficult to obtain by theoretical calculations and flowmeter measurements owing to the compressibility of high-pressure gas. In this paper, a new measurement method of the mass-flow-rate characterization parameters of HPSVs is proposed based on the principle of the series connection sonic discharge of valve orifices. The effective cross-sectional area and critical pressure ratio of the servo valve orifices can be accurately and efficiently determined by connecting two valve orifices in series and exchanging the flow sequence of the two valve orifices. The two assumptions including the sonic and adiabatic discharge of the proposed measurement method were verified. A comparison between the test and simulation data showed that the accuracy of the measured effective cross-sectional area and critical pressure ratio of the HPSV was high. The measured critical pressure ratio ranged from 0.46 to 0.50, and the flow coefficient represented by the effective cross-sectional area variation decreased with increasing valve opening. These findings have general implications for the accurate design, analysis, and control of high-pressure pneumatic servo systems.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dijia</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FESTO Pneumatics Centre, School of Mechanical Science and Engineering, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Longlong</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FESTO Pneumatics Centre, School of Mechanical Science and Engineering, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, China. festogl@hust.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shaoliang</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FESTO Pneumatics Centre, School of Mechanical Science and Engineering, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuxuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FESTO Pneumatics Centre, School of Mechanical Science and Engineering, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Baoren</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FESTO Pneumatics Centre, School of Mechanical Science and Engineering, Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, 430074, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>56</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35228636</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8885647</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-07377-z</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-022-07377-z</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nie S, Liu X, Yin F, Ji H, Zhang J. Development of a high-pressure pneumatic on/off valve with high transient performances direct-driven by voice coil motor. Appl. Sci.-Basel. 2018;8:6112018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong D, Li X. Development of a novel parallel-spool pilot operated high-pressure solenoid valve with high flow rate and high speed. Chinese J. Mech. Eng. 2015;28:369–378. doi: 10.3901/CJME.2015.0104.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3901/CJME.2015.0104.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu G, Wang J, Dang K, Yuan S. Effects of flow stress behaviour, pressure loading path and temperature variation on high-pressure pneumatic forming of ti-3al-2.5v tubes. Int. J. Adv. Manuf. Technol. 2015;85:869–879. doi: 10.1007/s00170-015-7977-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00170-015-7977-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan H, Liu Y, Ma L. Mechanism of temperature’s acting on electro-hydraulic servo valve. IEEE Access. 2019;7:80465–80477. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2922135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2922135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Li S. Cavity shedding dynamics in a flapper–nozzle pilot stage of an electro-hydraulic servo-valve: Experiments and numerical study. Energy Conv. Manag. 2015;100:370–379. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2015.04.047.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2015.04.047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Briones J, Espulgar W, Koyama S, et al.  A design and optimization of a high throughput valve based microfluidic device for single cell compartmentalization and analysis. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:12995. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-92472-w.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-92472-w</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8217553</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34155296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinken H, Ulrich S, Bruns R, Schneider S. High-response electrorheological servo valve. J. Intell. Mater. Syst. Struct. 2019;31:297–307. doi: 10.1177/1045389X19873427.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1045389X19873427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pawananont K, Leephakpreeda T. Sequential control of multichannel on–off valves for linear flow characteristics via averaging pulse width modulation without flow meter: An application for pneumatic valves. J. Dyn. Syst. Meas. Control-Trans. ASME. 2018;141:011007–011018. doi: 10.1115/1.4040969.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4040969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan C, Wu H, Dong F. Mass flow rate measurement of oil-water two-phase flow by a long-waist cone meter. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2013;62:2795–2804. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2013.2263660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2013.2263660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ISO 10770-2:2012. Hydraulic Fluid Power—Electrically Modulated Hydraulic Control Valves—Part 2: Test Methods for Three-Port Directional Flow-Control Valves. (2012)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ISO 6358-1-2013. Pneumatic Fluid Power—Determination of Flow-Rate Characteristics of Components Using Compressible Fluids—Part 1: General Rules and Test Methods for Steady-State Flow. (2013)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Y. Fan, L. Gangyan, H. Jian, L. Wengfeng, Q. Wang. Method for resultant and calculating the flow-rate characteristics of pneumatic circuit. in 2015 International Conference on Fluid Power and Mechatronics (FPM). 379–384. 10.1109/FPM.2015.7337144. (IEEE, 2015).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Righettini P, Giberti H, Strada R. A novel in field method for determining the flow rate characteristics of pneumatic servo axes. J. Dyn. Syst. Meas. Control-Trans. ASME. 2013;135:041013-1-041013-8. doi: 10.1115/1.4024010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.4024010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuroshita, K. &amp; Oneyama, N. Improvements of test method of flow-rate characteristics of pneumatic components. in SICE 2004 Annual Conference. 147–152. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5332874. (IEEE, 2004).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>JIS B8390-2000. Pneumatic Fluid Power Components Using Compressible Fluids Determination of Flow Rate Characteristics. (2000)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawashima K, Ishii Y, Funaki T, Kagawa T. Determination of flow rate characteristics of pneumatic solenoid valves using an isothermal chamber. J. Fluids Eng. Trans. ASME. 2004;126:273–279. doi: 10.1115/1.1667888.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1115/1.1667888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>T. Funaki, T. Kato, K. Kawashima, T. Kagawa. Study on a performance evaluation of oscillatory gas flow generator with highly precise inlet flow control system. in SICE 2009 Annual Conference. 3819–3824. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5332874. (IEEE, 2009) </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L, Gan Y, Liu P. Study on heat transfer of porous media for isothermal chamber. Exp. Therm. Fluid Sci. 2013;46:46–53. doi: 10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2012.11.019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2012.11.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L, Shen H, Ye Q, Liu C. Influence of the distribution of porous media on the heat conduction enhancement and isothermal performance for isothermal chamber. Chin. J. Mech. Eng. 2017;53:160–166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imamura K, Horinouchi O, Okuyama T, Isobe Y. The primary dynamic gravimetric system for gas mass flow measurement. Flow Meas. Instrum. 2020;76:101752–101760. doi: 10.1016/j.flowmeasinst.2020.101752.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.flowmeasinst.2020.101752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kashan MAM, Leong A, Saha T, Kalavally V, Swamy V, Ramakrishnan N. QCM-micropillar-based coupled resonators in the detection of gas mass flow rates. IEEE Trans. Instrum. Meas. 2019;68:303–305. doi: 10.1109/TIM.2018.2871234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIM.2018.2871234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>GB/T 14513-1993. Pneumatic Fluid Power-Determination of Flow Rate Characteristics of Pneumatic Component. (1993)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hui W, Xu W, Jiang W. Optimal selection of auxiliary components in serial connection method. Mach. Tool Hydraul. 2020;48:32–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Xu W. Study on critical pressure ratio and effective area. Hydraul. Pneum. Seals. 2013;9:12–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao L, Yang G, Li W, Li B. Measurement of mass flow rate and evaluation of heat transfer coefficient for high-pressure pneumatic components during charge and discharge processes. Flow Meas. Instrum. 2015;45:391–403. doi: 10.1016/j.flowmeasinst.2015.08.006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.flowmeasinst.2015.08.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li B, Gao L, Yang G. Evaluation and compensation of steady gas flow force on the high-pressure electro-pneumatic servo valve direct-driven by voice coil motor. Energy Convers. Manag. 2013;67:92–102. doi: 10.1016/j.enconman.2012.11.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.enconman.2012.11.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syah R, Elveny M, Nasution MKM, et al.  Numerical investigation of nanofluid flow using CFD and fuzzy-based particle swarm optimization. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:20973. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-00279-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-00279-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8545973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34697333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shoghl SN, Naderifar A, Farhadi F, et al.  A novel strategy for comprehensive optimization of structural and operational parameters in a supersonic separator using computational fluid dynamics modeling. Sci. Rep. 2021;11:21850. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-01303-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-01303-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575786</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molkov V, Dadashzadeh M, Makarov D. Physical model of onboard hydrogen storage tank thermal behaviour during fueling. Int. J. Hydrog. Energy. 2019;44:4374–4384. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2018.12.115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2018.12.115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawano Y, Kuroki T, Sakoda N, Monde M, Takata Y. Thermal analysis of high-pressure hydrogen during the discharging process. Int. J. Hydrog. Energy. 2019;44:27039–27045. doi: 10.1016/j.ijhydene.2019.08.167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijhydene.2019.08.167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauer, T. Thermophotovoltaics: Basic Principles and Critical Aspects of System Design. 85–99. https://link.springer.com/book/10.1007%2F978-3-642-19965-3. (Springer, 2011). </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao L, Wu C, Zhang D, Fu X, Li B. Research on a high-accuracy and high-pressure pneumatic servo valve with aerostatic bearing for precision control systems. Precis. Eng. 2019;60:355–367. doi: 10.1016/j.precisioneng.2019.09.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precisioneng.2019.09.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
