<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35227036</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2148-6247</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>28</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Turkish journal of pharmaceutical sciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Turk J Pharm Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Response Surface Methodology in Spectrophotometric Estimation of Saxagliptin, Derivatization with MBTH and Ninhydrin.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>9</StartPage>
          <EndPage>18</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>9-18</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4274/tjps.galenos.2021.93195</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">Design of experiments assisted spectrophotometric methods have been established for the quantification of saxagliptin in pharmaceutical formulation <i>via</i> charge transfer complexation and Schiff's base formation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS">Box-Behnken design was exploited in method-1, involved the measurement of absorbance of green/blue-colored complex (at 600 nm), formed by the reaction of saxagliptin with 3-methyl-2-benzothiazolinone hydrazone in the presence of ferric chloride. The central composite design was employed in method-2, involved the determination of absorbance of Ruhemann's purple (at 585 nm), formed by the reaction of the primary amine group of saxagliptin with ninhydrin reagent in presence of sodium hydroxide. Optimization of reaction variables namely, reagent concentration (A), oxidizing agent/alkalinity (B) and reaction/heat time (C) was performed through response surface methodology for the response (Y) <i>i.e.</i> absorbance of colored compound. The reliability of both methods was investigated through validation as <i>per</i> International Council for Harmonisation guidelines.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Saxagliptin executed linearity in the concentration range of 0.01-0.25 μg/mL and 1-10 μg/mL by method-1 and 2. A high value of molar absorptivity, low values of Sandell's sensitivity and limit of detection/limit of quantification divulges the good sensitivity methods. The % assay of saxagliptin in the marketed formulation was found to be 100.27 and 99.86 by method-1 and method-2, respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The proposed eco-friendly and economical methods can be routinely employed in quality control for the analysis of saxagliptin in the pharmaceutical dosage forms.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gurrala</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sunitha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6251-2763</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Osmania University, University College of Technology, Department of Pharmacy, Hyderabad, India</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Raj</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shiva</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2870-5112</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Osmania University, University College of Science, Department of Chemistry, Hyderabad, India</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cvs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Subrahmanyam</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5645-1922</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Osmania University, Gokaraju Rangaraju College of Pharmacy, Hyderabad, India</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Anumolu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Durga Panikumar</ForeName>
            <Initials>DP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5010-7488</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Osmania University, Gokaraju Rangaraju College of Pharmacy, Hyderabad, India</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Naraparaju</LastName>
            <ForeName>Swathi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1442-6435</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Osmania University, Gokaraju Rangaraju College of Pharmacy, Hyderabad, India</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nizampet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Harika</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3737-428X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Osmania University, Gokaraju Rangaraju College of Pharmacy, Hyderabad, India</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Turk J Pharm Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101717890</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1304-530X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">BBD,</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">CCD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">MBTH</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Saxagliptin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">ninhydrin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>
<i>Conflict of interest: No conflict of interest was declared by the authors. The authors are solely responsible for the content and writing of this paper.</i>
</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35227036</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8892554</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4274/tjps.galenos.2021.93195</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenstock J, Sankoh S, List JF. Glucose-lowering activity of the dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor saxagliptin in drug-naive patients with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2008;10:376–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18355324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jadzinsky M, Pfützner A, Paz-Pacheco E, Xu Z, Allen E, Chen R ; CV181-039 Investigators. Saxagliptin given in combination with metformin as initial therapy improves glycaemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes compared with either monotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2009;11:611–622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19515181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenstock J, Aguilar-Salinas C, Klein E, Nepal S, List J, Chen R; CV181-011 Study Investigators. Effect of saxagliptin monotherapy in treatment-naïve patients with type 2 diabetes. Curr Med Res Opin. 2009;25:2401–2411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19650754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koli SN, Belvotagi AV, Mudke RP, Patil SA. UV spectrophotometric method development and validation for estimation of saxagliptin in API and in pharmaceutical dosage form. Int J Pharm Pharm Res. 2019;14:166–179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zameeruddin M, Bundel SS, Bharkad VB, Khan HN, Sandip TT. Development and validation of UV spectroscopic method for simultaneous estimation of dapagliflozin and saxagliptin in synthetic mixture. Int J Pharm Anal Res. 2019;8:59–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhadauria RS, Agarwal V. Development and validation of UV spectroscopic method for simultaneous estimation of dapagliflozin and saxagliptin in marketed formulation. J Drug Deliv Ther. 2019;9:1160–1164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raveendra BG, Kumar RA, Shaheen SD, Greeshma A, Satyanarayana M, Manikanta RSHT, Syam CPB. A novel stability-indicating method for the simultaneous estimation of saxagliptin and dapagliflozin in rat serum by using UV spectroscopy. Pharm Anal Acta. 2018;9:3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suthar AS, Prajapati L, Joshi A, Patel J, Kharofiya ML, Sahah SBM. Estimation of saxagliptin hydrochloride and dapagliflozin propendiol monohydrate in combined dosage form. J Innov Appl Pharm Sci. 2018;3:1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sisode PS, Raj HA, Jain VC. Simultaneous determination of saxagliptin hydrochloride and glibenclamide in synthetic mixture using spectrophotometric technique (first order derivative method) Asian J Pharm Anal. 2016;6:77–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nyola N, Jeyebalan G. Development and validation of UV-Vis spectroscopy method for simultaneous estimation of saxagliptin hydrochloride and metformin hydrochloride in active pharmaceutical ingredient. J Pharm Edu Res. 2012;3:19–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalaichelvi R, Jayachandran E. Validated spectroscopic method for estimation of saxagliptin in pure and from tablet formulation. Int J Pharm Pharm Sci. 2011;3:179–180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veeresham C, Srividya S, Swetha E. Development and validation of high-performance thin layer chromatographic method for quantitative analysis of saxagliptin. Am J Analyt Chem. 2015;6:797–806.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donepudi S, Achanta S. Simultaneous estimation of saxagliptin and dapagliflozin in human plasma by validated high performance liquid chromatography - ultraviolet method. Turk J Pharm Sci. 2019;16:227–233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227962</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aswini R, Eswarudu MM, Babu PS. A novel RP-HPLC method for simultaneous estimation of dapagliflozin and saxagliptin in bulk and pharmaceutical dosage form. Int J Pharm Sci Res. 2018;9:5161–5167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adegoke OA, Babalola CP, Kotila OA, Obuebhor O. Simultaneous spectrophotometric determination of trimethoprim and sulphamethoxazole following charge-transfer complexation with chloranilic acid. Arab J Chem. 2017;10:S3848–S3860.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sunil Kumar AVVNK, Reddy TV, Sekharan CB. Utility of picric acid and 2,4 dinitrophenol as chromogenic reagents for visible spectrophotometric quantification of alogliptin. Bull Fac Pharm Cairo Univ. 2017;55:177–184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pani Kumar AD, Archana G, Sunitha G, Rachel Paul K, Harika R, Sowndarya NSKR. Simplistic application of 3-methy-2-benzothiazoline hydrazone (MBTH), an oxidative coupling chromogenic reagent for quantification of metaxalone and dabigatran etexilate mesylate bulk drug and their dosage forms. Pharm Anal Acta. 2015;6:5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varsha MS, Babu NR, Padmavathi Y, Kumar PR. Development of new spectrophotometric method for estimation of tenofovir disoproxil fumarate using MBTH reagent. Int Curr Pharm J. 2015;4:378–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ismail NBS, Narayana B. Spectrophotometric determination and spectroscopic studies on Schiff base and charge transfer complex of ketorolac tromethamine. J Anal Sci Technol. 2015;6:32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moneeb MS. Spectrophotometric and spectrofluorimetric methods for the determination of saxagliptin and vildagliptin in bulk and pharmaceutical preparations. Bull Fac Pharm Cairo Univ. 2013;51:139–150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Bagary RI, Elkady EF, Ayoub BM. Spectrophotometric methods based on charge transfer complexation reactions for the determination of saxagliptin in bulk and pharmaceutical preparation. Int J Biomed Sci. 2012;8:204–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3615277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23675274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abd-alaah HJ, Hamody AS. Design of experiments model for optimization of spectrophotometric determination of phenylephrine hydrochloride in pure and pharmaceutical formulations using p-bromanil. J Pharm Sci Res. 2019;11:501–507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wani YB, Patil DD. An experimental design approach for optimization of spectrophotometric method for estimation of cefixime trihydrate using ninhydrin as derivatizing reagent in bulk and pharmaceutical formulation. J Saudi Chem Soc. 2017;21:S101–S111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papanna RK, Gowda JBK, Nagaraja P. An experimental design approach for optimization of spectrophotometric estimation of mirabegron in bulk and pharmaceutical formulations. J Anal Chem. 2018;73:884–893.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demirkaya-Miloglu F, Polatdemir E, Senol O, Kadioglu Y. Design and optimization of a novel spectrophotometric method using response surface methodology for the determination of losartan potassium in pharmaceuticals. Curr Pharm Anal. 2017;13:552–558.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>No Authors. International conference on harmonization (ICH) of technical requirements for registration of pharmaceuticals for human use, Validation of analytical procedures: Text Q2 (R1) Geneva. 2005:1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>No Authors. International conference on harmonization (ICH) of technical requirements for registration of pharmaceuticals for human use, Validation of analytical procedures: Methodology. Q2 (R1) Geneva. 2005:6–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
