<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35234172</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1550-5065</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>37</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <MedlineDate>2022 Jul-Sep 01</MedlineDate>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of nursing care quality</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Nurs Care Qual</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Preventing Health Care-Associated Infections Through Implementation of an Interprofessional Visual Management Safety Tracker.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>231</StartPage>
          <EndPage>237</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>231-237</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/NCQ.0000000000000621</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The management of health care associated infections (HAIs) challenges acute care facilities due to variability in practices. The purpose of this quality improvement project was to decrease central line-associated bloodstream infection, catheter-associated urinary tract infection, and Clostridioides difficile infection in a high acuity care environment using a visual management (VM) tool to address practice variations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="LOCAL PROBLEM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">An acute care unit experienced increasing HAIs.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">An interprofessional team used Lean methodology to implement a VM tool reflective of evidence-based HAI prevention practices that staff had frequently omitted.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A VM tool called the Safety Tracker was created.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In 12 months, HAIs decreased from 9 events to 1, with a corresponding reduction in indwelling urinary catheter utilization and central line utilization. More than $160 000 were avoided in health care costs.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Creating an interprofessional VM Safety Tracker could significantly reduce HAIs.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frist Avila</LastName>
            <ForeName>Patricia</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nursing Administration (Ms Frist Avila), Indiana University Health Ball Memorial Hospital, Muncie (Dr Twibell); School of Nursing, Ball State University, Muncie, Indiana (Dr Twibell); and B4 Medical Progressive Unit, Indiana University Health Methodist Hospital, Indianapolis (Ms Demaree).</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Twibell</LastName>
            <ForeName>K Renee</ForeName>
            <Initials>KR</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Demaree</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heather</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Nurs Care Qual</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9200672</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1057-3631</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055499" MajorTopicYN="Y">Catheter-Related Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003428" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cross Infection</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D062885" MajorTopicYN="N">Urinary Catheters</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014552" MajorTopicYN="Y">Urinary Tract Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234172</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NCQ.0000000000000621</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00001786-202207000-00007</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frankel A, Haraden C, Federico F, Lenoci-Edwards J. A framework for safe, reliable, and effective care. IHI.org; 2017. Accessed May 19, 2021. http://www.ihi.org/resources/Pages/IHIWhitePapers/Framework-Safe-Reliable-Effective-Care.aspx</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. Health care-associated infections. AHRQ Patient Safety Primer. Updated September 2019. Accessed June 8, 2021. https://psnet.ahrq.gov/primer/health-care-associated-infections</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. Estimating the additional hospital inpatient cost and mortality associated with selected hospital-acquired conditions. Updated November 2017. Accessed May 26, 2021. https://www.ahrq.gov/hai/pfp/haccost2017-results.html</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Backman C, Bruce N, Marck P, Vanderloo S. Engaging direct care providers in improving infection prevention and control practices using participatory visual methods. J Nurs Care Qual. 2016;31(3):233–237. doi:10.1097/NCQ.0000000000000169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musuuza JS, Roberts TJ, Hundt AS, et al. Implementing daily chlorhexidine gluconate treatment for the prevention of healthcare-associated infections in non-intensive care settings: a multiple case analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15(4):e0232062. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0232062</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahsan A, Dewi ES, Suharsono T, et al. Knowledge management-based nursing care educational training: a key strategy to improve healthcare associated infection prevention behavior. SAGE Open Nurs. 2021;7:23779608211044601. doi:10.1177/23779608211044601</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunne CP, Kingston L, Slevin B, O'Connell NH. Hand hygiene and compliance behaviours are the under-appreciated human factors pivotal to reducing hospital-acquired infections. J Hosp Infect. 2018;98(4):328–330. doi:10.1016/j.jhin.2018.02.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boettcher PA, Hunter RB, McGonagle P. Using Lean principles of standard work to improve clinical nursing performance. Nurs Econ. 2019;37(3):152–163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palmer S, Dixon R. Reducing catheter-associated urinary tract infections through best practice: Sherwood Forest Hospitals' experience. Br J Nurs. 2019;28(1):11–15. doi:10.12968/bjon.2019.28.1.11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen RI. Lean methodology in health care. Chest. 2018;154(6):1448–1454. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2018.06.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmoud Z, Angele-Halgand N, Churruca K, Ellis LA, Braithwaite J. The impact of Lean management on frontline healthcare professionals: a scoping review of the literature. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):383. doi:10.1186/s12913-021-06344-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koloroutis M, Manthey M, Felgen J, et al. Relationship-Based Care: A Model for Transforming Practice. 1st ed. Creative Health Care Management; 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galsworth GD. Visual Systems: Harnessing the Power of the Visual Workplace. American Management Association; 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aherne J, Whelton J. Applying Lean in Healthcare: A Collection of International Case Studies. CRC Press; 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokoe D, Anderson D, Berenholtz S, et al. A compendium of strategies to prevent healthcare-associated infections in acute care hospitals: 2014 updates. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2015;35(S2):S21–S31. doi:10.1086/677216</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zegers M, Hesselink G, Geense W, et al. Evidence-based interventions to reduce adverse events in hospitals: a systematic review of systematic reviews. BMJ Open. 2016;6:e012555. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2016-012555</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamsson A, Dellve L, Karltun A. Nurses' use of visual management in hospitals—a longitudinal, quantitative study on its implications on systems performance and working conditions. J Adv Nurs. 2019;75(4):760–771. doi:10.1111/jan.13855</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. The NHSN Standardized Infection Ratio (SIR). Updated February 2021. Accessed December 23, 2021. https://www.cdc.gov/nhsn/pdfs/ps-analysis-resources/nhsn-sir-guide.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parkhi S. Lean management practices in healthcare sector: a literature review. Benchmarking. 2019;26(4):1275–1289. doi:10.1108/BIJ-06-2018-0166</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eriksson N. Hospital management from a high reliability organizational change perspective: a Swedish case on Lean and Six Sigma. Int J Public Sect Manag. 2017;30:67–84. doi:10.1108/IJPSM-12-2015-0221</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnabè F, Guercini J, Di Perna M. Assessing performance and value-creation capabilities in Lean healthcare: insights from a case study. Public Money Manage. 2019;39(7):503–511. doi:10.1080/09540962.2019.1598197</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glegg SMN, Ryce A, Brownlee K. A visual management tool for program planning, project management and evaluation in paediatric health care. Eval Program Plann. 2019;72:16–23. doi:10.1016/j.evalprogplan.2018.09.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurpjuweit S, Reinerth D, Schmidt CG, Wagner SM. Implementing visual management for continuous improvement: barriers, success factors and best practices. Int J Prod Res. 2019;57(17):5574–5588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
