<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35238477</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1756-185X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>25</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of rheumatic diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Rheum Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Angioedema-like presentation as the presenting finding of juvenile myositis and juvenile dermatomyositis in 2 patients.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>617</StartPage>
          <EndPage>625</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>617-625</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1756-185X.14311</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Juvenile dermatomyositis (JDM) is the most common subtype of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies in childhood. Gottron's papules, shawl sign, periorbital heliotrope rash, and periungual telengiectasis are characteristic skin findings of the disease. Besides characteristic skin involvement, some other skin findings, such as angioedema, may be seen prior or in the course of the disease. The presence of angioedema in JDM is emphasized in this report.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We present 2 unrelated girls, aged 2 (case 1) and 12 years (case 2), who had developed symmetrical weakness in the proximal muscles, muscle pain, elevated muscle enzymes and angioedema. Both cases had abnormal muscle magnetic resonance imaging findings, suggestive of inflammatory myositis. Muscle biopsy was performed only in case 1, and major histocompatibility complex-1 expression on myofibers was shown consistent with JDM. Cases were diagnosed as probable and definite JDM, respectively. Angioedema was prominent, particularly in the lips and extremities of both cases, without laboratory evidence of C1 inhibitor deficiency or capillary leak syndrome, and absence of family history. Mast cell-mediated, acquired angioedema was the most likely diagnosis. In both cases, skin and muscle findings improved significantly with steroid treatment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We suggest that angioedema may be among the characteristic skin findings in JDM, and may be included in subsequent definitions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Asia Pacific League of Associations for Rheumatology and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Karaca</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ömer</ForeName>
            <Initials>Ö</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8691-5268</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kocaeli University Medical Faculty, Division of Child Neurology, Department of Pediatrics, Izmit, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Güngör</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mesut</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kocaeli University Medical Faculty, Division of Child Neurology, Department of Pediatrics, Izmit, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sakarya Güneş</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ayfer</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child Neurology, Department of Pediatrics, Sakarya Education and Research Hospital, Sakarya, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eser Şimşek</LastName>
            <ForeName>Işıl</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kocaeli University Medical Faculty, Division of Child Allergy and Immunology, Department of Pediatrics, Izmit, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Anık</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yonca</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kocaeli University Medical Faculty, Department of Radiology, Izmit, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bülent</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kocaeli University Medical Faculty, Division of Child Neurology, Department of Pediatrics, Izmit, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Rheum Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101474930</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1756-1841</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000799" MajorTopicYN="Y">Angioedema</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001706" MajorTopicYN="N">Biopsy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003882" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatomyositis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009220" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myositis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">angioedema</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory myositis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">juvenile dermatomyositis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lip edema</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>56</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35238477</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1756-185X.14311</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendez EP, Lipton R, Ramsey-Goldman R, et al. US incidence of juvenile dermatomyositis, 1995-1998: results from the national institute of arthritis and musculoskeletal and skin diseases registry. Arthritis Rheum. 2013;49(3):300-305. 10.1002/art.11122</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman BM, Rider LG, Reed AM, Pachman LM. Juvenile dermatomyositis and other idiopathic inflammatory myopathies of childhood. Lancet. 2018;371(9631):2201-2212. 10.1016/S0140-6736(08)60955-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrestha S, Wershil B, Sarwark JF, Niewold TB, Philipp T, Pachman LM. Lesional and nonlesional skin from patients with untreated juvenile dermatomyositis displays increased number of mast cells and mature plasmacytoid dendritic cells. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62(9):2813-2822. 10.1002/art.27529</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen ML, Pachman LM, Schneiderman R, Patel DC, Friedman JM. Prevalence of coxsackie B virus antibodies in patients with juvenile dermatomyositis. Arthritis Rheum. 1986;29(11):1365-1370. 10.1002/art.1780291109</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mainetti C, Terziroli Beretta-Piccoli B, Selmi C. Cutaneous manifestations of dermatomyositis: a comprehensive review. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol. 2017;53(3):337-356. 10.1007/s12016-017-8652-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazandjieva J, Christoff G. Angioedema as a systemic disease. Clin Dermatol. 2019;37:636-643. 10.1016/j.clindermatol.2019.07.035</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batista M, Gonçalo M. The rash that presents as a red swollen face. Clin Dermatol. 2020;38:63-78. 10.1016/j.clindermatol.2019.10.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohan A, Peter JB. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis (first of two parts). N Engl J Med. 1975;292:344-347. 10.1056/NEJM197502132920706</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohan A, Peter JB. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis (second of two parts). N Engl J Med. 1975;292:403-407. 10.1056/NEJM197502202920807</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Hohlfed R. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Lancet. 2003;362:971-982. 10.1016/S0140-6736(03)14368-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundberg IE, Tjärnlund A, Bottai M, et al. 2017 European league against rheumatism/American college of rheumatology classification criteria for adult and juvenile idiopathic inflammatory myopathies and their major subgroups. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76(12):1955-1964. 10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-211468</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ichimura Y, Konishi R, Shobo M, et al. Anti-nuclear matrix protein 2 antibody-positive inflammatory myopathies represent extensive myositis without dermatomyositis-specific rash. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;keab518. 0:1-6. 10.1093/rheumatology/keab518</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li DM, Wang L, Liu MY, Xu L, Tang XM. The analysis of clinical phenotypes and autoantibodies in juvenile dermatomyositis. Zhonghua Er Ke Za Zhi. 2020;58(12):966-972. Chinese. 10.3760/cma.j.cn112140-20200724-00751</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell JP, Dennis GJ, Rider LG. Juvenile dermatomyositis presenting with anasarca: a possible indicator of severe disease activity. J Pediatr. 2001;138(6):942-945. 10.1067/mpd.2001.113363. PMID: 11391348</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sevigny GM, Mathes BM. Periorbital edema as the presenting sign of juvenile dermatomyositis. Pediatr Dermatol. 2002;16(1):43-45. 10.1046/j.1525-1470.1999.99013.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karabiber H, Aslan M, Alkan A, Yakinci C. A rare complication of generalized edema in juvenile dermatomyositis: a report of one case. Brain Dev. 2004;26(4):269-272. 10.1016/S0387-7604(03)00171-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehndiratta S, Banerjee P. Juvenile dermatomyositis presenting with anasarca. Indian Pediatr. 2004;41(7):752-753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taban M, Perry JD. Juvenile dermatomyositis presenting with periorbital edema. Ophthalmic Plast Reconstr Surg. 2006;22(5):393-395. 10.1097/01.iop.0000230271.21976.0d</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chandrakasan S, Singh S, Ratho RK, Kumar S, Mishra B. Anasarca as the presenting manifestation of parvovirus B19 associated juvenile dermatomyositis. Rheumatol Int. 2009;29(5):565-567. 10.1007/s00296-008-0702-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saygi S, Alehan F, Baskin E, Bayrakci US, Ulu EM, Ozbek N. Juvenile dermatomyositis presenting with anasarca. J Child Neurol. 2008;23(11):1353-1356. 10.1177/0883073808318544</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zedan M, El-Ayouty M, Abdel-Hady H, Shouman B, El-Assmy M, Fouda A. Anasarca: not a nephrotic syndrome but dermatomyositis. Eur J Pediatr. 2008;167(7):831-834. 10.1007/s00431-008-0716-z. Epub 2008 Apr 15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma D, Singh S, Suri D, Rawat A, Shava U, Sodhi KS. Anasarca as the initial presentation of juvenile polymyositis: an uncommon occurrence. Rheumatol Int. 2012;32(8):2589-2590. 10.1007/s00296-011-2054-0. Epub 2011 Jul 31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nickavar A, Mehr AM. Nephrotic syndrome and juvenile dermatomyositis. Rheumatol Int. 2012;32(9):2933-2935. 10.1007/s00296-011-2028-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakhlu A, Dhakad U, Nolkha NJ. Lack of neck holding and anasarca: important but ignored manifestations of juvenile dermatomyositis. Indian J Rheumatol. 2013;8:139-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rachadi H, Bouayad K, Chiheb S. Juvenile dermatomyositis: early onset and unusual presentation. Arch Pediatr. 2016;23(10):1071-1075. French. 10.1016/j.arcped.2016.07.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shelley BP, Chakraborti S. A viral polymyositis masquerade: life-threatening case of juvenile dermatomyositis complicated by systemic capillary leak syndrome. Ann Indian Acad Neurol. 2018;21(1):70-74. 10.4103/aian.AIAN_373_17</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deschamps R, Couture J, Hadjinicolaou A, LeBlanc CMA. A 17-year-old girl with facial edema and weakness. Paediatr Child Health. 2018;23(4):241-244. 10.1093/pch/pxx209</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres Jiménez AR, Solís-Vallejo E, Céspedes-Cruz AI, Sánchez-Uribe M. Subcutaneous edema in juvenile dermatomyositis. Reumatol Clin (Engl Ed). 2019;15(5):e49-e50. English, Spanish. 10.1016/j.reuma.2017.06.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimizu M, Inoue N, Mizuta M, Sakakibara Y, Hamaguchi Y, Yachie A. Periorbital edema as the initial sign of juvenile dermatomyositis. J Clin Rheumatol. 2020;26(3):e61. 10.1097/RHU.0000000000000890</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schildt EE, De Ranieri D. Anasarca as the presenting symptom of juvenile dermatomyositis: a case series. Pediatr Rheumatol Online J. 2021;19(1):120. 10.1186/s12969-021-00604-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narasimhan R, Lakshman R, Amos RS, Williams LH, Egner W, Finn A. Juvenile dermatomyositis associated with hereditary angioneurotic oedema. Arch Dis Child. 2002;87(6):563. 10.1136/adc.87.6.563-a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gradwohl-Matis I, Illig R, Salmhofer H, Neureiter D, Brunauer A, Dünse MW. Fulminant systemic capillary leak syndrome due to C1 inhibitor deficiency complicating acute dermatomyositis: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2014;8:28. 10.1186/1752-1947-8-28</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beck G, Yamashita R, Saeki C, Ogawa T, Shimizu M, Mochizuki H. C1-inhibitor deficiency induces myositis-like symptoms via the deposition of the membrane attack complex in the muscle. Intern Med. 2020;59:2173-2176. 10.2169/internalmedicine.4601-20</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meneghel A, Martini G, Birolo C, Tosoni A, Pettenazzo A, Zulian F. Life-threatening systemic capillary leak syndrome in juvenile dermatomyositis. Rheumatology. 2017;56(10):1822-1823. 10.1093/rheumatology/kex262</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin AJ, Sen ES, Emonts M. Atypical juvenile dermatomyositis complicated by systemic capillary leak syndrome: case report and review of the literature. Rheumatology. 2020;keaa406. 60:e1-e2. 10.1093/rheumatology/keaa406</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mourao AF, Pinto TL, Falcao Riberio C, et al. Juvenile dermatomyositis assoiated wtih anasarca- a clinical case. Acta Rheumatol Port. 2009;34(2A):276-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
