<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35247279</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4604</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>05</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Use of Physiologically Based Pharmacokinetic Modeling to Evaluate the Impact of Chronic Kidney Disease on CYP3A4-Mediated Metabolism of Saxagliptin.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcph.2043</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>We characterized the impact of chronic kidney disease (CKD) on the cytochrome P450 (CYP) 3A4-mediated metabolism of saxagliptin to its metabolite, 5-hydroxysaxagliptin, using a physiologically based pharmacokinetic (PBPK) model. A PBPK model of saxagliptin and its CYP3A4 metabolite, 5-hydroxysaxagliptin, was constructed and validated for oral doses ranging from 5 to 100 mg. The observed ratios of area under the plasma concentration-time curve (AUC) and maximum plasma concentration (C<sub>max</sub> ) between healthy subjects and subjects with CKD were compared with those predicted using PBPK model simulations. Simulations were performed with virtual CKD populations having decreased CYP3A4 activity (ie, 64%-75% of the healthy subjects' CYP3A4 abundance) and preserved CYP3A4 activity (ie, 100% of the healthy subjects' CYP3A4 abundance). We found that simulations using decreased CYP3A4 activity generally overpredicted the ratios of saxagliptin AUC and C<sub>max</sub> in CKD compared with those using preserved CYP3A4 activity. Similarly, simulations using decreased CYP3A4 activity underpredicted the ratio of 5-hydroxysaxagliptin AUC in moderate and severe CKD compared with simulations using preserved CYP3A4 activity. These findings suggest that decreased CYP3A4 activity in CKD underpredicts saxagliptin clearance compared with that observed clinically. Preserving CYP3A4 activity in CKD more closely estimates saxagliptin clearance and 5-hydroxysaxagliptin exposure changes observed in vivo. Our findings suggest that there is no clinically meaningful impact of CKD on the metabolism of saxagliptin by CYP3A4. Since saxagliptin is not a highly sensitive substrate and validated probe for CYP3A4, this work represents a case study of a CYP3A4 substrate-metabolite pair and is not a generalization for all CYP3A4 substrates.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. The Journal of Clinical Pharmacology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American College of Clinical Pharmacology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Butrovich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Morgan A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy and Therapeutics, University of Pittsburgh School of Pharmacy, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Weifeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology and Quantitative Pharmacology, Clinical Pharmacology and Safety Sciences, R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boulton</LastName>
            <ForeName>David W</ForeName>
            <Initials>DW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology and Quantitative Pharmacology, Clinical Pharmacology and Safety Sciences, R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Gaithersburg, Maryland, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nolin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas D</ForeName>
            <Initials>TD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy and Therapeutics, University of Pittsburgh School of Pharmacy, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sharma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pradeep</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology and Quantitative Pharmacology, Clinical Pharmacology and Safety Sciences, R&amp;D, AstraZeneca, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0366372</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0091-2700</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CYP3A</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CYP3A4</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cytochrome P450 3A4</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonrenal clearance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physiologically based pharmacokinetic modeling</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>4</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247279</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcph.2043</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason NA, Bakus JL. Strategies for reducing polypharmacy and other medication-related problems in chronic kidney disease. Semin Dial. 2010;23(1):55-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason NA. Polypharmacy and medication-related complications in the chronic kidney disease patient. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011;20(5):492-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardone KE, Bacchus S, Assimon MM, Pai AB, Manley HJ. Medication-related problems in CKD. Adv Chronic Kidney Dis. 2010;17(5):404-412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sommer J, Seeling A, Rupprecht H. Adverse drug events in patients with chronic kidney disease associated with multiple drug interactions and polypharmacy. Drugs Aging. 2020;37(5):359-372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolin TD, Frye RF, Matzke GR. Hepatic drug metabolism and transport in patients with kidney disease. Am J Kidney Dis. 2003;42(5):906-925.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolin TD, Naud J, Leblond FA, Pichette V. Emerging evidence of the impact of kidney disease on drug metabolism and transport. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2008;83(6):898-903.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Momper JD, Venkataramanan R, Nolin TD. Nonrenal drug clearance in CKD: Searching for the path less traveled. Adv Chronic Kidney Dis. 2010;17(5):384-391.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan ML, Yoshida K, Zhao P, et al. Effect of chronic kidney disease on nonrenal elimination pathways: a systematic assessment of CYP1A2, CYP2C8, CYP2C9, CYP2C19, and OATP. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2018;103(5):854-867.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Sun B, Zhang L, et al. Systematic and quantitative assessment of the effect of chronic kidney disease on CYP2D6 and CYP3A4/5. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2016;100(1):75-87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulton DW. Clinical pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of saxagliptin, a dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2017;56(1):11-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulton DW, Li L, Frevert EU, et al. Influence of renal or hepatic impairment on the pharmacokinetics of saxagliptin. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2011;50(4):253-265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heimbach T, Chen Y, Chen J, et al. Physiologically-based pharmacokinetic modeling in renal and hepatic impairment populations: a pharmaceutical industry perspective. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2020;110(2):297-310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan ML, Zhao P, Zhang L, et al. Use of physiologically based pharmacokinetic modeling to evaluate the effect of chronic kidney disease on the disposition of hepatic CYP2C8 and OATP1B drug substrates. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2019;105(3):719-729.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsueh CH, Hsu V, Zhao P, Zhang L, Giacomini KM, Huang SM. PBPK modeling of the effect of reduced kidney function on the pharmacokinetics of drugs excreted renally by organic anion transporters. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2018;103(3):485-492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Follman KE, Morris ME. Prediction of the effects of renal impairment on clearance for organic cation drugs that undergo renal secretion: a simulation-based study. Drug Metab Dispos. 2018;46(5):758-769.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fura A, Khanna A, Vyas V, et al. Pharmacokinetics of the dipeptidyl peptidase 4 inhibitor saxagliptin in rats, dogs, and monkeys and clinical projections. Drug Metab Dispos. 2009;37(6):1164-1171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Center for Biotechnology Information. PubChem Compound Summary for CID 23645678, 5-hydroxy saxagliptin https://pubchem.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/compound/5-Hydroxy-saxagliptin. Accessed October 1, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Medicines Agency. Onglyza. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/onglyza. Accessed October 1, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wishart DS, Feunang YD, Guo AC, et al. DrugBank 5.0: a major update to the DrugBank database for 2018. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018;46(D1):D1074-D1082. https://10.1093/nar/gkx1037</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wishart DS, Feunang YD, Marcu A, et al. HMDB 4.0: the human metabolome database for 2018. Nucleic Acids Res. 2018;46(D1):D608-D617. https://10.1093/nar/gkx1089</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulton DW, Kasichayanula S, Keung CF, et al. Simultaneous oral therapeutic and intravenous (1) (4)C-microdoses to determine the absolute oral bioavailability of saxagliptin and dapagliflozin. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;75(3):763-768.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su H, Boulton DW, Barros A, Jr., et al. Characterization of the in vitro and in vivo metabolism and disposition and cytochrome P450 inhibition/induction profile of saxagliptin in human. Drug Metab Dispos. 2012;40(7):1345-1356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulton DW &amp; Geraldes M. Safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of once-daily oral doses of saxagliptin for 2 weeks in type 2 diabetic and healthy subjects. Poster presented at the 67th Scientific Sessions of the American Diabetes Association. 2007; Chicago, IL. Abstract 606-P.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel CG, Li L, Girgis S, Kornhauser DM, Frevert EU, Boulton DW. Two-way pharmacokinetic interaction studies between saxagliptin and cytochrome P450 substrates or inhibitors: simvastatin, diltiazem extended-release, and ketoconazole. Clin Pharmacol. 2011;3:13-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Upreti VV, Boulton DW, Li L, et al. Effect of rifampicin on the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of saxagliptin, a dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor, in healthy subjects. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2011;72(1):92-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guest EJ, Aarons L, Houston JB, Rostami-Hodjegan A, Galetin A. Critique of the two-fold measure of prediction success for ratios: application for the assessment of drug-drug interactions. Drug Metab Dispos. 2011;39(2):170-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levey AS, Stevens LA, Schmid CH, et al. A new equation to estimate glomerular filtration rate. Ann Intern Med. 2009;150(9):604-612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tatosian DA, Yee KL, Zhang Z, et al. A microdose cocktail to evaluate drug interactions in patients with renal impairment. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2021;109(2):403-415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zanger UM, Schwab M. Cytochrome P450 enzymes in drug metabolism: regulation of gene expression, enzyme activities, and impact of genetic variation. Pharmacol Ther. 2013;138(1):103-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dani M, Boisvert C, Michaud J, et al. Down-regulation of liver drug-metabolizing enzymes in a murine model of chronic renal failure. Drug Metab Dispos. 2010;38(3):357-360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leblond FA, Petrucci M, Dube P, Bernier G, Bonnardeaux A, Pichette V. Downregulation of intestinal cytochrome p450 in chronic renal failure. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2002;13(6):1579-1585.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michaud J, Dube P, Naud J, et al. Effects of serum from patients with chronic renal failure on rat hepatic cytochrome P450. Br J Pharmacol. 2005;144(8):1067-1077.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michaud J, Nolin TD, Naud J, et al. Effect of hemodialysis on hepatic cytochrome P450 functional expression. J Pharmacol Sci. 2008;108(2):157-163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rege B, Krieg R, Gao N, Sarkar MA. Down-regulation of hepatic CYP3A in chronic renal insufficiency. Pharm Res. 2003;20(10):1600-1606.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velenosi TJ, Fu AY, Luo S, Wang H, Urquhart BL. Down-regulation of hepatic CYP3A and CYP2C mediated metabolism in rats with moderate chronic kidney disease. Drug Metab Dispos. 2012;40(8):1508-1514.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao P, Vieira Mde L, Grillo JA, et al. Evaluation of exposure change of nonrenally eliminated drugs in patients with chronic kidney disease using physiologically based pharmacokinetic modeling and simulation. J Clin Pharmacol. 2012;52(1 Suppl):91S-108S.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi MK, Song IS. Characterization of efflux transport of the PDE5 inhibitors, vardenafil and sildenafil. J Pharm Pharmacol. 2012;64(8):1074-1083.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolin TD, Frye RF, Le P, et al. ESRD impairs nonrenal clearance of fexofenadine but not midazolam. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2009;20(10):2269-2276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomson BK, Nolin TD, Velenosi TJ, et al. Effect of CKD and dialysis modality on exposure to drugs cleared by nonrenal mechanisms. Am J Kidney Dis. 2015;65(4):574-582.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolin TD. A synopsis of clinical pharmacokinetic alterations in advanced CKD. Semin Dial. 2015;28(4):325-329.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
