<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35244884</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2212-5469</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Tissue engineering and regenerative medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Tissue Eng Regen Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Tissue-Material Integration and Biostimulation Study of Collagen Acellular Matrices.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>477</StartPage>
          <EndPage>490</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>477-490</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13770-021-00420-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Breast reconstruction after mastectomy using silicone implants is a surgical procedure that occasionally leads to capsular contracture formation. This phenomenon constitutes an important and persistent cause of morbidity, and no successful therapies are available to date. Recently, the use of acellular membranes as a protective material for silicone prostheses has been gaining attention due to their ability to prevent this adverse outcome. For this reason, the evaluation of the tissue-material integration and the induced biostimulation by acellular membranes results crucial. Evaluation of in vivo tissue integration and biostimulation induced by three different natural acellular collagen membranes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Scanning electron microscopy was performed to analyse the membrane porosity and cells-biomaterial interaction in vitro, both in dry and wet conditions. Adipose-derived stem cells were cultured in the presence of membranes, and the colonisation capacity and differentiation potential of cells were assessed. In vivo tests and ex vivo analyses have been performed to evaluate dermal integration, absorption degree and biostimulation induced by the evaluated membrane.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Analysis performed in vitro on the three different acellular dermal matrices evidenced that porosity and the morphological structure of membranes influence the liquid swelling ratio, affecting the cell mobility and the colonisation capacity. Moreover, the evaluated membranes influenced in different manner the adipose derived stem cells differentiation and their survival. In vivo investigation indicated that the absorption degree and the fluid accumulation surrounding the implant were membrane-dependent. Finally, ex vivo analysis confirmed the membrane-dependent behavior revealing different degree of tissue integration and biostimulation, such as adipogenic stimulation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The physico-chemical characteristics of the membranes play a key role in the biostimulation of the cellular environment inducing the development of well-organized adipose tissue.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Quintero Sierra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lindsey Alejandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>LA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7336-0099</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy. lindseyalejandra.quinterosierra@univr.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Busato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alice</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zingaretti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicola</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinic of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Academic Hospital of Udine, Department of Medical Area (DAME), University of Udine, Piazzale Santa Maria della Misericordia 15, 33100, Udine, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Conti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Biswas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Reetuparna</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Governa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maurizio</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata, Piazzale Aristide Stefani 1, 37126, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vigato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Enrico</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata, Piazzale Aristide Stefani 1, 37126, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Parodi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pier Camillo</ForeName>
            <Initials>PC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinic of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery, Academic Hospital of Udine, Department of Medical Area (DAME), University of Udine, Piazzale Santa Maria della Misericordia 15, 33100, Udine, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bernardi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paolo</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sbarbati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrea</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Conti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giamaica</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, Biomedicine and Movement Sciences, University of Verona, Strada le Grazie 8, 37134, Verona, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Korea (South)</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Tissue Eng Regen Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101699923</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1738-2696</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acellular matrix</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adipogenic stimulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Capsular contracture</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tissue integration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35244884</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13770-021-00420-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13770-021-00420-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baxter RA. Acellular dermal matrices in breast implant surgery: defining the problem and proof of concept. Clin Plast Surg. 2012;39:103–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cps.2011.12.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meza Britez ME, Caballero Llano C, Chaux A. Periprosthetic breast capsules and immunophenotypes of inflammatory cells. Eur J Plast Surg. 2012;35:647–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atlan M, Nuti G, Wang H, Decker S, Perry TA. Breast implant surface texture impacts host tissue response. J Mech Behav Biomed Mater. 2018;88:377–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown T. Surface areas of textured breast implants: Implications for the biofilm theory of capsule formation. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2018;6:e1700.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright MA, Samadi A, Lin AJ, Lara DO, Harper AD, Zhao R, et al. Periprosthetic capsule formation and contracture in a rodent model of implant-based breast reconstruction with delayed radiotherapy. Ann Plast Surg. 2019;82:S264–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SAP.0000000000001892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tevlin R, Borrelli MR, Irizarry D, Nguyen D, Wan DC, Momeni A. Acellular dermal matrix reduces myofibroblast presence in the breast capsule. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2019;7:e2213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brouki Milan P, Pazouki A, Joghataei MT, Mozafari M, Amini N, Kargozar S, et al. Decellularization and preservation of human skin: A platform for tissue engineering and reconstructive surgery. Methods. 2019;171:62–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymeth.2019.07.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kornmuller A, Brown CFC, Yu C, Flynn LE. Fabrication of extra-cellular matrix-derived foams and microcarriers as tissue-specific cell culture and delivery platforms. J Vis Exp. 2017. https://doi.org/10.3791/55436</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/55436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28447989</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5564502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qi Y, Dong Z, Chu H, Zhao Q, Wang X, Jiao Y, et al. Denatured acellular dermal matrix seeded with bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells for wound healing in mice. Burns 2019;45:1685–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freytes DO, Tullius RS, Valentin JE, Stewart-Akers AM, Badylak SF. Hydrated versus lyophilized forms of porcine extra-cellular matrix derived from the urinary bladder. J Biomed Mater Res A. 2008;87:862–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadelkarim M, Abushouk AI, Ghanem E, Hamaad AM, Saad AM, Abdel-Daim MM. Adipose-derived stem cells: effectiveness and advances in delivery in diabetic wound healing. Biomed Pharmacother. 2018;107:625–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2018.08.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bush K, Gertzman AA. Process development and manufacturing of human and animal acellular dermal matrices. In: Albanna MZ, Holmes IV JH, editors. Skin Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine. 1st ed. Elsevier; 2016. p. 83–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carlsson AH, Gronet EM, Rose LF, Chan R. Clinical applications of acellular dermal matrices in reconstructive surgery. In: Albanna MZ, Holmes IV JH, editors. Skin Tissue Engineering and Regenerative Medicine. 1st ed. Elsevier; 2016. p. 109–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storti G, Scioli MG, Kim BS, Orlandi A, Cervelli V. Adipose-derived stem cells in bone tissue engineering: useful tools with new applications. Stem Cells Int. 2019;2019:3673857.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu S, Liu X, Yeung KW, Liu C, Yang X. Biomimetic porous scaffolds for bone tissue engineering. Mater Sci Eng R Rep. 2014;80:1–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan QW, Tang SL, Zhang Y, Yang JQ, Wang ZL, Xie HQ, et al. Hydrogel from acellular porcine adipose tissue accelerates wound healing by inducing intradermal adipocyte regeneration. J Invest Dermatol. 2019;139:455–63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoerst K, van den Broek L, Sachse C, Klein O, von Fritschen U, Gibbs S, et al. Regenerative potential of adipocytes in hypertrophic scars is mediated by myofibroblast reprogramming. J Mol Med (Berl). 2019;97:761–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00109-019-01772-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chun C, Lee DY, Kim JT, Kwon MK, Kim YZ, Kim SS. Effect of molecular weight of hyaluronic acid (HA) on viscoelasticity and particle texturing feel of HA dermal biphasic fillers. Biomater Res. 2016;20:24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghodbane SA, Dunn MG. Physical and mechanical properties of cross-linked type I collagen scaffolds derived from bovine, porcine, and ovine tendons. J Biomed Mater Res A. 2016;104:2685–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lou T, Wang X, Song G, Gu Z, Yang Z. Fabrication of PLLA/β-TCP nanocomposite scaffolds with hierarchical porosity for bone tissue engineering. Int J Biol Macromol. 2014;69:464–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2014.06.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lou T, Wang X, Yan X, Miao Y, Long YZ, Yin HL, et al. Fabrication and biocompatibility of poly(l-lactic acid) and chitosan composite scaffolds with hierarchical microstructures. Mater Sci Eng C Mater Biol Appl. 2016;64:341–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peroni D, Scambi I, Pasini A, Lisi V, Bifari F, Krampera M, et al. Stem molecular signature of adipose-derived stromal cells. Exp Cell Res. 2008;314:603–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yexcr.2007.10.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busato A, De Francesco F, Biswas R, Mannucci S, Conti G, Fracasso G, et al. Simple and rapid non-enzymatic procedure allows the isolation of structurally preserved connective tissue micro-fragments enriched with SVF. Cells. 2020;10:36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thrusfield M. Observational studies. In: Thrusfield M, Christley R. editors. Veterinary epidemiology, 4th ed. Wiley-Blackwell; 2017. p. 319–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitz M, Bertram M, Kneser U, Keller AK, Horch RE. Experimental total wrapping of breast implants with acellular dermal matrix: a preventive tool against capsular contracture in breast surgery? J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg. 2013;66:1382–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Headon H, Kasem A, Mokbel K. Capsular contracture after breast augmentation: an update for clinical practice. Arch Plast Surg. 2015;42:532–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5999/aps.2015.42.5.532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bukowska J, Szóstek-Mioduchowska AZ, Kopcewicz M, Walendzik K, Machcińska S, Gawrońska-Kozak B. Adipose-derived stromal/stem cells from large animal models: from basic to applied science. Stem Cell Rev Rep. 2021;17:719–38..</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polotto S, Bergamini ML, Pedrazzi G, Arcuri MF, Gussago F, Cattelani L. One-step prepectoral breast reconstruction with porcine dermal matrix-covered implant: a protective technique improving the outcome in post-mastectomy radiation therapy setting. Gland Surg. 2020;9:219–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/gs.2020.01.16</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dasgupta S, Maji K, Nandi SK. Investigating the mechanical, physiochemical and osteogenic properties in gelatin-chitosan-bioactive nanoceramic composite scaffolds for bone tissue regeneration: In vitro and in vivo. Mater Sci Eng C Mater Biol Appl. 2019;94:713–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uzunısmaıl A, Perk C, Fındık H, Beyhan G, Dıncler M. Effect of a fascial tissue interface on silicone implant capsule formation – a preliminary experimental study. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg. 2008;61:1199–204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdulghani S, Mitchell GR. Biomaterials for in situ tissue regeneration: A review. Biomolecules. 2019;9:750.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/biom9110750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carswell KA, Lee MJ, Fried SK. Culture of isolated human adipocytes and isolated adipose tissue. Methods Mol Biol. 2012;806:203–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharath SS, Ramu J, Nair SV, Iyer S, Mony U, Rangasamy J. Human adipose tissue derivatives as a potent native biomaterial for tissue regenerative therapies. Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2020;17:123–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X, Yang R, Wang J, Ruan S, Lin Z, Xin Q, et al. Porcine acellular dermal matrix accelerates wound healing through miR-124–3p1 and miR-139–5p. Cytotherapy. 2020;22:494–502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
