<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35247280</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-765X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>74</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Letters in applied microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lett Appl Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>RNA-seq analysis of green tea polyphenols modulation of differently expressed genes in Enterococcus faecalis under low pH.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>970</StartPage>
          <EndPage>980</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>970-980</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/lam.13686</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Enterococcus faecasslis (E. faecalis) is a resident bacterium in the host. The increase in internal stress like low pH may affect the biological effects of E. faecalis. The prebiotic-like function of tea polyphenols can enhance the beneficial effects of its tolerance to environmental stress. In this study, RNA-sequence analysis was used to explore the protective effect of green tea polyphenols (GTP) on E. faecalis under low pH stress. A total of 28 genes were found to be responsive to GTP under low pH stress, including 16 up-regulated and 12 down-regulated. GTP intervention can partly relieve some undesired negative influences, such as the down-regulation of the base excision repair gene and amino acid transport and metabolism gene. The significantly changes were associated with selenocompound metabolism and aminoacyl-tRNA biosynthesis after the intervention of GTP. The present study provided new insights into the growth and continuous adaptation of E. faecalis under stress.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Society for Applied Microbiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ruonan</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Engineering, Ningbo University, Ningbo, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huan</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Agriculture and Biotechnology, Wenzhou Vocational College of Science and Technology, Wenzhouss, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaojie</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Agriculture and Biotechnology, Wenzhou Vocational College of Science and Technology, Wenzhouss, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xin</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5795-9197</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Agriculture and Biotechnology, Wenzhou Vocational College of Science and Technology, Wenzhouss, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Lett Appl Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8510094</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0266-8254</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000975">Antioxidants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D059808">Polyphenols</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013662">Tea</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>86-01-1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D006160">Guanosine Triphosphate</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000975" MajorTopicYN="N">Antioxidants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013293" MajorTopicYN="Y">Enterococcus faecalis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006160" MajorTopicYN="N">Guanosine Triphosphate</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006863" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrogen-Ion Concentration</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059808" MajorTopicYN="Y">Polyphenols</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017423" MajorTopicYN="N">Sequence Analysis, RNA</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013662" MajorTopicYN="N">Tea</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Enterococcus faecalis
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">green tea polyphenols</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">low pH stress</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcriptome</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>4</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35247280</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/lam.13686</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akiko, E., Motoh, I., Yasuyuki, T., Mina, T., Shinji, T., Eiji, M., Hiroshi, H., Yoshinao, K. et al. (2021) Branched-chain amino acids protect the liver from cirrhotic injury via suppression of activation of lipopolysaccharide-binding protein, toll-like receptor 4, and signal transducer and activator of transcription 3, as well as Enterococcus faecalis translocation. Nutrition 86, 111194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alomar, J., Loubiere, P., Delbes, C., Nouaille, S. and Montel, M.C. (2008) Effect of Lactococcus garvieae, Lactococcus lactis and Enterococcus faecalis on the behaviour of Staphylococcus aureus in microfiltered milk. Food Microbiol 25, 502-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campenhout, R.V., Muyldermans, S., Vinken, M., Devoogdt, N. and De Groof, T.W.M. (2021) Therapeutic nanobodies targeting cell plasma membrane transport proteins: a high-risk/high-gain endeavor. Biomolecules 11, 63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang, L., Thompson, A.D., Ung, P., Carlson, H.A. and Gestwicki, J.E. (2010) Mutagenesis reveals the complex relationships between ATPase rate and the chaperone activities of Escherichia coli heat shock protein 70 (Hsp70/DnaK). J Biol Chem 285, 21282-21291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng, L., Zhang, X., Zheng, X.J., Wu, Z.F. and Weng, P.F. (2019) RNA-seq transcriptomic analysis of green tea polyphenols regulation of differently expressed genes in Saccharomyces cerevisiae under ethanol stress. World J Microbiol Biotechnol 35, 59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>David, S.S., O'Shea, V.L. and Kundu, S. (2007) Base-excision repair of oxidative DNA damage. Nature 447, 941-950.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhanyalakshmi, K.H. and Nataraja, K.N. (2021) Universal stress protein-like gene from mulberry enhances abiotic stress tolerance in Escherichia coli and transgenic tobacco cells. Plant Biol 23, 1190-1194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher, K. and Phillips, C. (2009) The ecology, epidemiology and virulence of Enterococcus. Microbiology (Reading) 155, 1749-1757.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foulquié Moreno, M.R., Sarantinopoulos, P., Tsakalidou, E. and De Vuyst, L. (2005) The role and application of enterococci in food and health. Int J Food Microbiol 106, 1-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>İspirli, H., Demirbaş, F. and Dertli, E. (2015) Characterization of functional properties of Enterococcus faecium strains isolated from human gut. Can J Microbiol 61, 861-870.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson, S.J. and Yim, M.K. (2020) Closing in on ATPase activity by an RNA helicase. Structure 28, 143-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalasariya, H.S., Patel, N.B., Yadav, A., Perveen, K., Yadav, V.K., Munshi, F.M., Yadav, K.K., Alam, S. et al. (2021) Characterization of fatty acids, polysaccharides, amino acids, and minerals in Marine Macroalga Chaetomorpha crassa and evaluation of their potentials in skin cosmetics. Molecules 26, 7515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, S., Lekshmi, M., Parvathi, A., Ojha, M., Wenzel, N. and Varela, M.F. (2020) Functional and structural roles of the major facilitator superfamily bacterial multidrug efflux pumps. Microorganisms 8, 266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, J.Y., Pajarillo, A.B., Kim, M.J., Chae, J.P. and Kang, D.K. (2012) Proteomic and transcriptional analysis of Lactobacillus johnsonii PF01 during bile salt exposure by iTRAQ shotgun proteomics and quantitative RT-PCR. J Proteome Res 12, 432-443.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, P., Niu, Q., Wei, Q., Zhang, Y., Ma, X., Kim, S.W., Lin, M. and Huang, R. (2017) Microbial shifts in the porcine distal gut in response to diets supplemented with Enterococcus faecalis as alternatives to antibiotics. Sci Rep 7, 1-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindenstrauß, A.G., Ehrmann, M.A., Behr, J., Landstorfer, R., Haller, D., Sartor, R.B. and Vogel, R.F. (2014) Transcriptome analysis of Enterococcus faecalis toward its adaption to surviving in the mouse intestinal tract. Arch Microbiol 196, 423-433.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, X. (2019) ABC family transporters. Adv Exp Med Biol 1141, 13-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, X., Li, J., Yang, Y. and Chen, X. (2012) Exposure of Pseudomonas aeruginosa to green tea polyphenols enhances the tolerance to various environmental stresses. World J Microbiol Biotechnol 28, 3373-3380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López de Lacey, A.M., Pérez-Santín, E., López-Caballero, M.E. and Montero, P. (2014) Biotransformation and resulting biological properties of green tea polyphenols produced by probiotic bacteria. LWT - Food Sci Technol 58, 633-638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macedo, J.A., Battestin, V., Ribeiro, M.L. and Macedo, G.A. (2011) Increasing the antioxidant power of tea extracts by biotransformation of polyphenols. Food Chem 126, 491-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mariotti, F. and Gardner, C.D. (2019) Dietary protein and amino acids in vegetarian diets-a review. Nutrients 11, 2661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morelli, A.M., Ravera, S. and Panfoli, I. (2020) The aerobic mitochondrial ATP synthesis from a comprehensive point of view. Open Biol 10, 200224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller, C., Cacaci, M., Sauvageot, N., Sanguinetti, M., Rattei, T., Eder, T., Giard, J.C., Kalinowski, J., Hain, T. and Axel, Hartke. (2019) The intraperitoneal transcriptome of the opportunistic pathogen Enterococcus faecalis in mice. PLoS One 10, e0126143.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy, V.S., Shlykov, M.A., Castillo, R., Sun, E.I. and Saier, M.H. Jr (2012) The major facilitator superfamily (MFS) revisited. FEBS J 279, 2022-2035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salze, M., Giard, J.-C., Riboulet-Bisson, E., Hain, T., Rincé, A. and Muller, C. (2020) Identification of the general stress stimulon related to colonization in Enterococcus faecalis. Arch Microbiol 202, 233-246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shiadeh, S.M.J., Pormohammad, A., Hashemi, A. and Lak, P. (2019) Global prevalence of antibiotic resistance in blood-isolated Enterococcus faecalis and Enterococcus faecium: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Infect Drug Resist 12, 2713-2725.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solheim, M., La Rosa, S.L.L., Mathisen, T., Snipen, L.G., Nes, I.F. and Brede, D.A. (2014) Transcriptomic and functional analysis of NaCl-induced stress in Enterococcus faecalis. PLoS One 9, e94571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza, E.L., De Albuquerque, T.M.R., Dos Santos, A.S., Massa, N.M.L. and de Brito Alves, J.L. (2019) Potential interactions among phenolic compounds and probiotics for mutual boosting of their health-promoting properties and food functionalities-a review. Crit Rev Food Sci Nutr 59, 1645-1659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teng, F., Nannini, E.C. and Murray, B.E. (2005) Importance of gls24 in virulence and stress response of Enterococcus faecalis and use of the Gls24 protein as a possible immunotherapy target. J Infect Dis 191, 472-480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du Toit, M., Franz, C.M., Dicks, L.M. and Holzapfel, W.H. (2000) Preliminary characterization of bacteriocins produced by Enterococcus faecium and Enterococcus faecalis isolated from pig faeces. J Appl Microbiol 88, 482-494.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tulini, F.L., Winkelströter, L.K. and Martinis, E.C. (2013) Identification and evaluation of the probiotic potential of Lactobacillus paraplantarum FT259, a bacteriocinogenic strain isolated from Brazilian semi-hard artisanal cheese. Anaerobe 22, 57-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan, N. (2013) Structural advances for the major facilitator superfamily (MFS) transporters. Trends Biochem Sci 38, 151-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, X., Wu, Z.F. and Weng, P.F. (2014) Antioxidant and hepatoprotective effect of (-)-epigallocatechin 3-O-(3-O-methyl) gallate (EGCG3’’Me) from Chinese oolong tea. J Agric Food Chem 62, 10046-10054.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu, Y., Li, T., Din, A.U., Hassan, A., Wang, Y. and Wang, G. (2019) Beneficial effects of Enterococcus faecalis in hypercholesterolemic mice on cholesterol transportation and gut microbiota. Appl Microbiol Biotechnol 103, 3181-3191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
