<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35259847</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A neurovascular unit-on-a-chip: culture and differentiation of human neural stem cells in a three-dimensional microfluidic environment.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2260</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2266</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2260-2266</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.337050</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Biological studies typically rely on a simple monolayer cell culture, which does not reflect the complex functional characteristics of human tissues and organs, or their real response to external stimuli. Microfluidic technology has advantages of high-throughput screening, accurate control of the fluid velocity, low cell consumption, long-term culture, and high integration. By combining the multipotential differentiation of neural stem cells with high throughput and the integrated characteristics of microfluidic technology, an in vitro model of a functionalized neurovascular unit was established using human neural stem cell-derived neurons, astrocytes, oligodendrocytes, and a functional microvascular barrier. The model comprises a multi-layer vertical neural module and vascular module, both of which were connected with a syringe pump. This provides controllable conditions for cell inoculation and nutrient supply, and simultaneously simulates the process of ischemic/hypoxic injury and the process of inflammatory factors in the circulatory system passing through the blood-brain barrier and then acting on the nerve tissue in the brain. The in vitro functionalized neurovascular unit model will be conducive to central nervous system disease research, drug screening, and new drug development.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wei</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wen-Juan</ForeName>
            <Initials>WJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem Cell Clinical Research Center, National Joint Engineering Laboratory, Regenerative Medicine Center, the First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University; Dalian Innovation Institute of Stem Cell and Precision Medicine, Dalian, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ya-Chen</ForeName>
            <Initials>YC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem Cell Clinical Research Center, National Joint Engineering Laboratory, Regenerative Medicine Center, the First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University; Dalian Innovation Institute of Stem Cell and Precision Medicine, Dalian, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xin</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem Cell Clinical Research Center, National Joint Engineering Laboratory, Regenerative Medicine Center, the First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University; Dalian Innovation Institute of Stem Cell and Precision Medicine, Dalian, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei-Gong</ForeName>
            <Initials>WG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem Cell Clinical Research Center, National Joint Engineering Laboratory, Regenerative Medicine Center, the First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University; Dalian Innovation Institute of Stem Cell and Precision Medicine, Dalian, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem Cell Clinical Research Center, National Joint Engineering Laboratory, Regenerative Medicine Center, the First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University; Dalian Innovation Institute of Stem Cell and Precision Medicine, Dalian, Liaoning Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">(neural) differentiation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocyte</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blood-brain barrier</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain microvascular endothelial cells</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central nervous system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microfluidics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural stem cells</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuron</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurovascular unit</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oligodendrocyte</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organ-on-a-chip</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35259847</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9083144</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.337050</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_10_2260_337050</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbott NJ, Friedman A. Overview and introduction:the blood-brain barrier in health and disease. Epilepsia 53 Suppl. 2012;6:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahadian S, Civitarese R, Bannerman D, Mohammadi MH, Lu R, Wang E, Davenport-Huyer L, Lai B, Zhang B, Zhao Y, Mandla S, Korolj A, Radisic M. Organ-on-a-chip platforms:a convergence of advanced materials, cells, and microscale technologies. Adv Healthc Mater. 2018;7:1700506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen NJ, Barres BA. Neuroscience:Glia - more than just brain glue. Nature. 2009;457:675–677.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19194443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson H, van den Berg A. Microfabrication and microfluidics for tissue engineering:state of the art and future opportunities. Lab Chip. 2004;4:98–103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15052347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armstead WM, Raghupathi R. Endothelin and the neurovascular unit in pediatric traumatic brain injury. Neurol Res. 2011;33:127–132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3545647</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21801587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banaeiyan AA, Theobald J, Paukštyte J, Wölfl S, Adiels CB, Goksör M. Design and fabrication of a scalable liver-lobule-on-a-chip microphysiological platform. Biofabrication. 2017;9:015014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28155845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bell RD, Zlokovic BV. Neurovascular mechanisms and blood-brain barrier disorder in Alzheimer's disease. Acta Neuropathol. 2009;118:103–113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19319544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhalerao A, Sivandzade F, Archie SR, Chowdhury EA, Noorani B, Cucullo L. In vitro modeling of the neurovascular unit:advances in the field. Fluids Barriers CNS. 2020;17:22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7077137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32178700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birbrair A. Pericyte biology:development, homeostasis, and disease. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2018;1109:1–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30523585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Booth R, Kim H. Characterization of a microfluidic in vitro model of the blood-brain barrier (μBBB) Lab Chip. 2012;12:1784–1792.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caffrey TM, Button EB, Robert J. Toward three-dimensional in vitro models to study neurovascular unit functions in health and disease. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:2132–2140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354124</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33818484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen-Kashi Malina K, Cooper I, Teichberg VI. Closing the gap between the in-vivo and in-vitro blood-brain barrier tightness. Brain Res. 2009;1284:12–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19501061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cucullo L, Hossain M, Rapp E, Manders T, Marchi N, Janigro D. Development of a humanized in vitro blood-brain barrier model to screen for brain penetration of antiepileptic drugs. Epilepsia. 2007;48:505–516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17326793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Luca C, Colangelo AM, Virtuoso A, Alberghina L, Papa M. Neurons, glia, extracellular matrix and neurovascular unit:a systems biology approach to the complexity of synaptic plasticity in health and disease. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:1539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epshteyn AA, Maher S, Taylor AJ, Holton AB, Borenstein JT, Cuiffi JD. Membrane-integrated microfluidic device for high-resolution live cell imaging. Biomicrofluidics. 2011;5:46501–465016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3364812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eriksson PS, Perfilieva E, Bjork-Eriksson T, Alborn AM, Nordborg C, Peterson DA, Gage FH. Neurogenesis in the adult human hippocampus. Nat Med. 1998;4:1313–1317.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9809557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh C, Marchi N, Desai NK, Puvenna V, Hossain M, Gonzalez-Martinez J, Alexopoulos AV, Janigro D. Cellular localization and functional significance of CYP3A4 in the human epileptic brain. Epilepsia. 2011;52:562–571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3056924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21294720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griep LM, Wolbers F, de Wagenaar B, ter Braak PM, Weksler BB, Romero IA, Couraud PO, Vermes I, van der Meer AD, van den Berg A. BBB on chip:microfluidic platform to mechanically and biochemically modulate blood-brain barrier function. Biomed Microdevices. 2013;15:145–150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22955726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grochowski C, Radzikowska E, Maciejewski R. Neural stem cell therapy-Brief review. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2018;173:8–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30053745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo JH, Liu Y, Lv ZJ, Wei WJ, Guan X, Guan QL, Leng ZQ, Zhao JY, Miao H, Liu J. Potential neurogenesis of human adipose-derived stem cells on electrospun catalpol-loaded composite nanofibrous scaffolds. Ann Biomed Eng. 2015;43:2597–2608.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25824369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harder DR, Zhang C, Gebremedhin D. Astrocytes function in matching blood flow to metabolic activity. News Physiol Sci. 2002;17:27–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11821533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holloway PM, Willaime-Morawek S, Siow R, Barber M, Owens RM, Sharma AD, Rowan W, Hill E, Zagnoni M. Advances in microfluidic in vitro systems for neurological disease modeling. J Neurosci Res. 2021;99:1276–1307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33583054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huh D, Matthews BD, Mammoto A, Montoya-Zavala M, Hsin HY, Ingber DE. Reconstituting organ-level lung functions on a chip. Science. 2010;328:1662–1668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8335790</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20576885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jang KJ, Suh KY. A multi-layer microfluidic device for efficient culture and analysis of renal tubular cells. Lab Chip. 2010;10:36–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20024048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kane BJ, Zinner MJ, Yarmush ML, Toner M. Liver-specific functional studies in a microfluidic array of primary mammalian hepatocytes. Anal Chem. 2006;78:4291–4298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16808435</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim L, Toh YC, Voldman J, Yu H. A practical guide to microfluidic perfusion culture of adherent mammalian cells. Lab Chip. 2007;7:681–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17538709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J, Kim S. Kidney-on-a-chip:a new technology for predicting drug efficacy, interactions, and drug-induced nephrotoxicity. Curr Drug Metab. 2018;19:577–583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29521220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S, Jin SP, Kim YK, Sung GY, Chung JH, Sung JH. Construction of 3D multicellular microfluidic chip for an in vitro skin model. Biomed Microdevices. 2017;19:22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28374277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lippmann ES, Weidenfeller C, Svendsen CN, Shusta EV. Blood-brain barrier modeling with co-cultured neural progenitor cell-derived astrocytes and neurons. J Neurochem. 2011;119:507–520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192906</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21854389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Zhang D, Sha B, Yin P, Xu Z, Liu C, Wang L, Xu F, Wang L. Fabrication of a three-layer SU-8 mould with inverted T-shaped cavities based on a sacrificial photoresist layer technique. Biomed Microdevices. 2014;16:655–660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24850230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu L, Zhang X, Liu X, Liu J, Lu G, Kaplan DL, Zhu H, Lu Q. Biomineralization of stable and monodisperse vaterite microspheres using silk nanoparticles. ACS Appl Mater Interfaces. 2015;7:1735–1745.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25578091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Han YS, Liu L, Tang L, Yang H, Meng P, Zhao HQ, Wang YH. Abnormal Glu/mGluR2/3/PI3K pathway in the hippocampal neurovascular unit leads to diabetes-related depression. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:727–733.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo EH, Rosenberg GA. The neurovascular unit in health and disease:introduction. Stroke. 2009;40:S2–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811575</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19064779</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ludwig PE, Thankam FG, Patil AA, Chamczuk AJ, Agrawal DK. Brain injury and neural stem cells. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13:7–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5840995</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451199</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lv ZJ, Liu Y, Miao H, Leng ZQ, Guo JH, Liu J. Effects of multiwalled carbon nanotubes on electrospun poly(lactide-co-glycolide)-based nanocomposite scaffolds on neural cells proliferation. J Biomed Mater Res B Appl Biomater. 2017;105:934–943.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26849161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma F, Pang X, Tang B. Alginate/chondroitin sulfate based hybrid hydrogel with different molecular weight and its capacity to regulate chondrocytes activity. Carbohydr Polym. 2019;206:229–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30553317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maschmeyer I, Lorenz AK, Schimek K, Hasenberg T, Ramme AP, Hübner J, Lindner M, Drewell C, Bauer S, Thomas A, Sambo NS, Sonntag F, Lauster R, Marx U. A four-organ-chip for interconnected long-term co-culture of human intestine, liver, skin and kidney equivalents. Lab Chip. 2015;15:2688–2699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25996126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McConnell HL, Kersch CN, Woltjer RL, Neuwelt EA. The translational significance of the neurovascular unit. J Biol Chem. 2017;292:762–770.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5247651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27920202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKay R. Stem cells in the central nervous system. Science. 1997;276:66–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9082987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moradi E, Jalili-Firoozinezhad S, Solati-Hashjin M. Microfluidic organ-on-a-chip models of human liver tissue. Acta Biomater. 2020;116:67–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32890749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muoio V, Persson PB, Sendeski MM. The neurovascular unit - concept review. Acta Physiol (Oxf) 2014;210:790–798.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24629161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Neill AT, Monteiro-Riviere NA, Walker GM. Characterization of microfluidic human epidermal keratinocyte culture. Cytotechnology. 2008;56:197–207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2553630</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19002858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obernier K, Alvarez-Buylla A. Neural stem cells:origin, heterogeneity and regulation in the adult mammalian brain. Development. 2019;146:dev156059.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6398449</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30777863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oleaga C, Bernabini C, Smith AS, Srinivasan B, Jackson M, McLamb W, Platt V, Bridges R, Cai Y, Santhanam N, Berry B, Najjar S, Akanda N, Guo X, Martin C, Ekman G, Esch MB, Langer J, Ouedraogo G, Cotovio J, et al.  Multi-Organ toxicity demonstration in a functional human in vitro system composed of four organs. Sci Rep. 2016;6:20030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4738272</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26837601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Payne LB, Zhao H, James CC, Darden J, McGuire D, Taylor S, Smyth JW, Chappell JC. The pericyte microenvironment during vascular development. Microcirculation. 2019;26:e12554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834874</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31066166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phan DT, Bender RHF, Andrejecsk JW, Sobrino A, Hachey SJ, George SC, Hughes CC. Blood-brain barrier-on-a-chip:microphysiological systems that capture the complexity of the blood-central nervous system interface. Exp Biol Med (Maywood) 2017;242:1669–1678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5786363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28195514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravi M, Paramesh V, Kaviya SR, Anuradha E, Solomon FD. 3D cell culture systems:advantages and applications. J Cell Physiol. 2015;230:16–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24912145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reardon S. 'Organs-on-chips'go mainstream. Nature. 2015;523:266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26178942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds BA, Weiss S. Generation of neurons and astrocytes from isolated cells of the adult mammalian central nervous system. Science. 1992;255:1707–1710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1553558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothbauer M, Bachmann BEM, Eilenberger C, Kratz SRA, Spitz S, Höll G, Ertl P. A decade of organs-on-a-chip emulating human physiology at the microscale:a critical status report on progress in toxicology and pharmacology. Micromachines. 2021;12:470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8143089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33919242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sackmann EK, Fulton AL, Beebe DJ. The present and future role of microfluidics in biomedical research. Nature. 2014;507:181–189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24622198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrestha J, Razavi Bazaz S, Aboulkheyr Es H, Yaghobian Azari D, Thierry B, Ebrahimi Warkiani M, Ghadiri M. Lung-on-a-chip:the future of respiratory disease models and pharmacological studies. Crit Rev Biotechnol. 2020;40:213–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31906727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sin A, Chin KC, Jamil MF, Kostov Y, Rao G, Shuler ML. The design and fabrication of three-chamber microscale cell culture analog devices with integrated dissolved oxygen sensors. Biotechnol Prog. 2004;20:338–345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14763861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stucki AO, Stucki JD, Hall SR, Felder M, Mermoud Y, Schmid RA, Geiser T, Guenat OT. A lung-on-a-chip array with an integrated bio-inspired respiration mechanism. Lab Chip. 2015;15:1302–1310.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25521475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sweeney MD, Ayyadurai S, Zlokovic BV. Pericytes of the neurovascular unit:key functions and signaling pathways. Nat Neurosci. 2016;19:771–783.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5745011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27227366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trujillo-Estrada L, Gomez-Arboledas A, Forner S, Martini AC, Gutierrez A, Baglietto-Vargas D, LaFerla FM. Astrocytes:from the physiology to the disease. Curr Alzheimer Res. 2019;16:675–698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31470787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Duinen V, Trietsch SJ, Joore J, Vulto P, Hankemeier T. Microfluidic 3D cell culture:from tools to tissue models. Curr Opin Biotechnol. 2015;35:118–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26094109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Ma J, Li N, Wang L, Shen L, Sun Y, Wang Y, Zhao J, Wei W, Ren Y, Liu J. Microfluidic engineering of neural stem cell niches for fate determination. Biomicrofluidics. 2017;11:014106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5533482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28798841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wareham LK, Calkins DJ. The neurovascular unit in glaucomatous neurodegeneration. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8:452.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7325980</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32656207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu HW, Lin CC, Lee GB. Stem cells in microfluidics. Biomicrofluidics. 2011;5:13401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082338</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Q, Liu J, Wang X, Feng L, Wu J, Zhu X, Wen W, Gong X. Organ-on-a-chip:recent breakthroughs and future prospects. Biomed Eng Online. 2020;19:9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7017614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32050989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wufuer M, Lee G, Hur W, Jeon B, Kim BJ, Choi TH, Lee S. Skin-on-a-chip model simulating inflammation, edema and drug-based treatment. Sci Rep. 2016;6:37471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5116589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27869150</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan L, Moriarty RA, Stroka KM. Recent progress and new challenges in modeling of human pluripotent stem cell-derived blood-brain barrier. Theranostics. 2021;11:10148–10170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8581424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye LX, An NC, Huang P, Li DH, Zheng ZL, Ji H, Li H, Chen DQ, Wu YQ, Xiao J, Xu K, Li XK, Zhang HY. Exogenous platelet-derived growth factor improves neurovascular unit recovery after spinal cord injury. Neural Regen Res. 2021;16:765–771.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8067950</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33063740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young EW, Beebe DJ. Fundamentals of microfluidic cell culture in controlled microenvironments. Chem Soc Rev. 2010;39:1036–1048.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20179823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu X, Ji C, Shao A. Neurovascular unit dysfunction and neurodegenerative disorders. Front Neurosci. 2020;14:334.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7201055</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32410936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zervantonakis IK, Kothapalli CR, Chung S, Sudo R, Kamm RD. Microfluidic devices for studying heterotypic cell-cell interactions and tissue specimen cultures under controlled microenvironments. Biomicrofluidics. 2011;5:13406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Q, Austin RH. Applications of Microfluidics in Stem Cell Biology. Bionanoscience. 2012;2:277–286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3546818</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23336098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou M, Zhang X, Wen X, Wu T, Wang W, Yang M, Wang J, Fang M, Lin B, Lin H. Development of a functional glomerulus at the organ level on a chip to mimic hypertensive nephropathy. Sci Rep. 2016;6:31771.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4997336</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27558173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zlokovic BV. Neurodegeneration and the neurovascular unit. Nat Med. 2010;16:1370–1371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21135839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
