<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35258034</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5857</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>37</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International clinical psychopharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int Clin Psychopharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Psychopharmacology: past, present and future.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>82</StartPage>
          <EndPage>83</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>82-83</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/YIC.0000000000000402</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The origin of modern psychopharmacology dates to the 50s, with the discovery of imipramine and chlorpromazine. At present, we can choose among over 100 different compounds, which are effective in many psychiatric disturbances but are far from perfect in terms of efficacy and tolerability. The main limitation of available treatments is their lack in specificity, both in terms of pharmacologic targets and regional brain specificity. Several new compounds with innovative mechanisms of action have been recently approved; however, pharmacologic treatments targeted for specific tissues are still not available. Recent imaging and genetic findings suggest that we may be close to discovering the regional pathophysiologic mechanisms of psychiatric disorders. Targeted treatment to specific proteins or even genes may be possible using monoclonal antibodies, RNA silencing, gene editing or drug repurposing. We may be therefore close to a shift of paradigm in the treatment of psychiatric disorders, with innovative and targeted treatments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Serretti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Neuromotor Sciences, University of Bologna, Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int Clin Psychopharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8609061</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0268-1315</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>OGG85SX4E4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007099">Imipramine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>U42B7VYA4P</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D002746">Chlorpromazine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002746" MajorTopicYN="N">Chlorpromazine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007099" MajorTopicYN="N">Imipramine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011600" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psychopharmacology</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258034</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YIC.0000000000000402</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00004850-900000000-99397</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castrén E, Monteggia LM. (2021). Brain-derived neurotrophic factor signaling in depression and antidepressant action. Biol Psychiatry. 90:128–136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabbri C, Pain O, Hagenaars SP, Lewis CM, Serretti A. (2021). Transcriptome-wide association study of treatment-resistant depression and depression subtypes for drug repurposing. Neuropsychopharmacology. 46:1821–1829.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jha MK, Trivedi MH. (2018). Personalized antidepressant selection and pathway to novel treatments: clinical utility of targeting inflammation. Int J Mol Sci. 19:E233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kane JM, Durgam S, Satlin A, Vanover KE, Chen R, Davis R, Mates S. (2021). Safety and tolerability of lumateperone for the treatment of schizophrenia: a pooled analysis of late-phase placebo- and active-controlled clinical trials. Int Clin Psychopharmacol. 36:244–250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koblan KS, Kent J, Hopkins SC, Krystal JH, Cheng H, Goldman R, Loebel A. (2020). A non-D2-receptor-binding drug for the treatment of schizophrenia. N Engl J Med. 382:1497–1506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledford H. (2020). CRISPR gene editing in human embryos wreaks chromosomal mayhem. Nature. 583:17–18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levin ML. (1959). A comparison of the effects of phenobarbital, promethazine, chlorpromazine, and placebo upon mental hospital patients. J Consult Psychol. 23:167–170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maya Vetencourt JF, Sale A, Viegi A, Baroncelli L, De Pasquale R, O’Leary OF, et al. (2008). The antidepressant fluoxetine restores plasticity in the adult visual cortex. Science. 320:385–388.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell PB, Hadzi-Pavlovic D. (2000). Lithium treatment for bipolar disorder. Bull World Health Organ. 78:515–517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrow AL, Balan I, Boero G. (2022). Mechanisms underlying recovery from postpartum depression following brexanolone therapy. Biol Psychiatry. 91:252–253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavani G, Amendola M. (2020). Targeted gene delivery: where to land. Front Genome Ed. 2:609650.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Presley CC, Lindsley CW. (2018). DARK classics in chemical neuroscience: opium, a historical perspective. ACS Chem Neurosci. 9:2503–2518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rancans E, Zambori J, Dalsgaard M, Baayen C, Areberg J, Ettrup A, Florea I. (2020). Intravenous vortioxetine to accelerate onset of effect in major depressive disorder: a 7-day randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled exploratory study. Int Clin Psychopharmacol. 35:305–312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Runia N, Yücel DE, Lok A, de Jong K, Denys DAJP, van Wingen GA, Bergfeld IO. (2022). The neurobiology of treatment-resistant depression: a systematic review of neuroimaging studies. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 132:433–448.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serretti A. (2018). The present and future of precision medicine in psychiatry: focus on clinical psychopharmacology of antidepressants. Clin Psychopharmacol Neurosci. 16:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sourkes TL. (1992). Early clinical neurochemistry of CNS-active drugs. Chloral hydrate. Mol Chem Neuropathol. 17:21–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ripke S, Walters JTR, O’Donovan MC, The Schizophrenia Working Group of the Psychiatric Genomics Consortium. (2020). Mapping genomic loci prioritises genes and implicates synaptic biology in schizophrenia. medRxiv. doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.09.12.20192922</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.09.12.20192922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinberg MS, Morris KV. (2016). Transcriptional gene silencing in humans. Nucleic Acids Res. 44:6505–6517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
