<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35260921</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-7339</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>30</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Supportive care in cancer : official journal of the Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Support Care Cancer</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A comparison of three preoperative nutritional assessment methods for predicting ovarian cancer patient prognosis: which is better?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>5221</StartPage>
          <EndPage>5229</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>5221-5229</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00520-022-06941-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The study aimed to compare the predictive values of three widely used nutritional assessment methods, body mass index (BMI), Nutritional Risk Screening 2002 (NRS 2002), and the prognostic nutritional index (PNI), for different clinical prognostic indicators of ovarian cancer patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients diagnosed with ovarian cancer treated in our hospital between January 2017 and March 2019 were retrospectively included. The three nutritional assessment methods were assessed, and multivariable analysis was conducted to explore predictive factors for clinical prognoses. Receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves and the area under the ROC curve (AUROC) were generated to evaluate the discriminative abilities of the three nutritional assessment tools.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 442 patients were recruited. Multivariable analysis revealed that the PNI value predicted 1-year death and 1-year recurrence and that both the NRS 2002 score and the PNI value predicted 30-day readmission (P &lt; 0.05). For PNI, AUROCs were 0.834 for predicting 1-year death and 0.719 for 1-year recurrence prediction; for NRS, the AUROC was 0.820 2002 for predicting 30-day readmission. The optimal cutoff values that maximized the prognostic prediction ability were PNI values of 47.75 g/L and 50.40 g/L for 1-year death and 1-year recurrence, respectively, and an NRS 2002 score of 3 points for 30-day readmission following discharge.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">For ovarian cancer patients, the PNI is better at predicting 1-year death and 30-day readmission after discharge, and the NRS 2002 is superior for predicting 1-year recurrence.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xing</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lu</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gynecological Nursing, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University/West China School of Nursing, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Birth Defects and Related Diseases of Women and Children (Sichuan University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ruiqi</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital of Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Qian</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jiahui</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>West China School of Public Health, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ren</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jianhua</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Birth Defects and Related Diseases of Women and Children (Sichuan University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China. huaxi_rjh@126.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gynecological and Obstetric Nursing, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University/West China School of Nursing, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China. huaxi_rjh@126.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Deng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xue</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gynecological Nursing, West China Second University Hospital, Sichuan University/West China School of Nursing, Sichuan University, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China. huaxi_dx@126.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Birth Defects and Related Diseases of Women and Children (Sichuan University), Ministry of Education, Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China. huaxi_dx@126.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Support Care Cancer</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9302957</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0941-4355</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015596" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nutrition Assessment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010051" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ovarian Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body mass index</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Risk Screening 2002</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional status</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ovarian cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis prediction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognostic Nutritional Index</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35260921</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-022-06941-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00520-022-06941-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandera EV, Lee V, Bo Q, Rodriguez L, Kushi LH (2017) Obesity and ovarian cancer survival revisited. Cancer Res 77:5323–5323</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bozkaya Y, Köstek O, Sakin A, Özyükseler DT, Şakalar T, Çil İ (2020) Is the prognostic nutritional index a prognostic and predictive factor in metastatic non-small cell lung cancer patients treated with first-line chemotherapy? Support Care Cancer 28:2273–2282</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-019-05055-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>C C (2001) Introduction of body mass index classification suggestion in Chinese adult. Zhonghua Yu Fang Yi Xue Za Zhi 35:349–350</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Y, Guan Y, Zheng L, Liu W, Chunhua W, Zhang Y, Chen L, Gong S (2017) Comparison of PG-SGA, NRS 2002 and BIA in nutritional assessment and screening of patients with gynecologic cancers. Parenteral Enteral Nutr 24:221–224</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cong M, Wang J, Fang Y, Liu Y, Sun M, Wu Q, Wang K, Huang Y, Ling Y, Liu Y (2018) A multi-center survey on dietary knowledge and behavior among inpatients in oncology department. Support Care Cancer 26:2285–2292</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-018-4057-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Congxing L, Xin S (2018) Discussion on the factors affecting unplanned readmission to hospital within 30 days after discharge of gastric cancer. J Southeast Univ ( Med Sci Edi) 37:178–182</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dholakia J, Vetter M, Felix A, Salani R (2019) Preoperative prognostic nutritional index scores are associated with progression free survival in patients with ovarian cancer. Gynecol Oncol 153:e13–e14</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygyno.2019.03.136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng Z, Wen H, Ju X, Bi R, Chen X, Yang W, Wu X (2018) The preoperative prognostic nutritional index is a predictive and prognostic factor of high-grade serous ovarian cancer. BMC Cancer 18:883</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-018-4732-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gohar S, Abdel-Ghany A, Soliman S (2016) Effect of body mass index on survival in patients with epithelial ovarian cancer. Res Oncol 12:54–59</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21608/resoncol.2017.223.1007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hertlein L, Kirschenhofer A, Fürst S, Beer D, Göß C, Lenhard M, Friese K, Burges A, Rittler P (2014) Malnutrition and clinical outcome in gynecologic patients. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 174:137–140</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejogrb.2013.12.028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hijaz M, Rasool N, Munkarah AR, Rattan R (2017) Weighing your risks: obesity and ovarian cancer. Gynecol Oncol 145:202</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygyno.2017.03.465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hongju C, Qian X, Yongzhou W (2018) Effects of prognostic nutritional index on the survival of patiens with ovarian cancer. Prog Obstet Gynecol 27:355–358</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hongyu H, Weiping P, Qianqian F, Yupin Y Perioperative nutritional status investigation and nutritional support analysis of patients with advanced ovarian cancer. World Latest Med Inform 17:212–213</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsueh S-W, Lai C-C, Hung C-Y, Lin Y-C, Lu C-H, Yeh K-Y, Tsang N-M, Hung Y-S, Chang P-H, Chou W-C (2021) A comparison of the MNA-SF, MUST, and NRS-2002 nutritional tools in predicting treatment incompletion of concurrent chemoradiotherapy in patients with head and neck cancer. Support Care Cancer 29:5455–5462</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-021-06140-w</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu W, Haijia Z, Lin S, Bo L, Xiao L, Zhenyu H, Wei Z, Mengbin L (2017) Preoperative nutritional risk is a risk factor for adverse clinical outcomes in gastric cancer patients. Parenteral Enteral Nutr 24:150–154</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jésus P, Achamrah N, Grigioni S, Charles J, Rimbert A, Folope V, Petit A, Déchelotte P, Coëffier M (2015) Validity of predictive equations for resting energy expenditure according to the body mass index in a population of 1726 patients followed in a Nutrition Unit. Clin Nutr 34:529–535</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2014.06.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondrup J, Allison SP, Elia M, Vellas B, Plauth M (2003) ESPEN guidelines for nutrition screening 2002. Clin Nutr 22:415–421</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0261-5614(03)00098-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Küçükarda A, Erdoğan B, Gökyer A, Sayın S, Gökmen İ, Özcan E, Hacıoğlu MB, Uzunoğlu S, Çiçin İ (2022) Prognostic nutritional index and its dynamics after curative treatment are independent prognostic factors on survival in non-metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Support Care Cancer 30:2131–2139</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-021-06627-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A, Torres ML, Cliby WA, Kalli KR, Bogani G, Aletti G, Nitschmann CC, Multinu F, Weaver AL, Block MS (2017) Inflammatory and nutritional serum markers as predictors of peri-operative morbidity and survival in ovarian cancer. Anticancer Res 37:3673–3677</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28668859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laky B, Janda M, Cleghorn G, Obermair A (2008) Comparison of different nutritional assessments and body-composition measurements in detecting malnutrition among gynecologic cancer patients. Am J Clin Nutr 87:1678–1685</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/87.6.1678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J (2017) The relationship between nutritional risk and corresponding nutritional support in gastric cancer patients with short-term prognosis and long-term survival. J Clin Res 34:3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miao Y, Li S, Yan Q, Li B, Feng Y (2016) Prognostic significance of preoperative prognostic nutritional index in epithelial ovarian cancer patients treated with platinum-based chemotherapy. Oncol Res Treat 39:712–719</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000452263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirili C, Yılmaz A, Demirkan S, Bilici M, Basol Tekin S (2019) Clinical significance of prognostic nutritional index (PNI) in malignant melanoma. Int J Clin Oncol 24:1301–1310</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10147-019-01461-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qun Z, Yong L, Xi Q, Shichao L, Liqiao F, Bibo T, Peigang Y, Yuan T (2015) Clinical research of nutritional status and life quality assessment in advanced gastric cancer patients. Parenteral Enteral Nutr 22:217–221</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reid BM, Permuth JB, Sellers TA (2017) Epidemiology of ovarian cancer: a review. Cancer Biol Med 14:9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20892/j.issn.2095-3941.2016.0084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigues CS, Chaves GV (2015) Patient-generated subjective global assessment in relation to site, stage of the illness, reason for hospital admission, and mortality in patients with gynecological tumors. Support Care Cancer 23:871–879</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-014-2409-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigues CS, Lacerda MS, Chaves GV (2015) Patient Generated Subjective Global Assessment as a prognosis tool in women with gynecologic cancer. Nutrition 31:1372–1378</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2015.06.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schouten LJ, Rivera C, Hunter DJ, Spiegelman D, Adami H-O, Arslan A, Beeson WL, Van Den Brandt PA, Buring JE, Folsom AR (2008) Height, body mass index, and ovarian cancer: a pooled analysis of 12 cohort studies. Cancer Epidemiol Biomark Prev 17:902–912</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-07-2524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sehouli J, Ali P, Braicu EI, Chekerov R, Grabowski JP (2016) The impact of preoperative malnutrition on surgery outcome and overall survival in ovarian or peritoneal cancer patients: a prospective study. J Clin Oncol 34:5574–5574</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2016.34.15_suppl.5574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torre LA, Bray F, Siegel RL, Ferlay J, Lortet-Tieulent J, Jemal A (2015) Global cancer statistics, 2012. CA Cancer J Clin 65:87–108</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White JV, Guenter P, Jensen G, Malone A, Schofield M (2012) Consensus statement of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics/American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition: characteristics recommended for the identification and documentation of adult malnutrition (undernutrition). J Acad Nutr Diet 112:730–738</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jand.2012.03.012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamauchi Y, Hasegawa W, Yasunaga H, Sunohara M, Jo T, Takami K, Matsui H, Fushimi K, Nagase T (2014) Paradoxical association between body mass index and in-hospital mortality in elderly patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease in Japan. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis 9:1337–1346</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S75175</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yong-ning C, Yang G, Li Z, Wen-lian L, Chun-hua W, Ya-di Z, Li C, Shi-peng G (2017) Comparison of PG-SGA, NRS 2002 and BIA in nutritional assessment and screening of patients with gynecologic cancers. Parenteral Enteral Nutr 24:221–224</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuelan H, Yue Z (2015) Comparison of two nutritional assessments in gYnecologie cancer patients. J Nurs Sci 30:84–85</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamorano AS, Hagemann AR, Morrison L, Lee JA, Liao LM, Brinton LA, Park Y, Toriola AT (2019) Pre-diagnosis body mass index, physical activity and ovarian cancer mortality. Gynecol Oncol 155:105–111</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygyno.2019.07.025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W, Ye B, Liang W, Ren Y (2017) Preoperative prognostic nutritional index is a powerful predictor of prognosis in patients with stage III ovarian cancer. Sci Rep 7:1–8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-016-0028-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhuang C-L, Wang S-L, Huang D-D, Pang W-Y, Lou N, Chen B-C, Chen X-L, Yu Z, Shen X (2015) Risk factors for hospital readmission after radical gastrectomy for gastric cancer: a prospective study. PLoS One 10:e0125572</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0125572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
