<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35266225</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0231</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Rapid communications in mass spectrometry : RCM</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Rapid Commun Mass Spectrom</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Detection of glutathione, cysteine, and homocysteine by online derivatization-based electrospray mass spectrometry.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e9291</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e9291</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/rcm.9291</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="RATIONALE" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Electrospray ionization mass spectrometry (ESI-MS) is one of the most popular techniques for obtaining structural information, which is commonly used in bioanalysis and clinical diagnostics. However, for the detection of complicated samples with high reactivities (such as reactive sulfur species, RSS), traditional ESI-MS usually suffers from overlapped and inaccurate signals. In this study, based on the multiphase flow of extractive electrospray ionization (MF-EESI), an ambient MS technique of online derivatization was proposed to detect thiols without any other sample pretreatment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">RSS molecules and the derivatization reagent of 4-chloro-7-nitro-1,2,3-benzoxadiazole (NBD-Cl) were introduced into the internal and innermost capillary of the MF-EESI system, respectively. By a high-velocity nebulizing stream of N<sub>2</sub> gas through an external capillary, both flows of innermost biothiols and internal NBD-Cl were electrosprayed and mixed for online reactions. Therefore, the fast derivatization of thiols was used to generate stable ionized derivatives for MS detection.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">By evaluating the changes in MS signals before and after the derivatization, the ions of RSS were identified simply and correctly. Without any sample pretreatment, the fast detection of cysteine, homocysteine, and glutathione has been achieved in the complicated samples.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The present online derivatization-based MF-EESI was successfully used for fast, simple, and accurate detection of biothiols. This presented a potential pathway for the fast identification of thiols in complicated samples.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yiyan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Radiopharmaceuticals, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Beijing Normal University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Boyu</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Radiopharmaceuticals, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Beijing Normal University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jianghui</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Radiopharmaceuticals, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Beijing Normal University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ouyang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jin</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Radiopharmaceuticals, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Beijing Normal University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Na</LastName>
            <ForeName>Na</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0474-8409</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Radiopharmaceuticals, Ministry of Education, College of Chemistry, Beijing Normal University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Rapid Commun Mass Spectrom</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8802365</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0951-4198</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013438">Sulfhydryl Compounds</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0LVT1QZ0BA</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D006710">Homocysteine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>GAN16C9B8O</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005978">Glutathione</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>K848JZ4886</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003545">Cysteine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003545" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cysteine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005978" MajorTopicYN="N">Glutathione</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006710" MajorTopicYN="N">Homocysteine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D021241" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spectrometry, Mass, Electrospray Ionization</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013438" MajorTopicYN="N">Sulfhydryl Compounds</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>49</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35266225</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rcm.9291</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacob C, Giles GL, Giles NM, Sies H. Sulfur and selenium: The role of oxidation state in protein structure and function. Angew Chem-Int Edit. 2003;42(39):4742-4758. doi:10.1002/anie.200300573</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Afanas'ev I. Signaling of reactive oxygen and nitrogen species in diabetes mellitus. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2010;3(6):361-373. doi:10.4161/oxim.3.6.14415</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Circu ML, Aw TY. Reactive oxygen species, cellular redox systems, and apoptosis. Free Radic Biol Med. 2010;48(6):749-762. doi:10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2009.12.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin VS, Chen W, Xian M, Chang CJ. Chemical probes for molecular imaging and detection of hydrogen sulfide and reactive sulfur species in biological systems. Chem Soc Rev. 2015;44(14):4596-4618. doi:10.1039/c4cs00298a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gruhlke MCH, Slusarenko AJ. The biology of reactive sulfur species (RSS). Plant Physiol Biochem. 2012;59:98-107. doi:10.1016/j.plaphy.2012.03.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giles GI, Tasker KM, Jacob C. Hypothesis: The role of reactive sulfur species in oxidative stress. Free Radic Biol Med. 2001;31(10):1279-1283. doi:10.1016/s0891-5849(01)00710-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bogdandi V, Ida T, Sutton TR, et al. Speciation of reactive sulfur species and their reactions with alkylating agents: Do we have any clue about what is present inside the cell? Br J Pharmacol. 2019;176(4):646-670. doi:10.1111/bph.14394</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bora P, Chauhan P, Pardeshi KA, Chakrapani H. Small molecule generators of biologically reactive sulfur species. RSC Advances. 2018;8(48):27359-27374. doi:10.1039/c8ra03658f</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turell L, Radi R, Alvarez B. The thiol pool in human plasma: The central contribution of albumin to redox processes. Free Radic Biol Med. 2013;65:244-253. doi:10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2013.05.050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun JG, Bai Y, Ma QJ, et al. A FRET-based ratiometric fluorescent probe for highly selective detection of hydrogen polysulfides based on a coumarin-rhodol derivative. Spectroc Acta Pt A-Molec Biomolec Spectr. 2020;241:118650. doi:10.1016/j.saa.2020.118650</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Opdenbosch N, Lamkanfi M. Caspases in cell death, inflammation, and disease. Immunity. 2019;50(6):1352-1364. doi:10.1016/j.immuni.2019.05.020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winder AF. Homocysteine and cardiovascular disease. J Clin Pathol. 1998;51(10):713. doi:10.1136/jcp.51.10.713</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H, Xu LZ, Chen WQ, et al. Simultaneous discrimination of cysteine, homocysteine, glutathione, and H2S in living cells through a multisignal combination strategy. Anal Chem. 2019;91(3):1904-1911. doi:10.1021/acs.analchem.8b03869</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tcherkas YV, Denisenko AD. Simultaneous determination of several amino acids, including homocysteine, cysteine and glutamic acid, in human plasma by isocratic reversed-phase high-performance liquid chromatography with fluorimetric detection. J Chromatogr a. 2001;913(1-2):309-313. doi:10.1016/s0021-9673(00)01201-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amarnath K, Amarnath V, Amarnath K, Valentine HL, Valentine WM. A specific HPLC-UV method for the determination of cysteine and related aminothiols in biological samples. Talanta. 2003;60(6):1229-1238. doi:10.1016/s0039-9140(03)00232-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolin TD, McMenamin ME, Himmelfarb J. Simultaneous determination of total homocysteine, cysteine, cysteinylglycine, and glutathione in human plasma by high-performance liquid chromatography: Application to studies of oxidative stress. J Chromatogr B. 2007;852(1-2):554-561. doi:10.1016/j.jchromb.2007.02.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu G, Yan QL, Lv XG, et al. Imaging of colorectal cancers using Activatable Nanoprobes with second near-infrared window emission. Angew Chem-Int Edit. 2018;57(14):3626-3630. doi:10.1002/anie.201712528</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu XL, Niu LY, Chen YZ, Yang YX, Yang QZ. A multi-emissive fluorescent probe for the discrimination of glutathione and cysteine. Biosens Bioelectron. 2017;90:403-409. doi:10.1016/j.bios.2016.06.076</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, He N, Huang Y, et al. Mitochondria-targeting near-infrared ratiometric fluorescent probe for selective imaging of cysteine in orthotopic lung cancer mice. Sens Actuators B: Chem. 2019;282:69-77. doi:10.1016/j.snb.2018.11.056</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawrence NS, Deo RP, Wang J. Detection of homocysteine at carbon nanotube paste electrodes. Talanta. 2004;63(2):443-449. doi:10.1016/j.talanta.2003.11.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fei SD, Chen JH, Yao SZ, Deng GH, He DL, Kuang YF. Electrochemical behavior of L-cysteine and its detection at carbon nanotube electrode modified with platinum. Anal Biochem. 2005;339(1):29-35. doi:10.1016/j.ab.2005.01.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mao FJ, Yu K, He J, et al. Real-time monitoring of electroreduction and labelling of disulfide-bonded peptides and proteins by mass spectrometry. Analyst. 2019;144(23):6898-6904. doi:10.1039/c9an01420a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vellasco AP, Haddad R, Eberlin MN, Hoehr NF. Combined cysteine and homocysteine quantitation in plasma by trap and release membrane introduction mass spectrometry. Analyst. 2002;127(8):1050-1053. doi:10.1039/b203832c</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu LL, Zhou CG, Li H, Zhang M, Xu W. Instantaneous response of bacteria to external stimuli monitored by syringe spray mass spectrometry. Anal Chem. 2018;90(19):11417-11422. doi:10.1021/acs.analchem.8b02443</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Z, Chen PY, Li GY, et al. Mechanistic study of CBT-Cys click reaction and its application for identifying bioactive N-terminal cysteine peptides in amniotic fluid. Chem Sci. 2017;8(1):214-222. doi:10.1039/c6sc01461e</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhai YB, Liu SY, Gao LJ, Hu LL, Xu W. Direct biological sample analyses by Laserspray ionization miniature mass spectrometry. Anal Chem. 2018;90(9):5696-5702. doi:10.1021/acs.analchem.7b05366</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang J, Zhang DM, Zhao DD, et al. Rapid determination of Adenine Arabinoside Monophosphate in Pharmaceutical Injections by Droplet Spray Ionization - Tandem Mass Spectrometry (DSI-MS/MS). Anal Lett. 2019;52(16):2484-2495. doi:10.1080/00032719.2019.1613423</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang J, Zhang D, Zhang H, et al. Rapid determination of melatonin by droplet spray ionization mass spectrometry. Int J Mass Spectrom. 2019;444:116191. doi:10.1016/j.ijms.2019.116191</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han J, Huang X, Liu HH, Wang JY, Xiong CQ, Nie ZX. Laser cleavable probes for in situ multiplexed glycan detection by single cell mass spectrometry. Chem Sci. 2020;11(4):1176. doi:10.1039/c9sc90270h</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang SH, Liu HH, Huang X, et al. The metabolism and distribution of imidazole alkaloids from Lepidium meyenii (Maca) in mouse by matrix-assisted laser desorption/ionization mass spectrometry imaging. Int J Mass Spectrom. 2018;434:93-99. doi:10.1016/j.ijms.2018.09.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Sun M, Qiao J, Ouyang J, Na N. FAD roles in glucose catalytic oxidation studied by multiphase flow of extractive electrospray ionization (MF-EESI) mass spectrometry. Chem Sci. 2018;9(3):594-599. doi:10.1039/c7sc04259k</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Fan X, Lu H, et al. Observation of intermediates by online mass spectrometry to demonstrate the multiple mechanisms of dye-sensitized photocatalysis. Chem Commun. 2021;57(32):3921-3924. doi:10.1039/d1cc00908g</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang YF, Zhang YB, Huo FG, Liu YM, Yin CX. Dual-channel red fluorescent probe for detection of Cys/Hcy and GSH in plants. Sens Actuators B. 2019;301:127123 doi:10.1016/j.snb.2019.127123</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
