<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35266562</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-8652</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>97</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>American journal of hematology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Hematol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Mantle cell lymphoma in 2022-A comprehensive update on molecular pathogenesis, risk stratification, clinical approach, and current and novel treatments.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>638</StartPage>
          <EndPage>656</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>638-656</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajh.26523</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The field of mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) has witnessed remarkable progress due to relentless advances in molecular pathogenesis, prognostication, and newer treatments. MCL consists of a spectrum of clinical subtypes. Rarely, atypical cyclin D1-negative MCL and in situ MCL neoplasia are identified. Prognostication of MCL is further refined by identifying somatic mutations (such as TP53, NSD2, KMT2D), methylation status, chromatin organization pattern, SOX-11 expression, minimal residual disease (MRD), and genomic clusters. Lymphoid tissue microenvironment studies demonstrated the role of B-cell receptor signaling, nuclear factor kappa B (NF-kB), colony-stimulating factor (CSF)-1, the CD70-SOX-11 axis. Molecular mechanism of resistance, mutation dynamics, and pathogenic pathways (B-cell receptor (BCR), oxidative phosphorylation, and MYC) were identified in mediating resistance to various treatments (bruton tyrosine kinase (BTK) inhibitors [ibrutinib, acalabrutinib]. Treatment options range from conventional chemoimmunotherapy and stem cell transplantation (SCT) to targeted therapies against BTK (covalent and noncovalent), Bcl2, ROR1, cellular therapy such as anti-CD19 chimeric antigen receptor therapy (CAR-T), and most recently bispecific antibodies against CD19 and CD20. MCL patients frequently relapse. Complex pathogenesis and the management of patients with progression after treatment with BTK/Bcl2 inhibitors and CAR-T (triple-resistant MCL) remain a challenge. Next-generation clinical trials incorporating newer agents and concurrent translational and molecular investigations are ongoing.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jain</LastName>
            <ForeName>Preetesh</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2735-168X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Lymphoma/Myeloma. Mantle cell lymphoma center of excellence, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael L</ForeName>
            <Initials>ML</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9748-5486</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Lymphoma/Myeloma. Mantle cell lymphoma center of excellence, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Hematol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7610369</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0361-8609</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000970">Antineoplastic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077329">Agammaglobulinaemia Tyrosine Kinase</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077329" MajorTopicYN="N">Agammaglobulinaemia Tyrosine Kinase</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000970" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020522" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lymphoma, Mantle-Cell</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009364" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Recurrence, Local</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018570" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Assessment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059016" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Microenvironment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35266562</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajh.26523</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weisenburger DD, Kim H, Rappaport H. Mantle-zone lymphoma: a follicular variant of intermediate lymphocytic lymphoma. Cancer. 1982;49(7):1429-1438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow SH, Campo E, Pileri SA, et al. The 2016 revision of the World Health Organization classification of lymphoid neoplasms. Blood. 2016;127(20):2375-2390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papin A, Tessoulin B, Bellanger C, et al. CSF1R and BTK inhibitions as novel strategies to disrupt the dialog between mantle cell lymphoma and macrophages. Leukemia. 2019;33(10):2442-2453.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Dreyling M, Seymour JF, Wang M. High-risk mantle cell lymphoma: definition, current challenges, and management. J Clin Oncol. 2020;38(36):4302-4316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi S, Yan Y, Jin M, et al. Genomic and transcriptomic profiling reveals distinct molecular subsets associated with outcomes in mantle cell lymphoma. J Clin Invest. 2022.132(3):e153283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hermine O, Jiang L, Walewski J, et al. Addition of high-dose Cytarabine to Immunochemotherapy before autologous stem-cell transplantation in patients aged 65 years or younger with mantle cell lymphoma (MCL younger): a long-term follow-up of the randomized, open-label, phase 3 trial of the European mantle cell lymphoma Network. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Gouill S, Thieblemont C, Oberic L, et al. Rituximab after autologous stem-cell transplantation in mantle-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(13):1250-1260.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen T, Wang J, Shi Y, Qian H, Liu P. Inhibitors targeting Bruton's tyrosine kinase in cancers: drug development advances. Leukemia. 2021;35(2):312-332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Shah NN, Alencar AJ, et al. Pirtobrutinib, a next generation, highly selective, non-covalent BTK inhibitor in previously treated mantle cell lymphoma: updated results from the phase 1/2 BRUIN study. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips T, Dickinson M, Morschhauser F, et al. Glofitamab step-up dosing induces high response rates in patients (pts) with relapsed or refractory (R/R) mantle cell lymphoma (MCL), Most of whom had failed prior Bruton's tyrosine kinase inhibitor (BTKi) therapy. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Mei M, Barr PM, et al. Phase 1 dose escalation and cohort expansion study of the anti-ROR1 antibody-drug conjugate Zilovertamab Vedotin (MK-2140) for the treatment of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao S, Kanagal-Shamanna R, Navsaria L, et al. Efficacy of venetoclax in high risk relapsed mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) - outcomes and mutation profile from venetoclax resistant MCL patients. Am J Hematol. 2020;95(6):623-629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di M, Cui C, Kothari S, et al. Survival of mantle cell lymphoma in the era of Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitors: a population-based analysis. Blood. Advances. 2022.35240689.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Munoz J, Goy A, et al. KTE-X19 CAR T-cell therapy in relapsed or refractory mantle-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(14):1331-1342.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Jiang VC, Han G, et al. Longitudinal single-cell profiling reveals molecular heterogeneity and tumor-immune evolution in refractory mantle cell lymphoma. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2877.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu S, Wang M, Lairson DR, Li R, Zhao B, Du XL. Trends and variations in mantle cell lymphoma incidence from 1995 to 2013: a comparative study between Texas and national SEER areas. Oncotarget. 2017;8(68):112516-112529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrahamsson A, Albertsson-Lindblad A, Brown PN, et al. Real world data on primary treatment for mantle cell lymphoma: a Nordic lymphoma group observational study. Blood. 2014;124(8):1288-1295.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teras LR, DeSantis CE, Cerhan JR, Morton LM, Jemal A, Flowers CR. 2016 US lymphoid malignancy statistics by World Health Organization subtypes. CA Cancer J Clin. 2016.66(6):443-459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Ma S. Racial differences in mantle cell lymphoma in the United States. BMC Cancer. 2014;14:764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee H, Park HJ, Park EH, et al. Nationwide statistical analysis of lymphoid malignancies in Korea. Cancer Res Treat. 2018;50(1):222-238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng J, Chang C, Pan H, et al. Epidemiologic characteristics of malignant lymphoma in Hubei, China: a single-center 5-year retrospective study. Medicine (Baltimore). 2018;97(35):e12120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glimelius I, Smedby KE, Eloranta S, Jerkeman M, Weibull CE. Comorbidities and sex differences in causes of death among mantle cell lymphoma patients - a nationwide population-based cohort study. Br J Haematol. 2020;189(1):106-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inga N, José IM-S, Florian W, et al. Recurrent loss of the Y chromosome and homozygous deletions within the pseudoautosomal region 1: association with male predominance in mantle cell lymphoma. Haematologica. 2008;93(6):949-950.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Ma S. Risk factors for etiology and prognosis of mantle cell lymphoma. Expert Rev Hematol. 2014;7(2):233-243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X, Song Y, Chen W, et al. Germline variants of DNA repair genes in early onset mantle cell lymphoma. Oncogene. 2021;40(3):551-563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schollkopf C, Melbye M, Munksgaard L, et al. Borrelia infection and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Blood. 2008;111(12):5524-5529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holtan SG, O'Connor HM, Fredericksen ZS, et al. Food-frequency questionnaire-based estimates of total antioxidant capacity and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Int J Cancer. 2012;131(5):1158-1168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smedby KE, Sampson JN, Turner JJ, et al. Medical history, lifestyle, family history, and occupational risk factors for mantle cell lymphoma: the InterLymph non-Hodgkin lymphoma subtypes project. J Natl Cancer Inst Monogr. 2014;2014(48):76-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skibola CF, Bracci PM, Nieters A, et al. Tumor necrosis factor (TNF) and lymphotoxin-alpha (LTA) polymorphisms and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma in the InterLymph consortium. Am J Epidemiol. 2010;171(3):267-276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Musiu P, Quattrocchi L, Barberi W, et al. Donor cell derived mantle cell lymphoma in a HSCT sibling donor-recipient pair: intrinsic biological clock in lymphomagenesis. Leuk Lymphoma. 2022;63(2):499-502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smedby KE, Hjalgrim H, Askling J, et al. Autoimmune and chronic inflammatory disorders and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma by subtype. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2006;98(1):51-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kleinstern G, Maurer MJ, Liebow M, et al. History of autoimmune conditions and lymphoma prognosis. Blood Cancer J. 2018;8(8):73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadzidimitriou A, Agathangelidis A, Darzentas N, et al. Is there a role for antigen selection in mantle cell lymphoma? Immunogenetic support from a series of 807 cases. Blood. 2011;118(11):3088-3095.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fichtner M, Spies E, Seismann H, et al. Complementarity determining region-independent recognition of a superantigen by B-cell antigen receptors of mantle cell lymphoma. Haematologica. 2016;101(9):e378-e381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leshchenko VV, Kuo PY, Shaknovich R, et al. Genomewide DNA methylation analysis reveals novel targets for drug development in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2010;116(7):1025-1034.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarro A, Bea S, Jares P, Campo E. Molecular pathogenesis of mantle cell lymphoma. Hematol Oncol Clin North Am. 2020;34(5):795-807.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pieters T, T'Sas S, Vanhee S, et al. Cyclin D2 overexpression drives B1a-derived MCL-like lymphoma in mice. J Exp Med. 2021;218(10).e20202280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Queiros AC, Beekman R, Vilarrasa-Blasi R, et al. Decoding the DNA Methylome of mantle cell lymphoma in the light of the entire B cell lineage. Cancer Cell. 2016;30(5):806-821.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navarro A, Clot G, Royo C, et al. Molecular subsets of mantle cell lymphoma defined by the IGHV mutational status and SOX11 expression have distinct biologic and clinical features. Cancer Res. 2012;72(20):5307-5316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nadeu F, Martin-Garcia D, Clot G, et al. Genomic and epigenomic insights into the origin, pathogenesis and clinical behavior of mantle cell lymphoma subtypes. Blood. 2020.136(12):1419-1432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvajal-Cuenca A, Sua LF, Silva NM, et al. In situ mantle cell lymphoma: clinical implications of an incidental finding with indolent clinical behavior. Haematologica. 2012;97(2):270-278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lecluse Y, Lebailly P, Roulland S, Gac AC, Nadel B, Gauduchon P. T(11;14)-positive clones can persist over a long period of time in the peripheral blood of healthy individuals. Leukemia. 2009;23(6):1190-1193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albero R, Enjuanes A, Demajo S, et al. Cyclin D1 overexpression induces global transcriptional downregulation in lymphoid neoplasms. J Clin Invest. 2018;128(9):4132-4147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demajo S, Albero R, Clot G, et al. A cyclin D1-dependent transcriptional program predicts clinical outcome in mantle cell lymphoma. Clin Cancer Res. 2021;27(1):213-225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Body S, Esteve-Arenys A, Miloudi H, et al. Cytoplasmic cyclin D1 controls the migration and invasiveness of mantle lymphoma cells. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):13946.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slotta-Huspenina J, Koch I, de Leval L, et al. The impact of cyclin D1 mRNA isoforms, morphology and p53 in mantle cell lymphoma: p53 alterations and blastoid morphology are strong predictors of a high proliferation index. Haematologica. 2012;97(9):1422-1430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiestner A, Tehrani M, Chiorazzi M, et al. Point mutations and genomic deletions in CCND1 create stable truncated cyclin D1 mRNAs that are associated with increased proliferation rate and shorter survival. Blood. 2007;109(11):4599-4606.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delfau-Larue MH, Klapper W, Berger F, et al. High-dose cytarabine does not overcome the adverse prognostic value of CDKN2A and TP53 deletions in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2015;126(5):604-611.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinyol M, Hernandez L, Cazorla M, et al. Deletions and loss of expression of p16INK4a and p21Waf1 genes are associated with aggressive variants of mantle cell lymphomas. Blood. 1997;89(1):272-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez L, Bea S, Pinyol M, et al. CDK4 and MDM2 gene alterations mainly occur in highly proliferative and aggressive mantle cell lymphomas with wild-type INK4a/ARF locus. Cancer Res. 2005;65(6):2199-2206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohanty A, Sandoval N, Das M, et al. CCND1 mutations increase protein stability and promote ibrutinib resistance in mantle cell lymphoma. Oncotarget. 2016;7(45):73558-73572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson JF, Baughn LB, Ketterling RP, et al. Characterization of a cryptic IGH/CCND1 rearrangement in a case of mantle cell lymphoma with negative CCND1 FISH studies. Blood Adv. 2019;3(8):1298-1302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marrero WD, Cruz-Chacon A, Cabanillas F. Mantle cell lymphoma with t(11;22) (q13;q11.2) an indolent clinical variant? Leuk Lymphoma. 2018;59(10):2509-2511.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maekawa F, Kishimori C, Nakagawa M, et al. Truncation of 3' CCND1 by t(11;22) leads to negative SP4 CCND1 immunohistochemistry in blastoid mantle cell lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2021;5(1):61-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iaccarino I, Afify L, Aukema SM, et al. T(11;14)-positive mantle cell lymphomas lacking cyclin D1 (CCND1) immunostaining because of a CCND1 mutation or exclusive expression of the CCND1b isoform. Haematologica. 2018;103(9):e432-e435.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaverria I, Royo C, Carvajal-Cuenca A, et al. CCND2 rearrangements are the most frequent genetic events in cyclin D1(−) mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2013;121(8):1394-1402.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin-Garcia D, Navarro A, Valdes-Mas R, et al. CCND2 and CCND3 hijack immunoglobulin light-chain enhancers in cyclin D1(−) mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2019;133(9):940-951.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ek S, Dictor M, Jerkeman M, Jirstrom K, Borrebaeck CA. Nuclear expression of the non B-cell lineage Sox11 transcription factor identifies mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2008;111(2):800-805.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohanty A, Sandoval N, Phan A, et al. Regulation of SOX11 expression through CCND1 and STAT3 in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2019;133(4):306-318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilarrasa-Blasi R, Verdaguer-Dot N, Belver L, et al. Insights into the mechanisms underlying aberrant SOX11 oncogene expression in mantle cell lymphoma. Leukemia. 2022.36(2):583-587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vegliante MC, Palomero J, Perez-Galan P, et al. SOX11 regulates PAX5 expression and blocks terminal B-cell differentiation in aggressive mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2013;121(12):2175-2185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuo PY, Jatiani SS, Rahman AH, et al. SOX11 augments BCR signaling to drive MCL-like tumor development. Blood. 2018;131(20):2247-2255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palomero J, Vegliante MC, Eguileor A, et al. SOX11 defines two different subtypes of mantle cell lymphoma through transcriptional regulation of BCL6. Leukemia. 2016;30(7):1596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palomero J, Vegliante MC, Rodriguez ML, et al. SOX11 promotes tumor angiogenesis through transcriptional regulation of PDGFA in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2014;124(14):2235-2247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balsas P, Palomero J, Eguileor A, et al. SOX11 promotes tumor protective microenvironment interactions through CXCR4 and FAK regulation in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2017;130(4):501-513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balsas P, Veloza L, Clot G, et al. SOX11, CD70 and Treg cells configure the tumor immune microenvironment of aggressive mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2021(138:(22):2202. .-2215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Streich L, Sukhanova M, Lu X, et al. Aggressive morphologic variants of mantle cell lymphoma characterized with high genomic instability showing frequent chromothripsis, CDKN2A/B loss, and TP53 mutations: a multi-institutional study. Genes Chromosomes Cancer. 2020;59(8):484-494.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrero S, Rossi D, Rinaldi A, et al. KMT2D mutations and TP53 disruptions are poor prognostic biomarkers in mantle cell lymphoma receiving high-dose therapy: a FIL study. Haematologica. 2020;105(6):1604-1612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal R, Chan YC, Tam CS, et al. Dynamic molecular monitoring reveals that SWI-SNF mutations mediate resistance to ibrutinib plus venetoclax in mantle cell lymphoma. Nat Med. 2019;25(1):119-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eskelund CW, Dahl C, Hansen JW, et al. TP53 mutations identify younger mantle cell lymphoma patients who do not benefit from intensive chemoimmunotherapy. Blood. 2017;130(17):1903-1910.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Yao Y, Zhang S, et al. Metabolic reprogramming toward oxidative phosphorylation identifies a therapeutic target for mantle cell lymphoma. Sci Transl Med. 2019;11(491).eaau1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigues JM, Nikkarinen A, Hollander P, et al. Infiltration of CD163-, PD-L1- and FoxP3-positive cells adversely affects outcome in patients with mantle cell lymphoma independent of established risk factors. Br J Haematol. 2021;193(3):520-531.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saba NS, Liu D, Herman SE, et al. Pathogenic role of B-cell receptor signaling and canonical NF-kappaB activation in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2016;128(1):82-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kridel R, Meissner B, Rogic S, et al. Whole transcriptome sequencing reveals recurrent NOTCH1 mutations in mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2012;119(9):1963-1971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swenson SA, Gilbreath TJ, Vahle H, et al. UBR5 HECT domain mutations identified in mantle cell lymphoma control maturation of B cells. Blood. 2020;136(3):299-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao X, Lwin T, Silva A, et al. Unification of de novo and acquired ibrutinib resistance in mantle cell lymphoma. Nat Commun. 2017;8:14920.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Kanagal-Shamanna R, Zhang S, et al. Long-term outcomes and mutation profiling of patients with mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) who discontinued ibrutinib. Br J Haematol. 2018;183(4):578-587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pararajalingam P, Coyle KM, Arthur S, et al. Coding and non-coding drivers of mantle cell lymphoma identified through exome and genome sequencing. Blood. 2020(136:(5):572. .-584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romaguera JE, Medeiros LJ, Hagemeister FB, et al. Frequency of gastrointestinal involvement and its clinical significance in mantle cell lymphoma. Cancer. 2003;97(3):586-591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheah CY, George A, Gine E, et al. Central nervous system involvement in mantle cell lymphoma: clinical features, prognostic factors and outcomes from the European mantle cell lymphoma Network. Ann Oncol. 2013;24(8):2119-2123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klapper W, Hoster E, Determann O, et al. Ki-67 as a prognostic marker in mantle cell lymphoma-consensus guidelines of the pathology panel of the European MCL Network. J Hematop. 2009;2(2):103-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fratoni S. P.31-49. Unusual variants of mantle cell lymphoma. Hema. 2017;2(1):31-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li S, Xu J, You MJ. The pathologic diagnosis of mantle cell lymphoma. Histol Histopathol. 2021;36(10):1037-1051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akhter A, Mahe E, Street L, et al. CD10-positive mantle cell lymphoma: biologically distinct entity or an aberrant immunophenotype? Insight, through gene expression profile in a unique case series. J Clin Pathol. 2015;68(10):844-848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Dong HY, Gorczyca W, et al. CD5- mantle cell lymphoma. Am J Clin Pathol. 2002;118(2):216-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu K, Weisenburger DD, Greiner TC, et al. Cyclin D1-negative mantle cell lymphoma: a clinicopathologic study based on gene expression profiling. Blood. 2005;106(13):4315-4321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlette E, Fu K, Medeiros LJ. CD23 expression in mantle cell lymphoma: clinicopathologic features of 18 cases. Am J Clin Pathol. 2003;120(5):760-766.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheson BD, Fisher RI, Barrington SF, et al. Recommendations for initial evaluation, staging, and response assessment of Hodgkin and non-Hodgkin lymphoma: the Lugano classification. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(27):3059-3068.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoster E, Dreyling M, Klapper W, et al. A new prognostic index (MIPI) for patients with advanced-stage mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2008;111(2):558-565.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoster E, Klapper W, Hermine O, et al. Confirmation of the mantle-cell lymphoma international prognostic index in randomized trials of the European mantle-cell lymphoma Network. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(13):1338-1346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoster E, Rosenwald A, Berger F, et al. Prognostic value of Ki-67 index, cytology, and growth pattern in mantle-cell lymphoma: results from randomized trials of the European mantle cell lymphoma Network. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34(12):1386-1394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husby S, Ralfkiaer U, Garde C, et al. miR-18b overexpression identifies mantle cell lymphoma patients with poor outcome and improves the MIPI-B prognosticator. Blood. 2015;125(17):2669-2677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Kanagal-Shamanna R, Zhang S, et al. Clinical and genomic characteristics in De novo Blastoid/pleomorphic (dnMCL) and transformed Blastoid/pleomorphic (t-MCL) mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) in the Ibrutinib era: comprehensive analysis of 168 patients. Blood. 2018;132(Suppl 1):1599-1599.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aukema SM, Hoster E, Rosenwald A, et al. Expression of TP53 is associated with the outcome of MCL independent of MIPI and Ki-67 in trials of the European MCL Network. Blood. 2018;131(4):417-420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clot G, Jares P, Gine E, et al. A gene signature that distinguishes conventional and leukemic nonnodal mantle cell lymphoma helps predict outcome. Blood. 2018;132(4):413-422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill HA, Qi X, Jain P, et al. Genetic mutations and features of mantle cell lymphoma: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Blood Adv. 2020;4(13):2927-2938.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorselius M, Walsh S, Eriksson I, et al. Somatic hypermutation and V(H) gene usage in mantle cell lymphoma. Eur J Haematol. 2002;68(4):217-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenwell IB, Staton AD, Lee MJ, et al. Complex karyotype in patients with mantle cell lymphoma predicts inferior survival and poor response to intensive induction therapy. Cancer. 2018;124(11):2306-2315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott DW, Abrisqueta P, Wright GW, et al. New molecular assay for the proliferation signature in mantle cell lymphoma applicable to formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded biopsies. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35(15):1668-1677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bomben R, Ferrero S, D'Agaro T, et al. A B-cell receptor-related gene signature predicts survival in mantle cell lymphoma: results from the Fondazione Italiana Linfomi MCL-0208 trial. Haematologica. 2018;103(5):849-856.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Agaro T, Zucchetto A, Vit F, et al. A B-cell receptor-related gene signature predicts response to ibrutinib treatmeant in mantle cell lymphoma cell lines. Haematologica. 2019(104:(9):e410. .-e414.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonbol MB, Maurer MJ, Stenson MJ, et al. Elevated soluble IL-2Ralpha, IL-8, and MIP-1beta levels are associated with inferior outcome and are independent of MIPI score in patients with mantle cell lymphoma. Am J Hematol. 2014;89(12):E223-E227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bond DA, Switchenko JM, Villa D, et al. Early relapse identifies MCL patients with inferior survival after intensive or less intensive frontline therapy. Blood Adv. 2021.5(23):5179-5189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoster E, Pott C. Minimal residual disease in mantle cell lymphoma: insights into biology and impact on treatment. Hematology Am Soc Hematol Educ Program. 2016;2016(1):437-445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladetto M, Tavarozzi R, Pott C. Minimal residual disease in mantle cell lymphoma: methods and clinical significance. Hematol Oncol Clin North Am. 2020.34(5):887-901.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin P, Maddocks K, Leonard JP, et al. Postibrutinib outcomes in patients with mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2016;127(12):1559-1563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honigberg LA, Smith AM, Sirisawad M, et al. The Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor PCI-32765 blocks B-cell activation and is efficacious in models of autoimmune disease and B-cell malignancy. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2010;107(29):13075-13080.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davids MS, Roberts AW, Seymour JF, et al. Phase I first-in-human study of Venetoclax in patients with relapsed or refractory non-Hodgkin lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35(8):826-833.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Kanagal-Shamanna R, Zhang S, et al. Outcomes, causes of discontinuation and mutation profile of patients with mantle cell lymphoma who progressed on Acalabrutinib. Blood. 2018;132(Suppl 1):4151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye H, Desai A, Zeng D, et al. Smoldering mantle cell lymphoma. J Exp Clin Cancer Res. 2017;36(1):185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin P, Chadburn A, Christos P, et al. Outcome of deferred initial therapy in mantle-cell lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27(8):1209-1213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gine E, de la Cruz F, Jimenez Ubieto A, et al. Ibrutinib in combination with rituximab for indolent clinical forms of mantle cell lymphoma (IMCL-2015): a multicenter, open-label, single-arm, phase II trial. J Clin Oncol. 2022;JCO2102321.JCO2102321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romancik JT, Cohen JB. Is limited-stage mantle cell lymphoma curable and how is it best managed? Hematol Oncol Clin North Am. 2020;34(5):849-859.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerson JN, Handorf E, Villa D, et al. Survival outcomes of younger patients with mantle cell lymphoma treated in the rituximab era. J Clin Oncol. 2019;37(6):471-480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khouri IF, Romaguera J, Kantarjian H, et al. Hyper-CVAD and high-dose methotrexate/cytarabine followed by stem-cell transplantation: an active regimen for aggressive mantle-cell lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 1998;16(12):3803-3809.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romaguera JE, Wang M, Feng L, et al. Phase 2 trial of bortezomib in combination with rituximab plus hyperfractionated cyclophosphamide, vincristine, doxorubicin, and dexamethasone alternating with bortezomib, rituximab, methotrexate, and cytarabine for untreated mantle cell lymphoma. Cancer. 2018;124(12):2561-2569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geisler CH, Kolstad A, Laurell A, et al. Long-term progression-free survival of mantle cell lymphoma after intensive front-line immunochemotherapy with in vivo-purged stem cell rescue: a nonrandomized phase 2 multicenter study by the Nordic lymphoma group. Blood. 2008;112(7):2687-2693.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eskelund CW, Kolstad A, Jerkeman M, et al. 15-year follow-up of the second Nordic mantle cell lymphoma trial (MCL2): prolonged remissions without survival plateau. Br J Haematol. 2016;175(3):410-418.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ML, Jain P, Zhao S, et al. Ibrutinib-rituximab followed by R-HCVAD as frontline treatment for young patients (&lt;/=65years) with mantle cell lymphoma (WINDOW-1): a single-arm, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2022.23(3):406-415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Jain P, Lee HJ, et al. Ibrutinib plus rituximab and Venetoclax (IRV) followed by risk-stratified observation or short course R-Hypercvad/MTX in young patients with previously untreated mantle cell lymphoma - phase-II Window-2 clinical trial. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):3525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rummel MJ, Niederle N, Maschmeyer G, et al. Bendamustine plus rituximab versus CHOP plus rituximab as first-line treatment for patients with indolent and mantle-cell lymphomas: an open-label, multicentre, randomised, phase 3 non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2013;381(9873):1203-1210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flinn IW, van der Jagt R, Kahl B, et al. First-line treatment of patients with indolent non-Hodgkin lymphoma or mantle-cell lymphoma with Bendamustine plus rituximab versus R-CHOP or R-CVP: results of the BRIGHT 5-year follow-up study. J Clin Oncol. 2019;JCO1800605. 37(12):984-991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rummel MJ, Maschmeyer G, Ganser A, et al. Bendamustine plus rituximab (B-R) versus CHOP plus rituximab (CHOP-R) as first-line treatment in patients with indolent lymphomas: nine-year updated results from the StiL NHL1 study. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35(15_suppl):7501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Visco C, Chiappella A, Nassi L, et al. Rituximab, bendamustine, and low-dose cytarabine as induction therapy in elderly patients with mantle cell lymphoma: a multicentre, phase 2 trial from Fondazione Italiana Linfomi. Lancet Haematol. 2017;4(1):e15-e23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villa D, Sehn LH, Savage KJ, et al. Bendamustine and rituximab as induction therapy in both transplant-eligible and -ineligible patients with mantle cell lymphoma. Blood Adv. 2020;4(15):3486-3494.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albertsson-Lindblad A, Palsdottir T, Smedby KE, Weibull CE, Glimelius I, Jerkeman M. Survival in mantle cell lymphoma after frontline treatment with Rbendamustine, R-CHOP and the Nordic MCL2 regimen - a real world study on patients diagnosed in Sweden 2007-2017. Haematologica. 2022.107(3):740-743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castellino A, Wang Y, Larson MC, et al. Evolving frontline Immunochemotherapy for mantle cell lymphoma and the impact on survival outcomes. Blood Adv. 2022(6:(4):1350. .-1360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamshon S, Martin P, Shah B, et al. Initial treatment with Lenalidomide plus rituximab for mantle cell lymphoma (MCL): 7-year analysis from a multi-center phase II study. Blood. 2020;136(Supplement 1):45-46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Zhao S, Lee HJ, et al. Ibrutinib with rituximab in first-line treatment of older patients with mantle cell lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2022;JCO2101797. 40(2):202-212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goy A, Bernstein SH, Kahl BS, et al. Bortezomib in patients with relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma: updated time-to-event analyses of the multicenter phase 2 PINNACLE study. Ann Oncol. 2009;20(3):520-525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hess G, Herbrecht R, Romaguera J, et al. Phase III study to evaluate temsirolimus compared with investigator's choice therapy for the treatment of relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27(23):3822-3829.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trneny M, Lamy T, Walewski J, et al. Lenalidomide versus investigator's choice in relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma (MCL-002; SPRINT): a phase 2, randomised, multicentre trial. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17(3):319-331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ML, Rule S, Martin P, et al. Targeting BTK with ibrutinib in relapsed or refractory mantle-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2013;369(6):507-516.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rule S, Dreyling M, Goy A, et al. Ibrutinib for the treatment of relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma: extended 3.5-year follow-up from a pooled analysis. Haematologica. 2019.104(5):e211-e214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Rule S, Zinzani PL, et al. Acalabrutinib in relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma (ACE-LY-004): a single-arm, multicentre, phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2018;391(10121):659-667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song Y, Zhou K, Zou D, et al. Safety and activity of the investigational Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor Zanubrutinib (BGB-3111) in patients with mantle cell lymphoma from a phase 2 trial. Blood. 2018;132(Suppl 1):148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tam CS, Anderson MA, Pott C, et al. Ibrutinib plus Venetoclax for the treatment of mantle-cell lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(13):1211-1223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMullen JR, Boey EJ, Ooi JY, Seymour JF, Keating MJ, Tam CS. Ibrutinib increases the risk of atrial fibrillation, potentially through inhibition of cardiac PI3K-Akt signaling. Blood. 2014;124(25):3829-3830.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin JS, Johnstone TG, Baturevych A, et al. Antitumor potency of an anti-CD19 chimeric antigen receptor T-cell therapy, Lisocabtagene Maraleucel in combination with Ibrutinib or Acalabrutinib. J Immunother. 2020;43(4):107-120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubovsky JA, Beckwith KA, Natarajan G, et al. Ibrutinib is an irreversible molecular inhibitor of ITK driving a Th1-selective pressure in T lymphocytes. Blood. 2013;122(15):2539-2549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rule S, Jurczak W, Jerkeman M, et al. Ibrutinib versus temsirolimus: 3-year follow-up of patients with previously treated mantle cell lymphoma from the phase 3, international, randomized, open-label RAY study. Leukemia. 2018.32(8):1799-1803.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rule S, Dreyling M, Goy A, et al. Outcomes in 370 patients with mantle cell lymphoma treated with ibrutinib: a pooled analysis from three open-label studies. Br J Haematol. 2017;179(3):430-438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng C, Woronow D, Nayernama A, Wroblewski T, Jones SC. Ibrutinib-associated ventricular arrhythmia in the FDA adverse event reporting system. Leuk Lymphoma. 2018;59(12):3016-3017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamel S, Horton L, Ysebaert L, et al. Ibrutinib inhibits collagen-mediated but not ADP-mediated platelet aggregation. Leukemia. 2015;29(4):783-787.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobie G, Kuriri FA, Omar MMA, et al. Ibrutinib, but not zanubrutinib, induces platelet receptor shedding of GPIb-IX-V complex and integrin alphaIIbbeta3 in mice and humans. Blood Adv. 2019;3(24):4298-4311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Romaguera J, Srour SA, et al. Four-year follow-up of a single arm, phase II clinical trial of ibrutinib with rituximab (IR) in patients with relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma (MCL). Br J Haematol. 2018;182(3):404-411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jerkeman M, Hutchings M, Räty R, et al. Ibrutinib-Lenalidomide-rituximab in patients with relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma: final results from the Nordic lymphoma group MCL6 (PHILEMON) phase II trial. Blood. 2020;136:36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Handunnetti SM, Anderson MA, Burbury K, et al. Three year update of the phase II ABT-199 (Venetoclax) and Ibrutinib in mantle cell lymphoma (AIM) study. Blood. 2019;134(Supplement_1):756.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lionakis MS, Dunleavy K, Roschewski M, et al. Inhibition of B cell receptor signaling by Ibrutinib in primary CNS lymphoma. Cancer Cell. 2017;31(6):833-843 e835.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grommes C, Tang SS, Wolfe J, et al. Phase 1b trial of an ibrutinib-based combination therapy in recurrent/refractory CNS lymphoma. Blood. 2019;133(5):436-445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Gouill S, Morschhauser F, Chiron D, et al. Ibrutinib, obinutuzumab, and venetoclax in relapsed and untreated patients with mantle cell lymphoma: a phase 1/2 trial. Blood. 2021;137(7):877-887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu M, Deng H, Mu J, et al. Ibrutinib improves the efficacy of anti-CD19-CAR T-cell therapy in patients with refractory non-Hodgkin lymphoma. Cancer Sci. 2021;112(7):2642-2651.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barf T, Covey T, Izumi R, et al. Acalabrutinib (ACP-196): a covalent Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor with a differentiated selectivity and in vivo potency profile. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2017;363(2):240-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byrd JC, Hillmen P, Ghia P, et al. Acalabrutinib versus Ibrutinib in previously treated chronic lymphocytic leukemia: results of the first randomized phase III trial. J Clin Oncol. 2021;39(31):3441-3452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Rule S, Zinzani PL, et al. ACALABRUTINIB monotherapy in patients with relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma: final results from a phase 2 study. Hematol Oncol. 2021;39(S2).213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song Y, Zhou KS, Zou D, et al. Treatment of patients with relapsed or refractory mantle cell lymphoma with Zanubrutinib, a selective inhibitor of Bruton's tyrosine kinase. Clin Cancer Res. 2020.26(16):4216-4224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou K, Zou D, Zhou J, et al. Zanubrutinib monotherapy in relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma: a pooled analysis of two clinical trials. J Hematol Oncol. 2021;14(1):167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davids MS, Roberts AW, Kenkre VP, et al. Long-term follow-up of patients with relapsed or refractory non-Hodgkin lymphoma treated with Venetoclax in a phase I, First-in-Human Study. Clin Cancer Res. 2021;27(17):4690-4695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eyre TA, Walter HS, Iyengar S, et al. Efficacy of venetoclax monotherapy in patients with relapsed, refractory mantle cell lymphoma after Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitor therapy. Haematologica. 2019;104(2):e68-e71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCulloch R, Visco C, Eyre TA, et al. Efficacy of R-BAC in relapsed, refractory mantle cell lymphoma post BTK inhibitor therapy. Br J Haematol. 2020;189(4):684-688.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zoellner AK, Unterhalt M, Stilgenbauer S, et al. Long-term survival of patients with mantle cell lymphoma after autologous haematopoietic stem-cell transplantation in first remission: a post-hoc analysis of an open-label, multicentre, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet Haematol. 2021;8(9):e648-e657.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Gouill S, Kroger N, Dhedin N, et al. Reduced-intensity conditioning allogeneic stem cell transplantation for relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma: a multicenter experience. Ann Oncol. 2012;23(10):2695-2703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson SP, Boumendil A, Finel H, et al. Long-term outcome analysis of reduced-intensity allogeneic stem cell transplantation in patients with mantle cell lymphoma: a retrospective study from the EBMT lymphoma working party. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2018;53(5):617-624.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreger P, Michallet M, Bosman P, et al. Ibrutinib for bridging to allogeneic hematopoietic cell transplantation in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia or mantle cell lymphoma: a study by the EBMT chronic malignancies and lymphoma working parties. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2019;54(1):44-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newcomb R, Jacobson C. Chimeric antigen receptor T cells for B-cell lymphoma. Cancer J. 2021;27(2):107-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Munoz J, Goy A, et al. Outcomes with KTE-X19 in patients (pts) with relapsed/refractory (R/R) mantle cell lymphoma (MCL) in ZUMA-2 who had progression of disease within 24 months of diagnosis (POD24). J Clin Oncol. 2021;39(15_suppl):7547.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Jain P, Locke FL, et al. Brexucabtagene Autoleucel for relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma: real world experience from the US lymphoma CAR T consortium. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):744.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herbaux C, Bret C, Di Blasi R, et al. Kte-X19 in relapsed or refractory mantle-cell lymphoma, a "real-life" study from the Descar-T registry and Lysa group. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Nastoupil L, Westin J, et al. Outcomes and management of patients with mantle cell lymphoma after progression on brexucabtagene autoleucel therapy. Br J Haematol. 2021;192(2):e38-e42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He Y, Khan S, Huo Z, et al. Proteolysis targeting chimeras (PROTACs) are emerging therapeutics for hematologic malignancies. J Hematol Oncol. 2020;13(1):103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palomba ML, Gordon LI, Siddiqi T, et al. Safety and preliminary efficacy in patients with relapsed/refractory mantle cell lymphoma receiving Lisocabtagene Maraleucel in transcend NHL 001. Blood. 2020;136(Supplement 1):10-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chihara D, Asano N, Ohmachi K, et al. Ki-67 is a strong predictor of central nervous system relapse in patients with mantle cell lymphoma (MCL). Ann Oncol. 2015;26(5):966-973.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrer A, Bosch F, Villamor N, et al. Central nervous system involvement in mantle cell lymphoma. Ann Oncol. 2008;19(1):135-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Li Y, Zhuang Z, et al. Preliminary evaluation of Zanubrutinib-containing regimens in DLBCL and the cerebrospinal fluid distribution of Zanubrutinib: a 13-case series. Front Oncol. 2021;11:760405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiara Rusconi CYC, Tucker D, Eyre TA, et al. IBRUTINIB COMPARED TO IMMUNO-CHEMOTHERAPY FOR CENTRAL NERVOUS SYSTEM RELAPSE OF MANTLE CELL LYMPHOMA: A REPORT FROM FONDAZIONE ITALIANA LINFOMI (FIL) AND EUROPEAN MANTLE CELL LYMPHOMA NETWORK (EMCLN). 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thibaud S, Tremblay D, Bhalla S, Zimmerman B, Sigel K, Gabrilove J. Protective role of Bruton tyrosine kinase inhibitors in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukaemia and COVID-19. Br J Haematol. 2020;190(2):e73-e76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghione P, Gu JJ, Attwood K, et al. Impaired humoral responses to COVID-19 vaccination in patients with lymphoma receiving B-cell-directed therapies. Blood. 2021;138(9):811-814.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marchesi F, Pimpinelli F, Giannarelli D, et al. Impact of anti-CD20 monoclonal antibodies on serologic response to BNT162b2 vaccine in B-cell non-Hodgkin's lymphomas. Leukemia. 2022.36(2):588-590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellinghoff SC, Robrecht S, Mayer L, et al. SARS-CoV-2 specific cellular response following COVID-19 vaccination in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Leukemia. 2022.36(2):562-565.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herzog Tzarfati K, Gutwein O, Apel A, et al. BNT162b2 COVID-19 vaccine is significantly less effective in patients with hematologic malignancies. Am J Hematol. 2021;96(10):1195-1203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee CY, Shah MK, Hoyos D, et al. Prolonged SARS-CoV-2 infection in patients with lymphoid malignancies. Cancer Discov. 2022.12(1):62-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenberger LM, Saltzman LA, Senefeld JW, Johnson PW, DeGennaro LJ, Nichols GL. Anti-spike antibody response to SARS-CoV-2 booster vaccination in patients with B cell-derived hematologic malignancies. Cancer Cell. 2021;39(10):1297-1299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parvathaneni K, Torres-Rodriguez K, Meng W, et al. SARS-CoV-2 spike-specific T-cell responses in patients with B-cell depletion who received chimeric antigen receptor T-cell treatments. JAMA Oncologia. 2022.8(1):164-167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gastinne T, Le Bourgeois A, Coste-Burel M, et al. Safety and antibody response after one and/or two doses of BNT162b2 anti-SARS-CoV-2 mRNA vaccine in patients treated by CAR T cells therapy. Br J Haematol. 2022.196(2):360-362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romaguera JE, Fayad L, Rodriguez MA, et al. High rate of durable remissions after treatment of newly diagnosed aggressive mantle-cell lymphoma with rituximab plus hyper-CVAD alternating with rituximab plus high-dose methotrexate and cytarabine. J Clin Oncol. 2005;23(28):7013-7023.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chihara D, Cheah CY, Westin JR, et al. Rituximab plus hyper-CVAD alternating with MTX/Ara-C in patients with newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma: 15-year follow-up of a phase II study from the MD Anderson Cancer Center. Br J Haematol. 2016;172(1):80-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geisler CH, Kolstad A, Laurell A, et al. Nordic MCL2 trial update: six-year follow-up after intensive immunochemotherapy for untreated mantle cell lymphoma followed by BEAM or BEAC + autologous stem-cell support: still very long survival but late relapses do occur. Br J Haematol. 2012;158(3):355-362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hermine O, Hoster E, Walewski J, et al. Addition of high-dose cytarabine to immunochemotherapy before autologous stem-cell transplantation in patients aged 65 years or younger with mantle cell lymphoma (MCL younger): a randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial of the European mantle cell lymphoma Network. Lancet. 2016;388(10044):565-575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flinn IW, van der Jagt R, Kahl BS, et al. Randomized trial of bendamustine-rituximab or R-CHOP/R-CVP in first-line treatment of indolent NHL or MCL: the BRIGHT study. Blood. 2014;123(19):2944-2952.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robak T, Jin J, Pylypenko H, et al. Frontline bortezomib, rituximab, cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, and prednisone (VR-CAP) versus rituximab, cyclophosphamide, doxorubicin, vincristine, and prednisone (R-CHOP) in transplantation-ineligible patients with newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma: final overall survival results of a randomised, open-label, phase 3 study. Lancet Oncol. 2018;19(11):1449-1458.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tisi MC, Nassi L, Patti C, et al. Rituximab plus Bendamustine and Cytarabine (R-BAC) in elderly patients with newly diagnosed mantle cell lymphoma: long term follow-up and Mrd results of a phase 2 study from the Fondazione Italiana Linfomi. Blood. 2021;138(Supplement 1):384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruan J, Martin P, Christos P, et al. Five-year follow-up of lenalidomide plus rituximab as initial treatment of mantle cell lymphoma. Blood. 2018;132(19):2016-2025.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
