<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35278051</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0189-160X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>39</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Feb</Month>
              <Day>28</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>West African journal of medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>West Afr J Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Drugs of Abuse among In-Patients Receiving Treatment for Substance Use Disorders in a Tertiary Health Care Center in South-South Nigeria: An Exploratory Qualitative Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>147</StartPage>
          <EndPage>153</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>147-153</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recently, there has been an increase in the abuse of relatively newer substances sometimes in unusual combinations. Some of these drugs and their street names are unfamiliar to researchers and clinicians, hindering their identification. Our objective was to investigate current trends in drug abuse, focusing on eliciting drugs of use and their street names in Calabar, Nigeria.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Using a qualitative design, we conducted focus group discussions among 15 male in-patients of the drug treatment ward of the Federal Neuropsychiatric Hospital, Calabar. Data was collected as audio recordings and handwritten notes and was analyzed using the Nvivo software.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Prescription drugs like flunitrazepam (street name Blueboy, Sweetnol), trihexyphenidyl, codeine and tramadol were commonly abused. Illicit substances included cannabis of various potencies (each having unique street names), vulcanizing gum (street name Solution), cocaine and heroin (street name Thailand). Some unusual substances such as soakaway fumes, formaldehyde or gammalin (lindane) mixed with cannabis were described. Few supposedly nonpsychoactive substances were reportedly potent when consumed alone (e.g., leaves of the papaya plant) or in mixtures, such as menthol candy dissolved in soft drinks. Other prescription drugs such as Benadol or D4, unfamiliar to the researchers, were volunteered.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Newer substances of abuse in their various combinations are abused by Nigerian youth. More studies are needed to elucidate further the chemical composition of these drugs/mixtures and their mechanism of action.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by West African Journal of Medicine.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Okafor</LastName>
            <ForeName>C J</ForeName>
            <Initials>CJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Calabar, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Essien</LastName>
            <ForeName>E A</ForeName>
            <Initials>EA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Services, Federal Neuropsychiatric Hospital, Calabar, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Edet</LastName>
            <ForeName>B E</ForeName>
            <Initials>BE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Services, Federal Neuropsychiatric Hospital, Calabar, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Okoro</LastName>
            <ForeName>A C</ForeName>
            <Initials>AC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Services, Federal Neuropsychiatric Hospital, Calabar, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Udofia</LastName>
            <ForeName>O</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Calabar, Nigeria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Nigeria</Country>
        <MedlineTA>West Afr J Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8301891</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0189-160X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006761" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009549" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Nigeria</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019966" MajorTopicYN="Y">Substance-Related Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">
        <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Récemment, il y a eu une augmentation de l’abus de substances relativement nouvelles parfois dans des Combinaisons. Certaines de ces drogues et leurs noms de rue sont peu familiers aux chercheurs et aux cliniciens, ce qui entrave leur identification. Notre objectif était d’étudier les tendances actuelles dans l’abus de drogues, en mettant l’accent sur l’obtention de drogues de consommation et leur noms de rues à Calabar, Nigeria.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="MÉTHODES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">À l’aide d’une conception qualitative, nous avons mené des discussions de groupe entre 15 patients masculins hospitalisés du médicament service de traitement de l’Hôpital fédéral neuropsychiatrique, Calabar. Les données ont été recueillies sous forme d’enregistrements audio et d’écriture manuscrite, et a été analysé à l’aide du logiciel Nvivo.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="RÉSULTATS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Médicaments sur ordonnance comme le flunitrazépam (nom de la rue Blueboy, Sweetnol), trihexyphénidyle, codéine et tramadol ont été couramment maltraités. Les substances illicites comprenaient le cannabis de différentes puissances (chacune ayant des noms de rue uniques), gomme vulcanisante (nom de rue Solution), cocaïne et héroïne (nom de la rue Thaïlande). Certaines substances inhabituelles telles quefumées trempées, formaldéhyde ou gammaline (lindane) mélangés avec du cannabis ont été décrits. Peu de substances prétendument non psychoactives étaient apparemment puissantes lorsque consommés seuls (par exemple, feuilles de la papaye) ou en mélanges, tels que les bonbons au menthol dissous dans les boissons gazeuses. Autres médicaments d’ordonnance tels que Benadol ou D4, inconnus de l’chercheurs, ont été volontaires.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nouvelles substances d’abus dans leurs divers combinaisons sont abusées par les jeunes Nigérians. D’autres études sont nécessaires pour élucider davantage la composition chimique de ces médicaments/mélanges et leur mécanisme d’action.</AbstractText>
        <AbstractText Label="MOTS-CLÉS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Drogues psychoactives, étude qualitative, abus, hospitalisé.</AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by West African Journal of Medicine.</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Abuse</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychoactive drugs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative study</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">in-patient</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The Authors declare that no competing interest exists.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>10</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35278051</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">West Afr J Med. 2022 February; 39 (2) 147-153</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
