<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35274336</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2990</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuropathology and applied neurobiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neuron types in the primate striatum: Stereological analysis of projection neurons and interneurons in control and parkinsonian monkeys.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e12812</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e12812</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nan.12812</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The striatum is mainly composed of projection neurons. It also contains interneurons, which modulate and control striatal output. The aim of the present study was to assess the percentages of projection neurons and interneuron populations in the striatum of control monkeys and of parkinsonian monkeys.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Unbiased stereology was used to estimate the volume density of every neuron population in the caudate, putamen and ventral striatum of control monkeys and of monkeys treated with MPTP, which results in striatal dopamine depletion. The various neuron population phenotypes were identified by immunohistochemistry. All analyses were performed within the same subjects using similar processing and analysis parameters, thus allowing for reliable data comparisons.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In control monkeys, the projection neurons, which express the dopamine-and-cAMP-regulated-phosphoprotein, 32-KDa (DARPP-32), were the most abundant: ~86% of the total neurons counted. The interneurons accounted for the remaining 14%. Among the interneurons, those expressing calretinin were the most abundant (Cr+: ~57%; ~8% of the total striatal neurons counted), followed those expressing Parvalbumin (Pv+: ~18%; 2.6%), dinucleotide phosphate-diaphorase (NADPH+: ~13%; 1.8%), choline acetyltransferase (ChAT+: ~11%; 1.5%) and tyrosine hydroxylase (TH+: ~0.5%; 0.1%). No significant changes in volume densities occurred in any population following dopamine depletion, except for the TH+ interneurons, which increased in parkinsonian non-symptomatic monkeys and even more in symptomatic monkeys.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These data are relevant for translational studies targeting specific neuron populations of the striatum. The fact that dopaminergic denervation does not cause neuron loss in any population has potential pathophysiological implications.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Neuropathology and Applied Neurobiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Neuropathological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Del Rey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Natalia López-González</ForeName>
            <Initials>NL</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1546-1825</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>HM CINAC (Centro Integral de Neurociencias Abarca Campal), Hospital Universitario HM Puerta del Sur, HM Hospitales, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CIBERNED (Center for Networked Biomedical Research on Neurodegenerative Diseases), Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PhD Program in Neuroscience Autónoma de Madrid University-Cajal Institute, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Trigo-Damas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Inés</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7821-2973</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>HM CINAC (Centro Integral de Neurociencias Abarca Campal), Hospital Universitario HM Puerta del Sur, HM Hospitales, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CIBERNED (Center for Networked Biomedical Research on Neurodegenerative Diseases), Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Obeso</LastName>
            <ForeName>José A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6996-8613</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>HM CINAC (Centro Integral de Neurociencias Abarca Campal), Hospital Universitario HM Puerta del Sur, HM Hospitales, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CIBERNED (Center for Networked Biomedical Research on Neurodegenerative Diseases), Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cavada</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carmen</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7230-1388</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PhD Program in Neuroscience Autónoma de Madrid University-Cajal Institute, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy, Histology and Neuroscience, School of Medicine, Autónoma de Madrid University, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Blesa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Javier</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4257-1325</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>HM CINAC (Centro Integral de Neurociencias Abarca Campal), Hospital Universitario HM Puerta del Sur, HM Hospitales, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CIBERNED (Center for Networked Biomedical Research on Neurodegenerative Diseases), Instituto Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7609829</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0305-1846</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DARPP-32</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calretinin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cholinergic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nitrergic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">parvalbumin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tyrosine hydroxylase</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35274336</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nan.12812</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox J, Witten IB. Striatal circuits for reward learning and decision-making. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2019;20(8):482-494. doi:10.1038/s41583-019-0189-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouimet CC, Lamantia AS, Goldman-Rakic P, Rakic P, Greengard P. Immunocytochemical localization of DARPP-32, a dopamine and cyclic-AMP-regulated phosphoprotein, in the primate brain. J Comp Neurol. 1992;323(2):209-218. doi:10.1002/cne.903230206</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouimet CC, Langley-Gullion KC, Greengard P. Quantitative immunocytochemistry of DARPP-32-expressing neurons in the rat caudatoputamen. Brain Res. 1998;808(1):8-12. doi:10.1016/S0006-8993(98)00724-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tepper JM, Koós T, Ibanez-Sandoval O, Tecuapetla F, Faust TW, Assous M. Heterogeneity and diversity of striatal GABAergic interneurons: update 2018. Front Neuroanat. 2018;12:91. doi:10.3389/fnana.2018.00091</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tepper JM, Tecuapetla F, Koós T, Ibáñez-Sandoval O. Heterogeneity and diversity of striatal GABAergic interneurons. Front Neuroanat. 2010;4:150. doi:10.3389/fnana.2010.00150</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz-Manchado AB, Bengtsson Gonzales C, Zeisel A, et al. Diversity of interneurons in the dorsal striatum revealed by single-cell RNA sequencing and PatchSeq. Cell Rep. 2018;24(8):2179-2190.e7. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2018.07.053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao L, Bornmann C, Hatstatt-Burklé L, Scheiffele P. Regulation of striatal cells and goal-directed behavior by cerebellar outputs. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):3133. doi:10.1038/s41467-018-05565-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johansson Y, Silberberg G. The functional organization of cortical and thalamic inputs onto five types of striatal neurons is determined by source and target cell identities. Cell Rep. 2020;30(4):1178-1194.e3. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2019.12.095</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters AJ, Fabre JMJ, Steinmetz NA, Harris KD, Carandini M. Striatal activity topographically reflects cortical activity. Nature. 2021;18(591):420-425. doi:10.1038/s41586-020-03166-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dautan D, Huerta-Ocampo I, Gut NK, et al. Cholinergic midbrain afferents modulate striatal circuits and shape encoding of action strategies. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):1739. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-15514-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assous M, Kaminer J, Shah F, Garg A, Koós T, Tepper JM. Differential processing of thalamic information via distinct striatal interneuron circuits. Nat Commun. 2017;8(1):15860. doi:10.1038/ncomms15860</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorst MC, Tokarska A, Zhou M, et al. Polysynaptic inhibition between striatal cholinergic interneurons shapes their network activity patterns in a dopamine-dependent manner. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):5113. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-18882-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Tsutsui-Kimura I, Kono A, et al. Opposing ventral striatal medium spiny neuron activities shaped by striatal parvalbumin-expressing interneurons during goal-directed behaviors. Cell Rep. 2020;31(13):107829. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2020.107829</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hjorth J, Kozlov A, Carannante I, et al. The microcircuits of striatum in silico. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117(17):9554-9565. doi:10.1073/pnas.2000671117</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gritton HJ, Howe WM, Romano MF, et al. Unique contributions of parvalbumin and cholinergic interneurons in organizing striatal networks during movement. Nat Neurosci. 2019;22(4):586-597. doi:10.1038/s41593-019-0341-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silberberg G, Bolam JPP. Local and afferent synaptic pathways in the striatal microcircuitry. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2015;33:182-187. doi:10.1016/j.conb.2015.05.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocaturk S, Shah F, Guven B, Tepper JM, Assous M. Cholinergic control of striatal GABAergic microcircuits. bioRxiv. 2021. doi:10.1101/2021.11.22.469580</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plotkin JL, Goldberg JA. Thinking outside the box (and arrow): current themes in striatal dysfunction in movement disorders. Neuroscientist. 2019;25(4):359-379. doi:10.1177/1073858418807887</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis RG, Serra M, Radl D, et al. Dopaminergic control of striatal cholinergic interneurons underlies cocaine-induced psychostimulation. Cell Rep. 2020;31(3):107527. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2020.107527</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhai S, Shen W, Graves SM, Surmeier DJ. Dopaminergic modulation of striatal function and Parkinson's disease. J Neural Transm. 2019;126(4):411-422. doi:10.1007/s00702-019-01997-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedman A, Hueske E, Drammis SM, et al. Striosomes mediate value-based learning vulnerable in age and a Huntington's disease model. Cell. 2020;183(4):918-934.e49. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2020.09.060</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuzon Carlson VC, Gremel CM, Lovinger DM. Gestational alcohol exposure disrupts cognitive function and striatal circuits in adult offspring. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):2555. doi:10.1038/s41467-020-16385-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vormstein-Schneider D, Lin JD, Pelkey KA, et al. Viral manipulation of functionally distinct interneurons in mice, non-human primates and humans. Nat Neurosci. 2020;23(12):1629-1636. doi:10.1038/s41593-020-0692-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi SJ, Ma TC, Ding Y, et al. Alterations in the intrinsic properties of striatal cholinergic interneurons after dopamine lesion and chronic l-dopa. Elife. 2020;9:e56920. doi:10.7554/eLife.56920</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enterría-Morales D, del Rey NL-G, Blesa J, et al. Molecular targets for endogenous glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor modulation in striatal parvalbumin interneurons. Brain Commun. 2020;2(2):fcaa105. doi:10.1093/braincomms/fcaa105</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crevier-Sorbo G, Rymar VV, Crevier-Sorbo R, Sadikot AF. Thalamostriatal degeneration contributes to dystonia and cholinergic interneuron dysfunction in a mouse model of Huntington's disease. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8(1):14. doi:10.1186/s40478-020-0878-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graveland GA, Difiglia M. The frequency and distribution of medium-sized neurons with indented nuclei in the primate and rodent neostriatum. Brain Res. 1985;327(1-2):307-311. doi:10.1016/0006-8993(85)91524-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oorschot DE. The percentage of interneurons in the dorsal striatum of the rat, cat, monkey and human: a critique of the evidence. Basal Ganglia. 2013;3(1):19-24. doi:10.1016/j.baga.2012.11.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng YP, Shelby E, Reiner AJ. Immunohistochemical localization of AMPA-type glutamate receptor subunits in the striatum of rhesus monkey. Brain Res. 2010;1344:104-123. doi:10.1016/j.brainres.2010.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krienen FM, Goldman M, Zhang Q, et al. Innovations present in the primate interneuron repertoire. Nature. 2020;586(7828):262-269. doi:10.1038/s41586-020-2781-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernácer J, Prensa L, Giménez-Amaya JM. Distribution of GABAergic interneurons and dopaminergic cells in the functional territories of the human striatum. PLoS ONE. 2012;7:e30504. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0030504</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts RC, Gaither LA, Peretti FJ, Lapidus B, Chute DJ. Synaptic organization of the human striatum: a postmortem ultrastructural study. J Comp Neurol. 1996;374(4):523-534. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19961028)374:4%3C523::AID-CNE4%3E3.0.CO;2-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graveland GA, Williams RS, Difiglia M. A Golgi study of the human neostriatum: neurons and afferent fibers. J Comp Neurol. 1985;234(3):317-333. doi:10.1002/cne.902340304</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernácer J, Prensa L, Giménez-Amaya JMM, Bernacer J, Prensa L, Gimenez-Amaya JM. Cholinergic interneurons are differentially distributed in the human striatum. PLoS ONE. 2007;2(11):e1174. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0001174</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Figueredo-Cardenas G, Morello M, Sancesario G, Bernardi G, Reiner A. Colocalization of somatostatin, neuropeptide Y, neuronal nitric oxide synthase and NADPH-diaphorase in striatal interneurons in rats. Brain Res. 1996;735(2):317-324. doi:10.1016/0006-8993(96)00801-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiménez-Sánchez L, Blesa J, Del Rey NL, Monje MHG, Obeso JA, Cavada C. Serotonergic innervation of the striatum in a nonhuman primate model of Parkinson's disease. Neuropharmacology. 2020;170:107806. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.107806</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blesa J, Pifl C, Sánchez-González MA, et al. The nigrostriatal system in the presymptomatic and symptomatic stages in the MPTP monkey model: a PET, histological and biochemical study. Neurobiol Dis. 2012;48(1):79-91. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2012.05.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monje MHG, Blesa J, García-Cabezas MÁ, Obeso JA, Cavada C. Changes in thalamic dopamine innervation in a progressive Parkinson's disease model in monkeys. Mov Disord. 2020;35(3):419-430. doi:10.1002/mds.27921</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blesa J, Juri C, Collantes M, et al. Progression of dopaminergic depletion in a model of MPTP-induced Parkinsonism in non-human primates: an (18)F-DOPA and (11)C-DTBZ PET study. Neurobiol Dis. 2010;38(3):456-463. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2010.03.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C, Goel P, Kaeser PS. Spatial and temporal scales of dopamine transmission. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2021;22(6):345-358. doi:10.1038/s41583-021-00455-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blesa J, Juri C, García-Cabezas MÁ, et al. Inter-hemispheric asymmetry of nigrostriatal dopaminergic lesion: a possible compensatory mechanism in Parkinson's disease. Front Syst Neurosci. 2011;5:92. doi:10.3389/fnsys.2011.00092</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurlan R, Kim MHH, Gash DMM. The time course and magnitude of spontaneous recovery of parkinsonism produced by intracarotid administration of 1-methyl-4-phenyl-1,2,3,6-tetrahydropyridine to monkeys. Ann Neurol. 1991;29(6):677-679. doi:10.1002/ana.410290618</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cavada C, Compañy T, Hernández-González A, et al. Acetylcholinesterase histochemistry in the macaque thalamus reveals territories selectively connected to frontal, parietal and temporal association cortices. J Chem Neuroanat. 1995;8(4):245-257. doi:10.1016/0891-0618(95)00050-H</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matamales M, Bertran-Gonzalez J, Salomon L, et al. Striatal medium-sized spiny neurons: identification by nuclear staining and study of neuronal subpopulations in BAC transgenic mice. PLoS ONE. 2009;4(3):e4770. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0004770</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertran-Gonzalez J, Bosch C, Maroteaux M, et al. Opposing patterns of signaling activation in dopamine D1 and D2 receptor-expressing striatal neurons in response to cocaine and haloperidol. J Neurosci. 2008;28(22):5671-5685. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1039-08.2008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hope BT, Vincent SR. Histochemical characterization of neuronal NADPH-diaphorase. J Histochem Cytochem. 1989;37(5):653-661. doi:10.1177/37.5.2703701</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gundersen HJG, Jensen EBV, Kiêu K, Nielsen J. The efficiency of systematic sampling in stereology-reconsidered. J Microsc. 1999;193(3):199-211. doi:10.1046/j.1365-2818.1999.00457.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keuker JIH, Vollmann-Honsdorf GK, Fuchs E. How to use the optical fractionator: an example based on the estimation of neurons in the hippocampal CA1 and CA3 regions of tree shrews. Brain Res Protoc. 2001;7(3):211-221. doi:10.1016/S1385-299X(01)00064-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorph-Petersen KA, Nyengaard JR, Gundersen HJG. Tissue shrinkage and unbiased stereological estimation of particle number and size. J Microsc. 2001;204(3):232-246. doi:10.1046/j.1365-2818.2001.00958.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carlo CN, Stevens CF. Analysis of differential shrinkage in frozen brain sections and its implications for the use of guard zones in stereology. J Comp Neurol. 2011;519(14):2803-2810. doi:10.1002/cne.22652</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lecumberri A, Lopez-Janeiro A, Corral-Domenge C, Bernacer J. Neuronal density and proportion of interneurons in the associative, sensorimotor and limbic human striatum. Brain Struct Funct. 2018;223(4):1615-1625. doi:10.1007/s00429-017-1579-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graybiel AMM, Ragsdale CW. Histochemically distinct compartments in the striatum of human, monkeys, and cat demonstrated by acetylthiocholinesterase staining. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1978;75(11):5723-5726. 10.1073/pnas.75.11.5723</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petryszyn S, Di Paolo T, Parent A, Parent M. The number of striatal cholinergic interneurons expressing calretinin is increased in parkinsonian monkeys. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;95:46-53. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2016.07.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cicchetti F, Beach TG, Parent A. Chemical phenotype of calretinin interneurons in the human striatum. Synapse. 1998;30(3):284-297. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1098-2396(199811)30:3%3C284::AID-SYN6%3E3.0.CO;2-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faust TW, Assous M, Shah F, Tepper JM, Koós T. Novel fast adapting interneurons mediate cholinergic-induced fast GABAA inhibitory postsynaptic currents in striatal spiny neurons. Eur J Neurosci. 2015;42(2):1764-1774. doi:10.1111/ejn.12915</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assous M, Faust TW, Assini R, Shah F, Sidibe Y, Tepper JM. Identification and characterization of a novel spontaneously active bursty GABAergic interneuron in the mouse striatum. J Neurosci. 2018;38(25):5688-5699. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.3354-17.2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz-Manchado AB, Foldi C, Szydlowski S, et al. Novel striatal GABAergic interneuron populations labeled in the 5HT3a(EGFP) mouse. Cereb Cortex. 2016;26(1):96-105. doi:10.1093/cercor/bhu179</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garas FN, Shah RS, Kormann E, et al. Secretagogin expression delineates functionally-specialized populations of striatal parvalbumin-containing interneurons. Elife. 2016;5:e16088 10.7554/eLife.16088</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebenheim L, Booker SA, Derst C, et al. A novel giant non-cholinergic striatal interneuron restricted to the ventrolateral striatum coexpresses Kv3.3 potassium channel, parvalbumin, and the vesicular GABA transporter. Mol Psychiatry. 2020. doi:10.1038/s41380-020-00948-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawaguchi Y, Wilson CJ, Augood SJ, Emson PC. Striatal interneurons-chemical, physiological and morphological characterization. Trends Neurosci. 1995;18(12):527-535. doi:10.1016/0166-2236(95)98374-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett BD, Bolam JP. Two populations of calbindin D28k-immunoreactive neurones in the striatum of the rat. Brain Res. 1993;610(2):305-310. doi:10.1016/0006-8993(93)91414-N</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petryszyn S, Parent A, Parent M. The calretinin interneurons of the striatum: comparisons between rodents and primates under normal and pathological conditions. J Neural Transm. 2018;125(3):279-290. doi:10.1007/s00702-017-1687-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y, Parent A. Striatal interneurons expressing calretinin, parvalbumin or NADPH-diaphorase: a comparative study in the rat, monkey and human. Brain Res. 2000;863(1-2):182-191. doi:10.1016/S0006-8993(00)02135-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villalba RMM, Pare J-FF, Lee S, Smith Y. Thalamic degeneration in MPTP-treated Parkinsonian monkeys: impact upon glutamatergic innervation of striatal cholinergic interneurons. Brain Struct Funct. 2019;224(9):3321-3338. doi:10.1007/s00429-019-01967-w</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mura A, Feldon J, Mintz M. The expression of the calcium binding protein calretinin in the rat striatum: effects of dopamine depletion and L-DOPA treatment. Exp Neurol. 2000;164(2):322-332. doi:10.1006/exnr.2000.7441</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petryszyn S, Saidi L, Gagnon D, Parent A, Parent M. The density of calretinin striatal interneurons is decreased in 6-OHDA-lesioned mice. Brain Struct Funct. 2021;226(6):1879-1891. doi:10.1007/s00429-021-02298-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Y, Feng Q, OuYang L, et al. Morphological diversity of GABAergic and cholinergic interneurons in the striatal dorsolateral and ventromedial regions of rats. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2014;34(3):351-359. doi:10.1007/s10571-013-0019-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tandé D, Höglinger G, Debeir T, Freundlieb N, Hirsch ECC, François C. New striatal dopamine neurons in MPTP-treated macaques result from a phenotypic shift and not neurogenesis. Brain. 2006;129(5):1194-1200. doi:10.1093/brain/awl041</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Betarbet R, Turner R, Chockkan V, et al. Dopaminergic neurons intrinsic to the primate striatum. J Neurosci. 1997;17(17):6761-6768. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.17-17-06761.1997</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazloom M, Smith Y. Synaptic microcircuitry of tyrosine hydroxylase-containing neurons and terminals in the striatum of 1-methyl-4-phenyl-1,2,3,6-tetrahydropyridine- treated monkeys. J Comp Neurol. 2006;495(4):453-469. doi:10.1002/cne.20894</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huot P, Lévesque M, Parent A. The fate of striatal dopaminergic neurons in Parkinson's disease and Huntington's chorea. Brain. 2007;130(Pt 1):222-232. doi:10.1093/brain/awl332</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ibáñez-Sandoval O, Tecuapetla F, Unal B, et al. Electrophysiological and morphological characteristics and synaptic connectivity of tyrosine hydroxylase-expressing neurons in adult mouse striatum. J Neurosci. 2010;30(20):6999-7016. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.5996-09.2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xenias HSS, Ibanez-Sandoval O, Koos T, et al. Are striatal tyrosine hydroxylase interneurons dopaminergic? J Neurosci. 2015;35(16):6584-6599. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0195-15.2015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ibáñez-Sandoval O, Xenias HSS, Tepper JMM, Koós T. Dopaminergic and cholinergic modulation of striatal tyrosine hydroxylase interneurons. Neuropharmacology. 2015;95:468-476. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2015.03.036</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unal B, Ibáñez-Sandoval O, Shah F, Abercrombie ED, Tepper JM. Distribution of tyrosine hydroxylase-expressing interneurons with respect to anatomical organization of the neostriatum. Front Syst Neurosci. 2011;5:41. doi:10.3389/fnsys.2011.00041</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porritt MJ, Batchelor PE, Hughes AJ, Kalnins R, Donnan GA, Howells DW. New dopaminergic neurons in Parkinson's disease striatum. Lancet. 2000;356(9223):44-45. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(00)02437-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porritt MJ, Kingsbury AE, Hughes AJ, Howells DW. Striatal dopaminergic neurons are lost with Parkinson's disease progression. Mov Disord. 2006;21(12):2208-2211. doi:10.1002/mds.21129</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huot P, Lévesque M, Morissette M, et al. L-Dopa treatment abolishes the numerical increase in striatal dopaminergic neurons in parkinsonian monkeys. J Chem Neuroanat. 2008;35(1):77-84. doi:10.1016/j.jchemneu.2007.06.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busceti CL, Bucci D, Molinaro G, et al. Lack or inhibition of dopaminergic stimulation induces a development increase of striatal tyrosine hydroxylase-positive interneurons. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(9):e44025. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0044025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darmopil S, Muñetón-Gómez VC, De Ceballos ML, Bernson M, Moratalla R. Tyrosine hydroxylase cells appearing in the mouse striatum after dopamine denervation are likely to be projection neurones regulated by L-DOPA. Eur J Neurosci. 2008;27(3):580-592. doi:10.1111/j.1460-9568.2008.06040.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espadas I, Darmopil S, Vergaño-Vera E, et al. L-DOPA-induced increase in TH-immunoreactive striatal neurons in parkinsonian mice: insights into regulation and function. Neurobiol Dis. 2012;48(3):271-281. doi:10.1016/j.nbd.2012.07.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meredith GE. Immunocytochemical characterization of catecholaminergic neurons in the rat striatum following dopamine-depleting lesions. Eur J Neurosci. 1999;11(10):3585-3596. doi:10.1046/j.1460-9568.1999.00774.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Real A, Rodriguez-Pallares J, Guerra MJ, Labandeira-Garcia JL. Localization and functional significance of striatal neurons immunoreactive to aromatic L-amino acid decarboxylase or tyrosine hydroxylase in rat Parkinsonian models. Brain Res. 2003;969(1-2):135-146. doi:10.1016/S0006-8993(03)02291-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tashiro Y, Sugimoto T, Hattori T, et al. Tyrosine hydroxylase-like immunoreactive neurons in the striatum of the rat. Neurosci Lett. 1989;97(1-2):6-10. doi:10.1016/0304-3940(89)90130-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palfi S, Leventhal L, Chu Y, et al. Lentivirally delivered glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor increases the number of striatal dopaminergic neurons in primate models of nigrostriatal degeneration. J Neurosci. 2002;22(12):4942-4954. doi:10.1523/JNEUROSCI.22-12-04942.2002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huot P, Parent A. Dopaminergic neurons intrinsic to the striatum. J Neurochem. 2007;101(6):1441-1447. doi:10.1111/j.1471-4159.2006.04430.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assous M, Tepper JM. Cortical and thalamic inputs exert cell type-specific feedforward inhibition on striatal GABAergic interneurons. J Neurosci Res. 2019;97(12):1491-1502. doi:10.1002/jnr.24444</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaminer J, Espinoza D, Bhimani S, Tepper JM, Koos T, Shiflett MW. Loss of striatal tyrosine-hydroxylase interneurons impairs instrumental goal-directed behavior. Eur J Neurosci. 2019;50(4):2653-2662. doi:10.1111/ejn.14412</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen W, Ren W, Zhai S, et al. Striatal Kir2 K+ channel inhibition mediates the antidyskinetic effects of amantadine. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(5):2593-2601. doi:10.1172/JCI133398</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gittis AH, Hang GB, LaDow ES, et al. Rapid target-specific remodeling of fast-spiking inhibitory circuits after loss of dopamine. Neuron. 2011;71(5):858-868. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2011.06.035</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee K, Holley SM, Shobe JL, et al. Parvalbumin interneurons modulate striatal output and enhance performance during associative learning. Neuron. 2017;93(6):1451-1463.e4. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2017.02.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klug JR, Engelhardt MD, Cadman CN, et al. Differential inputs to striatal cholinergic and parvalbumin interneurons imply functional distinctions. Elife. 2018;7:e35657. doi:10.7554/eLife.35657</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mamaligas AA, Barcomb K, Ford CP. Cholinergic transmission at muscarinic synapses in the striatum is driven equally by cortical and thalamic inputs. Cell Rep. 2019;28(4):1003-1014.e3. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2019.06.077</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holly EN, Davatolhagh MF, Choi K, Alabi OO, Cifuentes LV, Fuccillo MV. Striatal low-threshold spiking interneurons regulate goal-directed learning. Neuron. 2019;103(1):92-101.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2019.04.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fino E, Vandecasteele M, Perez S, Saudou F, Venance L. Region-specific and state-dependent action of striatal GABAergic interneurons. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):1-17. doi:10.1038/s41467-018-05847-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurice N, Liberge M, Jaouen F, et al. Striatal cholinergic interneurons control motor behavior and basal ganglia function in experimental parkinsonism. Cell Rep. 2015;13(4):657-666. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2015.09.034</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albaugh DL, Gittis AH. Stressing the importance of cholinergic interneurons in striatal function. Mov Disord. 2021;37:36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKinley JW, Shi Z, Kawikova I, et al. Dopamine deficiency reduces striatal cholinergic interneuron function in models of Parkinson's disease. Neuron. 2019;103(6):1056-1072.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2019.06.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanimura A, Du Y, Kondapalli J, Wokosin DL, Surmeier DJ. Cholinergic interneurons amplify thalamostriatal excitation of striatal indirect pathway neurons in Parkinson's disease models. Neuron. 2019;101(3):444-458.e6. doi:10.1016/j.neuron.2018.12.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lozovaya N, Eftekhari S, Cloarec R, et al. GABAergic inhibition in dual-transmission cholinergic and GABAergic striatal interneurons is abolished in Parkinson disease. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):1422. doi:10.1038/s41467-018-03802-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assous M. Striatal cholinergic transmission. Focus on nicotinic receptors' influence in striatal circuits. Eur J Neurosci. 2021;53(8):2421-2442. doi:10.1111/ejn.15135</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duarte Azevedo M, Sander S, Jeanneret C, Olfat S, Tenenbaum L. Selective targeting of striatal parvalbumin-expressing interneurons for transgene delivery. J Neurosci Methods. 2021;354:109105. doi:10.1016/j.jneumeth.2021.109105</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padovan-Neto FE, Cavalcanti-Kiwiatkoviski R, Carolino ROG, Anselmo-Franci J, Del Bel E. Effects of prolonged neuronal nitric oxide synthase inhibition on the development and expression of l-DOPA-induced dyskinesia in 6-OHDA-lesioned rats. Neuropharmacology. 2015;89:87-99. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2014.08.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lerchner W, Adil AA, Mumuney S, et al. RNAi and chemogenetic reporter co-regulation in primate striatal interneurons. Gene Ther. 2021;29(1-2):69-80. doi:10.1038/s41434-021-00260-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xua M, Kobetsa A, Dua JC, et al. Targeted ablation of cholinergic interneurons in the dorsolateral striatum produces behavioral manifestations of Tourette syndrome. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2015;112(3):893-898. doi:10.1073/pnas.1419533112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennington JB, Coppola G, Kataoka-Sasaki Y, et al. Transcriptome Analysis of the Human Striatum in Tourette Syndrome. Biol Psychiatry. 2016;79(5):372-382. doi:10.1016/j.biopsych.2014.07.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schall TA, Wright WJ, Dong Y. Nucleus accumbens fast-spiking interneurons in motivational and addictive behaviors. Mol Psychiatry. 2021;26(1):234-246. doi:10.1038/s41380-020-0683-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarke R, Adermark L. Dopaminergic regulation of striatal interneurons in reward and addiction: focus on alcohol. Neural Plast. 2015;2015:814567. doi:10.1155/2015/814567</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
