<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35278044</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0496</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>57</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pediatric pulmonology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Pulmonol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Daytime predictors of nocturnal hypercapnic hypoventilation in children with neuromuscular disorders.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1497</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1504</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1497-1504</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ppul.25890</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To examine objective daytime predictors of nocturnal hypercapnic hypoventilation (NHH) and identify a forced vital capacity (FVC) z-score cut off that predicts NHH using the 2012 Global Lung Function Initiative (GLI) reference equations in pediatric neuromuscular patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">Single-centre retrospective medical record review.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SETTING" NlmCategory="METHODS">Tertiary pediatric hospital in Australia.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Children (&lt;18 years old) with a neuromuscular disorder (NMD) who had a diagnostic sleep study over a 5-year period.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifty children were included, median age 11.9 years (interquartile range [IQR]: 4.5-14.3). The majority of children had a diagnosis of Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy (32%). NHH was diagnosed in 18 children (36%). Multivariate logistic regression analysis performed for the entire cohort confirmed a statistically significant association between NHH and scoliosis (odds ratio [OR]: 3.3, p = 0.03), but not age (OR: 1.01, p = 0.26), body mass index z-score (OR: 0.86, p = 0.26) or use of a wheelchair for mobility (OR: 1.25, p = 0.72). For the subset of 29 children who had spirometry testing (median age 12.9 years [IQR: 10.2-14.3]), FVC z-score was the only statistically significant predictor of NHH (OR: 0.45, p = 0.02). NHH was predicted by an FVC z-score &lt;-3.24 (sensitivity 78%, specificity 73%), or FVC &lt;60% predicted (sensitivity 78%, specificity 73%). There was a strong positive correlation between FVC and forced expiratory volume in 1 s z-scores (r<sub>p</sub>  = 0.98, p = 0.00) and FVC and peak expiratory flow  z-scores (r<sub>p</sub>  = 0.72, p = 0.00).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Children with a NMD and scoliosis or a lower FVC z-score have increased odds of having NHH.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frohlich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Megan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1899-3392</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Sydney Children's Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Widger</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Sydney Children's Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Women's and Children's Health, UNSW Sydney, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thambipillay</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ganesh</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Sleep Medicine, Sydney Children's Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Teng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Arthur</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Women's and Children's Health, UNSW Sydney, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Sleep Medicine, Sydney Children's Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Farrar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michelle</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Women's and Children's Health, UNSW Sydney, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Sydney Children's Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chuang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Sydney Children's Hospital, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Women's and Children's Health, UNSW Sydney, Randwick, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Pulmonol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8510590</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1099-0496</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005541" MajorTopicYN="N">Forced Expiratory Volume</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006935" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypercapnia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007040" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoventilation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009468" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuromuscular Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012600" MajorTopicYN="Y">Scoliosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013147" MajorTopicYN="N">Spirometry</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014797" MajorTopicYN="N">Vital Capacity</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular disorders</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nocturnal hypoventilation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatrics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polysomnography</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep disordered breathing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spirometry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">z-score</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>35</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35278044</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.25890</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz SL, Gaboury I, Keilty K, et al. Nocturnal hypoventilation: predictors and outcomes in childhood progressive neuromuscular disease. Arch Dis Child. 2010;95(12):998-1003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellies U, Ragette R, Schwake C, Boehm H, Voit T, Teschler H. Daytime predictors of sleep disordered breathing in children and adolescents with neuromuscular disorders. Neuromuscul Disord. 2003;13(2):123-128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panitch HB. Respiratory implications of pediatric neuromuscular disease. Respir Care. 2017;62(6):826-848.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves RS, Resende MB, Skomro RP, Souza FJ, Reed UC. Sleep and neuromuscular disorders in children. Sleep Med Rev. 2009;13(2):133-148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simonds AK, Muntoni F, Heather S, Fielding S. Impact of nasal ventilation on survival in hypercapnic duchenne muscular dystrophy. Thorax. 1998;53(11):949-952.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suresh S, Wales P, Dakin C, Harris MA, Cooper DG. Sleep-related breathing disorder in duchenne muscular dystrophy: disease spectrum in the paediatric population. J Paediatr Child Health. 2005;41(9-10):500-503.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawnani H, Thampratankul L, Szczesniak RD, Fenchel MC, Simakajornboon N. Sleep disordered breathing in young boys with duchenne muscular dystrophy. J Pediatr. 2015;166(3):640-645 e641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toussaint M, Steens M, Soudon P. Lung function accurately predicts hypercapnia in patients with duchenne muscular dystrophy. Chest. 2007;131(2):368-375.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hukins CA, Hillman DR. Daytime predictors of sleep hypoventilation in duchenne muscular dystrophy. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2000;161(1):166-170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips MF, Quinlivan RC, Edwards RH, Calverley PM. Changes in spirometry over time as a prognostic marker in patients with duchenne muscular dystrophy. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2001;164(12):2191-2194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbe F, Quera-Salva MA, McCann C, et al. Sleep-related respiratory disturbances in patients with duchenne muscular dystrophy. Eur Respir J. 1994;7(8):1403-1408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragette R, Mellies U, Schwake C, Voit T, Teschler H. Patterns and predictors of sleep disordered breathing in primary myopathies. Thorax. 2002;57(8):724-728.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoque R. Sleep-disordered breathing in duchenne muscular dystrophy: an assessment of the literature. J Clin Sleep Med. 2016;12(6):905-911.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quanjer PH, Stanojevic S, Cole TJ, et al. Multi-ethnic reference values for spirometry for the 3-95-yr age range: the global lung function 2012 equations. Eur Respir J. 2012;40(6):1324-1343.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper BG, Stocks J, Hall GL, et al. The global lung function initiative (gli) network: Bringing the world's respiratory reference values together. Breathe (Sheff). 2017;13(3):e56-e64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hull J, Aniapravan R, Chan E, et al. British thoracic society guideline for respiratory management of children with neuromuscular weakness. Thorax. 2012;67(Suppl 1):i1-i40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pamula Y, Nixon GM, Edwards E, et al. Australasian sleep association clinical practice guidelines for performing sleep studies in children. Sleep Med. 2017;36(Suppl 1):S23-S42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berry RB, Budhiraja R, Gottlieb DJ, et al. Rules for scoring respiratory events in sleep: Update of the 2007 aasm manual for the scoring of sleep and associated events. Deliberations of the sleep apnea definitions task force of the american academy of sleep medicine. J Clin Sleep Med. 2012;8(5):597-619.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller MR, Hankinson J, Brusasco V, et al. Standardisation of spirometry. Eur Respir J. 2005;26(2):319-338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iber C, Ancoli-Israel S, Chesson AL, Quan SF. The aasm manual for the scoring of sleep and associated events: rules, terminology and technical specifications. Am Acad Sleep Med. 2007: 19-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J. Set correlation and contingency tables. Appl Psychol Meas. 1988;12(4):425-434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simonds AK. Chronic hypoventilation and its management. Eur Respir Rev. 2013;22(129):325-332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogna A, Quera Salva MA, Prigent H, et al. Nocturnal hypoventilation in neuromuscular disease: prevalence according to different definitions issued from the literature. Sleep Breath. 2016;20(2):575-581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dehlink E, Tan HL. Update on paediatric obstructive sleep apnoea. J Thorac Dis. 2016;8(2):224-235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaditis AG, Alonso Alvarez ML, Boudewyns A, et al. Obstructive sleep disordered breathing in 2- to 18-year-old children: diagnosis and management. Eur Respir J. 2016;47(1):69-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marcus CL, Omlin KJ, Basinki DJ, et al. Normal polysomnographic values for children and adolescents. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1992;146(5 Pt 1):1235-1239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uliel S, Tauman R, Greenfeld M, Sivan Y. Normal polysomnographic respiratory values in children and adolescents. Chest. 2004;125(3):872-878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montgomery-Downs HE, O'Brien LM, Gulliver TE, Gozal D. Polysomnographic characteristics in normal preschool and early school-aged children. Pediatrics. 2006;117(3):741-753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo Mauro A, D'Angelo MG, Romei M, et al. Abdominal volume contribution to tidal volume as an early indicator of respiratory impairment in duchenne muscular dystrophy. Eur Respir J. 2010;35(5):1118-1125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz SL. Assessment of sleep-disordered breathing in pediatric neuromuscular diseases. Pediatrics. 2009;123(Suppl 4):S222-S225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellies U, Dohna-Schwake C, Stehling F, Voit T. Sleep disordered breathing in spinal muscular atrophy. Neuromuscul Disord. 2004;14(12):797-803.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellies U, Ragette R, Dohna Schwake C, Boehm H, Voit T, Teschler H. Long-term noninvasive ventilation in children and adolescents with neuromuscular disorders. Eur Respir J. 2003;22(4):631-636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simonds AK, Ward S, Heather S, Bush A, Muntoni F. Outcome of paediatric domiciliary mask ventilation in neuromuscular and skeletal disease. Eur Respir J. 2000;16(3):476-481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young HK, Lowe A, Fitzgerald DA, et al. Outcome of noninvasive ventilation in children with neuromuscular disease. Neurology. 2007;68(3):198-201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raphael JC, Chevret S, Chastang C, Bouvet F. Randomised trial of preventive nasal ventilation in duchenne muscular dystrophy. French multicentre cooperative group on home mechanical ventilation assistance in duchenne de boulogne muscular dystrophy. Lancet. 1994;343(8913):1600-1604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrow BM, Angelil L, Forsyth J, Huisamen A, Juries E, Corten L. The utility of using peak expiratory flow and forced vital capacity to predict poor expiratory cough flow in children with neuromuscular disorders. S Afr J Physiother. 2019;75(1):1296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gauld LM, Boynton A. Relationship between peak cough flow and spirometry in duchenne muscular dystrophy. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2005;39(5):457-460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang J, Mehta K, Amin R. Respiratory diagnostic tools in neuromuscular disease. Children (Basel). 2018;5(6):78 doi:10.3390/children5060078</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
