<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35289455</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2672</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>132</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of applied microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Appl Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Isolation and characterization of competitive exclusion microorganisms from animal wastes-based composts against Listeria monocytogenes.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>4531</StartPage>
          <EndPage>4543</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>4531-4543</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jam.15528</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To isolate the slow-growing or viable but non-culturable competitive exclusion (CE) microorganisms from composts and then verify the anti-Listeria monocytogenes activities of those CE isolates in compost.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">CE strains were isolated from composts using double- or triple-layer agar methods, purified, and then characterized. Both compost extracts and solid compost samples were spiked with a cocktail of 3 L. monocytogenes strains which were co-inoculated with or without CE strain cocktail and incubated at both 22 and 35°C for 168 h. Results indicated that the addition of resuscitation promoting factor (Rpf) promoted the growth of slow-growing species from composts. About 50% of the isolated CE strains (n = 40) were identified as Bacillus spp., 17 strains can inhibit more than 10 tested L. monocytogenes strains, and nine strains were motile and competitive biofilm formers. In compost extracts, the growth potentials of L. monocytogenes were reduced up to 2.2 logs when co-culturing with CE strains. In compost samples, the addition of CE strains reduced L. monocytogenes population by ca. 1.3 log CFU/g at 22°C after 24-168 h incubation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our modified double/triple-layer agar procedure with Rpf as growth supplement coupled with spot-on-lawn testing can be a quick and efficient method for isolating CE candidates from composts. The efficacy of CE strains against L. monocytogenes in compost extracts and compost samples was affected by compost type, nutrient level, and incubation temperature.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE AND IMPACT OF THE STUDY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Compost is a rich source of CE microorganisms, and compost-adapted CE microorganisms have the potential as a biological agent to control L. monocytogenes in agricultural environments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Society for Applied Microbiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hongye</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6072-7541</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Food, Nutrition, and Packaging Sciences, Clemson University, Clemson, South Carolina, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiuping</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3705-0530</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Food, Nutrition, and Packaging Sciences, Clemson University, Clemson, South Carolina, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Appl Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9706280</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1364-5072</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010936">Plant Extracts</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>9002-18-0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000362">Agar</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000362" MajorTopicYN="N">Agar</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018441" MajorTopicYN="N">Biofilms</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015169" MajorTopicYN="N">Colony Count, Microbial</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000076282" MajorTopicYN="Y">Composting</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005516" MajorTopicYN="N">Food Microbiology</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008089" MajorTopicYN="Y">Listeria monocytogenes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010936" MajorTopicYN="N">Plant Extracts</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
L. monocytogenes
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">competitive exclusion microorganisms</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compost</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">growth potential</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>44</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35289455</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jam.15528</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ammor, S., Tauveron, G., Dufour, E. &amp; Chevallier, I. (2006a) Antibacterial activity of lactic acid bacteria against spoilage and pathogenic bacteria isolated from the same meat small-scale facility: 1-screening and characterization of the antibacterial compounds. Food Control, 17, 454-461. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodcont.2005.02.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ammor, S., Tauveron, G., Dufour, E. &amp; Chevallier, I. (2006b) Antibacterial activity of lactic acid bacteria against spoilage and pathogenic bacteria isolated from the same meat small-scale facility: 2-behaviour of pathogenic and spoilage bacteria in dual species biofilms including a bacteriocin-like-producing lactic acid bacteria. Food Control, 17, 462-468. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foodcont.2005.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An, D., Danhorn, T., Fuqua, C. &amp; Parsek, M.R. (2006) Quorum sensing and motility mediate interactions between Pseudomonas aeruginosa and agrobacterium tumefaciens in biofilm cocultures. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 103, 3828-3833.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avcı, A., Üzmez, S., Alkan, F.B., Bagana, İ., Nurçeli, E. &amp; Çiftçi, E. (2016) Antimicrobial activity spectrums of some bacillus strains from various sources. GIDA/The Journal of Food, 41, 323-328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baindara, P., Singh, N., Ranjan, M., Nallabelli, N., Chaudhry, V., Pathania, G.L. et al. (2016) Laterosporulin10: a novel defensin like class IId bacteriocin from Brevibacillus sp. strain SKDU10 with inhibitory activity against microbial pathogens. Microbiology, 162, 1286-1299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauer, M.A., Kainz, K., Carmona-Gutierrez, D. &amp; Madeo, F. (2018) Microbial wars: competition in ecological niches and within the microbiome. Microbial Cell, 5, 215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>California Leafy Greens Marketing Agreement (2010). Environmental health standards for composting operations CCR Title 14, Division 7, Chapter 3.1, Article 7. Available at: https://lgma-assets.sfo2.digitaloceanspaces.com/downloads/Appendix_E.pdf [Accessed Nov 2021].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, H., Fu, L., Luo, L., Lu, J., White, W.L. &amp; Hu, Z. (2012) Induction and resuscitation of the viable but nonculturable state in a cyanobacteria-lysing bacterium isolated from cyanobacterial bloom. Microbial Ecology, 63, 64-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das, G., Park, S. &amp; Baek, K.-H. (2017) Diversity of endophytic bacteria in a fern species Dryopteris uniformis (Makino) Makino and evaluation of their antibacterial potential against five foodborne pathogenic bacteria. Foodborne Pathogens and Disease, 14, 260-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaur, V.K., Tripathi, V., Gupta, P., Dhiman, N., Regar, R.K., Gautam, K. et al. (2020) Rhamnolipids from Planococcus spp. and their mechanism of action against pathogenic bacteria. Bioresource Technology, 307, 123206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gensler, C.A., Brown, S.R.B., Aljasir, S.F. &amp; D′amico, D.J. (2020) Compatibility of commercially produced protective cultures with common cheesemaking cultures and their antagonistic effect on foodborne pathogens. Journal of Food Protection, 83, 1010-1019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gholipour, S., Nikaeen, M., Farhadkhani, M. &amp; Nikmanesh, B. (2020) Survey of listeria monocytogenes contamination of various environmental samples and associated health risks. Food Control, 108, 106843.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gueimonde, M., Jalonen, L., He, F., Hiramatsu, M. &amp; Salminen, S. (2006) Adhesion and competitive inhibition and displacement of human enteropathogens by selected lactobacilli. International Food Research Journal, 39, 467-471.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin, Y., Gan, G., Yu, X., Wu, D., Zhang, L., Yang, N. et al. (2017) Isolation of viable but non-culturable bacteria from printing and dyeing wastewater bioreactor based on resuscitation promoting factor. Current Microbiology, 74, 787-797.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato, S., Yamagishi, A., Daimon, S., Kawasaki, K., Tamaki, H., Kitagawa, W. et al. (2018) Isolation of previously uncultured slow-growing bacteria by using a simple modification in the preparation of agar media. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 84, e00807-e00818.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, J. &amp; Jiang, X. (2010) The growth potential of Escherichia coli O157: H7, salmonella spp. and listeria monocytogenes in dairy manure-based compost in a greenhouse setting under different seasons. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 109, 2095-2104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, M., Morrison, M. &amp; Yu, Z. (2011) Evaluation of different partial 16S rRNA gene sequence regions for phylogenetic analysis of microbiomes. Journal of Microbiological Methods, 84, 81-87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y., Kim, H., Beuchat, L.R. &amp; Ryu, J.H. (2018) Development of non-pathogenic bacterial biofilms on the surface of stainless steel which are inhibitory to Salmonella enterica. Food Microbiology, 69, 136-142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lapidot, D., Dror, R., Vered, E., Mishli, O., Levy, D. &amp; Helman, Y. (2015) Disease protection and growth promotion of potatoes (Solanum tuberosum L.) by Paenibacillus dendritiformis. Plant Pathology, 64, 545-551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, J.P., Lee, S.-W., Kim, C.S., Son, J.H., Song, J.H., Lee, K.Y. et al. (2006) Evaluation of formulations of Bacillus licheniformis for the biological control of tomato gray mold caused by Botrytis cinerea. Biological Control, 37, 329-337.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, B., Wang, B., Pan, P., Li, P., Qi, Z., Zhang, Q. et al. (2019) Bacillus altitudinis strain AMCC 101304: a novel potential biocontrol agent for potato common scab. Biocontrol Science and Technology, 29, 1009-1022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magalhães, L. &amp; Nitschke, M. (2013) Antimicrobial activity of rhamnolipids against listeria monocytogenes and their synergistic interaction with nisin. Food Control, 29, 138-142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz, N., Sonar, C.R., Bhunia, K., Tang, J., Barbosa-Cánovas, G.V. &amp; Sablani, S.S. (2019) Use of protective culture to control the growth of listeria monocytogenes and Salmonella typhimurium in ready-to-eat cook-chill products. Food Control, 102, 81-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neher, D.A., Cutler, A.J., Weicht, T.R., Sharma, M. &amp; Millner, P.D. (2019) Composts of poultry litter or dairy manure differentially affect survival of enteric bacteria in fields with spinach. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 126, 1910-1922.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nurmi, E., Nuotio, L. &amp; Schneitz, C. (1992) The competitive exclusion concept: development and future. International Journal of Food Microbiology, 15, 237-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira, M., Usall, J., Viñas, I., Solsona, C. &amp; Abadias, M. (2011) Transfer of listeria innocua from contaminated compost and irrigation water to lettuce leaves. Food Microbiology, 28, 590-596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O′Toole, G.A. (2011) Microtiter dish biofilm formation assay. Journal of Visualized Experiments, 47, 2437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinto, D., Almeida, V., Almeida Santos, M. &amp; Chambel, L. (2011) Resuscitation of Escherichia coli VBNC cells depends on a variety of environmental or chemical stimuli. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 110, 1601-1611.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powell, J.E., Witthuhn, R.C., Todorov, S.D. &amp; Dicks, L.M.T. (2007) Characterization of bacteriocin ST8KF produced by a kefir isolate Lactobacillus plantarum ST8KF. International Dairy Journal, 17, 190-198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramamurthy, T., Ghosh, A., Pazhani, G.P. &amp; Shinoda, S. (2014) Current perspectives on viable but non-culturable (VBNC) pathogenic bacteria. Public Health Front, 2, 103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabaté, D.C. &amp; Audisio, M.C. (2013) Inhibitory activity of surfactin, produced by different Bacillus subtilis subsp. subtilis strains, against listeria monocytogenes sensitive and bacteriocin-resistant strains. Microbiological Research, 168, 125-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scallan, E., Hoekstra, R.M., Angulo, F.J., Tauxe, R.V., Widdowson, M.-A., Roy, S.L. et al. (2011) Foodborne illness acquired in the United States-major pathogens. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 17, 7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharifuzzaman, S.M., Rahman, H., Austin, D.A. &amp; Austin, B. (2018) Properties of probiotics Kocuria SM1 and Rhodococcus SM2 isolated from fish guts. Probiotics and Antimicrobial Proteins, 10, 534-542.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shields, P. and Cathcart, L. (2011) Motility test medium protocol. Available at: https://asm.org/ASM/media/Protocol-Images/Motility-Test-Medium-Protocol.pdf?ext=.pdf [Accessed Dec 2021].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shukla, S.K. &amp; Rao, T.S. (2017) An improved crystal violet assay for biofilm quantification in 96-well microtitre plate. Biorxiv, 100214. https://doi.org/10.1101/100214</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slimene, I. ben, Tabbene, O., Gharbi, D., Mnasri, B., Schmitter, J.M., Urdaci, M.-C. and Limam, F. (2015) Isolation of a chitinolytic bacillus licheniformis S213 strain exerting a biological control against Phoma medicaginis infection. Applied Biochemistry and Biotechnology 175, 3494-3506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Son, H., Park, S., Beuchat, L.R., Kim, H. &amp; Ryu, J.-H. (2016) Inhibition of Staphylococcus aureus by antimicrobial biofilms formed by competitive exclusion microorganisms on stainless steel. International Journal of Food Microbiology, 238, 165-171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stepanović, S., Vuković, D., Dakić, I., Savić, B. &amp; Švabić-Vlahović, M. (2000) A modified microtiter-plate test for quantification of staphylococcal biofilm formation. Journal of Microbiological Methods, 40, 175-179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strawn, L.K., Fortes, E.D., Bihn, E.A., Nightingale, K.K., Gröhn, Y.T., Worobo, R.W. et al. (2013) Landscape and meteorological factors affecting prevalence of three food-borne pathogens in fruit and vegetable farms. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 79, 588-600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Su, X., Zhang, S., Mei, R., Zhang, Y., Hashmi, M.Z., Liu, J. et al. (2018) Resuscitation of viable but non-culturable bacteria to enhance the cellulose-degrading capability of bacterial community in composting. Microbial Biotechnology, 11, 527-536.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turhan, E.U., Erginkaya, Z., Uney, M.H. &amp; Ozer, E.A. (2017) Inactivation effect of probiotic biofilms on growth of Listeria monocytogenes. Kafkas Üniversitesi Veteriner Fakültesi Dergisi, 23, 541-546.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Houdt, R. &amp; Michiels, C.W. (2010) Biofilm formation and the food industry, a focus on the bacterial outer surface. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 109, 1117-1131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watabe, M., Rao, J.R., Murphy, A.R. &amp; Moore, J.E. (2003) Inhibition of listeria ivanovii by Paenibacillus lentimorbus isolated from phase II mushroom compost. World Journal of Microbiology and Biotechnology, 19, 875.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, T., Podtburg, T.C., Zhao, P., Schmidt, B.E., Baker, D.A., Cords, B. et al. (2006) Control of Listeria spp. by competitive-exclusion bacteria in floor drains of a poultry processing plant. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 72, 3314-3320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
