<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35280179</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-0640</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>13</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Frontiers in psychiatry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antipsychotic-Related Risks of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus in Enrollees With Schizophrenia in the National Basic Public Health Service Program in Hunan Province, China.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>754775</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>754775</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">754775</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.754775</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Antipsychotics contribute to the development of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in individuals with schizophrenia. However, the extent of the relationship between antipsychotic use and T2DM varies in different settings, and the magnitude of the drug-specific effects fluctuates widely. This study aimed to explore the association of T2DM with antipsychotic use among enrollees with schizophrenia in China's National Basic Public Health Service Program (NBPHSP) and the drug-specific relationship with T2DM among patients receiving antipsychotic monotherapy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We recruited diabetes-free patients with schizophrenia who were enrolled in the NBPHSP of Hunan Province from October 2009 to December 2018. The participants were classified into the following three groups: regular antipsychotic use, intermittent antipsychotic use, and antipsychotic-free groups. The patients were followed up until they received a T2DM diagnosis or until April 2019. Cox regression models were constructed to calculate the overall and drug-specific hazard ratios (HRs) to determine the antipsychotic-T2DM relationship. Interactive and subgroup analyses were performed to assess the heterogeneity of the effects across subgroups.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 122,064 NBPHSP enrollees with schizophrenia were followed up for 1,507,829 cumulative person-years, and 2,313 (1.89%) patients developed T2DM. Patients who regularly and intermittently used antipsychotics had 117% (HR: 2.17, 95% CI: 1.83-2.57) and 53% (HR: 1.53, 95% CI: 1.23-1.90) higher risks of developing T2DM than antipsychotic-free patients, respectively. Regarding monotherapy, the T2DM risk increased by 66, 80, 62, and 64% after the regular use of clozapine, risperidone, chlorpromazine, and perphenazine, respectively. In addition, the antipsychotic-related risk of T2DM decreased as the patient's baseline body mass index, and baseline fasting plasma glucose level, as well as the dietary proportion of animal products, increased.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Antipsychotics, especially clozapine, risperidone, chlorpromazine, and perphenazine, increased the T2DM risk among NBPHSP enrollees with schizophrenia. Mental health officers should accurately identify enrollees at a high risk of T2DM and take appropriate preventive measures to reduce the incidence of T2DM among patients with schizophrenia.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Ouyang, He, Cheng, Zhou, Xiao and Fang.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ouyang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Feiyun</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Social Medicine and Health Management, Xiangya School of Public Health, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Social Medicine and Health Management, Xiangya School of Public Health, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xunjie</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Geriatric Medicine, Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Research Center for Public Health and Social Security, School of Public Administration, Hunan University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xiao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shuiyuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Social Medicine and Health Management, Xiangya School of Public Health, Central South University, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junqun</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Management, Maternal and Child Health Hospital of Hunan Province, Changsha, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Front Psychiatry</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101545006</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1664-0640</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antipsychotic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">monotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polytherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes mellitus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>7</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35280179</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8909132</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2022.754775</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charlson FJ, Ferrari AJ, Santomauro DF, Diminic S, Stockings E, Scott JG, et al. . Global epidemiology and burden of Schizophrenia: findings from the global burden of disease study 2016. Schizophr Bull. (2018) 44:1195–203. 10.1093/schbul/sby058</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sby058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6192504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29762765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jääskeläinen E, Juola P, Hirvonen N, McGrath JJ, Saha S, Isohanni M, et al. . A systematic review and meta-analysis of recovery in Schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. (2013) 39:1296–306. 10.1093/schbul/sbs130</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sbs130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3796077</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23172003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saha S, Chant D, McGrath J. A systematic review of mortality in Schizophrenia: is the differential mortality gap worsening over time?
Arch Gen Psychiatry. (2007) 64:1123–31. 10.1001/archpsyc.64.10.1123</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.64.10.1123</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hennekens CH, Hennekens AR, Hollar D, Casey DE. Schizophrenia and increased risks of cardiovascular disease. Am Heart J. (2005) 150:1115–21. 10.1016/j.ahj.2005.02.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2005.02.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16338246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suvisaari J, Partti K, Perälä J, Viertiö S, Saarni SE, Lönnqvist J, et al. . Mortality and its determinants in people with psychotic disorder. Psychosom Med. (2013) 75:60–7. 10.1097/PSY.0b013e31827ad512</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0b013e31827ad512</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23257931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vancampfort D, Wampers M, Mitchell AJ, Correll CU, De Herdt A, Probst M, et al. . A meta-analysis of cardio-metabolic abnormalities in drug naïve, first-episode and multi-episode patients with Schizophrenia versus general population controls. World Psychiatry. (2013) 12:240–50. 10.1002/wps.20069</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799255</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24096790</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajkumar AP, Horsdal HT, Wimberley T, Cohen D, Mors O, Børglum AD, et al. . Endogenous and antipsychotic-related risks for diabetes mellitus in young people with Schizophrenia: a Danish population-based cohort study. Am J Psychiatry. (2017) 174:686–94. 10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16040442</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16040442</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28103712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McEvoy JP, Meyer JM, Goff DC, Nasrallah HA, Davis SM, Sullivan L, et al. . Prevalence of the metabolic syndrome in patients with schizophrenia: baseline results from the Clinical Antipsychotic Trials of Intervention Effectiveness (CATIE) Schizophrenia trial and comparison with national estimates from NHANES III. Schizophr Res. (2005) 80:19–32. 10.1016/j.schres.2005.07.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2005.07.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16137860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polcwiartek C, Kragholm K, Rohde C, Hashemi N, Vang T, Nielsen J. Diabetic ketoacidosis and diabetes associated with antipsychotic exposure among a previously diabetes-naive population with schizophrenia: a nationwide nested case-control study. Diabetologia. (2017) 60:1678–90. 10.1007/s00125-017-4320-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-017-4320-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28593353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishtala PS, Chyou TY. Real-world risk of diabetes with antipsychotic use in older New Zealanders: a case-crossover study. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. (2017) 73:233–9. 10.1007/s00228-016-2158-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00228-016-2158-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27885398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rondanelli M, Sarra S, Antoniello N, Mansi V, Govoni S, Falvo F, et al. . No effect of atypical antipsychotic drugs on weight gain and risk of developing type II diabetes or lipid abnormalities among nursing home elderly patients with Alzheimer's disease. Minerva Med. (2006) 97:147–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16760853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holt RI, Peveler RC. Antipsychotic drugs and diabetes–an application of the Austin Bradford Hill criteria. Diabetologia. (2006) 49:1467–76. 10.1007/s00125-006-0279-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-006-0279-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16752165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holt RIG. Association between antipsychotic medication use and diabetes. Curr Diab Rep. (2019) 19:96. 10.1007/s11892-019-1220-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11892-019-1220-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6718373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31478094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingimarsson O, MacCabe JH, Haraldsson M, Jónsdóttir H, Sigurdsson E. Risk of diabetes and dyslipidemia during clozapine and other antipsychotic drug treatment of schizophrenia in Iceland. Nord J Psychiatry. (2017) 71:496–502. 10.1080/08039488.2017.1334821</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08039488.2017.1334821</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28632422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreyenbuhl J, Zito JM, Buchanan RW, Soeken KL, Lehman AF. Racial disparity in the pharmacological management of Schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. (2003) 29:183–93. 10.1093/oxfordjournals.schbul.a006996</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.schbul.a006996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14552495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puyat JH, Daw JR, Cunningham CM, Law MR, Wong ST, Greyson DL, et al. . Racial and ethnic disparities in the use of antipsychotic medication: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. (2013) 48:1861–72. 10.1007/s00127-013-0753-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-013-0753-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23942793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mangurian C, Keenan W, Newcomer JW, Vittinghoff E, Creasman JM, Schillinger D. Diabetes prevalence among racial-ethnic minority group members with severe mental illness taking antipsychotics: double jeopardy?
Psychiatr Serv. (2017) 68:843–6. 10.1176/appi.ps.201600356</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.201600356</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch L, Yang J, Bresee L, Jette N, Patten S, Pringsheim T. Second-generation antipsychotics and metabolic side effects: a systematic review of population-based studies. Drug Saf. (2017) 40:771–81. 10.1007/s40264-017-0543-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-017-0543-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28585153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foley DL, Mackinnon A, Morgan VA, Watts GF, Castle DJ, Waterreus A, et al. . Effect of age, family history of diabetes, and antipsychotic drug treatment on risk of diabetes in people with psychosis: a population-based cross-sectional study. Lancet Psychiatry. (2015) 2:1092–8. 10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00276-X</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00276-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26477242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan KY, Zhao FF, Meng S, Demaio AR, Reed C, Theodoratou E, et al. . Prevalence of Schizophrenia in China between 1990 and 2010. J Glob Health. (2015) 5:010410. 10.1002/wps.20222</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4663755</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26649171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma H. Integration of hospital and community services-the '686 Project'-is a crucial component in the reform of China's mental health services. Shanghai Arch Psychiatry. (2012) 24:172–4. 10.3969/j.issn.1002-0829.2012.03.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3969/j.issn.1002-0829.2012.03.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4198849</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25324622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X, Ma N, Wu X, Zhang W, Guan L, Ma H, et al. . Management and services for psychosis in People′s Republic of China in 2018. Chin J Psychiatry. (2020) 53:438–45. 10.3760/cma.j.cn113661-20200622-00290</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3760/cma.j.cn113661-20200622-00290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L, Wang Z, Ma Q, Fang G, Yang J. The development and reform of public health in China from 1949 to 2019. Global Health. (2019) 15:45. 10.1186/s12992-019-0486-6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12992-019-0486-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6604346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31266514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization . The ICD-10 Classification of Mental and Behavioural Disorders—Diagnostic Criteria for Research. Geneva, Switzerland: World Health Organization;  (1992).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lachin JM. Sample size and power for a logrank test and Cox proportional hazards model with multiple groups and strata, or a quantitative covariate with multiple strata. Stat Med. (2013) 32:4413–25. 10.1002/sim.5839</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.5839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3775959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23670965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization . Definition, Diagnosis and Classification of Diabetes Mellitus and Its Complications: Report of a WHO Consultation. Part 1, Diagnosis and Classification of Diabetes Mellitus. Geneva: World Health Organization;  (1999).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng J, Ji L, Jia W, Lu J, Zhou Z, Zou D, et al. . Standards of care for type 2 diabetes in China. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. (2016) 32:442–58. 10.1002/dmrr.2827</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/dmrr.2827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5108436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27464265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suvisaari J, Perälä J, Saarni SI, Härkänen T, Pirkola S, Joukamaa M, et al. . Type 2 diabetes among persons with schizophrenia and other psychotic disorders in a general population survey. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. (2008) 258:129–36. 10.1007/s00406-007-0762-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-007-0762-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17990051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vancampfort D, Correll CU, Galling B, Probst M, De Hert M, Ward PB, et al. . Diabetes mellitus in people with schizophrenia, bipolar disorder and major depressive disorder: a systematic review and large scale meta-analysis. World Psychiatry. (2016) 15:166–74. 10.1002/wps.20309</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4911762</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27265707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galling B, Roldán A, Nielsen RE, Nielsen J, Gerhard T, Carbon M, et al. . Type 2 diabetes mellitus in youth exposed to antipsychotics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. (2016) 73:247–59. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.2923</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.2923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leucht S, Cipriani A, Spineli L, Mavridis D, Orey D, Richter F, et al. . Comparative efficacy and tolerability of 15 antipsychotic drugs in schizophrenia: a multiple-treatments meta-analysis. Lancet. (2013) 382:951–62. 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60733-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60733-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23810019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Correll CU, Detraux J, De Lepeleire J, De Hert M. Effects of antipsychotics, antidepressants and mood stabilizers on risk for physical diseases in people with schizophrenia, depression and bipolar disorder. World Psychiatry. (2015) 14:119–36. 10.1002/wps.20204</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4471960</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26043321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng C. Effects of antipsychotic medications on appetite, weight, and insulin resistance. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am. (2013) 42:545–63. 10.1016/j.ecl.2013.05.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecl.2013.05.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24011886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rummel-Kluge C, Komossa K, Schwarz S, Hunger H, Schmid F, Lobos CA, et al. . Head-to-head comparisons of metabolic side effects of second generation antipsychotics in the treatment of schizophrenia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. (2010) 123:225–33. 10.1016/j.schres.2010.07.012</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2010.07.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2957510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20692814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kessing LV, Thomsen AF, Mogensen UB, Andersen PK. Treatment with antipsychotics and the risk of diabetes in clinical practice. Br J Psychiatry. (2010) 197:266–71. 10.1192/bjp.bp.109.076935</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.109.076935</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20884948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Folnegović-Smalc V, Jukić V, Kozumplik O, Mimica N, Uzun S. Olanzapine use in a patient with schizophrenia and the risk of diabetes. Eur Psychiatry. (2004) 19:62–4. 10.1016/j.eurpsy.2003.09.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eurpsy.2003.09.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14969784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleischhaker C, Heiser P, Hennighausen K, Herpertz-Dahlmann B, Holtkamp K, Mehler-Wex C, et al. . Weight gain in children and adolescents during 45 weeks treatment with clozapine, olanzapine and risperidone. J Neural Transm. (2008) 115:1599–608. 10.1007/s00702-008-0105-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-008-0105-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18779922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rico-Villademoros F, Calandre EP. Risk of bias in observational studies of interventions: the case of antipsychotic-induced diabetes. Lancet Psychiatry. (2016) 3:103–4. 10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00541-6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00541-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851323</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ley SH, Hamdy O, Mohan V, Hu FB. Prevention and management of type 2 diabetes: dietary components and nutritional strategies. Lancet. (2014) 383:1999–2007. 10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60613-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60613-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4751088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24910231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preiss D, Welsh P, Murray HM, Shepherd J, Packard C, Macfarlane P, et al. . Fasting plasma glucose in non-diabetic participants and the risk for incident cardiovascular events, diabetes, and mortality: results from WOSCOPS 15-year follow-up. Eur Heart J. (2010) 31:1230–6. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehq095</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehq095</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4209362</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20395260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shu L. Chinese Schizophrenia Prevention and Control Guideline. Beijing: Peking University Medical Press;  (2007).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The National Health Commission of the People's Republic of China . National Basic Public Health Service Specifications, 3rd Edn. Beijin:  (2017).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holt RI. The prevention of diabetes and cardiovascular disease in people with Schizophrenia. Acta Psychiatr Scand. (2015) 132:86–96. 10.1111/acps.12443</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.12443</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25976975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suvisaari J, Keinänen J, Eskelinen S, Mantere O. Diabetes and Schizophrenia. Curr Diab Rep. (2016) 16:16. 10.1007/s11892-015-0704-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11892-015-0704-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26803652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perälä J, Saarni SI, Ostamo A, Pirkola S, Haukka J, Härkänen T, et al. . Geographic variation and sociodemographic characteristics of psychotic disorders in Finland. Schizophr Res. (2008) 106:337–47. 10.1016/j.schres.2008.08.017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2008.08.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18804345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evert AB, Boucher JL, Cypress M, Dunbar SA, Franz MJ, Mayer-Davis EJ, et al. . Nutrition therapy recommendations for the management of adults with diabetes. Diabetes Care. (2014) 37:S120–43. 10.2337/dc14-S120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc14-S120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dworatzek PD, Arcudi K, Gougeon R, Husein N, Sievenpiper JL, Williams SL. Nutrition therapy. Can J Diabetes. (2013) 37:S45–55. 10.1016/j.jcjd.2013.01.019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcjd.2013.01.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24070963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He J, Fang A, Yu S, Shen X, Li K. Dietary nonheme, heme, and total iron intake and the risk of diabetes in adults: results from the China health and nutrition survey. Diabetes Care. (2020) 43:776–84. 10.2337/dc19-2202</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc19-2202</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansen JB, Moen IW, Mandrup-Poulsen T. Iron: the hard player in diabetes pathophysiology. Acta Physiol. (2014) 210:717–32. 10.1111/apha.12256</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apha.12256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24521359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Diabetes Association American Psychiatric Association American American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists North North American Association for the Study of Obesity . Consensus development conference on antipsychotic drugs and obesity and diabetes. Diabetes Care. (2004) 27:596–601. 10.2337/diacare.27.2.596</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.27.2.596</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14747245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ulcickas Yood M, Delorenze GN, Quesenberry CP Jr, Oliveria SA, Tsai AL, et al. . Association between second-generation antipsychotics and newly diagnosed treated diabetes mellitus: does the effect differ by dose?
BMC Psychiatry. (2011) 11:197. 10.1186/1471-244X-11-197</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-11-197</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3264670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22171594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirigo AT, Teshome T. The magnitude of undiagnosed diabetes and Hypertension among adult psychiatric patients receiving antipsychotic treatment. Diabetol Metab Syndr. (2020) 12:79. 10.1186/s13098-020-00588-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13098-020-00588-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7487878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32944092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
