<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35290608</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7479</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurotherapeutics : the journal of the American Society for Experimental NeuroTherapeutics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurotherapeutics</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Autoimmune Neurological Disorders with IgG4 Antibodies: a Distinct Disease Spectrum with Unique IgG4 Functions Responding to Anti-B Cell Therapies.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13311-022-01210-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The main IgG4 antibody-mediated neurological disorders (IgG4-ND) include MuSK myasthenia; CIDP with nodal/paranodal antibodies to Neurofascin-155, contactin-1/caspr-1, or pan-neurofascins; anti-LGI1 and CASPR2-associated limbic encephalitis, Morvan syndrome, or neuromyotonia; and several cases of the anti-IgLON5 and anti-DPPX-spectrum CNS diseases. The paper is centered on the clinical spectrum of IgG4-ND and their immunopathogenesis highlighting the unique functional effects of the IgG4 subclass compared to IgG1-3 antibody subclasses. The IgG4 antibodies exert pathogenic effects on their targeted antigens by blocking enzymatic activity or disrupting protein-protein interactions affecting signal transduction pathways, but not by activating complement, binding to inhibitory FcγRIIb receptor or engaging in cross-linking of the targeted antigen with immune complex formation as the IgG1-IgG3 antibody subclasses do. IgG4 can even inhibit the classical complement pathway by affecting the affinity of IgG1-2 subclasses to C1q binding. Because the IgG4 antibodies do not trigger inflammatory processes or complement-mediated immune responses, the conventional anti-inflammatory therapies, especially with IVIg, immunosuppressants, and plasmapheresis, are ineffective or not sufficiently effective in inducing long-term remissions. In contrast, aiming at the activated plasmablasts connected with IgG4 antibody production is a meaningful therapeutic target in IgG4-ND. Indeed, data from large series of patients with MuSK myasthenia, CIDP with nodal/paranodal antibodies, and anti-LGI1 and CASPR2-associated syndromes indicate that B cell depletion therapy with rituximab exerts long-lasting clinical remissions by targeting memory B cells and IgG4-producing CD20-positive short-lived plasma cells. Because IgG4 antibody titers seem reduced in remissions and increased in exacerbation, they may serve as potential biomarkers of treatment response supporting further the pathogenic role of self-reacting B cells. Controlled trials are needed in IgG4-ND not only with rituximab but also with the other anti-B cell agents that target CD19/20, especially those like obexelimab and obinutuzumab, that concurrently activate the inhibitory FcγRIIb receptors which have low binding affinity to IgG4, exerting a more prolonged anti-B cell action affecting also antigen presentation and cytotoxic T cells. Antibody therapies targeting FcRn, testing those anti-FcRn inhibitors that effectively catabolize the IgG4 antibody subclass, may be especially promising.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dalakas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marinos C</ForeName>
            <Initials>MC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7070-1134</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, PA, USA. marinos.dalakas@jefferson.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neuroimmunology Unit National and Kapodistrian University of Athens Medical School, Athens, Greece. marinos.dalakas@jefferson.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurotherapeutics</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101290381</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1878-7479</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FcγRIIb receptors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IVIg</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IgG4 antibodies to nerve antigens</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IgG4-autoimmune neurological diseases</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anti-B cell therapies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complement activation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35290608</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-022-01210-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13311-022-01210-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. IgG4-mediated neurological autoimmunities: understanding pathogenicity of IgG4, ineffectiveness of IVIg and long-lasting benefits of anti-B cell therapies. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2022;9:e1116.  https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000001116 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koneczny I. A new classification system for IgG4 autoantibodies. Front Immunol. 2018;9:97.  https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2018.00097 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perugino CA, Stone JH. IgG4-related disease: an update on pathophysiology and implications for clinical care. Nat Rev Rheumatol 2020.  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41584-020-0500-7 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto M. B cell targeted therapy for immunoglobulin G4-related disease. Immunol Med. 2021.  https://doi.org/10.1080/25785826.2021.1886630 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huijbers MG, Querol LA, Niks EH, et al. The expanding field of IgG4-mediated neurological autoimmune disorders. Europ Journal of Neurol. 2015;22:1151–1161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koneczny I, Cossins J, Waters P, Beeson D, Vincent A. MuSK myasthenia gravis IgG4 disrupts the interaction of LRP4 with MuSK but both IgG4 and IgG1–3 can disperse preformed agrin-independent AChR clusters. PLoS One. 2013;8:e80695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Querol L, Nogales-Gadea G, Rojas-Garcia R, et al. Neurofascin IgG4 antibodies in CIDP associate with disabling tremor and poor response to IVIg. Neurology. 2014;82:879–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalmau J, Geis C, Graus F. Autoantibodies to synaptic receptors and neuronal cell surface proteins in autoimmune diseases of the central nervous system. Physiol Rev. 2017;97:839–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00010.2016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastiaansen AEM, van Sonderen A, Titulaer MJ. Autoimmune encephalitis with anti-leucine-rich glioma-inactivated 1 or anti-contactin-associated protein-like 2 antibodies (formerly called voltage-gated potassium channel-complex antibodies). Curr Opin Neurol. 2017;30:302–9. https://doi.org/10.1097/wco.0000000000000444 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/wco.0000000000000444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28248701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaig C, Graus F, Compta Y, et al. Clinical manifestations of the anti-IgLON5 disease. Neurology. 2017;88:1736–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000003887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vidarsson G, Dekkers G, Rispens T. IgG subclasses and allotypes: from structure to effector functions. Front Immunol. 2014;5:520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2014.00520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips WD, Vincent A. Pathogenesis of myasthenia gravis: update on disease types, models, and mechanisms. F1000Res. 2016;5:1513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Immunotherapy in myasthenia gravis in the era of biologics. Nature Rev Neurol. 2018.  https://doi.org/10.1038/s41582-018-0110-z .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evoli A, Tonali PA, Padua L, et al. Clinical correlates with anti-MuSK antibodies in generalized seronegative myasthenia gravis. Brain. 2003;126(Pt 10):2304–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awg223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Querol L, Nogales-Gadea G, Rojas-Garcia R, et al. Antibodies to contactin-1 in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. Ann Neurol. 2013;73:370–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.23794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pascual-Goñi E, Fehmi J, Lleixà C, et al. Antibodies to the Caspr1/contactin-1 complex in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. Brain. 2021;144(4):1183–1196.  https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awab014 . PMID: 33880507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stathopoulos P, Alexopoulos H, Dalakas MC. Autoimmune antigenic targets at the node of Ranvier in demyelinating disorders. Nature Rev Neurol. 2015;11:80-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manso C, Querol L, Mekaouche M, et al. Contactin-1 IgG4 antibodies cause paranode dismantling and conduction defects. Brain. 2016;139(Pt 6):1700–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/aww062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manso C, Querol L, Lleixa C, et al. Anti–neurofascin-155 IgG4 antibodies prevent paranodal complex formation in vivo. J Clin Invest. 2019;129(6):2222–2236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martín-Aguilar L, Lleixà C, Pascual-Goñi E, et al. Clinical and laboratory features in anti-NF155 autoimmune nodopathy. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2021;9(1):e1098.  https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000001098 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gr¨uner J, Stengel H, Werner C, et al. Anti–contactin-1 antibodies affect surface expression and sodium currents in dorsal root ganglia. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2021;8:e1056. https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000001056 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Gooch C. Close to the node but far enough; what nodal antibodies tell us about CIDP and its therapies. Neurology. 2016;86(9):796–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramberger M, Beretta A, Tan J, Sun B, Michaeal S, Yeo T, et al. Distinctive binding properties of human monoclonal LGI1 autoantibodies determine pathogenic mechanisms. Brain. 2020;143:1731–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patterson KR, Dalmau J, Lancaster E. Mechanisms of Caspr2 antibodies in autoimmune encephalitis and neuromyotonia. Ann Neurol. 2018;83(1):40–51.  https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.25120 . Epub 2018 Jan 10. PMID: 29244234; PMCID: PMC5876120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramanathan S, Tseng M, Davies AJ, et al. Leucine-rich glioma-inactivated 1 versus contactin-associated protein-like 2 antibody neuropathic pain: clinical and biological comparisons. Annals of Neurol. 2021;90:683–690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landa J, Gaig C, Plagumà I, et al. Effects of IgLON5 antibodies on neuronal cytoskeleton: a link between autoimmunity and neurodegeneration. Ann Neurol. 2020;88:1023–1027.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabater L, Gaig C, Gelpi E, et al. A novel non-rapid eye movement and rapid-eye-movement parasomnia with sleep breathing disorder associated with antibodies to IgLON5: a case series, characterisation of the antigen, and post-mortem study. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13:575–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70051-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaig C, Compta Y, Heidbreder A, et al. Frequency and characterization of movement disorders in anti-IgLON5 disease. Neurology. 2021;97:e1367-e1381.  https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000012639 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hara M, Arinos H, Petit-Pedrol M, et al. DPPX antibody-associated encephalitis: main syndrome and antibody effects. Neurology. 2017;88:1340–1348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tobin WO, Lennon V, Komorowski L, et al. DPPX potassium channel antibody: frequency, clinical accompaniments, and outcomes in 20 patients. Neurology. 2014;83:1797–1803.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Stiff-person syndrome and GAD antibody-spectrum disorders: GABAergic neuronal excitability, immunopathogenesis and update on antibody therapies. Neurotherapeutics. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-022-01188-w .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Neut KM, Schuurman J, Losen M, et al. Antiinflammatory activity of human IgG4 antibodies by dynamic Fab arm exchange. Science. 2007;317:1554–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1144603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prodjinotho UF, Hoerauf A, Adjobimey T. IgG4 antibodies from patients with asymptomatic bancroftian filariasis inhibit the binding of IgG1 and IgG2 to C1q in a Fc-Fc-dependent mechanism. Parasitol Res. 2019;118:2957–2968.  https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-019-06451-2 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haddad G, Lorenzen JM, Ma H, et al. Altered glycosylation of IgG4 promotes lectin complement pathway activation in anti-PLA2R1–associated membranous nephropathy J Clin Invest. 2021;131(5):e140453. https://doi.org/10.1172/JCI140453 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akiyama M, Suzuki K, Yamaoka K, et al. Number of circulating follicular helper 2 T cells correlates with IgG4 and interleukin-4 levels and plasmablast numbers in IgG4-related disease. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2015;67(9):2476–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appeltshauser L, Brunder A-M, Heinius A, et al. Antiparanodal antibodies and IgG subclasses in acute autoimmune neuropathy. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2020;7:e817. https://doi.org/10.1212/NXI.0000000000000817 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niks EH, van Leeuwen Y, Leite MI, et al. Clinical fluctuations in MuSK myasthenia gravis are related to antigen-specific IgG4 instead of IgG1. J Neuroimmunol. 2008;195:151–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2008.01.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Mechanism of action of IVIg and therapeutic considerations in the treatment of acute and chronic demyelinating neuropathies. Neurology. 2002;59:S13-21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.59.12_suppl_6.S13</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Intravenous immunoglobulin in autoimmune neuromuscular diseases. JAMA. 2004;291(19):2367–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.291.19.2367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Update on intravenous immunoglobulin in neurology: modulating neuro-autoimmunity, evolving factors on efficacy and dosing and challenges on stopping chronic IVIg therapy. Neurotherapeutics. 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13311-021-01108-4 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roux KH, Tankersley DL. A view of the human idiotypic repertoire. Electron microscopic and immunologic analyses of spontaneous idiotype--anti-idiotype dimers in pooled human IgG. J Immunol. 1990;144:1387–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dietrich G, Kazatchkine MD. Normal immunoglobulin G (IgG) for therapeutic use (intravenous Ig) contains anti-idiotypic specificities against an immunodominant, disease-associated, cross-reactive idiotype of human anti-thyroglobulin autoantibodies. J Clin Invest. 1990;85:620–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI114483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buchwald B, Ahangari R, Weishaupt A, Toyka KV. Intravenous immunoglobulins neutralize blocking antibodies in Guillain-Barré syndrome. Ann Neurol. 2002;51:673–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.10205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs BC, O’Hanlon GM, Bullens RWM, et al. Immunoglobulins inhibit pathophysiological effects of anti-GQ1b-positive sera at motor nerve terminals through inhibition of antibody binding. Brain. 2003;126:2220–2234.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik U, Oleksowicz L, Latov N, Cardo LJ. Intravenous y-globulin inhibits binding of anti-GMI to its target antigen. Ann Neurol. 1996;39:136–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410390121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basta M, Dalakas MC. High-dose intravenous immunoglobulin exerts its beneficial effect in patients with dermatomyositis by blocking endomysial deposition of activated complement fragments. J Clin Invest. 1994;94:1729–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI117520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Illa I, Dambrosia JM, et al. A controlled trial of high-dose intravenous immunoglobulin infusions as treatment for dermatomyositis. N Engl J Med. 1993;329:1993–2000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tackenberg B, et al. Impaired inhibitory Fcgamma receptor IIB expression on B cells in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106:4788–92. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0807319106 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0807319106</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19261857</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2660764</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anthony RM, et al. Recapitulation of IVIG anti-inflammatory activity with a recombinant IgG Fc. Science. 2008;320:373–6. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1154315 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1154315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18420934</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2409116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lunneman JD, Nimmerjahn F. Dalakas MC Intravenous immunoglobulin in neurology: mode of action and clinical efficacy. Nat Rev Neurol. 2015;11:80–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2014.253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quast I, Keller CW, Maurer MA, et al. Sialylation of IgG Fc domain impairs complement dependent cytotoxicity. J Clin Invest. 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Spaeth PJ. The importance of FcRn in Neuro-immunotherapies: from IgG catabolism. FCGRT gene polymorphisms, IVIg dosing and efficiency to specific FcRn inhibitors Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2021;14:1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu Z, Lennon VA. Mechanism of intravenous immune globulin therapy in antibody-mediated autoimmune diseases. N Engl J Med. 1999;340:227–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199901213400311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li N, et al. Complete FcRn dependence for intravenous Ig therapy in autoimmune skin blistering diseases. J Clin Invest. 2005;115:3440–50. Epub 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Inhibition of B cell functions: implications for neurology. Neurology. 2008;70:2252–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000313840.27060.bf</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. B cells as therapeutic targets in autoimmune neurological disorders. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2008;4(10):557–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncpneuro0901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unger PA, Lighaam LC, Vermeulen E, et al. Divergent chemokine receptor expression and the consequence for human IgG4 B cell responses. Eur J Immunol. 2020;50(8):1113–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eji.201948454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallace ZS, et al. Predictors of disease relapse in IgG4-related disease following rituximab. Rheumatology. 2016;55:1000–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kev438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hehir MK, Hobson-Webb LD. Benatar M Rituximab as treatment for anti-MuSK myasthenia gravis. Neurology. 2017;89:1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000004341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marino MM, Basile U, Spagni G, et al. Long-lasting rituximab-induced reduction of specific—but not total—IgG4 in MuSK-positive myasthenia gravis. Front Immunol. 2020;11:613.  https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2020.00613 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Progress in the therapy of myasthenia gravis: getting closer to effective targeted immunotherapies. Curr Opin Neurol. 2020;33:545–552.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shelly S, Klein C, Dyck PJ, et al. Neurofascin-155 immunoglobulin subtypes: clinicopathologic associations and neurologic outcomes. Neurology.  https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000012932 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadoth A, Zekeridou A, Klein CJ et al Elevated LGI1-IgG CSF index predicts worse neurological outcome. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2018;5(5):646–650.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubey D, Britton J, McKeon A, et al. Randomized placebo-controlled trial of intravenous immunoglobulin in autoimmune LGI1/CASPR2 epilepsy. Ann Neurol. 2019;00:1–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith KM, Dubey D, Liebo GB, et al. Clinical course and features of seizures associated with LGI1-antibody. Neurology. 2021;97(11):e1141-e1149.  https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0000000000012465 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye L, Schnegelsberg M. Obermann M Dipeptidyl-peptidase-like protein encephalitis treated with immunotherapy. 2021;34(1):114–5. https://doi.org/10.1080/08998280.2020.1822132 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08998280.2020.1822132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majumder S, Mohapatra S, Lennon RJ, et al. Rituximab maintenance therapy reduces rate of relapse of pancreaticobiliary immunoglobulin G4-related disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;16(12):1947–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2018.02.049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Della- Torre E, et al. B-cell depletion attenuates serological biomarkers of fibrosis and myofibroblast activation in IgG4-related disease. Ann Rheum Dis. 2015;74:2236–2243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosmidis M, Dalakas MC. Practical considerations on the use of rituximab in autoimmune neurological disorders. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2010;3(2):93–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756285609356135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebrun C. Bourg V Bresch S et al Therapeutic target of memory B cells depletion helps to tailor administration frequency of rituximab in myasthenia gravis. J Neuroimmunol. 2016;298:79–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jneuroim.2016.07.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Rakocevic G, Salajegheh M, et al. Placebo-controlled trial of rituximab in IgM anti-myelin-associated glycoprotein antibody demyelinating neuropathy. Ann Neurol. 2009;65(3):286–93.  https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.21577 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexopoulos H, Biba A, Dalakas MC. Anti-B-cell therapies in autoimmune neurological diseases: rationale and efficacy trials. Neurotherapeutics. 2016;13(1):20–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-015-0402-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cree BAC, et al. Inebilizumab for the treatment of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (N-MOmentum): a double-blind, randomized placebo-controlled phase 2/3 trial. Lancet. 2019;394:1352–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)31817-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stathopoulos P, Dalakas MC. Evolution of anti-B-cell therapeutics in autoimmune Neurological diseases. Neurotherapeutics, In press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rakocevic G, Martinez-Outschoorn U, Dalakas MC. Obinutuzumab, a potent anti–B-cell agent, for rituximab-unresponsive IgM anti-MAG neuropathy. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2018;5:e460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reich DS, Arnold DL, Vermersch P, et al. Safety and efficacy of tolebrutinib, an oral brain-penetrant BTK inhibitor, in relapsing multiple sclerosis: a phase 2b, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(9):729–738.  https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(21)00237-4 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, et al. Safety, efficacy, and tolerability of efgartigimod in patients with generalised myasthenia gravis (ADAPT): a multicentre, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20:526–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(21)00159-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF, Nowak RJ, Wolfe GI, et al. Clinical effects of the self-administered subcutaneous complement inhibitor zilucoplan in patients with moderate to severe generalized myasthenia gravis results of a phase 2 randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020.  https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.5125 . Published online February 17, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
