<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35293078</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-2149</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>26</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European journal of pain (London, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Pain</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Efficacy and safety of botulinum A toxin for the treatment of chronic peripheral neuropathic pain: A systematic review of randomized controlled trials and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>980</StartPage>
          <EndPage>990</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>980-990</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ejp.1941</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE">Botulinum toxin type A (BTX-A) is a recently developed treatment for the management of peripheral neuropathic pain. The objective of this study was to provide a synthesis of the evidence concerning the efficacy and safety of subcutaneous botulinum toxin type A injections.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATABASES AND DATA TREATMENT">We searched the MEDLINE, EMBASE, LILACS, Cochrane, and Clinical Trial Register databases for randomized controlled trials comparing subcutaneous BTX-A to placebo injections for treating chronic peripheral neuropathic pain. The primary endpoint was the assessment of pain 1 month after the injection. The secondary outcomes were the assessment of pain at 3 months, neuropathic pain intensity and quality of life at 1 and 3 months, and adverse effects. A random-effect meta-analysis was performed on the combined data. Evidence quality was rated by the Grades of Recommendation, Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) method.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Ten randomized controlled trials including 505 patients were included in this review (registration number CRD42021239108). At 1 and 3 months after injection, the BTX-A groups had a lower mean difference (MD) in pain score (MD -1.87 (confidence intervals [CIs] -2.91; -0.83) and -1.38 (CI -1.95; -0.81), respectively). Subgroup analysis showed greater efficacy for diabetic polyneuropathy (MD -2.48, [-3.22; -1.74]). We found no impact of BTX-A on quality of life and no difference in adverse effect between BTX-A and placebo. The evidence was considered of moderate quality.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The pooled data suggest that subcutaneous BTX-A injections have a clinically significant effect, decreasing pain for three months after the injection, but no benefit in terms of quality of life has yet been demonstrated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE">We found that botulinum toxin is efficient and safe for the treatment of neuropathic pain, especially for diabetic polyneuropathy. Botulinum toxin type A, used for years in neurology, rehabilitation and physical medicine, has proved innocuous and effective, and should be considered as a serious alternative for pain treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 European Pain Federation - EFIC®.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hary</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vincent</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of medecine, Université de Paris, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pain Unit, Hôpital Raymond Poincaré, APHP, Garches, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schitter</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sebastien</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pain Unit, Hôpital Raymond Poincaré, APHP, Garches, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty de medecine, Université Versailles Saint Quentin, Versailles, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martinez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Valeria</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pain Unit, Hôpital Raymond Poincaré, APHP, Garches, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty de medecine, Université Versailles Saint Quentin, Versailles, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>INSERM U 987, CETD, Hôpital Ambroise Paré, APHP, Boulogne-Billancourt, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Hôpital Raymond Poincaré, APHP, Garches, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Pain</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9801774</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1090-3801</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.24.69</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D019274">Botulinum Toxins, Type A</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019274" MajorTopicYN="Y">Botulinum Toxins, Type A</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003014" MajorTopicYN="Y">Clostridium botulinum</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003929" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetic Neuropathies</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015201" MajorTopicYN="N">Meta-Analysis as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009437" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuralgia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293078</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejp.1941</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The Cochrane Collaboration. (2020). Review Manager (RevMan) [Computer program].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apalla, Z., Sotiriou, E., Lallas, A., Lazaridou, E., &amp; Ioannides, D. (2013). Botulinum toxin A in postherpetic neuralgia: A parallel, randomized, double-blind, single-dose, placebo-controlled trial. Clinical Journal of Pain, 29, 857-864. https://doi.org/10.1097/AJP.0b013e31827a72d2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attal, N., de Andrade, D. C., Adam, F., Ranoux, D., Teixeira, M. J., Galhardoni, R., Raicher, I., Üçeyler, N., Sommer, C., &amp; Bouhassira, D. (2016). Safety and efficacy of repeated injections of botulinum toxin A in peripheral neuropathic pain (BOTNEP): A randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. The Lancet Neurology, 15, 555-565. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(16)00017-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attal, N., Lanteri-Minet, M., Laurent, B., Fermanian, J., &amp; Bouhassira, D. (2011). The specific disease burden of neuropathic pain: Results of a French nationwide survey. Pain, 152, 2836-2843. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pain.2011.09.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balshem, H., Helfand, M., Schünemann, H. J., Oxman, A. D., Kunz, R., Brozek, J., Vist, G. E., Falck-Ytter, Y., Meerpohl, J., Norris, S., &amp; Guyatt, G. H. (2011). GRADE guidelines: 3. Rating the quality of evidence. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 64, 401-406. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.07.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bendtsen, L., Zakrzewska, J. M., Abbott, J., Braschinsky, M., Di Stefano, G., Donnet, A., Eide, P. K., Leal, P. R. L., Maarbjerg, S., May, A., Nurmikko, T., Obermann, M., Jensen, T. S., &amp; Cruccu, G. (2019). European Academy of Neurology guideline on trigeminal neuralgia. European Journal of Neurology, 26, 831-849. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.13950</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colloca, L., Ludman, T., Bouhassira, D., Baron, R., Dickenson, A. H., Yarnitsky, D., Freeman, R., Truini, A., Attal, N., Finnerup, N. B., Eccleston, C., Kalso, E., Bennett, D. L., Dworkin, R. H., &amp; Raja, S. N. (2017). Neuropathic pain. Nature Reviews Disease Primers, 3, 17002. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrdp.2017.2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui, M., Khanijou, S., Rubino, J., &amp; Aoki, K. R. (2004). Subcutaneous administration of botulinum toxin A reduces formalin-induced pain. Pain, 107, 125-133. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pain.2003.10.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Heer, E. W., Gerrits, M. M. J. G., Beekman, A. T. F., Dekker, J., van Marwijk, H. W. J., de Waal, M. W. M., Spinhoven, P., Penninx, B. W. J. H., &amp; van der Feltz-Cornelis, C. M. (2014). The association of depression and anxiety with pain: a study from NESDA. PLoS One, 9, e106907.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derry, S., Rice, A. S., Cole, P., Tan, T., &amp; Moore, R. A. (2017). Topical capsaicin (high concentration) for chronic neuropathic pain in adults. Cochrane Database Systematic Review, 1, CD007393.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dressler, D., &amp; Adib Saberi, F. (2005). Botulinum toxin: Mechanisms of action. European Neurology, 53, 3-9. https://doi.org/10.1159/000083259</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egger, M., Smith, G. D., Schneider, M., &amp; Minder, C. (1997). Bias in meta-analysis detected by a simple, graphical test. BMJ, 315, 629-634. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.315.7109.629</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finnerup, N. B., Attal, N., Haroutounian, S., McNicol, E., Baron, R., Dworkin, R. H., Gilron, I., Haanpää, M., Hansson, P., Jensen, T. S., Kamerman, P. R., Lund, K., Moore, A., Raja, S. N., Rice, A. S. C., Rowbotham, M., Sena, E., Siddall, P., Smith, B. H., &amp; Wallace, M. (2015). Pharmacotherapy for neuropathic pain in adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis. The Lancet Neurology, 14, 162-173. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(14)70251-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finnerup, N. B., Haroutounian, S., Kamerman, P., Baron, R., Bennett, D. L. H., Bouhassira, D., Cruccu, G., Freeman, R., Hansson, P., Nurmikko, T., Raja, S. N., Rice, A. S. C., Serra, J., Smith, B. H., Treede, R.-D., &amp; Jensen, T. S. (2016). Neuropathic pain: an updated grading system for research and clinical practice. Pain, 157, 1599-1606. https://doi.org/10.1097/j.pain.0000000000000492</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi, M., Ansari, M., Basiri, K., &amp; Shaigannejad, V. (2014). The effects of intradermal botulinum toxin type A injections on pain symptoms of patients with diabetic neuropathy. Journal of Research in Medical Sciences, 19, 106-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hozo, S. P., Djulbegovic, B., &amp; Hozo, I. (2005). Estimating the mean and variance from the median, range, and the size of a sample. BMC Medical Research Methodology, 5, 13. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2288-5-13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lakhan, S. E., Velasco, D. N., &amp; Tepper, D. (2015). Botulinum toxin-A for painful diabetic neuropathy: A meta-analysis. Pain Medicine, 16, 1773-1780. https://doi.org/10.1111/pme.12728</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langley, P. C., Van Litsenburg, C., Cappelleri, J. C., &amp; Carroll, D. (2013). The burden associated with neuropathic pain in Western Europe. Journal of Medical Economics, 16, 85-95. https://doi.org/10.3111/13696998.2012.729548</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Man-Son-Hing, M., Laupacis, A., O’Rourke, K., Molnar, F. J., Mahon, J., Chan, K. B. Y., &amp; Wells, G. (2002). Determination of the clinical importance of study results. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 17, 469-476. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1525-1497.2002.11111.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matak, I., Bölcskei, K., Bach-Rojecky, L., &amp; Helyes, Z. (2019). Mechanisms of botulinum toxin type A action on pain. Toxins, 11, 459. https://doi.org/10.3390/toxins11080459</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng, F., Peng, K., Yang, J.-P., Ji, F.-H., Xia, F., &amp; Meng, X.-W. (2018). Botulinum toxin-A for the treatment of neuralgia: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Pain Research, 11, 2343-2351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng, J., Wang, J., Lawrence, G., &amp; Dolly, J. O. (2007). Synaptobrevin I mediates exocytosis of CGRP from sensory neurons and inhibition by botulinum toxins reflects their anti-nociceptive potential. Journal of Cell Science, 120, 2864-2874. https://doi.org/10.1242/jcs.012211</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moisset, X., Bouhassira, D., Avez Couturier, J., Alchaar, H., Conradi, S., Delmotte, M. H., Lanteri-Minet, M., Lefaucheur, J. P., Mick, G., Piano, V., Pickering, G., Piquet, E., Regis, C., Salvat, E., &amp; Attal, N. (2020). Pharmacological and non-pharmacological treatments for neuropathic pain: Systematic review and French recommendations. Revue Neurologique, 176, 325-352. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neurol.2020.01.361</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moon, J.-Y., Lee, P.-B., Kim, Y.-C., Lee, S.-C., Nahm, F. S., &amp; Choi, E. (2017). Efficacy and safety of 0.625% and 1.25% capsaicin patch in peripheral neuropathic pain: Multi-center, randomized, and semi-double blind controlled study. Pain Physician, 20, 27-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page, M. J., McKenzie, J. E., Bossuyt, P. M., Boutron, I., Hoffmann, T. C., Mulrow, C. D., Shamseer, L., Tetzlaff, J. M., Akl, E. A., Brennan, S. E., Chou, R., Glanville, J., Grimshaw, J. M., Hróbjartsson, A., Lalu, M. M., Li, T., Loder, E. W., Mayo-Wilson, E., McDonald, S., … Moher, D. (2021). The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ, 372, n71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranoux, D., Attal, N., Morain, F., &amp; Bouhassira, D. (2008). Botulinum toxin type A induces direct analgesic effects in chronic neuropathic pain. Annals of Neurology, 64, 274-283. https://doi.org/10.1002/ana.21427</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salaffi, F., Stancati, A., Silvestri, C. A., Ciapetti, A., &amp; Grassi, W. (2004). Minimal clinically important changes in chronic musculoskeletal pain intensity measured on a numerical rating scale. European Journal of Pain, 8, 283-291. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejpain.2003.09.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salehi, H., Moussaei, M., Kamiab, Z., &amp; Vakilian, A. (2019). The effects of botulinum toxin type A injection on pain symptoms, quality of life, and sleep quality of patients with diabetic neuropathy: A randomized double-blind clinical trial. Iranian Journal of Neurology, 18, 99-107. https://doi.org/10.18502/ijnl.v18i3.1632</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scaglione, F. (2016). Conversion ratio between Botox®, Dysport®, and Xeomin® in clinical practice. Toxins (Basel), 8, E65. https://doi.org/10.3390/toxins8030065</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shackleton, T., Ram, S., Black, M., Ryder, J., Clark, G. T., &amp; Enciso, R. (2016). The efficacy of botulinum toxin for the treatment of trigeminal and postherpetic neuralgia: A systematic review with meta-analyses. Oral Surgery, Oral Medicine, Oral Pathology and Oral Radiology, 122, 61-71. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oooo.2016.03.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin, M.-C., Wakita, M., Xie, D.-J., Yamaga, T., Iwata, S., Torii, Y., Harakawa, T., Ginnaga, A., Kozaki, S., &amp; Akaike, N. (2012). Inhibition of membrane Na+ channels by A type botulinum toxin at femtomolar concentrations in central and peripheral neurons. Journal of Pharmacological Sciences, 118, 33-42. https://doi.org/10.1254/jphs.11060FP</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson, D. M., Robinson-Papp, J., Van, J., Stoker, M., Jacobs, H., Snijder, R. J., Schregardus, D. S., Long, S. K., Lambourg, B., &amp; Katz, N. (2017). Capsaicin 8% patch in painful diabetic peripheral neuropathy: A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. The Journal of Pain, 18, 42-53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpain.2016.09.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Small, R. (2014). Botulinum toxin injection for facial wrinkles. American Family Physician, 90, 168-175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun, L.-C., Chen, R., Fu, C., Chen, Y., Wu, Q., Chen, R., Lin, X., &amp; Luo, S. (2019). Efficacy and safety of botulinum toxin type A for limb spasticity after stroke: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. BioMed Research International, 2019, 8329306. https://doi.org/10.1155/2019/8329306</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taheri, M., Sedaghat, M., Solhpour, A., Rostami, P., &amp; Safarpour Lima, B. (2020). The effect of intradermal botulinum toxin A injections on painful diabetic polyneuropathy. Diabetes &amp; Metabolic Syndrome, 14, 1823-1828. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dsx.2020.09.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hecke, O., Austin, S. K., Khan, R. A., Smith, B. H., &amp; Torrance, N. (2014). Neuropathic pain in the general population: A systematic review of epidemiological studies. Pain, 155, 654-662. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pain.2013.11.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei, J., Zhu, X., Yang, G., Shen, J., Xie, P., Zuo, X., Xia, L., Han, Q., &amp; Zhao, Y. (2019). The efficacy and safety of botulinum toxin type A in treatment of trigeminal neuralgia and peripheral neuropathic pain: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Brain and Behavior, 9, e01409. https://doi.org/10.1002/brb3.1409</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wissel, J., Fheodoroff, K., Hoonhorst, M., Müngersdorf, M., Gallien, P., Meier, N., Hamacher, J., Hefter, H., Maisonobe, P., &amp; Koch, M. (2020). Effectiveness of abobotulinumtoxina in post-stroke upper limb spasticity in relation to timing of treatment. Frontiers in Neurology, 11, 104. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2020.00104</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao, L., Mackey, S., Hui, H., Xong, D., Zhang, Q., &amp; Zhang, D. (2010). Subcutaneous injection of botulinum toxin a is beneficial in postherpetic neuralgia. Pain Medicine, 11, 1827-1833. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1526-4637.2010.01003.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yiannakopoulou, E. (2015). Serious and long-term adverse events associated with the therapeutic and cosmetic use of botulinum toxin. Pharmacology, 95, 65-69. https://doi.org/10.1159/000370245</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan, R. Y., Sheu, J. J., Yu, J. M., Chen, W. T., Tseng, I. J., Chang, H. H., &amp; Hu, C. J. (2009). Botulinum toxin for diabetic neuropathic pain: A randomized double-blind crossover trial. Neurology, 72, 1473-1478. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000345968.05959.cf</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
