<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35293153</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0496</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>57</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pediatric pulmonology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Pulmonol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>High-flow nasal cannula oxygen in children with bronchiolitis: A randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1527</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1534</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1527-1534</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ppul.25893</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine whether high-flow nasal cannula oxygen (HFNCO) provided enhanced respiratory support in bronchiolitis than low-flow oxygen (LFO).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a prospective, randomized controlled trial in children between 1 and 24 months diagnosed with moderate-to-severe bronchiolitis requiring oxygen therapy. Participants received LFO via face mask (6-10 L/min) or HFNCO (2 L/kg/min). Primary outcomes were the time that heart rate (HR) and respiratory rate (RR) return to their normal range for age and the time that baseline clinical respiratory score (CRS) regress to a lower severity score. Secondary outcomes were changes in HR, RR, and CRS over time, length of stay (LOS), duration of oxygen requirement, treatment failure, and adverse event (AE).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty-seven children were enrolled (48 in LFO; 39 in HFNCO). The time that HR and RR baseline values reached their normal range for age was shorter in HFNCO therapy (2.0 h [1.0-4.0] vs. 12.0 h [2.0-24.0], and 4.0 h [2.0-12.0] vs. 24.0 h [4.0-48.0], respectively; p &lt; 0.001); additionally, the improvement in CRS emerged more quickly in children treated with HFNCO (2.0 h [1.0-4.0] vs. 4.0 h [2.0-24.0]; p = 0.003). While the duration of oxygen requirement (19.0 h [4.0-30.0] vs. 29.5 h [14.0-45.7]; p = 0.009) and treatment failure (3% vs. 21%) was statistically lower in children who received HFNCO, there were no differences in LOS and AE between groups.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">HFNCO may provide enhanced respiratory support with a notable improvement in HR, RR, and CRS than LFO. Comprehensive studies are needed to assess the clinical efficacy of HFNCO therapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eşki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aykut</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5378-5663</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Department of Pediatrics, Gazi Yaşargil Gynecology, Child Health, and Diseases Training and Research Hospital, University of Health Sciences, Diyarbakır, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Öztürk</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gökçen Kartal</ForeName>
            <Initials>GK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0793-9710</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Department of Pediatrics, Ege University Medical Faculty, Ege University Children Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Turan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Caner</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9469-5162</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Emergency Medicine, Department of Pediatrics, Ege University Medical Faculty, Ege University Children Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Özgül</LastName>
            <ForeName>Semiha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Informatics, School of Medicine, Ege University, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gülen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Figen</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Department of Pediatrics, Ege University Medical Faculty, Ege University Children Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Demir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Esen</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Pulmonology, Department of Pediatrics, Ege University Medical Faculty, Ege University Children Hospital, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Pulmonol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8510590</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1099-0496</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>S88TT14065</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010100">Oxygen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001988" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bronchiolitis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000072601" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cannula</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010100" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010102" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen Inhalation Therapy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bronchiolitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical respiratory score</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-flow nasal cannula oxygen</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoxia</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293153</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ppul.25893</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florin TA, Plint AC, Zorc JJ. Viral bronchiolitis. Lancet. 2017;389(10065):211-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall CB, Weinberg GA, Blumkin AK, et al. Respiratory syncytial virus-associated hospitalizations among children less than 24 months of age. Pediatrics. 2013;132:2-e348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall CB, Weinberg GA, Iwane MK, et al. The Burden of respiratory syncytial virus infection in young children. N Engl J Med. 2009;360(6):588-598.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stockman LJ, Curns AT, Anderson LJ, Fischer-Langley G. Respiratory syncytial virus-associated hospitalizations among infants and young children in the United States, 1997-2006. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31(1):5-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain S, Williams DJ, Arnold SR, et al. Community-acquired pneumonia requiring hospitalization among U.S. children. N Engl J Med. 2015;372(9):835-845.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasegawa K, Tsugawa Y, Brown DFM, Mansbach JM, Camargo CA. Trends in bronchiolitis hospitalizations in the United States, 2000-2009. Pediatrics. 2013;132(1):28-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlapbach LJ, Straney L, Gelbart B, et al. Burden of disease and change in practice in critically ill infants with bronchiolitis. Eur Respir J. 2017;49:6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meissner HC. Viral bronchiolitis in children. N Engl J Med. 2016;374(1):62-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hough JL, Pham TMT, Schibler A. Physiologic effect of high-flow nasal cannula in infants with bronchiolitis. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2014;15:5-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schibler A, Pham TMT, Dunster KR, et al. Reduced intubation rates for infants after introduction of high-flow nasal prong oxygen delivery. Intensive Care Med. 2011;37(5):847-852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milani GP, Plebani AM, Arturi E, et al. Using a high-flow nasal cannula provided superior results to low-flow oxygen delivery in moderate to severe bronchiolitis. Acta Paediatr. 2016;105:e368-e372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franklin D, Babl FE, Schlapbach LJ, et al. A randomized trial of high-flow oxygen therapy in infants with bronchiolitis. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(12):1121-1131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kepreotes E, Whitehead B, Attia J, et al. High-flow warm humidified oxygen versus standard low-flow nasal cannula oxygen for moderate bronchiolitis (HFWHO RCT): an open, phase 4, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2017;389(10072):930-939.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen DY, Zee ED, Gildengorin G, Fong EW. A pilot study of heated and humidified low flow oxygen therapy: An assessment in infants with mild and moderate bronchiolitis (HHOT AIR study). Pediatr Pulmonol. 2019;54(5):620-627.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballestero Y, De Pedro J, Portillo N, Martinez-Mugica O, Arana-Arri E, Benito J. Pilot Clinical Trial of High-Flow Oxygen Therapy in Children with Asthma in the Emergency Service. J Pediatr. 2018;194:204-210.e3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beggs S, Wong ZH, Kaul S, Ogden KJ, Walters JAE. High-flow nasal cannula therapy for infants with bronchiolitis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;2014:1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ralston SL, Lieberthal AS, Meissner HC, et al. Clinical practice guideline: The diagnosis, management, and prevention of bronchiolitis. Pediatrics. 2014;134(5):e1474-e1502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Hopewell S, Schulz KF, et al. CONSORT 2010 explanation and elaboration: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. BMJ. 2010;340:340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu LL, Gallaher MM, Davis RL, Rutter CM, Lewis TC, Marcuse EK. Use of a respiratory clinical score among different providers. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2004;37(3):243-248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daymont C, Bonafide CP, Brady PW. Heart rates in hospitalized children by age and body temperature. Pediatrics. 2015;135(5):e1173-e1181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nijman RG, Thompson M, Van Veen M, Perera R, Moll HA, Oostenbrink R. Derivation and validation of age and temperature specific reference values and centile charts to predict lower respiratory tract infection in children with fever: prospective observational study. BMJ. 2012;345(7867):1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis PD The Essential Guide to Effect Sizes. The Essential Guide to Effect Sizes 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Field A. Discovering Statistics using IBM SPSS Statistics-Cluster. Analysis. 2013:297-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schibler A, Franklin D. Respiratory support for children in the emergency department. J Paediatr Child Health. 2016;52(2):192-196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pham TMT, O'Malley L, Mayfield S, Martin S, Schibler A. The effect of high flow nasal cannula therapy on the work of breathing in infants with bronchiolitis. Pediatr Pulmonol. 2015;50(7):713-720.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilliard TN, Archer N, Laura H, et al. Pilot study of vapotherm oxygen delivery in moderately severe bronchiolitis. Arch Dis Child. 2012;97(2):182-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ergul AB, Calıskan E, Samsa H, et al. Using a high-flow nasal cannula provides superior results to OxyMask delivery in moderate to severe bronchiolitis: a randomized controlled study. Eur J Pediatr. 2018;177(8):1299-1307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasani A, Chapman TH, McCool D, Smith RE, Dilworth JP, Agnew JE. Domiciliary humidification improves lung mucociliary clearance in patients with bronchiectasis. Chron Respir Dis. 2008;5(2):81-86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegde S, Prodhan P. Serious air leak syndrome complicating high-flow nasal cannula therapy: a report of 3 cases. Pediatrics. 2013;131:3-e944.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
