<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35293977</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-6084</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>158</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>JAMA dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Systemic Immunomodulatory Treatments for Atopic Dermatitis: Update of a Living Systematic Review and Network Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>523</StartPage>
          <EndPage>532</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>523-532</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamadermatol.2022.0455</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">Systemic treatments for atopic dermatitis are being evaluated primarily in placebo-controlled trials; network meta-analysis can provide relative efficacy and safety estimates for treatments that have not been compared head to head.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To compare reported measures of efficacy and assessments of safety in clinical trials of systemic treatments for atopic dermatitis in a living systematic review and network meta-analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES">The Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, MEDLINE, Embase, Latin American and Caribbean Health Science Information database, Global Resource of EczemA Trials database, and trial registries were searched through June 15, 2021.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="STUDY SELECTION">Randomized clinical trials examining 8 or more weeks of treatment with systemic immunomodulatory medications for moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis were included after screening titles, abstracts, and papers in duplicate.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA EXTRACTION AND SYNTHESIS">Data were abstracted in duplicate. Bayesian network meta-analyses and assessed Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation certainty of evidence were performed. The updated analysis was completed from June to December 2021.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES">Outcomes include change in Eczema Area and Severity Index (EASI), Patient Oriented Eczema Measure (POEM), Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI), and Peak Pruritus Numeric Rating Scales (PP-NRS).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Since October 2019, 21 new studies were added, for a total of 60 trials with 16 579 patients. Up to 16 weeks of treatment in adults, abrocitinib, 200 mg daily (mean difference [MD], 2.2; 95% credible interval [CrI], 0.2-4.0; high certainty) and upadacitinib, 30 mg daily (MD, 2.7; 95% CrI, 0.6-4.7; high certainty) were associated with reduced EASI slightly more than dupilumab, 600 mg then 300 mg every 2 weeks. Abrocitinib, 100 mg daily (MD, -2.1; 95% CrI, -4.1 to -0.3; high certainty), baricitinib, 4 mg daily (MD, -3.2; 95% CrI, -5.7 to -0.8; high certainty), baricitinib, 2 mg daily (MD, -5.2; 95% CrI, -7.5 to -2.9; high certainty) and tralokinumab, 600 mg then 300 mg every 2 weeks (MD, -3.5; 95% CrI, -5.8 to -1.3; high certainty) were associated with reduced EASI slightly less than dupilumab. There was little or no difference between upadacitinib, 15 mg daily, and dupilumab (MD, 0.2; 95% CrI, -1.9 to 2.2; high certainty). The pattern of results was similar for POEM, DLQI, and PP-NRS.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">In this systematic review and meta-analysis, abrocitinib, 200 mg; and upadacitinib, 30 mg daily, were associated with slightly better scores than dupilumab, and upadacitinib, 15 mg daily, was associated with similar scores to dupilumab. Abrocitinib, 100 mg daily, baricitinib, 4 mg and 2 mg daily, and tralokinumab, 300 mg, every 2 weeks were associated with slightly worse scores.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Drucker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aaron M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Women's College Research Institute, Women's College Hospital, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deanna E</ForeName>
            <Initials>DE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prieto-Merino</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unit for Population-Based Dermatology Research, St John's Institute of Dermatology, King's College London and Guy's and St Thomas' Hospital, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ellis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexandra G</ForeName>
            <Initials>AG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Brown University, Providence, Rhode Island.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yiu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zenas Z N</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZZN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Centre, Salford Royal NHS Foundation Trust, The University of Manchester, Manchester Academic Health Science Centre, NIHR Manchester Biomedical Research Centre, Manchester, United Kingodm.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rochwerg</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bram</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Medicine and Health Research Methods, Evidence and Impact, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Di Giorgio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sonya</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Libraries &amp; Collections, King's College London, London, United Kingodm.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arents</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bernd W M</ForeName>
            <Initials>BWM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dutch Association for People with Atopic Dermatitis (VMCE), Nijkerk, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Burton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tim</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Patient Representative (independent), Nottingham, United Kingodm.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spuls</LastName>
            <ForeName>Phyllis I</ForeName>
            <Initials>PI</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Amsterdam Public Health/Infection and Immunology, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schmitt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jochen</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Evidence-Based Healthcare, Faculty of Medicine Carl Gustav Carus, Technische Universität (TU) Dresden, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Flohr</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carsten</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unit for Population-Based Dermatology Research, St John's Institute of Dermatology, King's College London and Guy's and St Thomas' Hospital, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>JAMA Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101589530</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2168-6068</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatitis, Atopic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004485" MajorTopicYN="Y">Eczema</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000071076" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Meta-Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011537" MajorTopicYN="N">Pruritus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> The authors declare no potential conflicts of interest involving the work under consideration for publication. Dr Drucker has received compensation from the <i>British Journal of Dermatology</i> (reviewer and Section Editor), American Academy of Dermatology (guidelines writer), and National Eczema Association (grant reviewer). He has been a paid consultant for the Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technology in Health. Dr Ellis is an employee of Stratevi, LLC, a healthcare consultancy that receives financial compensation from numerous pharmaceutical companies; Stratevi had no involvement with the submitted work. Dr Spuls has done consultancies in the past for Sanofi (111017) and AbbVie (041217) (unpaid), was principal investigator of the MAcAD RCTs (Schram et al, JACI 2011, Roekevisch et al, JACI 2018, Gerbens et al, BJD 2018), receives departmental independent research grants for TREAT NL registry, for which she is chief investigator, from pharma companies since December 2019, is involved in performing clinical trials with many pharmaceutical industries that manufacture drugs used for the treatment of skin conditions such as psoriasis and atopic dermatitis, for which financial compensation is paid to the department/hospital. Dr Schmitt received institutional funding for investigator-initiated trials from Novartis, Sanofi, Pfizer, ALK. He received fees for consulting from Novartis and Pfizer. He is co-principal investigatorof the German National Atopic Dermatitis Registry TREAT germany, which is funded by Sanofi Aventis Deutschland GmbH, Galderma SA, LEO Pharma GmbH, and Lilly Deutschland GmbH. Dr Flohr is Chief Investigator of the UK National Institute for Health Research-funded TREAT (ISRCTN15837754) and SOFTER (Clinicaltrials.gov: NCT03270566) trials as well as the UK-Irish Atopic eczema Systemic Therapy Register (A-STAR; ISRCTN11210918), and a principal investigator in the European Union (EU) Horizon 2020-funded BIOMAP Consortium (http://www.biomap-imi.eu/). He also leads the EU Trans-Foods consortium. His department has received funding from Sanofi-Genzyme for skin microbiome work. No other conflicts were reported.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35293977</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8928094</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2022.0455</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">2790388</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drucker AM, Ellis AG, Bohdanowicz M, et al. . Systemic immunomodulatory treatments for patients with atopic dermatitis: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156(6):659-667. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.0796</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.0796</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7177646</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yosipovitch G, Reaney M, Mastey V, et al. . Peak Pruritus Numerical Rating Scale: psychometric validation and responder definition for assessing itch in moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis. Br J Dermatol. 2019;181(4):761-769. doi:10.1111/bjd.17744</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.17744</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6850643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30729499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drucker AM, Ellis A, Jabbar-Lopez Z, et al. . Systemic immunomodulatory treatments for atopic dermatitis: protocol for a systematic review with network meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8(8):e023061. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2018-023061</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-023061</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6119412</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30158235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt J, Spuls PI, Thomas KS, et al. ; HOME initiative collaborators . The Harmonising Outcome Measures for Eczema (HOME) statement to assess clinical signs of atopic eczema in trials. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2014;134(4):800-807. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2014.07.043</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2014.07.043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25282560</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schram ME, Spuls PI, Leeflang MM, Lindeboom R, Bos JD, Schmitt J. EASI, (objective) SCORAD and POEM for atopic eczema: responsiveness and minimal clinically important difference. Allergy. 2012;67(1):99-106. doi:10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02719.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02719.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spuls PI, Gerbens LAA, Simpson E, et al. ; HOME initiative collaborators . Patient-Oriented Eczema Measure (POEM), a core instrument to measure symptoms in clinical trials: a Harmonising Outcome Measures for Eczema (HOME) statement. Br J Dermatol. 2017;176(4):979-984. doi:10.1111/bjd.15179</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.15179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27858989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finlay AY, Khan GK. Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)—a simple practical measure for routine clinical use. Clin Exp Dermatol. 1994;19(3):210-216. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8033378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basra MK, Salek MS, Camilleri L, Sturkey R, Finlay AY. Determining the minimal clinically important difference and responsiveness of the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI): further data. Dermatology. 2015;230(1):27-33. doi:10.1159/000365390</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000365390</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25613671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt J, Apfelbacher C, Spuls PI, et al. . The Harmonizing Outcome Measures for Eczema (HOME) roadmap: a methodological framework to develop core sets of outcome measurements in dermatology. J Invest Dermatol. 2015;135(1):24-30. doi:10.1038/jid.2014.320</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jid.2014.320</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25186228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins J, Thomas J, Chandler J. Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Version 6.0 Cochrane, 2019. In:2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell M, Muftakhidinov B, Winchen T. Engauge Digitizer Software. Published 2019. Accessed June 18, 2020. http://markummitchell.github.io/engauge-digitizer. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Network Meta-Analysis Using Bayesian Methods . R package [computer program]. Version 0.8-22016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidbury R, Davis DM, Cohen DE, et al. ; American Academy of Dermatology . Guidelines of care for the management of atopic dermatitis: section 3. Management and treatment with phototherapy and systemic agents. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2014;71(2):327-349. doi:10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.030</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410179</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24813298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner RM, Jackson D, Wei Y, Thompson SG, Higgins JP. Predictive distributions for between-study heterogeneity and simple methods for their application in Bayesian meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2015;34(6):984-998. doi:10.1002/sim.6381</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.6381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4383649</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25475839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golder S, Loke YK, Wright K, Norman G. Reporting of adverse events in published and unpublished studies of health care interventions: a systematic review. PLoS medicine. 2016;13(9):e1002127.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5029817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27649528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Sinclair R, Forman S, et al. . Efficacy and safety of abrocitinib in adults and adolescents with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (JADE MONO-1): a multicentre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2020;396(10246):255-266. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30732-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30732-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guttman-Yassky E, Teixeira HD, Simpson EL, et al. . Once-daily upadacitinib versus placebo in adolescents and adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (Measure Up 1 and Measure Up 2): results from two replicate double-blind, randomised controlled phase 3 trials. Lancet. 2021;397(10290):2151-2168. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00588-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00588-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reich K, Teixeira HD, de Bruin-Weller M, et al. . Safety and efficacy of upadacitinib in combination with topical corticosteroids in adolescents and adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (AD Up): results from a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;397(10290):2169-2181. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00589-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00589-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meggitt SJ, Gray JC, Reynolds NJ. Azathioprine dosed by thiopurine methyltransferase activity for moderate-to-severe atopic eczema: a double-blind, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2006;367(9513):839-846. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(06)68340-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(06)68340-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16530578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schram ME, Roekevisch E, Leeflang MM, Bos JD, Schmitt J, Spuls PI. A randomized trial of methotrexate versus azathioprine for severe atopic eczema. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2011;128(2):353-359. doi:10.1016/j.jaci.2011.03.024</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2011.03.024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21514637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berth-Jones J, Takwale A, Tan E, et al. . Azathioprine in severe adult atopic dermatitis: a double-blind, placebo-controlled, crossover trial. Br J Dermatol. 2002;147(2):324-330. doi:10.1046/j.1365-2133.2002.04989.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2133.2002.04989.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12174106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goujon C, Viguier M, Staumont-Sallé D, et al. . Methotrexate versus cyclosporine in adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: a phase III randomized noninferiority trial. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2018;6(2):562-569.e3. doi:10.1016/j.jaip.2017.07.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2017.07.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28967549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czech W, Bräutigam M, Weidinger G, Schöpf E. A body-weight-independent dosing regimen of cyclosporine microemulsion is effective in severe atopic dermatitis and improves the quality of life. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2000;42(4):653-659.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10727313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacor ML, Di Lorenzo G, Martinelli N, Mansueto P, Rini GB, Corrocher R. Comparing tacrolimus ointment and oral cyclosporine in adult patients affected by atopic dermatitis: a randomized study. Clin Exp Allergy. 2004;34(4):639-645. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2222.2004.1907.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2222.2004.1907.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15080819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bemanian MH, Movahedi M, Farhoudi A, et al. . High doses intravenous immunoglobulin versus oral cyclosporine in the treatment of severe atopic dermatitis. Iran J Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2005;4(3):139-143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17301437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granlund H, Erkko P, Remitz A, et al. . Comparison of cyclosporin and UVAB phototherapy for intermittent one-year treatment of atopic dermatitis. Acta Derm Venereol. 2001;81(1):22-27. doi:10.1080/000155501750208137</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/000155501750208137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11411908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munro CS, Levell NJ, Shuster S, Friedmann PS. Maintenance treatment with cyclosporin in atopic eczema. Br J Dermatol. 1994;130(3):376-380. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2133.1994.tb02936.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.1994.tb02936.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8148281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sowden JM, Berth-Jones J, Ross JS, et al. . Double-blind, controlled, crossover study of cyclosporin in adults with severe refractory atopic dermatitis. Lancet. 1991;338(8760):137-140. doi:10.1016/0140-6736(91)90134-B</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0140-6736(91)90134-B</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1677063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Caldwell DM, Ades AE. Checking consistency in mixed treatment comparison meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2010;29(7-8):932-944. doi:10.1002/sim.3767</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.3767</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20213715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salanti G, Ades AE, Ioannidis JP. Graphical methods and numerical summaries for presenting results from multiple-treatment meta-analysis: an overview and tutorial. J Clin Epidemiol. 2011;64(2):163-171. doi:10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.03.016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.03.016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20688472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, Gøtzsche PC, et al. ; Cochrane Bias Methods Group; Cochrane Statistical Methods Group . The Cochrane Collaboration’s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928. doi:10.1136/bmj.d5928</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.d5928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brignardello-Petersen R, Bonner A, Alexander PE, et al. ; GRADE Working Group . Advances in the GRADE approach to rate the certainty in estimates from a network meta-analysis. J Clin Epidemiol. 2018;93:36-44. doi:10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.10.005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2017.10.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051107</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puhan MA, Schünemann HJ, Murad MH, et al. ; GRADE Working Group . A GRADE Working Group approach for rating the quality of treatment effect estimates from network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2014;349:g5630. doi:10.1136/bmj.g5630</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g5630</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25252733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santesso N, Glenton C, Dahm P, et al. ; GRADE Working Group . GRADE guidelines 26: informative statements to communicate the findings of systematic reviews of interventions. J Clin Epidemiol. 2020;119:126-135. doi:10.1016/j.jclinepi.2019.10.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2019.10.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutton B, Salanti G, Caldwell DM, et al. . The PRISMA extension statement for reporting of systematic reviews incorporating network meta-analyses of health care interventions: checklist and explanations. Ann Intern Med. 2015;162(11):777-784. doi:10.7326/M14-2385</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M14-2385</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan S, Cornelius V, Cro S, Harper JI, Lack G. Treatment effect of omalizumab on severe pediatric atopic dermatitis: the ADAPT Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Pediatr. 2020;174(1):29-37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902112</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31764962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfizer. JAK1 Inhibitor With Medicated Topical Therapy in Adolescents With Atopic Dermatitis (JADE TEEN). Accessed June 25, 2021. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03796676</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfizer. Study Evaluating Efficacy and Safety of PF-04965842 and Dupilumab in Adult Subjects With Moderate to Severe Atopic Dermatitis on Background Topical Therapy (JADE Compare). Accessed March 1, 2021. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03720470</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Simpson EL, Thyssen JP, et al. . Efficacy and safety of abrocitinib in patients with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156(8):863-873. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.1406</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.1406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Lacour JP, Spelman L, et al. . Baricitinib in patients with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis and inadequate response to topical corticosteroids: results from two randomized monotherapy phase III trials. Br J Dermatol. 2020;183(2):242-255. doi:10.1111/bjd.18898</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.18898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31995838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reich K, Kabashima K, Peris K, et al. . Efficacy and safety of baricitinib combined with topical corticosteroids for treatment of moderate to severe atopic dermatitis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156(12):1333-1343. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.3260</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.3260</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7527941</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson EL, Forman S, Silverberg JI, et al. . Baricitinib in patients with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: Results from a randomized monotherapy phase 3 trial in the United States and Canada (BREEZE-AD5). J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;85(1):62-70. doi:10.1016/j.jaad.2021.02.028</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2021.02.028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33600915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Co ELa . A Long-term Study of Baricitinib (LY3009104) With Topical Corticosteroids in Adults With Moderate to Severe Atopic Dermatitis That Are Not Controlled With Cyclosporine or for Those Who Cannot Take Oral Cyclosporine Because it is Not Medically Advisable (BREEZE-AD4). Accessed March 1, 2021. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03428100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paller AS, Siegfried EC, Thaçi D, et al. . Efficacy and safety of dupilumab with concomitant topical corticosteroids in children 6 to 11 years old with severe atopic dermatitis: A randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83(5):1282-1293. doi:10.1016/j.jaad.2020.06.054</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.06.054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32574587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanofi. Evaluation of Dupilumab in Chinese Adult Patients With Moderate to Severe Atopic Dermatitis. Accessed June 23, 2021. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03912259</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guttman-Yassky E, Blauvelt A, Eichenfield LF, et al. . Efficacy and safety of lebrikizumab, a high-affinity interleukin 13 inhibitor, in adults with moderate to severe atopic dermatitis: a phase 2b randomized clinical trial. JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156(4):411-420. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.0079</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.0079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7142380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kabashima K, Matsumura T, Komazaki H, Kawashima M; Nemolizumab-JP01 Study Group . Trial of nemolizumab and topical agents for atopic dermatitis with pruritus. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(2):141-150. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1917006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1917006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32640132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Toth D, Bieber T, et al. ; ECZTRA 3 study investigators . Tralokinumab plus topical corticosteroids for the treatment of moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: results from the double-blind, randomized, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase III ECZTRA 3 trial. Br J Dermatol. 2021;184(3):450-463. doi:10.1111/bjd.19573</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.19573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33000503</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wollenberg A, Blauvelt A, Guttman-Yassky E, et al. ; ECZTRA 1 and ECZTRA 2 study investigators . Tralokinumab for moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: results from two 52-week, randomized, double-blind, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase III trials (ECZTRA 1 and ECZTRA 2). Br J Dermatol. 2021;184(3):437-449. doi:10.1111/bjd.19574</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.19574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986411</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33000465</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merola JF, Bagel J, Almgren P, et al. . Tralokinumab does not impact vaccine-induced immune responses: Results from a 30-week, randomized, placebo-controlled trial in adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;85(1):71-78. doi:10.1016/j.jaad.2021.03.032</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2021.03.032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bieber T, Simpson EL, Silverberg JI, et al. ; JADE COMPARE Investigators . Abrocitinib versus placebo or dupilumab for atopic dermatitis. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(12):1101-1112. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2019380</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2019380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33761207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blauvelt A, Teixeira HD, Simpson EL, et al. . Efficacy and safety of upadacitinib vs dupilumab in adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Dermatol. 2021;157(9):1047-1055. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.3023</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.3023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8340015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Afach S, Chaimani A, Evrenoglou T, et al. . Meta-analysis results do not reflect the real safety of biologics in psoriasis. Br J Dermatol. 2021;184(3):415-424. doi:10.1111/bjd.19244</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.19244</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32446286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleming P, Drucker AM. Risk of infection in patients with atopic dermatitis treated with dupilumab: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018;78(1):62-69.e1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28987493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawangjit R, Dilokthornsakul P, Lloyd-Lavery A, Lai NM, Dellavalle R, Chaiyakunapruk N. Systemic treatments for eczema: a network meta-analysis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;9:CD013206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8128359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32927498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Thyssen JP, Fahrbach K, et al. . Comparative efficacy and safety of systemic therapies used in moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: a systematic literature review and network meta-analysis. JEADV. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senn SJPotISI . 55th Session, Sydney. Dichotomania: an obsessive compulsive disorder that is badly affecting the quality of analysis of pharmaceutical trials. 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverberg JI, Simpson EL, Ardeleanu M, et al. . Dupilumab provides important clinical benefits to patients with atopic dermatitis who do not achieve clear or almost clear skin according to the Investigator’s Global Assessment: a pooled analysis of data from two phase III trials. Br J Dermatol. 2019;181(1):80-87. doi:10.1111/bjd.17791</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.17791</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6849829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30791102</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leshem YA, Bissonnette R, Paul C, et al. . Optimization of placebo use in clinical trials with systemic treatments for atopic dermatitis: an International Eczema Council survey-based position statement. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2019;33(5):807-815. doi:10.1111/jdv.15480</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6594032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30859656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam M, Zhu JW, Maqbool T, et al. . Inclusion of older adults in randomized clinical trials for systemic medications for atopic dermatitis: a systematic review. JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156(11):1240-1245. doi:10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.2940</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2020.2940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32822481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
