<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35292610</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-3694</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>44</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Therapeutic drug monitoring</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ther Drug Monit</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Simultaneous Quantification of 11 Antiseizure Medications and Metabolites in Serum for Therapeutic Drug Monitoring Using High-Performance Liquid Chromatography with Ultraviolet Detection: A Short Communication.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>345</StartPage>
          <EndPage>350</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>345-350</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/FTD.0000000000000908</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Therapeutic drug monitoring (TDM) of antiseizure medications (ASMs) is widely used to guide therapy, avoid toxicity, and assess patient compliance. Commercial immunologic quantification methods are common practice; however, as they are only applicable to one specific drug and prone to cross-reacting metabolites, their practical applicability is limited. In this article, the authors proposed a high-performance liquid chromatography method using ultraviolet detection (HPLC-UV) for simultaneous quantification of 11 ASMs and active metabolites (carbamazepine, felbamate, lacosamide, lamotrigine, levetiracetam, phenobarbital, phenytoin, primidone, zonisamide, carbamazepine-10,11-epoxide, and licarbazepine) in serum.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Chromatographic separation was performed on a Phenomenex Luna PFP(2) (3-µm particle size; 150 × 4.6 mm i.d.) analytical column. The mobile phase comprised phosphate buffer (20 mM; pH 3), acetonitrile (ACN), and methanol using gradient elution. Analyses were conducted at 35°C and a 1.3-mL/min flow rate. The detection wavelength for all analytes was 210 nm. The samples were prepared by protein precipitation using ACN.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The HPLC-UV method was validated according to the FDA guidelines and applied to measure patient samples in TDM. Calibration curves showed excellent linearity (r2 &gt; 0.99) and covered the entire reference range for each analyte. Intraday and interday imprecisions and inaccuracies were &lt;10% for all samples. Extensive stability testing showed no significant degradation (&lt;15%), and interference measurements additionally ensured clinical applicability. Furthermore, the sensitivity was comparable with that of previously published HPLC methods using mass spectrometry.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The authors developed an HPLC-UV method for the simultaneous quantification of 11 ASMs in the human serum and demonstrated its practical applicability in TDM. The method requires only standard laboratory equipment and simple sample preparation, making TDM available in less specialized laboratories.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lipecki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yannick</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy and Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany; and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Institute AGATE gGmbH, Pentling, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Haen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ekkehard</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy and Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany; and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Institute AGATE gGmbH, Pentling, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ther Drug Monit</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7909660</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0163-4356</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>33CM23913M</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D002220">Carbamazepine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>6158TKW0C5</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010672">Phenytoin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002220" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbamazepine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002851" MajorTopicYN="N">Chromatography, High Pressure Liquid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016903" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug Monitoring</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010672" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenytoin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>56</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35292610</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/FTD.0000000000000908</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00007691-202204000-00012</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johannessen Landmark C. Targets for antiepileptic drugs in the synapse. Med Sci Monit. 2007;13:1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deckers CLP. Overtreatment in adults with epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 2002;52:43–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patsalos PN, Spencer EP, Berry DJ. Therapeutic drug monitoring of antiepileptic drugs in epilepsy: a 2018 update. Ther Drug Monit. 2018;40:526–548.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neels HM, Sierens AC, Naelaerts K, et al. Therapeutic drug monitoring of old and newer anti-epileptic drugs. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2004;42:1228–1255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shibata M, Hashi S, Nakanishi H, et al. Detection of 22 antiepileptic drugs by ultra-performance liquid chromatography coupled with tandem mass spectrometry applicable to routine therapeutic drug monitoring. Biomed Chromatogr. 2012;26:1519–1528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carlow DC, Shi H, Schofield RC. Simultaneous quantitation of lamotrigine, levetiracetam, 10-hydroxycarbazepine, topiramate, and zonisamide in serum using HPLC-MS/MS. Methods Mol Biol. 2016;1383:29–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budakova L, Brozmanova H, Grundmann M, et al. Simultaneous determination of antiepileptic drugs and their two active metabolites by HPLC. J Sep Sci. 2008;31:1–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Contin M, Mohamed S, Candela C, et al. Simultaneous HPLC-UV analysis of rufinamide, zonisamide, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine monohydroxy derivative and felbamate in deproteinized plasma of patients with epilepsy. J Chromatogr B Analyt Technol Biomed Life Sci. 2010;878:461–465.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA. Bioanalytical Method Validation: Guidance for Industry. US Department of Health and Human Services, Food and Drug Administration, Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER). Silver Spring, MD: Center for Veterinary Medicine (CVM); 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiemke C, Bergemann N, Clement HW, et al. Consensus guidelines for therapeutic drug monitoring in neuropsychopharmacology: update 2017. Pharmacopsychiatry. 2018;51:9–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patsalos PN, Perucca E. Clinically important drug interactions in epilepsy: general features and interactions between antiepileptic drugs. Lancet Neurol. 2003;2:347–356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patsalos PN, Berry DJ, Bourgeois BFD, et al. Antiepileptic drugs-best practice guidelines for therapeutic drug monitoring: a position paper by the subcommission on therapeutic drug monitoring, ILAE Commission on Therapeutic Strategies. Epilepsia. 2008;49:1239–1276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosak M, Słowik A, Iwańska A, et al. Co-medication and potential drug interactions among patients with epilepsy. Seizure. 2019;66:47–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sommerfeld-Klatta K, Zielińska-Psuja B, Karaźniewcz-Łada M, et al. New methods used in pharmacokinetics and therapeutic monitoring of the first and newer generations of antiepileptic drugs (AEDs). Molecules. 2020:25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
