<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35304761</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-1561</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>92</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of school health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Sch Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Classroom Teacher Efficacy Toward Implementation of Physical Activity in the D-SHINES Intervention.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>619</StartPage>
          <EndPage>628</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>619-628</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/josh.13163</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Given levels of sedentary behavior among youth, teachers have been called upon to increase physical activity (PA) by implementing classroom PA breaks. School-based interventions enacted in classroom settings have shown promise in increasing youth PA. Yet little is known about how teacher efficacy toward implementing classroom PA breaks may influence intervention effects.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Therefore, the purpose of this study was to examine how the Dearborn School Health through Integrated Nutrition and Exercise Strategies (D-SHINES) intervention, implemented across 8 schools, influenced classroom teacher's efficacy toward providing classroom PA breaks.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A mixed-methods design examined classroom teachers' efficacy toward implementing classroom PA breaks and used semi-structured interviews to better understand teachers' efficacy and implementation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Quantitative results indicated that teacher efficacy significantly increased over the intervention period and that general and institutional efficacy predicted higher amounts of PA breaks offered. Qualitative results suggested that to enhance teachers' facilitation of classroom PA breaks, one must tap into the institutional, student, and educational factors that constitute teacher efficacy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR SCHOOL HEALTH" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Designing interventions that focus on teacher efficacy toward classroom PA may be a viable way to increase PA breaks in schools. Implications for the whole school, whole community, whole child model are discussed.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 American School Health Association.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barcelona</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeanne M</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6758-7633</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Kinesiology, Health and Sport Science, Wayne State University, 656 W. Kirby Ave, Room 2171 Faculty Administration Building, Detroit, MI, 48202, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Centeio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Erin E</ForeName>
            <Initials>EE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5465-4243</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Rehabilitation Science, University of Hawai'i at Mānoa, 1337 Lower Campus Rd, PE/A Room 227, Honolulu, HI, 96822, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hijazi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kowsar</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Behavioral Sciences, College of Health Sciences, Midwestern University, Downers Grove, IL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pedder</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christine</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Olivet College, Olivet, MI, 49076, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Sch Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0376370</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-4391</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009752" MajorTopicYN="N">Nutritional Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000070777" MajorTopicYN="N">School Teachers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012574" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schools</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057185" MajorTopicYN="N">Sedentary Behavior</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">classroom physical activity breaks</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mixed-methods</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">professional development</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">teacher efficacy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whole school-whole community-whole child</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35304761</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/josh.13163</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lubans D, Richards J, Hillman C, et al. Physical activity for cognitive and mental health in youth: a aystematic review of mechanisms. Pediatrics. 2016;138(3):e20161642. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2016-1642.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Northey JM, Cherbuin N, Pumpa KL, Smee DJ, Rattray B. Exercise interventions for cognitive function in adults older than 50: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2018;52(3):154-160. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2016-096587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helal L, Domingues MR, Umpierre D. Association between cardiovascular risk factors and sedentary behavior prevalence: a cross-sectional analysis of the national health survey-2013. Circulation. 2018;138(Suppl_1):A16675. https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.138.suppl_1.16675.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arundell L, Fletcher E, Salmon J, Veitch J, Hinkley T. A systematic review of the prevalence of sedentary behavior during the after-school period among children aged 5-18 years. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2016;13(1):93. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-016-0419-1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira JR, Cliff DP, Sousa-Sá E, Zhang Z, Santos R. Prevalence of objectively measured sedentary behavior in early years: systematic review and meta-analysis. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2019;29(3):308-328. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.13339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibbs BB, Hergenroeder AL, Katzmarzyk PT, Lee I-M, Jakicic JM. Definition, measurement, and health risks associated with sedentary behavior. Med Sci Sport Exec. 2015;47(6):1295-1300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healy GN, Dunstan DW, Salmon J, Shaw JE, Zimmet PZ, Owen N. Television time and continuous metabolic risk in physically active adults. Med Sci Sport Exec. 2008;40(4):639-645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healy GN, Wijndaele K, Dunstan DW, et al. Objectively measured sedentary time, physical activity, and metabolic risk. Diabetes Care. 2008;31(2):369-371. https://doi.org/10.2337/dc07-1795.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lemes IR, Sui X, Fernandes RA, et al. Association of sedentary behavior and metabolic syndrome. Public Health. 2019;167:96-102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.puhe.2018.11.007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mann KD, Howe LD, Basterfield L, et al. Longitudinal study of the associations between change in sedentary behavior and change in adiposity during childhood and adolescence: Gateshead millennium study. Int J Obes. 2017;41(7):1042-1047. https://doi.org/10.1038/ijo.2017.69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute of Medicine. Educating the Student Body: Taking Physical Activity and Physical Education to School. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egan CA, Webster CA, Beets MW, et al. Sedentary time and behavior during school: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Health Educ. 2019;50(5):283-290. https://doi.org/10.1080/19325037.2019.1642814.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). A Guide for Developing Comprehensive School Physical Activity Programs. Atlanta, GA: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, US Dept of Health and Human Services; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norris E, van Steen T, Direito A, Stamatakis E. Physically active lessons in schools and their impact on physical activity, educational, health and cognition outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Sports Med. 2020;54(14):826-838. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2018-100502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuksel HS, Şahin FN, Maksimovic N, Drid P, Bianco A. School-based intervention programs for preventing obesity and promoting physical activity and fitness: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(1):347. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17010347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Errisuriz VL, Golaszewski NM, Born K, Bartholomew JB. Systematic review of physical education-based physical activity interventions among elementary school children. J Prim Prev. 2018;39(3):303-327. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10935-018-0507-x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van de Kop JH, van Kernebeek WG, RHJ O, Toussaint HM, Verhoeff AP. School-based physical activity interventions in prevocational adolescents: a systematic review and meta-analyses. J Adolesc Health. 2019;65(2):185-194. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jadohealth.2019.02.022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centeio EE, McCaughtry N, Gutuskey L, et al. Physical activity change through comprehensive school physical activity programs in urban elementary schools. J Teach Phys Educ. 2014;33(4):573-591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centeio EE, Moore EWG, Barcelona J, Erwin H, McKown H, Garn A. Development of the teacher efficacy toward providing physical activity in the classroom scale. Int J Phys Act Health, In press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin R, Murtagh EM. Preliminary findings of active classrooms: an intervention to increase physical activity levels of primary school children during class time. Teach Teach Educ. 2015;52:113-127. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2015.09.007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson A, Timperio A, Brown H, Best K, Hesketh KD. Effect of classroom-based physical activity interventions on academic and physical activity outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2017;14(1):114. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-017-0569-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brittin J, Frerichs L, Sirard JR, et al. Impacts of active school design on school-time sedentary behavior and physical activity: a pilot natural experiment. PLoS One. 2017;12(12):e0189236. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0189236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell AL, Lassiter JW. Teacher perceptions of facilitators and barriers to implementing classroom physical activity breaks. J Educ Res. 2020;113(2):108-119. https://doi.org/10.1080/00220671.2020.1752613.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronfenbrenner U. Ecological models of human development. Read Dev Child. 1994;2(1):37-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewallen TC, Hunt H, Potts-Datema W, Zaza S, Giles W. The whole school, whole community, whole child model: a new approach for improving educational attainment and healthy development for students. J Sch Health. 2015;85(11):729-739. https://doi.org/10.1111/josh.12310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darling-Hammond L, Cook-Harvey CM. Educating the Whole Child: Improving School Climate to Support Student Success. Palo Alto, CA: Learning Policy Institute; 2018. Available at: https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/educating-whole-child-report. Accessed March 22, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sibley E, Theodorakakis M, Walsh ME, Foley C, Petrie J, Raczek A. The impact of comprehensive student support on teachers: knowledge of the whole child, classroom practice, and teacher support. Teach Teach Educ. 2017;65:145-156. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2017.02.012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandura A. The explanatory and predictive scope of self-efficacy theory. J Soc Clin Psychol. 1986;4(3):359-373. https://doi.org/10.1521/jscp.1986.4.3.359.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ernst MP, Pangrazi RP. Effects of a physical activity program on children's activity levels and attraction to physical activity. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 1999;11(4):393-405. https://doi.org/10.1123/pes.11.4.393.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centeio EE, Barcelona J, Moore EWG, McKown H, Erwin H. Elementary and Secondary Classroom Teachers' Efficacy for Providing Physical Activity Breaks. Accepted for roundtable presentation at the 2020 American Educational Research Association International Conference, San Francisco, CA. Conference canceled due to COVID-19; 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Creswell JW, Plano Clark VL. Designing and Conducting Mixed Methods Research. 3rd ed. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbin J, Strauss A. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willis JW. Foundations of Qualitative Research: Interpretive and Critical Approaches. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashton PT, Webb RB. Making a Difference: Teachers' Sense of Efficacy and Student Achievement. White Plains, NY: Longman; 1986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centeio EE. Director of Physical Activity Professional Development Outcomes. Austin, Texas: University of Texas; 2012. Available at https://bit.ly/3K70MXm. Accessed January 11, 2022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandura A. Self-Efficacy: The Exercise of Control. New York, NY: Freeman and Co.; 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin JJ, Kulinna PH. The development of a physical education teachers' physical activity self-efficacy instrument. J Teach Phys Educ. 2003;22(2):219-232. https://doi.org/10.1123/jtpe.22.2.219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klassen RM, Tze VM. Teachers' self-efficacy, personality, and teaching effectiveness: a meta-analysis. Educ Res Rev. 2014;12:59-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abi Nader P, Hilberg E, Schuna JM, John DH, Gunter KB. Association of teacher-level factors with implementation of classroom-based physical activity breaks. J Sch Health. 2019;89(6):435-443.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parks M, Solmon M, Lee A. Understanding classroom teachers' perceptions of integrating physical activity: a collective efficacy perspective. J Res Child Educ. 2007;21(3):316-328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hivner EA, Hoke AM, Francis EB, Lehman EB, Hwang GW, Kraschnewski JL. Training teachers to implement physical activity: applying social cognitive theory. Health Educ J. 2019;78(4):464-475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fritz JJ, Miller-Heyl J, Kreutzer JC, Macphee D. Fostering personal teaching efficacy through staff development and classroom activities. J Educ Res. 1995;88(4):200-208. https://doi.org/10.1080/00220671.1995.9941301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vangrieken K, Meredith C, Packer T, Kyndt E. Teacher communities as a context for professional development: a systematic review. Teach Teach Educ. 2017;61:47-59. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2016.10.001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castelli DM, Centeio EE, Nicksic HM. Preparing educators to promote physical activity in schools. Am J Lifestyle Med. 2013;7(5):324-332. https://doi.org/10.1177/1559827613490488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
