<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35309857</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0264-2751</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>125</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cities (London, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cities</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Exploring mobility pattern changes between before, during and after COVID-19 lockdown periods for young adults.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>103662</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>103662</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cities.2022.103662</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The paper aims to investigate changes in travel behavior due to COVID-19 focusing in one of the most active social groups in Greece. A questionnaire survey was conducted and 306 young adults (age 18-34 years) living in various Greek cities responded. The survey collected information about travel-related preferences before, during and after the 1st lockdown and during the 2nd lockdown of the COVID-19 pandemic in Greece. City attributes of the respondent's residency location before and after the 1st lockdown were collected. The data are analyzed descriptively and through statistical modelling techniques. During the 1st lockdown an important increase in physical exercise frequency was observed, but this increase was not permanent. The COVID-19 pandemic resulted in essential reductions in the frequency of public transport use and in an increase of walking frequency. The public transport use reduction was mainly attributed to people that had access to a private car and after the 1st lockdown moved to a smaller city. On the other hand, the changes in walking frequency are closely linked to the city's attributes. Useful policy implications are being derived about how the pandemic can assist in promoting sustainable urban mobility goals.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nikiforiadis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andreas</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Transportation and Hydraulic Engineering, School of Rural and Surveying Engineering, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, 54124 Thessaloniki, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mitropoulos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lambros</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Infrastructure and Rural Development, National Technical University of Athens, 9 Iroon Polytechneiou Str, 15780 Athens, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kopelias</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pantelis</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, University of Thessaly, Pedion Areos, 38334 Volos, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Basbas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Socrates</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Transportation and Hydraulic Engineering, School of Rural and Surveying Engineering, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, 54124 Thessaloniki, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stamatiadis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nikiforos</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kroustali</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sofia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, University of Thessaly, Pedion Areos, 38334 Volos, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cities</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101085015</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0264-2751</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobility changes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Travel behavior</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Young adults</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>55</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35309857</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8923996</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cities.2022.103662</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0264-2751(22)00101-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdullah M., Dias C., Muley D., Shahin M. Exploring the impacts of COVID-19 on travel behavior and mode preferences. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed S., Pantangi S., Eker U., Fountas G., Still S., Anastasopoulos P. Analysis of safety benefits and security concerns from the use of autonomous vehicles: A grouped random parameters bivariate probit approach with heterogeneity in means. Analytic Methods in Accident Research. 2020;28</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed S., Fountas G., Eker U., Still S., Anastasopoulos P. An exploratory empirical analysis of willingness to hire and pay for flying taxis and shared flying car services. Journal of Air Transport Management. 2021;90</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anastasopoulos P., Karlaftis M., Haddock J., Mannering F. Household automobile and motorcycle ownership analyzed with random parameters bivariate ordered probit model. Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board. 2012;2279:12–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apple . Apple; 2020. COVID-19 mobility trends reports.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhaduri E., Manoj B.S., Wadud Z., Goswami A.K., Choudhury C.F. Modelling the effects of COVID-19 on travel mode choice behaviour in India. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borkowski P., Jażdżewska-Gutta M., Szmelter-Jarosz A. Lockdowned: Everyday mobility changes in response to COVID-19. Journal of Transport Geography. 2021;90 doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2020.102906.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2020.102906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brezina T., Takeru S., Leth U., Sandholzer F., Laa B., Kapfenberger M., Lemmerer H., Emberger G.  2020. Dataset: International survey on covid-19 lockdowns and mobility behaviour.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17632/hkb3923nj3.1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bucsky P. Modal share changes due to COVID-19: The case of Budapest. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buehler R., Pucher P. COVID-19 impacts on cycling, 2019–2020. Transport Reviews. 2021;41(4):393–400. doi: 10.1080/01441647.2021.1914900.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01441647.2021.1914900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campisi T., Basbas S., Skoufas A., Akgün N., Ticali D., Tesoriere G. The impact of COVID-19 pandemic on the resilience of sustainable mobility in Sicily. Sustainability. 2020;12:8829.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campisi T., Basbas S., Ahmad Al-Rashid M., Tesoriere G., Georgiadis G. A region-wide survey on emotional and psychological impacts of COVID-19 on public transport choices in Sicily, Italy. Transactions on Transport Sciences. 2021;2 doi: 10.5507/tots.2021.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5507/tots.2021.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang H.H., Lee B., Yang F.A., Liou Y.Y. Does COVID-19 affect metro use in Taipei? Journal of Transport Geography. 2021;91 doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2021.102954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2021.102954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chib S., Greenberg E. Analysis of multivariate probit models. Biometrika. 1998;85:347–361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durlin T., Plevnik A., Balant M., Mladenovič L.  2018. The status of SUMPs in EU member states. CIVITAS 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ehsani J., Michael J., Duren M., Mui Y., Pollack Porter K. Mobility patterns before, during, and anticipated after the COVID-19 pandemic: An opportunity to nurture bicycling. American Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2021;60(6):e277–e279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33674071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ETSC COVID-19: The impact of covid-19 lockdowns on road deaths in April 2020. 2020. https://etsc.eu/wp-content/uploads/PIN-Corona-Briefing_final.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filippini M., Greene W., Kumar N., Martinez-Cruz A. A note on the different interpretation of the correlation parameters in the bivariate probit and the recursive bivariate probit. Economics Letters. 2018;167:104–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Google LLC . 2020. Google COVID-19 community mobility reports.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greene W.H.  5th ed. Pearson Education, Inc; New Jersey: 2003. Econometric analysis.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hellenic Statistical Authority Demographic characteristics. 2011. https://www.statistics.gr/el/statistics/-/publication/SAM03/- Available at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenelius Ε., Cebecauer Μ. Impacts of COVID-19 on public transport ridership in Sweden: Analysis of ticket validations, sales and passenger counts. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jobe J., Griffin G.P. Bike share responses to COVID-19. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;10 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2021.100353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2021.100353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kathimerini Daily news. 2021. https://www.kathimerini.gr/society/561509797/apogoiteymenoi-apo-ton-megalo-peripato/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katrakazas C., Michelaraki E., Sekadakis M., Yannis G. A descriptive analysis of the effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on driving behavior and road safety. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;7 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khaddar S., Fatmi M.R. COVID-19: Are you satisfied with traveling during the pandemic? Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;9 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li C., Poskitt D.C., Zhao X. The bivariate probit model, maximum likelihood estimation, pseudo true parameters and partial identification. Journal of Econometrics. 2019;209:94–113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Likert R. A technique for the measurement of attitudes. Archiv für Psychologie. 1932;140:1–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marra G., Radice R. GJRM-package: Generalised joint regression modelling. 2020. https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/GJRM/index.html Available at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milioti C., Karlaftis M., Akkogiounoglou E. Traveler perceptions and airline choice: A multivariate probit approach. Journal of Air Transport Management. 2015;49:46–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MOBIS Research project MOBIS. COVID-19. 2021. https://ivtmobis.ethz.ch/mobis/covid19/en</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molloy J.  2020. MOBIS Covid19 mobility report.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moslem S., Campisi T., Szmelter-Jarosz A., Duleba S., Nahiduzzaman K.M., Tesoriere G. Best-worst method for modelling mobility choice after COVID-19: Evidence from Italy. Sustainability. 2020;12(17):6824.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nahiduzzaman K.M., Lai S.K. What does the global pandemic COVID-19 teach us? Some reflections. Journal of Urban Management. 2020;9:261–262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforiadis A., Ayfantopoulou G., Stamelou A. Assessing the impact of COVID-19 on bike-sharing usage: The case of Thessaloniki, Greece. Sustainability. 2020;12(19) doi: 10.3390/su12198215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12198215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforiadis A., Basbas S., Garyfalou M.I. A methodology for the assessment of pedestrians-cyclists shared space level of service. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2020;254</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforiadis A., Paschalidis E., Stamatiadis N., Raptopoulou A., Kostareli A., Basbas S. Analysis of attitudes and engagement of shared e-scooter users. Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment. 2021;94</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforiadis A., Basbas S., Mikiki F., Oikonomou A., Polymeroudi E. Pedestrians-cyclists shared spaces level of service: Comparison of methodologies and critical discussion. Sustainability. 2021;13(1):361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikitas A., Tsigdinos S., Karolemeas C., Kourmpa E., Bakogiannis E. Cycling in the era of COVID-19: Lessons learnt and best practice policy recommendations for a more bike-centric future. Sustainability. 2021;3(9):4620. doi: 10.3390/su13094620.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su13094620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padmanabhan V., Penmetsa P., Li X., Dhondia F., Dhondia S., Parrish A. COVID-19 effects on shared-biking in New York, Boston, and Chicago. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;9 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petraki V., Yannis G., Chaziris A. Pilot assessment of Athens Great Walk. PIONEERing solutions for the Smart City challenge. 2021. https://www.nrso.ntua.gr/geyannis/wp-content/uploads/geyannis-cp457.pdf Available at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>POLIS, Rupprecht Consult . Forschung &amp; Beratung GmbH; 2021. Topic guide: Planning for more resilient and robust urban mobility.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Politis I., Georgiadis G., Papadopoulos E., Fyrogenis I., Nikolaidou A., Kopsacheilis A., Sdoukopoulos A., Verani E. COVID-19 lockdown measures and travel behavior: The case of Thessaloniki, Greece. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;10 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2021.100345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2021.100345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R Core Team . R Foundation for Statistical Computing; Vienna, Austria: 2017. R: A language and environment for statistical computing.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabat I., Neuman-Böhme S., Varghese N.E., Barros P.P., van Brouwer W., Exel J., Schreyögg J., Stargardt T. United but divided: Policy responses and people’s perceptions in the EU during the COVID-19 outbreak. Health Policy. 2020;124:909–918. doi: 10.1016/j.healthpol.2020.06.0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthpol.2020.06.0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7307992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32631613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schweizer A.M., Leiderer A., Mitterwallner V., Walentowitz A., Mathes G.H., Steinbauer M.J. Outdoor cycling activity affected by COVID-19 related epidemic-control-decisions. PLoS ONE. 2021;16 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0249268. (5 May)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0249268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scorrano M., Danielis R. Active mobility in an italian city: Mode choice determinants and attitudes before and during the Covid-19 emergency. Research in Transportation Economics. 2021;86 doi: 10.1016/j.retrec.2021.101031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.retrec.2021.101031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaer A., Haghshenas H. The impacts of COVID-19 on older adults’ active transportation mode usage in Isfahan, Iran. Journal of Transport &amp; Health. 2021;23</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrestha N., Yousaf Shad M., Ulvi O., et al.  The impact of COVID-19 on globalization. One Health. 2020;11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sustainable Mobility Unit Cycling map of Greece. 2021. https://www.smu.gr/greece_cycle_map/ Available at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teixeira J.F., Lopes M. The link between bike sharing and subway use during the COVID-19 pandemic: The case-study of New York's citi bike. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;6 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tirachini A., Cats O. COVID-19 and public transportation: Current assessment, prospects, and research needs. Journal of Public Transportation. 2020;22(1):1–21. doi: 10.5038/2375-091.22.1.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5038/2375-091.22.1.1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vandy K.  BBC News; 2021. Coronavirus: How pandemic sparked european cycling revolution.https://www.bbc.com/news/world-europe-54353914</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization  WHO Coronavirus (COVID-19) dashboard. 2021. https://covid19.who.int/ Available at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y., Fricker J. Quantifying the impact of COVID-19 on non-motorized transportation: A bayesian structural time series model. Transport Policy. 2021;103:11–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
