<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35302237</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6584</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>18</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ground water</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ground Water</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Demonstration of Managed Aquifer Recharge in a Coastal Plain Aquifer: Lessons Learned.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/gwat.13197</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The sustainable water initiative for tomorrow (SWIFT) is a 378,000 m<sup>3</sup> /day (100 MGD) managed aquifer recharge (MAR) program designed by the Hampton Roads Sanitation District (HRSD) to rehabilitate the Potomac Aquifer System (PAS) in the Coastal Plain of Eastern Virginia. Groundwater is a primary water source in Eastern Virginia with over 93% of reported use derived from the PAS. Starting in May 2018, HRSD has operated a 3780 m<sup>3</sup> /day (1.0 MGD) MAR demonstration facility at the SWIFT Research Center (SWIFT-RC) in Suffolk, Virginia. The primary aim of the SWIFT-RC is to demonstrate, at a meaningful scale, the feasibility of MAR using deep well recharge into confined PAS hydrostratigraphic unit. The SWIFT-RC employs advanced water treatment technology to bring secondary effluent from an HRSD wastewater treatment plant to drinking water standards. Lessons learned include the evaluation and selection of a multiple barrier carbon-based treatment system to ensure water quality and maintain geochemical compatibility between MAR water and native groundwater, and the evaluation and selection of aluminum chlorohydrate for stabilizing aquifer clays immediately around the well to accept the fresher recharge water. The distribution of flow in the SWIFT-RC multiscreen recharge well and associated well injectivity were variable with time resulting from changing conditions in the well. Dynamic recharge well performance was quantified through the combined analysis of intrinsic and artificial tracer transport, in situ flowmeter testing, and water level analysis. Monitoring well nests and a depth-discrete sampling system supported a robust sampling plan to analyze chemical transport and attenuation in SWIFT-RC groundwater.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 National Ground Water Association.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martinez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Meredith B</ForeName>
            <Initials>MB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2220-9887</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Widdowson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mark A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9752-2523</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Charles E. Via Jr. Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, Virginia Tech, 750 Drillfield Drive, 200 Patton Hall, Blacksburg, Virginia, 24061, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bott</LastName>
            <ForeName>Charles</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hampton Roads Sanitation District, Virginia Beach, VA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Holloway</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hampton Roads Sanitation District, Virginia Beach, VA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Heisig-Mitchell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jamie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hampton Roads Sanitation District, Virginia Beach, VA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wilson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christopher</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hampton Roads Sanitation District, Virginia Beach, VA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ground Water</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9882886</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0017-467X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>41</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35302237</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gwat.13197</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown, D.L., and W.D. Silvey. 1977. Artificial Recharge to a Freshwater-Sensitive Brackish-Water Sand Aquifer, Norfolk, Virginia. U.S. Geological Survey Professional Paper 939. doi:10.3133/pp939.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bullard, M.G., M. Widdowson, G. Salazar-Benites, J. Heisig-Mitchell, A. Nelson, and C. Bott. 2019. Managed Aquifer Recharge: Transport and Attenuation in a Coastal Plain Aquifer. Proceedings of the EWRI World Environmental and Water Resources Congress 2019: Groundwater, Sustainability, Hydro-Climate/Climate Change, and Environmental Engineering, 1-14. Pittsburgh: EWRI. doi: 10.1061/9780784482346.011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CH2M. 2015. Aquifer Replenishment System Concept Cost Evaluation. VA, USA: Newport News.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Civan, F. 2007. Reservoir Formation Damage, 2nd ed. Oxford: Elsevier. https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-0-7506-7738-7.X5000-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dziura, T. 2020. Evaluation of Contaminant Removal through Soil Aquifer Treatment by a Lab Scale Soil Column Experiment Including a Trace Contaminant Spike Test. Masters Thesis. Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Virginia.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eggleston, J., and J. Pope. 2013. Land Subsidence and Relative Sea-Level Rise in the Southern Chesapeake Bay Region. U.S. Geological Survey Circular 1392. doi:10.3133/cir1392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heywood, C.E., and J.P. Pope. 2009. Simulation of groundwater flow in the coastal plain aquifer system of Virginia. U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Report 2009-5039. doi:https://doi.org/10.3133/sir20095039.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs Engineering Group. 2021. Conditioning the Potomac Aquifer System Around Managed Recharge Test Wells at Sustained Water for Tomorrow Facilities at Nansemond, York River, James River, and the Virginia Initiative Plant: Methods and Baseline Results. Hampton, VA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keller, C. 2017. A new rapid method for measuring the vertical head profile. Groundwater 55, no. 2: 244-254. https://doi.org/10.1111/gwat.12455</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khilar, K.C., and H.S. Fogler. 1981. Permeability reduction in water sensitivity of sandstones. In Surface Phenomena in Enhanced Oil Recovery, 721-740. Boston, MA: Springer US. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4757-0337-5_34</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovelace, J.K, M.G. Nielsen, A.L. Read, C.J. Murphy, and M.A. Maupin. 2020. Estimated groundwater withdrawals from principal aquifers in the United States, 2015. U.S. Geological Survey Circular 1464. doi:10.3133/cir1464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarland, E.R., and T.S. Bruce. 2006. The Virginia coastal plain hydrogeologic framework. U.S. Geological Survey Professional Paper 1731. https://doi.org/10.3133/pp1731.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarland, E.R., 2010, Groundwater-quality data and regional trends in the Virginia Coastal Plain, 1906-2007: U.S. Geological Survey Professional Paper 1772, 86 p., 14 pls. doi:10.3133/pp1772.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarland, E.R., 2015, A conceptual framework and monitoring strategy for movement of saltwater in the Coastal Plain aquifer system of Virginia: U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Report 2015-5117, 30 p., 1 pl., doi:10.3133/sir20155117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosthaf, K., B. Brauns, A.S. Fjordbøge, M.M. Rohde, H. Kerrn-Jespersen, P.L. Bjerg, P.J. Binning, and M.M. Broholm. 2018. Conceptualization of flow and transport in a limestone aquifer by multiple dedicated hydraulic and tracer tests. Journal of Hydrology 561: June: 532-546. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2018.04.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nylen, N.G. 2021. Surface water quality regulation as a driver for groundwater recharge. Case Studies in the Environment 5, no. 1: 1124592. https://doi.org/10.1525/cse.2020.1124592</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pyne, R.D.G. 2005. Aquifer Storage Recovery, 2nd ed. Gainesville: ASR Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren, S., S. Gragg, Y. Zhang, B.J. Carr, and G. Yao. 2018. Borehole characterization of hydraulic properties and groundwater flow in a crystalline fractured aquifer of a headwater mountain watershed, Laramie range, Wyoming. Journal of Hydrology 561: June: 780-795. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2018.04.048</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, B.S. 1999. The potential for saltwater intrusion in the Potomac aquifers of the York-James peninsula, Virginia. U.S. Geological Survey Water-Resources Investigations Report 98-4187. doi: 10.3133/wri984187</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virginia Department of Environmental Quality. 2018. Status of Virginia's Water Resources. https://rga.lis.virginia.gov/Published/2018/RD347 (accessed October 22, 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virginia Department of Environmental Quality. 2020. Status of Virginia's Water Resources. https://www.deq.virginia.gov/home/showpublisheddocument/2119/637432838113030000 (accessed October 22, 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
