<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35301732</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-2075</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The EMBO journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>EMBO J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Novel transient cytoplasmic rings stabilize assembling bacterial flagellar motors.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e109523</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e109523</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.15252/embj.2021109523</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The process by which bacterial cells build their intricate flagellar motility apparatuses has long fascinated scientists. Our understanding of this process comes mainly from studies of purified flagella from two species, Escherichia coli and Salmonella enterica. Here, we used electron cryo-tomography (cryo-ET) to image the assembly of the flagellar motor in situ in diverse Proteobacteria: Hylemonella gracilis, Helicobacter pylori, Campylobacter jejuni, Pseudomonas aeruginosa, Pseudomonas fluorescens, and Shewanella oneidensis. Our results reveal the in situ structures of flagellar intermediates, beginning with the earliest flagellar type III secretion system core complex (fT3SScc) and MS-ring. In high-torque motors of Beta-, Gamma-, and Epsilon-proteobacteria, we discovered novel cytoplasmic rings that interact with the cytoplasmic torque ring formed by FliG. These rings, associated with the MS-ring, assemble very early and persist until the stators are recruited into their periplasmic ring; in their absence the stator ring does not assemble. By imaging mutants in Helicobacter pylori, we found that the fT3SScc proteins FliO and FliQ are required for the assembly of these novel cytoplasmic rings. Our results show that rather than a simple accretion of components, flagellar motor assembly is a dynamic process in which accessory components interact transiently to assist in building the complex nanomachine.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaplan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Oikonomou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Catherine M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2312-4746</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wood</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cecily R</ForeName>
            <Initials>CR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1259-3862</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Science, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chreifi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Georges</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Subramanian</LastName>
            <ForeName>Poorna</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ortega</LastName>
            <ForeName>Davi R</ForeName>
            <Initials>DR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi-Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>YW</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2391-473X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Biophysics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Beeby</LastName>
            <ForeName>Morgan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Life Sciences, Imperial College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shaffer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carrie L</ForeName>
            <Initials>CL</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7457-7422</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Science, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology, Immunology, and Molecular Genetics, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jensen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Grant J</ForeName>
            <Initials>GJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1556-4864</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Biology and Biological Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P20 GM130456</GrantID>
            <Acronym>GM</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AI127401</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P20 GM130456</GrantID>
            <Acronym>GM</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 AI127401</GrantID>
            <Acronym>AI</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>EMBO J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8208664</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0261-4189</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001426">Bacterial Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000069296">Type III Secretion Systems</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001426" MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016123" MajorTopicYN="Y">Campylobacter jejuni</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055032" MajorTopicYN="N">Electron Microscope Tomography</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005407" MajorTopicYN="N">Flagella</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016480" MajorTopicYN="Y">Helicobacter pylori</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069296" MajorTopicYN="N">Type III Secretion Systems</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">assembly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial flagellar motor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cryo-ET</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-torque</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tomography</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35301732</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embj.2021109523</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrusci P, Vergara-Irigaray M, Johnson S, Beeby MD, Hendrixson DR, Roversi P, Friede ME, Deane JE, Jensen GJ, Tang CM et al (2013) Architecture of the major component of the type III secretion system export apparatus. Nat Struct Mol Biol 20: 99-104</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beeby M, Ferreira JL, Tripp P, Albers S-V, Mitchell DR (2020) Propulsive nanomachines: the convergent evolution of archaella, flagella and cilia. FEMS Microbiol Rev 44: 253-304</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beeby M, Ribardo DA, Brennan CA, Ruby EG, Jensen GJ, Hendrixson DR (2016) Diverse high-torque bacterial flagellar motors assemble wider stator rings using a conserved protein scaffold. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 113: E1917-E1926</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd CD, Smith TJ, El-Kirat-Chatel S, Newell PD, Dufrene YF, O’Toole GA (2014) Structural features of the pseudomonas fluorescens biofilm adhesin LapA required for LapG-dependent cleavage, biofilm formation, and cell surface localization. J Bacteriol 196: 2775-2788</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Briegel A, Ortega DR, Tocheva EI, Wuichet K, Li Z, Chen S, Müller A, Iancu CV, Murphy GE, Dobro MJ et al (2009) Universal architecture of bacterial chemoreceptor arrays. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 106: 17181-17186</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown PN (2002) Crystal structure of the middle and C-terminal domains of the flagellar rotor protein FliG. The EMBO Journal 21: 3225-3234</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butan C, Lara-Tejero M, Li W, Liu J, Galán JE (2019) High-resolution view of the type III secretion export apparatus in situ reveals membrane remodeling and a secretion pathway. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 116: 24786-24795</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carroll BL, Nishikino T, Guo W, Zhu S, Kojima S, Homma M, Liu J (2020) The flagellar motor of Vibrio alginolyticus undergoes major structural remodeling during rotational switching. eLife 9: e61446</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaban B, Coleman I, Beeby M (2018) Evolution of higher torque in Campylobacter-type bacterial flagellar motors. Sci Rep 8: 97</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang Y-W, Shaffer CL, Rettberg LA, Ghosal D, Jensen GJ (2018) In vivo structures of the Helicobacter pylori cag Type IV secretion system. Cell Rep 23: 673-681</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang Y, Zhang K, Carroll BL, Zhao X, Charon NW, Norris SJ, Motaleb MA, Li C, Liu J (2020) Molecular mechanism for rotational switching of the bacterial flagellar motor. Nat Struct Mol Biol 27: 1041-1047</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen M, Zhao Z, Yang J, Peng K, Baker MA, Bai F, Lo C-J (2017) Length-dependent flagellar growth of Vibrio alginolyticus revealed by real time fluorescent imaging. eLife 6: e22140</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen S, Beeby M, Murphy GE, Leadbetter JR, Hendrixson DR, Briegel A, Li Z, Shi J, Tocheva EI, Müller A et al (2011) Structural diversity of bacterial flagellar motors: Structural diversity of bacterial flagellar motors. EMBO J 30: 2972-2981</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chilcott GS, Hughes KT (2000) Coupling of flagellar gene expression to flagellar assembly in Salmonella enterica serovar typhimurium and Escherichia coli. Microbiol Mol Biol Rev 64: 694-708</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chreifi G, Chen S, Metskas LA, Kaplan M, Jensen GJ (2019) Rapid tilt-series acquisition for electron cryotomography. J Struct Biol 205: 163-169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen EJ, Ferreira JL, Ladinsky MS, Beeby M, Hughes KT (2017) Nanoscale-length control of the flagellar driveshaft requires hitting the tethered outer membrane. Science 356: 197-200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deme JC, Johnson S, Vickery O, Aron A, Monkhouse H, Griffiths T, James RH, Berks BC, Coulton JW, Stansfeld PJ et al (2020) Structures of the stator complex that drives rotation of the bacterial flagellum. Nat Microbiol 5: 1553-1564</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding HJ, Oikonomou CM, Jensen GJ (2015) The caltech tomography database and automatic processing pipeline. J Struct Biol 192: 279-286</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenstein F, Danev R, Pilhofer M (2019) Improved applicability and robustness of fast cryo-electron tomography data acquisition. J Struct Biol 208: 107-114</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erhardt M, Singer HM, Wee DH, Keener JP, Hughes KT (2011) An infrequent molecular ruler controls flagellar hook length in Salmonella enterica: Infrequent molecular ruler controls flagellar hook length in S. enterica. EMBO J 30: 2948-2961</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans LDB, Poulter S, Terentjev EM, Hughes C, Fraser GM (2013) A chain mechanism for flagellum growth. Nature 504: 287-290</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabiani FD, Renault TT, Peters B, Dietsche T, Gálvez EJC, Guse A, Freier K, Charpentier E, Strowig T, Franz-Wachtel M et al (2017) A flagellum-specific chaperone facilitates assembly of the core type III export apparatus of the bacterial flagellum. PLoS Biol 15: e2002267</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukumura T, Makino F, Dietsche T, Kinoshita M, Kato T, Wagner S, Namba K, Imada K, Minamino T (2017) Assembly and stoichiometry of the core structure of the bacterial flagellar type III export gate complex. PLoS Biol 15: e2002281</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosal D, Jeong KC, Chang Y-W, Gyore J, Teng L, Gardner A, Vogel JP, Jensen GJ (2019) Molecular architecture, polar targeting and biogenesis of the Legionella Dot/Icm T4SS. Nat Microbiol 4: 1173-1182</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilbreath JJ, Cody WL, Merrell DS, Hendrixson DR (2011) Change Is Good: variations in common biological mechanisms in the epsilonproteobacterial genera Campylobacter and Helicobacter. Microbiol Mol Biol Rev 75: 84-132</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godessart P, Lannoy A, Dieu M, Van der Verren SE, Soumillion P, Collet J-F, Remaut H, Renard P, De Bolle X (2020) β-Barrels covalently link peptidoglycan and the outer membrane in the α-proteobacterium Brucella abortus. Nat Microbiol 6, 27-33</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guse A, Rohde M, Erhardt M (2020). Controlling minimal and maximal hook-length of the bacterial flagellum (Microbiology). bioRxiv https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.03.25.007062 [PREPRINT]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hagen WJH, Wan W, Briggs JAG (2017) Implementation of a cryo-electron tomography tilt-scheme optimized for high resolution subtomogram averaging. J Struct Biol 197: 191-198</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henderson LD, Matthews-Palmer TRS, Gulbronson CJ, Ribardo DA, Beeby M, Hendrixson DR (2020) Diversification of Campylobacter jejuni flagellar C-ring composition impacts its structure and function in motility, flagellar assembly, and cellular processes. MBio 11, e02286-19</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes KT (2017) Flagellum length control: how long is long enough? Curr Biol 27: R413-R415</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito M, Takahashi Y (2017) Nonconventional cation-coupled flagellar motors derived from the alkaliphilic Bacillus and Paenibacillus species. Extremophiles 21: 3-14</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson S, Fong YH, Deme JC, Furlong EJ, Kuhlen L, Lea SM (2020) Symmetry mismatch in the MS-ring of the bacterial flagellar rotor explains the structural coordination of secretion and rotation. Nat Microbiol 5: 966-975</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson S, Furlong EJ, Deme JC, Nord AL, Caesar JJE, Chevance FFV, Berry RM, Hughes KT, Lea SM (2021) Molecular structure of the intact bacterial flagellar basal body. Nat Microbiol 6: 712-721</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones CJ, Macnab RM (1990) Flagellar assembly in Salmonella typhimurium: analysis with temperature-sensitive mutants. J Bacteriol 172: 1327-1339</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joslin SN, Hendrixson DR (2009) Activation of the Campylobacter jejuni FlgSR two-component system is linked to the Flagellar export apparatus. J Bacteriol 191: 2656-2667</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan M, Ghosal D, Subramanian P, Oikonomou CM, Kjaer A, Pirbadian S, Ortega DR, Briegel A, El-Naggar MY, Jensen GJ (2019a) The presence and absence of periplasmic rings in bacterial flagellar motors correlates with stator type. eLife 8: e43487</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan M, Subramanian P, Ghosal D, Oikonomou CM, Pirbadian S, Starwalt-Lee R, Mageswaran SK, Ortega DR, Gralnick JA, El-Naggar MY et al (2019b). In situ imaging of the bacterial flagellar motor disassembly and assembly processes. EMBO J 38: e100957</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan M, Sweredoski MJ, Rodrigues JPGLM, Tocheva EI, Chang Y-W, Ortega DR, Beeby M, Jensen GJ (2020) Bacterial flagellar motor PL-ring disassembly subcomplexes are widespread and ancient. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 117: 8941-8947</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawamoto A, Miyata T, Makino F, Kinoshita M, Minamino T, Imada K, Kato T, Namba K (2021) Native flagellar MS ring is formed by 34 subunits with 23-fold and 11-fold subsymmetries. Nat Commun 12: 4223</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kodera N, Uchida K, Ando T, Aizawa S-I (2015) Two-ball structure of the flagellar hook-length control protein FliK as revealed by high-speed atomic force microscopy. J Mol Biol 427: 406-414</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kremer JR, Mastronarde DN, McIntosh JR (1996) Computer visualization of three-dimensional image data using IMOD. J Struct Biol 116: 71-76</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubori T, Shimamoto N, Yamaguchi S, Namba K, Aizawa S-I (1992) Morphological pathway of flagellar assembly in Salmonella typhimurium. J Mol Biol 226: 433-446</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhlen L, Abrusci P, Johnson S, Gault J, Deme J, Caesar J, Dietsche T, Mebrhatu MT, Ganief T, Macek B et al (2018) Structure of the core of the type III secretion system export apparatus. Nat Struct Mol Biol 25: 583-590</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee LK, Ginsburg MA, Crovace C, Donohoe M, Stock D (2010) Structure of the torque ring of the flagellar motor and the molecular basis for rotational switching. Nature 466: 996-1000</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lele PP, Hosu BG, Berg HC (2013) Dynamics of mechanosensing in the bacterial flagellar motor. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110: 11839-11844</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lertsethtakarn P, Ottemann KM, Hendrixson DR (2011) Motility and Chemotaxis in Campylobacter and Helicobacter. Annu Rev Microbiol 65: 389-410</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, Sourjik V (2011) Assembly and stability of flagellar motor in Escherichia coli: Flagellar motor assembly. Mol Microbiol 80: 886-899</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu R, Ochman H (2007) Stepwise formation of the bacterial flagellar system. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 104: 7116-7121</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macnab RM (2003) How bacteria assemble flagella. Annu Rev Microbiol 57: 77-100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mastronarde DN (2005) Automated electron microscope tomography using robust prediction of specimen movements. J Struct Biol 152: 36-51</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller SI, Salama NR (2018) The gram-negative bacterial periplasm: size matters. PLoS Biol 16: e2004935</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milne-Davies B, Wimmi S, Diepold A (2021) Adaptivity and dynamics in type III secretion systems. Mol Microbiol 115: 395-411</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minamino T, Kawamoto A, Kinoshita M, Namba K (2020) Molecular organization and assembly of the export apparatus of Flagellar Type III secretion systems. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol 427: 91-107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicastro D, Schwartz C, Pierson J, Gaudette R, Porter ME, McIntosh JR (2006) The molecular architecture of axonemes revealed by cryoelectron tomography. Science 313: 944-948</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortega DR, Oikonomou CM, Ding HJ, Rees-Lee P, Alexandria, Jensen GJ (2019) ETDB-Caltech: a blockchain-based distributed public database for electron tomography. PLoS One 14: e0215531</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pettersen EF, Goddard TD, Huang CC, Couch GS, Greenblatt DM, Meng EC, Ferrin TE (2004) UCSF Chimera-a visualization system for exploratory research and analysis. J Comput Chem 25: 1605-1612</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin Z, Lin W, Zhu S, Franco AT, Liu J (2017) Imaging the motility and chemotaxis machineries in Helicobacter pylori by cryo-electron tomography. J Bacteriol 199: e00695-16</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renault TT, Abraham AO, Bergmiller T, Paradis G, Rainville S, Charpentier E, Guet CC, Tu Y, Namba K, Keener JP et al (2017) Bacterial flagella grow through an injection-diffusion mechanism. eLife 6: e23136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renault TT, Guse A, Erhardt M (2019). Export mechanisms and energy transduction in type-III secretion machines. Curr Top Microbiol Immunol 427: 143-159</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribardo DA, Kelley BR, Johnson JG, Hendrixson DR (2019) A chaperone for the stator units of a bacterial flagellum. MBio 10: e01732-19</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossmann FM, Hug I, Sangermani M, Jenal U, Beeby M (2020) In situ structure of the Caulobacter crescentus flagellar motor and visualization of binding of a CheY-homolog. Mol Microbiol 114: 443-453</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandoz KM, Moore RA, Beare PA, Patel AV, Smith RE, Bern M, Hwang H, Cooper CJ, Priola SA, Parks JM et al (2021) β-Barrel proteins tether the outer membrane in many Gram-negative bacteria. Nat Microbiol 61: 19-26</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santiveri M, Roa-Eguiara A, Kühne C, Wadhwa N, Hu H, Berg HC, Erhardt M, Taylor NMI (2020) Structure and function of stator units of the bacterial flagellar motor. Cell 183: 244-257.e16</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaffer CL, Gaddy JA, Loh JT, Johnson EM, Hill S, Hennig EE, McClain MS, McDonald WH, Cover TL (2011) Helicobacter pylori exploits a unique repertoire of type IV secretion system components for pilus assembly at the bacteria-host cell interface. PLoS Pathog 7: e1002237</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan J, Zhang X, Wang X, Xu C, Chang S, Wu H, Wang T, Liang H, Gao H, Zhou Y et al (2021) Structural basis of assembly and torque transmission of the bacterial flagellar motor. Cell 184: 2665-2679.e19</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terahara N, Krulwich TA, Ito M (2008) Mutations alter the sodium versus proton use of a Bacillus clausii flagellar motor and confer dual ion use on Bacillus subtilis motors. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 105: 14359-14364</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terahara N, Sano M, Ito M (2012) A bacillus flagellar motor that can use both Na+ and K+ as a coupling ion is converted by a single mutation to use only Na+. PLoS One 7: e46248</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terashima H, Hirano K, Inoue Y, Tokano T, Kawamoto A, Kato T, Yamaguchi E, Namba K, Uchihashi T, Kojima S et al (2020) Assembly mechanism of a supramolecular MS-ring complex to initiate bacterial flagellar biogenesis in Vibrio species. J Bacteriol 202: e00236-20</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thormann KM, Paulick A (2010) Tuning the flagellar motor. Microbiology 156: 1275-1283</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsang J, Hoover TR (2014) Requirement of the flagellar protein export apparatus component FliO for optimal expression of flagellar genes in Helicobacter pylori. J Bacteriol 196: 2709-2717</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamaguchi T, Makino F, Miyata T, Minamino T, Kato T, Namba K (2021) Structure of the molecular bushing of the bacterial flagellar motor. Nat Commun 12: 4469</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao X, Norris SJ, Liu J (2014) Molecular architecture of the bacterial flagellar motor in cells. Biochemistry 53: 4323-4333</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao X, Zhang K, Boquoi T, Hu B, Motaleb MA, Miller KA, James ME, Charon NW, Manson MD, Norris SJ et al (2013) Cryoelectron tomography reveals the sequential assembly of bacterial flagella in Borrelia burgdorferi. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 110: 14390-14395</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng SQ, Keszthelyi B, Branlund E, Lyle JM, Braunfeld MB, Sedat JW, Agard DA (2007) UCSF tomography: an integrated software suite for real-time electron microscopic tomographic data collection, alignment, and reconstruction. J Struct Biol 157: 138-147</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu S, Schniederberend M, Zhitnitsky D, Jain R, Galán JE, Kazmierczak BI, Liu J (2019) In situ structures of polar and lateral flagella revealed by cryo-electron tomography. J Bacteriol 201: e00117-19</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
