<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35315086</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-4514</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of food biochemistry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Food Biochem</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Rosa centifolia petal extract induces endothelium-dependent and endothelium-independent vasorelaxation in rat aorta and prevents accumulation of inflammatory factors in human umbilical vein endothelial cells.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14148</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14148</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jfbc.14148</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study aims to investigate the vasorelaxation effects of a Rosa centifolia petal extract (ROSE CRYSTA®-70: ROSE-70) on the isolated aorta and the protective effect of ROSE-70 on human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) dysfunction. ROSE-70 inhibited phenylephrine (PE) -induced contraction in an endothelium-dependent and endothelium-independent manner; however, this relaxation was lower in the endothelium-denuded aorta. ROSE-70-induced relaxation was attenuated by L-N<sup>G</sup> -nitroarginine methyl ester (L-NAME), a nitric oxide synthase inhibitor in the endothelium-intact aorta. Moreover, the relaxation in the endothelium-denuded aorta in response to increases in cAMP was inhibited by SQ22536, an adenylate cyclase inhibitor, and this relaxation was also attenuated by 4-aminopyridine, a voltage-activated K<sup>+</sup> channel inhibitor. ROSE-70 contains high concentrations of quercetin, rutin, and other compounds. Pure quercetin and rutin also inhibited PE-induced contraction in an endothelium-dependent manner, although rutin-induced relaxation was milder in the endothelium-denuded aorta. ROSE-70 significantly increased the phosphorylation (at Ser1177) of eNOS in HUVECs. Moreover, ROSE-70 potently suppressed high glucose- and H<sub>2</sub> O<sub>2</sub> -induced accumulation of tumor necrosis factor-α (TNF-α) and nuclear factor-kappa B (NF-κB) were investigated in human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs). In this study, we defined the mechanism of ROSE-70-induced vasorelaxation in rat aorta and demonstrated that ROSE-70 has anti-inflammatory effects in endothelial cells. PRACTICAL APPLICATIONS: Endothelial cells play a role in vascular homeostasis. Endothelial dysfunction is caused by a variety of risk factors such as hypertension, arteriosclerosis, hyperglycemia, and oxidative stress. ROSE-70 is a food ingredient and the powdered form of an extract from the rose petal with &gt;70% of the content corresponding to rose petal polyphenols such as rutin, quercetin, and protocatechuic acid. This study revealed that vasorelaxation effects of ROSE-70 and the protective role of ROSE-70 on the dysfunction of endothelial cells by high glucose and superoxides were investigated for the first time. We showed the mechanisms of ROSE-70- induced endothelium-dependent vasorelaxation and the protective effects of endothelial cells from high glucose and superoxide. ROSE-70 has been shown to have antiaging, skin elasticity-enhancing, skin-lightening, anti-allergic, sugar-absorbing, and lipolytic effects (URL: https://www.toyohakko-healthcare. com/en/rose_crysta70/). Therefore, the authors believe that ROSE-70 is an excellent food ingredient that has preventive and antiaging effects on lifestyle-related diseases.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaneda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hisako</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Pharmacology, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Misa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Pharmacology, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Veterinary Nursing and Technology, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shinomiya</LastName>
            <ForeName>Haruka</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Pharmacology, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakajima</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ayaka</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Pharmacology, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yamazaki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shingo</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Pharmacology, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sasaki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Noriyasu</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Biochemistry, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tsuyoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaneda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takeharu</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1254-100X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Veterinary Pharmacology, School of Veterinary Medicine, Nippon Veterinary and Life Science University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Food Biochem</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7706045</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0145-8884</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HUVECs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NF-κB</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROSE-70</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TNF-α</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cAMP</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eNOS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vasorelaxation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35315086</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfbc.14148</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arts, I. C., &amp; Hollman, P. C. (2005). Polyphenols and disease risk in epidemiologic studies. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 81(1 Suppl), 317s-325s. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/81.1.317S</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner-Parzer, S. M., Wagner, L., Pettermann, M., Grillari, J., Gessl, A., &amp; Waldhäusl, W. (1995). High-glucose--triggered apoptosis in cultured endothelial cells. Diabetes, 44(11), 1323-1327. https://doi.org/10.2337/diab.44.11.1323</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulden, B. M., Widder, J. D., Allen, J. C., Smith, D. A., Al-Baldawi, R. N., Harrison, D. G., Dikalov, S. I., Jo, H., &amp; Dudley, S. C., Jr. (2006). Early determinants of H2O2-induced endothelial dysfunction. Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 41(5), 810-817. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2006.05.030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai, H. (2005). Hydrogen peroxide regulation of endothelial function: Origins, mechanisms, and consequences. Cardiovascular Research, 68(1), 26-36. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cardiores.2005.06.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, C. K., &amp; Pace-Asciak, C. R. (1996). Vasorelaxing activity of resveratrol and quercetin in isolated rat aorta. General Pharmacology, 27(2), 363-366. https://doi.org/10.1016/0306-3623(95)02001-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, T., Zhang, X., Zhu, G., Liu, H., Chen, J., Wang, Y., &amp; He, X. (2020). Quercetin inhibits TNF-α induced HUVECs apoptosis and inflammation via downregulating NF-kB and AP-1 signaling pathway in vitro. Medicine (Baltimore), 99(38), e22241. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000022241</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, T. L., Zhu, G. L., Wang, J. A., Zhang, G. D., Liu, H. F., Chen, J. R., Wang, Y., &amp; He, X. L. (2015). Protective effects of isorhamnetin on apoptosis and inflammation in TNF-α-induced HUVECs injury. International Journal of Clinical and Experimental Pathology, 8(3), 2311-2320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deanfield, J. E., Halcox, J. P., &amp; Rabelink, T. J. (2007). Endothelial function and dysfunction: Testing and clinical relevance. Circulation, 115(10), 1285-1295. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.652859</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duarte, J., Pérez-Palencia, R., Vargas, F., Ocete, M. A., Pérez-Vizcaino, F., Zarzuelo, A., &amp; Tamargo, J. (2001). Antihypertensive effects of the flavonoid quercetin in spontaneously hypertensive rats. British Journal of Pharmacology, 133(1), 117-124. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.bjp.0704064</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fusi, F., Saponara, S., Pessina, F., Gorelli, B., &amp; Sgaragli, G. (2003). Effects of quercetin and rutin on vascular preparations: A comparison between mechanical and electrophysiological phenomena. European Journal of Nutrition, 42(1), 10-17. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00394-003-0395-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gil-Longo, J., &amp; González-Vázquez, C. (2010). Vascular pro-oxidant effects secondary to the autoxidation of gallic acid in rat aorta. Journal of Nutritional Biochemistry, 21(4), 304-309. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jnutbio.2009.01.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giugliano, D., Ceriello, A., &amp; Paolisso, G. (1996). Oxidative stress and diabetic vascular complications. Diabetes Care, 19(3), 257-267. https://doi.org/10.2337/diacare.19.3.257</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hou, X., Liu, Y., Niu, L., Cui, L., &amp; Zhang, M. (2014). Enhancement of voltage-gated K+ channels and depression of voltage-gated Ca2+ channels are involved in quercetin-induced vasorelaxation in rat coronary artery. Planta Medica, 80(6), 465-472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaneda, H., Otomo, R., Sasaki, N., Omi, T., Sato, T., &amp; Kaneda, T. (2019). Endothelium-independent vasodilator effects of nobiletin in rat aorta. Journal of Pharmacological Sciences, 140(1), 48-53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphs.2019.04.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaneda, T., Sasaki, N., Urakawa, N., &amp; Shimizu, K. (2018). Effects of chlorogenic acid on carbachol-induced contraction of mouse urinary bladder. Journal of Pharmacological Sciences, 136(1), 26-30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphs.2017.12.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaneda, T., Takeuchi, Y., Matsui, H., Shimizu, K., Urakawa, N., &amp; Nakajyo, S. (2005). Inhibitory mechanism of papaverine on carbachol-induced contraction in bovine trachea. Journal of Pharmacological Sciences, 98(3), 275-282. https://doi.org/10.1254/jphs.FPJ05013X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawamura, N., Kubota, T., Kawano, S., Monden, Y., Feldman, A. M., Tsutsui, H., Takeshita, A., &amp; Sunagawa, K. (2005). Blockade of NF-kappaB improves cardiac function and survival without affecting inflammation in TNF-alpha-induced cardiomyopathy. Cardiovascular Research, 66(3), 520-529. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cardiores.2005.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, K. J., Kim, Y. K., Krupa, M., Nguyen, A. N., Do, B. H., Chung, B., Vu, T. T. T., Kim, S. C., &amp; Choe, H. (2016). Crotamine stimulates phagocytic activity by inducing nitric oxide and TNF-α via p38 and NFκ-B signaling in RAW 264.7 macrophages. BMB Reports, 49(3), 185-190. https://doi.org/10.5483/BMBRep.2016.49.3.271</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim, J. W., Kim, H., &amp; Kim, K. H. (2001). NF-kappaB, inducible nitric oxide synthase and apoptosis by helicobacter pylori infection. Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 31(3), 355-366. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0891-5849(01)00592-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, J., Deng, W., Fan, L., Tian, L., Jin, L., Jin, Z., Guo, Q., Xu, Y., &amp; Li, N. (2012). The role of radix hedysari polysaccharide on the human umbilical vein endothelial cells (HUVECs) induced by high glucose. European Journal of Internal Medicine, 23(3), 287-292. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejim.2011.10.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, X., Yi, M., Jin, R., Feng, X., Ma, L., Wang, Y., Shan, Y., Yang, Z., &amp; Zhao, B. (2020). Correlation between oxidative stress and NF-κB signaling pathway in the obesity-asthma mice. Molecular Biology Reports, 47(5), 3735-3744. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11033-020-05466-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manach, C., Scalbert, A., Morand, C., Rémésy, C., &amp; Jiménez, L. (2004). Polyphenols: Food sources and bioavailability. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 79(5), 727-747. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/79.5.727</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moncada, S., &amp; Higgs, E. A. (2006). The discovery of nitric oxide and its role in vascular biology. British Journal of Pharmacology, 147(Suppl 1), S193-S201. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.bjp.0706458</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nohl, H., Kozlov, A. V., Gille, L., &amp; Staniek, K. (2003). Cell respiration and formation of reactive oxygen species: Facts and artefacts. Biochemical Society Transactions, 31(Pt 6), 1308-1311. https://doi.org/10.1042/bst0311308</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obiefuna, P. C., Sofola, O. A., &amp; Ebeigbe, A. B. (1991). Dietary salt-loading attenuates endothelium-dependent relaxation in response to histamine but not to acetylcholine in rat aortic rings. Experimental Physiology, 76(1), 135-138. https://doi.org/10.1113/expphysiol.1991.sp003475</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okada, T. (2012). Bara hana bira polyphenol no Biyo Kou rouka kouka. FOOD Style, 21(16), 32-37 (in Japanese).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palacz-Wrobel, M., Borkowska, P., Paul-Samojedny, M., Kowalczyk, M., Fila-Danilow, A., Suchanek-Raif, R., &amp; Kowalski, J. (2017). Effect of apigenin, kaempferol and resveratrol on the gene expression and protein secretion of tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNF-alpha) and interleukin-10 (IL-10) in RAW-264.7 macrophages. Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy, 93, 1205-1212. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2017.07.054</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pérez-Vizcaíno, F., Ibarra, M., Cogolludo, A. L., Duarte, J., Zaragozá-Arnáez, F., Moreno, L., López-López, G., &amp; Tamargoet, J. (2002). Endothelium-independent vasodilator effects of the flavonoid quercetin and its methylated metabolites in rat conductance and resistance arteries. Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, 302(1), 66-72. https://doi.org/10.1124/jpet.302.1.66</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Revuelta, M. P., Hidalgo, A., &amp; Cantabrana, B. (1999). Involvement of cAMP and beta-adrenoceptors in the relaxing effect elicited by flavonoids on rat uterine smooth muscle. Journal of Autonomic Pharmacology, 19(6), 353-358. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2680.1999.tb00008.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanae, F., Miyaichi, Y., &amp; Hayashi, H. (2003). Endothelium-dependent contraction of rat thoracic aorta induced by gallic acid. Phytotherapy Research, 17(2), 187-189. https://doi.org/10.1002/ptr.1255</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sánchez, M., Romero, M., Gómez-Guzmán, M., Tamargo, J., Pérez-Vizcaino, F., &amp; Duarte, J. (2019). Cardiovascular effects of flavonoids. Current Medical Chemistry, 26(39), 6991-7034. https://doi.org/10.2174/0929867326666181220094721</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi, S., Uchiyama, T., &amp; Toda, K. (2009). Differential effect of resveratrol on nitric oxide production in endothelial f-2 cells. Biological and Pharmaceutical Bulletin, 32(11), 1840-1843. https://doi.org/10.1248/bpb.32.1840</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tep-areenan, P., Kendall, D. A., &amp; Randall, M. D. (2003). Mechanisms of vasorelaxation to 17beta-oestradiol in rat arteries. European Journal of Pharmacology, 476(1-2), 139-149. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0014-2999(03)02152-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsutsui, H., Kinugawa, S., &amp; Matsushima, S. (2011). Oxidative stress and heart failure. American Journal of Physiology-Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 301(6), H2181-H2190. https://doi.org/10.1152/ajpheart.00554.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner, C., Vargas, A. P., Roos, D. H., Morel, A. F., Farina, M., Nogueira, C. W., Aschner, M., &amp; Rochaet, J. B. (2010). Comparative study of quercetin and its two glycoside derivatives quercitrin and rutin against methylmercury (MeHg)-induced ROS production in rat brain slices. Archives of Toxicology, 84(2), 89-97. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00204-009-0482-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, W., Wu, Q. H., Sui, Y., Wang, Y., &amp; Qiu, X. (2017). Rutin protects endothelial dysfunction by disturbing Nox4 and ROS-sensitive NLRP3 inflammasome. Biomedicine and Pharmacotherapy, 86, 32-40. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2016.11.134</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, X. F., Song, S. D., Li, Y. J., Hu, Z. Q., Zhang, Z. W., Yan, C. G., Li, Z. G., &amp; Tang, H. F. (2018). Protective effect of quercetin in LPS-induced murine acute lung injury mediated by cAMP-Epac pathway. Inflammation, 41(3), 1093-1103. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10753-018-0761-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao, X. Q., Lee, N. T., Carlier, P. R., Pang, Y., &amp; Han, Y. F. (2000). Bis(7)-tacrine, a promising anti-Alzheimer's agent, reduces hydrogen peroxide-induced injury in rat pheochromocytoma cells: Comparison with tacrine. Neuroscience Letters, 290(3), 197-200. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0304-3940(00)01357-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu, D., Wu, L., Yang, L., Liu, D., Chen, H., Geng, G., &amp; Li, Q. (2020). Rutin protects boar sperm from cryodamage via enhancing the antioxidative defense. Animal Science Journal, 91(1). https://doi.org/10.1111/asj.13328</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, B., Oo, T. N., &amp; Rizzo, V. (2006). Lipid rafts mediate H2O2 prosurvival effects in cultured endothelial cells. FASEB Journal, 20(9), 1501-1503. https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.05-5359fje</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, F., Suo, Y., Chen, D., &amp; Tong, L. (2016). Protection against vascular endothelial dysfunction by polyphenols in sea buckthorn berries in rats with hyperlipidemia. Bioscience Trends, 10(3), 188-196. https://doi.org/10.5582/bst.2016.01056</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, D. Y., Su, Y., Gao, P., Yang, Q. H., Wang, Z., &amp; Xu, Q. (2015). Resveratrol ameliorates high glucose-induced oxidative stress injury in human umbilical vein endothelial cells by activating AMPK. Life Science, 136, 94-99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lfs.2015.07.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
