<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35318352</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-2322</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>22</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Scientific reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sci Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A green protocol for the electrochemical synthesis of a fluorescent dye with antibacterial activity from imipramine oxidation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>4921</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>4921</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">4921</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41598-022-08770-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Electrochemical oxidation of imipramine (IMP) has been studied in aqueous solutions by cyclic voltammetry and controlled-potential coulometry techniques. Our voltammetric results show a complex behavior for oxidation of IMP at different pH values. In this study, we focused our attention on the electrochemical oxidation of IMP at a pH of about 5. Under these conditions, our results show that the oxidation of IMP leads to the formation of a unique dimer of IMP (DIMP). The structure of synthesized dimer is fully characterized by UV-visible, FTIR, <sup>1</sup>H NMR, <sup>13</sup>C NMR and mass spectrometry techniques. It seems that the first step in the oxidation of IMP is the cleavage of the alkyl group (formation of IMPH). After this, a domino oxidation-hydroxylation-dimerization-oxidation reaction, converts IMPH to (E)-10,10',11,11'-tetrahydro-[2,2'-bidibenzo[b,f]azepinylidene]-1,1'(5H,5'H)-dione (DIMP). The synthesis of DIMP is performed in an aqueous solution under mild conditions, without the need for any catalyst or oxidant. Based on our electrochemical findings as well as the identification of the final product, a possible reaction mechanism for IMP oxidation has been proposed. Conjugated double bonds in the DIMP structure cause the compound to become colored with sufficient fluorescence activity (excitation wave-length 535 nm and emission wave-length 625 nm). Moreover, DIMP has been evaluated for in vitro antibacterial. The antibacterial tests indicated that DIMP showed good antibacterial performance against all examined gram-positive and gram-negative bacteria (Staphylococcus aureus, Bacillus cereus, Escherichia coli and Shigella sonnei).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Souri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zahra</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, Yazd University, Yazd, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Masoudi Khoram</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mahmood</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Chemistry, Bu-Ali Sina University, 65178-38683, Hamedan, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nematollahi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Davood</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9638-224X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Chemistry, Bu-Ali Sina University, 65178-38683, Hamedan, Iran. nemat@basu.ac.ir.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mazloum-Ardakani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammad</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Science, Yazd University, Yazd, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alizadeh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hojjat</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rooyana Veterinary Laboratory, Saqqez, Kurdistan, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Sci Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101563288</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2045-2322</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005456">Fluorescent Dyes</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>131-99-7</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007291">Inosine Monophosphate</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>OGG85SX4E4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D007099">Imipramine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004926" MajorTopicYN="N">Escherichia coli</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005456" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluorescent Dyes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006090" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gram-Negative Bacteria</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006094" MajorTopicYN="N">Gram-Positive Bacteria</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007099" MajorTopicYN="N">Imipramine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007291" MajorTopicYN="N">Inosine Monophosphate</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008826" MajorTopicYN="N">Microbial Sensitivity Tests</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35318352</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8941072</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-022-08770-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41598-022-08770-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staub K, Levina GA, Fortd A. Synthesis and stability studies of conformationally locked 4- (diarylamino)aryl- and 4-(dialkylamino)phenyl-substituted second-order nonlinear optical polyene chromophores. J. Mater. Chem. 2003;13:825–833.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, et al.  Influence of the donor size in panchromatic D–π-A–π-A dyes bearing 5-phenyl-5H-dibenzo-[b, f]azepine units for dye-sensitized solar cells. Dyes Pigm. 2016;127:204–212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Datar PA. Quantitative bioanalytical and analytical method development of dibenzazepine derivative, carbamazepine: A review. J. Pharm. Anal. 2015;5:213–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5762214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele J, Holzinger O. Properties of o-diaminodibenzyl. Liebigs Ann. Chem. 1899;305:96–102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindler W, Häfliger F. Derivatives of iminodibenzyl. Helv. Chim. Acta. 1954;37:472–483.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai YL, Chang CC, Kang CC, Chang TC. Effect of different electronic properties on 9-aryl-substituted BMVC derivatives for new fluorescence probes. J. Lumin. 2007;127:41–47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li W, Qiao J, Duan L, Wang LD, Qiu Y. Novel fluorene/carbazole hybrids with steric bulk as host materials for blue organic electrophosphorescent devices. Tetrahedron. 2007;63:10161–10168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoon KR, Ko SO, Lee SM, Lee H. Synthesis and characterization of carbazole derived nonlinear optical dyes. Dye Pigm. 2007;75:567–573.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu Q, et al.  Novel polyamides with 5H-dibenzo [b, f] azepin-5-yl-substituted triphenylamine: Synthesis and visible-NIR electrochromic properties. Polymers. 2017;9:542–562.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6418813</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30965843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou YH, Peng P, Han L, Tian WJ. Novel donor–acceptor molecules as donors for bulk heterojunction solar cells. Synth. Met. 2007;157:502–507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, et al.  Influence of the donor size in panchromatic D-π-A-π-A dyes bearing 5-phenyl-5H-dibenzo-[b, f]azepine units for dye-sensitized solar cells. Dyes Pigm. 2016;127:204–212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li XH, et al.  A new carbazole-based phenanthrenyl ruthenium complex as sensitizer for a dye-sensitized solar cell. Inorg. Chim. Acta. 2008;361:2835–2840.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang YZ, Liu ZQ. Free-radical-scavenging effect of carbazole derivatives on AAPH-induced hemolysis of human erythrocytes. Bioorg. Med. Chem. 2007;15:1903–1913.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17236778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balaure PC, Costea I, Iordache F, Drăghici C, Enache C. Synthesis of new dibenzo[b, f]azepine derivatives. Rev. Roum. Chim. 2009;54:935–942.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kricka LJ, Ledwith A. Dibenz[b, f]azepines and related ring systems. Chem. Rev. 1974;74:101–123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knell A, Monti D, Maciejewski M, Baiker A. Catalytic dehydrogenation of 10,11-dihydro-5H-dibenz [b, f]azepine (iminodibenzyl) to 5H-dibenz[b, f]azepine (iminostilbene) over potassium-promoted iron oxides: Effect of steam, potassium promotion and carbon dioxide treatment. Appl. Catal. A. 1995;124:367–390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliott EC, et al.  Convenient syntheses of benzo-fluorinated dibenz[b, f]azepines: Rearrangements of isatins, acridines, and indoles. Org. Lett. 2011;13:5592–5595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21939196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Yang Y, Liang Y. Palladium-catalyzed double N-arylation to synthesize multisubstituted dibenzoazepine derivatives. Tetrahedron Lett. 2012;53:6406–6408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsvelikhovsky D, Buchwald SL. Synthesis of heterocycles via Pd-ligand controlled cyclization of 2-Chloro-N-(2-vinyl) aniline: Preparation of carbazoles, indoles, dibenzazepines, and acridines. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2010;132:14048–14051.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2951481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20858012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Modha SG, Vachhani DD, Jacobs J, Van Meervelt L, Van der Eycken EV. A concise route to indoloazocines via a sequential Ugi–gold-catalyzed intramolecular hydroarylation. Chem Comm. 2012;48:6550–6552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22622200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito M, Takaki A, Okamura M, Kanyiva KS, Shibata T. Catalytic synthesis of dibenzazepines and dibenzazocines by 7-exo-and 8-endo-dig-selective cycloisomerization. Eur. J. Org. Chem. 2021;2021:1688–1692.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romero KJ, Galliher MS, Pratt DA, Stephenson CR. Radicals in natural product synthesis. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2018;47:7851–7866.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6205920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30101272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lotfi S, Tammari E, Nezhadali A. Mechanistic study of in vitro chemical interaction of trimipramine drug with barbituric derivative after its oxidation: Electrochemical synthesis of new dibenzazepine derivative. Mater. Sci. Eng. C. 2017;76:153–160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28482512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiong P, Xu HH, Song J, Xu HC. Electrochemical difluoromethylarylation of alkynes. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2018;140:2460–2464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29406700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martins GM, Shirinfar B, Hardwick T, Murtaza A, Ahmed N. Organic electrosynthesis: electrochemical alkyne functionalization. Catal. Sci. Technol. 2019;9:5868–5881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tammari E, Nezhadali A, Lotfi S. Electrochemical oxidation of desipramine drug in the presence of 4, 6-dimethylpyrimidine-2-thiol nucleophile in aqueous acidic medium. Electroanalysis. 2015;27:1693–1698.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Momeni S, Nematollahi D. Electrosynthesis of new quinone sulfonimide derivatives using a conventional batch and a new electrolyte-free flow cell. Green Chem. 2018;20:4036–4042.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goljani H, Tavakkoli Z, Sadatnabi A, Nematollahi D. Two-phase electrochemical generation of aryldiazonium salts: Application in electrogenerated copper-catalyzed sandmeyer reactions. Org. Lett. 2020;22:5920–5924.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32700535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goljani H, Tavakkoli Z, Sadatnabi A, Masoudi-Khoram M, Nematollahi D. A new electrochemical strategy for the synthesis of a new type of sulfonamide derivatives. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33087774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masoudi-Khoram M, Nematollahi D, Jamshidi M, Goljani H. Electrochemical study of fast blue BB: A green strategy for sulfination of fast blue BB. New J. Chem. 2019;43:10382–10389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zivari-Moshfegh F, Nematollahi D, Masoudi-Khoram M, Rahimi A. Electrochemical oxidation of o-phenylenediamine and 1,3 dihydrospiro[benzo[d] imidazole-2,1′-cyclohexane]: A comprehensive study and introducing a novel case of CE mechanism. Electrochim. Acta. 2020;354:136700.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masoudi-Khoram M, Nematollahi D, Khazalpour S, Momeni S, Jamshidi M. Comparative evaluation of the efficiency of batch and flow electrochemical cells in the synthesis of a new derivative of 2-thenoyltrifluoroacetone. J. Electroanal. Chem. 2020;879:114796.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youseflouei N, Alizadeh S, Masoudi-Khoram M, Nematollahi D, Alizadeh H. A comprehensive electrochemical study of 2-mercaptobenzoheterocyclic derivatives: Air-assisted electrochemical synthesis of new sulfonamide derivatives. Electrochim. Acta. 2020;353:136451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sbei N, Hardwick T, Ahmed N. Green chemistry: Electrochemical organic transformations via paired electrolysis. ACS Sustain. Chem. Eng. 2021;9:6148–6169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marken F, Cresswell AJ, Bull SD. Recent advances in paired electrosynthesis. Chem. Rec. 2021;21:2585–2600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33834595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martins GM, Shirinfar B, Hardwick T, Ahmed N. A green approach: Vicinal oxidative electrochemical alkene difunctionalization. ChemElectroChem. 2019;6:1300–1315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sbei N, Martins GM, Shirinfar B, Ahmed N. Electrochemical phosphorylation of organic molecules. Chem. Rec. 2020;20:1530–1552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33021077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martins GM, Zimmer GC, Mendes SR, Ahmed N. Electrifying green synthesis: Recent advances in electrochemical annulation reactions. Green Chem. 2020;22:4849–4870.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan ZUH, et al.  Ionic liquids based fluorination of organic compounds using electrochemical method. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2015;31:26–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyer TH, Choi I, Tian C, Ackermann L. Powering the future: How can electrochemistry make a difference in organic synthesis? Chem. 2020;6:2484–2496.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Toledo RA, et al.  Use of graphite polyurethane composite electrode for imipramine oxidation—Mechanism proposal and electroanalytical determination. Anal. Lett. 2006;39:507–520.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanghavi BJ, Srivastava AK. Adsorptive stripping voltammetric determination of imipramine, trimipramine and desipramine employing titanium dioxide nanoparticles and an Amberlite XAD-2 modified glassy carbon paste electrode. Analyst. 2013;138:1395–1404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23324861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiśniewska J, Wrzeszcz G, Kurzawa M, van Eldik R. The oxidative degradation of dibenzoazepine derivatives by cerium (IV) complexes in acidic sulfate media. Dalton Trans. 2012;41:1259–1267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22124379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop E, Hussein W. Electroanalytical study of tricyclic antidepressants. Analyst. 1984;109:73–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinez MA, Sánchez de laTorre C, Almarza E. A comparative solid-phase extraction study for the simultaneous determination of fiuoxetine, amitriptyline, nortriptyline, trimipramine, maprotiline, clomipramine and trazodone in whole blood by capillary gas-liquid chromatography with nitrogen-phosphorus detection. J. Anal. Toxicol. 2003;27:353–358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14516488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Souri Z, Ansari A, Nematollahi D, Mazloum-Ardakani M. Electrocatalytic degradation of dibenzoazepine drugs by fluorine doped β-PbO2 electrode: New insight into the electrochemical oxidation and mineralization mechanisms. J. Electroanal. Chem. 2020;862:114037.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Souri Z, Alizadeh S, Nematollahi D, Mazloum-Ardakani M, Karami A. A green and template-free electropolymerization of imipramine: The decoration of sponge-like polymer film with gold nanoparticles. J. Electroanal. Chem. 2021;894:115340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masui, M. &amp; Sayo, H. Anodic oxidation of amines: Part II—Electrochemical dealkylation of aliphatic tertiary amines. J. Chem. Soc. B 1593–1596 (1971).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eberhardt MK. Reaction of benzene radical cation with water: Evidence for the reversibility of hydroxyl radical addition to benzene. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1981;103:3876–3878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eberhardt MK. Radiation-induced homolytic aromatic substitution, 6: The effect of metal ions on the hydroxylation of benzonitrile, anisole, and fluorobenzene. J. Phys. Chem. 1977;81:1051–1057.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu H, et al.  Simple approach to regulate the spectra of novel kinds of polyazomethines containing bulky triphenylamine: Electrochemistry, electrochromism and photophysical responsive to environment. Dyes Pigm. 2013;96:158–169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azadbakht R, Koolivand M, Menati S. Salicylimine-based fluorescent chemosensor for magnesium ions in aqueous solution. Inorganica Chim. Acta. 2021;514:120021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García C, Oyola R, Piñero L, Hernández D, Arce R. Photophysics and photochemistry of imipramine, desimipramine, and clomipramine in several solvents: A fluorescence, 266 nm laser flash, and theoretical study. J. Phys. Chem. B. 2008;112:168–178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18085762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, et al.  Effect of structural modification on the performances of phenothiazine-dye sensitized solar cells. Dyes Pigm. 2015;121:118–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaki H, Gharanjig K, Rouhani S, Khosravi A. Synthesis and photophysical properties of some novel fluorescent dyes based on naphthalimide derivatives. J. Photochem. Photobiol. A. 2010;216:44–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosseinnezhad M, Rouhani S. Synthesis and application of new fluorescent dyes in dye-sensitized solar cells. Appl. Phys. A. 2017;123:1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan ZUH, et al.  Enhanced antimicrobial, anti-oxidant applications of green synthesized AgNPs—An acute chronic toxicity study of phenolic azo dyes &amp; study of materials surface using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. J. Photochem. Photobiol. B Biol. 2018;180:208–217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29459312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan AU, et al.  Electrochemical and antioxidant properties of biogenic silver nanoparticles. Int. J. Electrochem. Sci. 2015;10:7905–7916.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonev B, Hooper J, Parisot J. Principles of assessing bacterial susceptibility to antibiotics using the agar diffusion method. J. Antimicrob. Chemother. 2008;61:1295–1301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18339637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rex JH, et al.  Development of interpretive breakpoints for antifungal susceptibility testing: Conceptual framework and analysis of in vitro-in vivo correlation data for fluconazole, itraconazole, and candida infections. Clin. Infect. Dis. 1997;24:235–247.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9114154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
