<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35311740</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4040</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>90</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurosurgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurosurgery</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Angiographic, Cerebral Hemodynamic, and Cognitive Outcomes of Indirect Revascularization Surgery Alone for Adult Patients With Misery Perfusion due to Ischemic Moyamoya Disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>676</StartPage>
          <EndPage>683</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>676-683</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1227/neu.0000000000001907</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Revascularization surgery for adult patients with ischemic moyamoya disease (MMD) may improve both cognitive function and cerebral perfusion.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine angiographic, cerebral hemodynamic, and cognitive outcomes of indirect revascularization surgery alone for adult patients with misery perfusion due to ischemic MMD (IDR group) and to test the superiority of indirect revascularization surgery for cognitive improvement by conducting comparisons with historical control patients who had undergone direct revascularization surgery (DR group) through prospective cohort study with historical controls.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty adult patients with cerebral misery perfusion underwent encephalo-duro-myo-arterio-pericranial-synangiosis alone. Cerebral angiography through arterial catheterization, brain perfusion single-photon emission computed tomography, and neuropsychological testing were performed preoperatively and at 6 months postoperatively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In 17 patients of the IDR group, collateral flows that were newly formed after surgery on angiograms fed more than one-third of the middle cerebral artery (MCA) cortical territory. In the IDR group, perfusion in the MCA territory was significantly increased after surgery (P &lt; .0001), and the difference in MCA perfusion between before and after surgery was significantly greater (P = .0493) compared with the DR group. Improved cognition was significantly more frequent in the IDR group (65%) than in the DR group (31%, P = .0233).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Indirect revascularization surgery alone forms sufficient collateral circulation, improves cerebral hemodynamics, and recovers cognitive function in adult patients with misery perfusion due to ischemic MMD. The latter 2 beneficial effects may be higher when compared with patients undergoing direct revascularization surgery.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © Congress of Neurological Surgeons 2022. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kimura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kubo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoshitaka</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dobashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazumasa</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Katakura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yasukazu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chida</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kohei</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kobayashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masakazu</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yoshida</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenji</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fujiwara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shunrou</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Terasaki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kawamura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tsuyoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Hachinohe City Hospital, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ogasawara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kuniaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8529-6688</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurosurgery</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7802914</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-396X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C536991">Moyamoya disease 1</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002533" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral Angiography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002548" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebral Revascularization</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009072" MajorTopicYN="Y">Moyamoya Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010477" MajorTopicYN="N">Perfusion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35311740</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/neu.0000000000001907</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006123-202206000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimura M, Tominaga T. Current status of revascularization surgery for moyamoya disease: special consideration for its ‘internal carotid-external carotid (IC-EC) conversion’ as the physiological reorganization system. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2015;236(1):45-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guzman R, Lee M, Achrol A, et al. Clinical outcome after 450 revascularization procedures for moyamoya disease. J Neurosurg. 2009;111(5):927-935.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyoshi K, Chida K, Kobayashi M, et al. Two-year clinical, cerebral hemodynamic, and cognitive outcomes of adult patients undergoing medication alone for symptomatically ischemic moyamoya disease without cerebral misery perfusion: a prospective cohort study. Neurosurgery. 2019;84(6):1233-1241.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai PMR, Patel NJ, Frerichs KU, et al. Direct vs indirect revascularization in a north American cohort of moyamoya disease. Neurosurgery. 2021;89(2):315-322.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SB, Kim DS, Huh PW, Yoo DS, Lee TG, Cho KS. Long-term follow-up results in 142 adult patients with moyamoya disease according to management modality. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 2012;154(7):1179-1187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanagihara W, Chida K, Kobayashi M, et al. Impact of cerebral blood flow changes due to arterial bypass surgery on cognitive function in adult patients with symptomatic ischemic moyamoya disease. J Neurosurg. 2018;131(6):1716-1724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobashi K, Kubo Y, Kimura K, et al. De novo cerebral microbleeds and cognitive decline in cerebral hyperperfusion after direct revascularization for adult moyamoya disease. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2022;31(1):106-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogasawara K, Komoribayashi N, Kobayashi M, et al. Neural damage caused by cerebral hyperperfusion after arterial bypass surgery in a patient with moyamoya disease: case report. Neurosurgery. 2005;56(6):E1380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimada Y, Kojima D, Yoshida J, et al. Transient symptomatic downregulation of cortical neurotransmitter receptor function due to cerebral hyperperfusion after arterial bypass surgery for a patient with ischemic moyamoya disease. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2018;58(11):481-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ando T, Shimada Y, Fujiwara S, et al. Revascularisation surgery improves cognition in adult patients with moyamoya disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(3):332-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Research Committee on the Pathology and Treatment of Spontaneous Occlusion of the Circle of Willis; Health Labour Sciences Research Grant for Research on Measures for Infractable Diseases. Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of moyamoya disease (spontaneous occlusion of the circle of Willis). Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2012;52(5):245-266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsushima T, Inoue T, Suzuki SO, Fujii K, Fukui M, Hasuo K. Surgical treatment of moyamoya disease in pediatric patients--comparison between the results of indirect and direct revascularization procedures. Neurosurgery. 1992;31(3):401-405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishimiya M, Matsuda H, Imabayashi E, Kuji I, Sato N. Comparison of SPM and NEUROSTAT in voxelwise statistical analysis of brain SPECT and MRI at the early stage of Alzheimer's disease. Ann Nucl Med. 2008;22(10):921-927.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeuchi R, Matsuda H, Yoshioka K, Yonekura Y. Cerebral blood flow SPET in transient global amnesia with automated ROI analysis by 3DSRT. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2004;31(4):578-589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Ogasawara K, Kobayashi M, et al. Improvement and impairment in cognitive function after carotid endarterectomy: comparison of objective and subjective assessments. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2012;52(3):154-160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiba T, Setta K, Shimada Y, et al. Comparison of effects between clopidogrel and cilostazol on cerebral perfusion in nonsurgical adult patients with symptomatically ischemic moyamoya disease: subanalysis of a prospective cohort. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2018;27(11):3373-3379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hikiami H, Goto H, Sekiya N, et al. Comparative efficacy of Keishi-bukuryo-gan and pentoxifylline on RBC deformability in patients with “oketsu” syndrome. Phytomedicine. 2003;10(6-7):459-466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakae H, Yokoi A, Kodama H, et al. Comparison of the effects on rib fracture between the traditional Japanese medicine Jidabokuippo and nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs: a randomized controlled trial. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2012;2012:837958.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimura M, Kaneta T, Shimizu H, Tominaga T. Cerebral ischemia owing to compression of the brain by swollen temporal muscle used for encephalo-myo-synangiosis in moyamoya disease. Neurosurg Rev. 2009;32(2):245-249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machida T, Higuchi Y, Nakano S, et al. Sagittal splitting of the temporalis muscle for encephalo-myo-synangiosis to prevent ischemic complications due to a swollen temporalis muscle without inhibiting collateral developments in patients with moyamoya disease. J Neurosurg. 2018;130(6):1957-1964.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim DS, Huh PW, Kim HS, et al. Surgical treatment of moyamoya disease in adults: combined direct and indirect vs. indirect bypass surgery. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2012;52(5):333-338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Yu S, Lu J, et al. Direct bypass surgery vs. combined bypass surgery for hemorrhagic moyamoya disease: a comparison of angiographic outcomes. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omote Y, Deguchi K, Tian F, et al. Clinical and pathological improvement in stroke-prone spontaneous hypertensive rats related to the pleiotropic effect of cilostazol. Stroke. 2012;43(6):1639-1646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamai Y, Takami H, Nakahata R, Ono F, Munakata A. Comparison of the effects of acetylsalicylic acid, ticlopidine and cilostazol on primary hemostasis using a quantitative bleeding time test apparatus. Haemostasis. 1999;29(5):269-276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadashiva N, Reddy YV, Arima A, Saini J, Shukla D, Pandey P. Moyamoya disease: experience with direct and indirect revascularization in 70 patients from a nonendemic region. Neurol India. 2016;64(suppl):S78-S86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baron JC, Bousser MG, Rey A, et al. Reversal of focal “misery-perfusion syndrome” by extra-intracranial arterial bypass in hemodynamic cerebral ischemia: a case study with 15O positron emission tomography. Stroke. 1981;12(4):454-459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Ogasawara K, Saura H, et al. Post-carotid endarterectomy changes in cerebral glucose metabolism on (18)F-fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography associated with postoperative improvement or impairment in cognitive function. J Neurosurg. 2015;123(6):1546-1554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchino H, Kim JH, Fujima N, et al. Synergistic interactions between direct and indirect bypasses in combined procedures: the significance of indirect bypasses in moyamoya disease. Neurosurgery. 2017;80(2):201-209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Li ZY, Chen C, et al. Postoperative neovascularization, cerebral hemodynamics, and clinical prognosis between combined and indirect bypass revascularization procedures in hemorrhagic moyamoya disease. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2021;208:106869.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roder C, Haas P, Fudali M, et al. Neuropsychological impairment in adults with moyamoya angiopathy: preoperative assessment and correlation to MRI and H215O PET. Neurosurg Rev. 2020;43(6):1615-1622.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinagawa F, Kobayashi S, Fujita K. Japanese Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale–Revised. Nihon Bunka Kagakusha; 1990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koyama M. Clinical Psychology of Brain Damage, Vol 48-54. Gakuen Sha; 1985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35311740</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4040</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>90</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurosurgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurosurgery</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Angiographic, Cerebral Hemodynamic, and Cognitive Outcomes of Indirect Revascularization Surgery Alone for Adult Patients With Misery Perfusion due to Ischemic Moyamoya Disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>676</StartPage>
          <EndPage>683</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>676-683</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1227/neu.0000000000001907</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Revascularization surgery for adult patients with ischemic moyamoya disease (MMD) may improve both cognitive function and cerebral perfusion.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine angiographic, cerebral hemodynamic, and cognitive outcomes of indirect revascularization surgery alone for adult patients with misery perfusion due to ischemic MMD (IDR group) and to test the superiority of indirect revascularization surgery for cognitive improvement by conducting comparisons with historical control patients who had undergone direct revascularization surgery (DR group) through prospective cohort study with historical controls.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty adult patients with cerebral misery perfusion underwent encephalo-duro-myo-arterio-pericranial-synangiosis alone. Cerebral angiography through arterial catheterization, brain perfusion single-photon emission computed tomography, and neuropsychological testing were performed preoperatively and at 6 months postoperatively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In 17 patients of the IDR group, collateral flows that were newly formed after surgery on angiograms fed more than one-third of the middle cerebral artery (MCA) cortical territory. In the IDR group, perfusion in the MCA territory was significantly increased after surgery (P &lt; .0001), and the difference in MCA perfusion between before and after surgery was significantly greater (P = .0493) compared with the DR group. Improved cognition was significantly more frequent in the IDR group (65%) than in the DR group (31%, P = .0233).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Indirect revascularization surgery alone forms sufficient collateral circulation, improves cerebral hemodynamics, and recovers cognitive function in adult patients with misery perfusion due to ischemic MMD. The latter 2 beneficial effects may be higher when compared with patients undergoing direct revascularization surgery.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © Congress of Neurological Surgeons 2022. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kimura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kubo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoshitaka</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dobashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazumasa</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Katakura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yasukazu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chida</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kohei</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kobayashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masakazu</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yoshida</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenji</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fujiwara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shunrou</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Terasaki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kawamura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tsuyoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Hachinohe City Hospital, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ogasawara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kuniaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8529-6688</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biomedical Sciences, School of Medicine, Iwate Medical University, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurosurgery</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7802914</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-396X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C536991">Moyamoya disease 1</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002533" MajorTopicYN="N">Cerebral Angiography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002548" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cerebral Revascularization</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006439" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemodynamics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009072" MajorTopicYN="Y">Moyamoya Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010477" MajorTopicYN="N">Perfusion</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35311740</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/neu.0000000000001907</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006123-202206000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimura M, Tominaga T. Current status of revascularization surgery for moyamoya disease: special consideration for its ‘internal carotid-external carotid (IC-EC) conversion’ as the physiological reorganization system. Tohoku J Exp Med. 2015;236(1):45-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guzman R, Lee M, Achrol A, et al. Clinical outcome after 450 revascularization procedures for moyamoya disease. J Neurosurg. 2009;111(5):927-935.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyoshi K, Chida K, Kobayashi M, et al. Two-year clinical, cerebral hemodynamic, and cognitive outcomes of adult patients undergoing medication alone for symptomatically ischemic moyamoya disease without cerebral misery perfusion: a prospective cohort study. Neurosurgery. 2019;84(6):1233-1241.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai PMR, Patel NJ, Frerichs KU, et al. Direct vs indirect revascularization in a north American cohort of moyamoya disease. Neurosurgery. 2021;89(2):315-322.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SB, Kim DS, Huh PW, Yoo DS, Lee TG, Cho KS. Long-term follow-up results in 142 adult patients with moyamoya disease according to management modality. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 2012;154(7):1179-1187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanagihara W, Chida K, Kobayashi M, et al. Impact of cerebral blood flow changes due to arterial bypass surgery on cognitive function in adult patients with symptomatic ischemic moyamoya disease. J Neurosurg. 2018;131(6):1716-1724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobashi K, Kubo Y, Kimura K, et al. De novo cerebral microbleeds and cognitive decline in cerebral hyperperfusion after direct revascularization for adult moyamoya disease. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2022;31(1):106-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogasawara K, Komoribayashi N, Kobayashi M, et al. Neural damage caused by cerebral hyperperfusion after arterial bypass surgery in a patient with moyamoya disease: case report. Neurosurgery. 2005;56(6):E1380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimada Y, Kojima D, Yoshida J, et al. Transient symptomatic downregulation of cortical neurotransmitter receptor function due to cerebral hyperperfusion after arterial bypass surgery for a patient with ischemic moyamoya disease. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2018;58(11):481-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ando T, Shimada Y, Fujiwara S, et al. Revascularisation surgery improves cognition in adult patients with moyamoya disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020;91(3):332-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Research Committee on the Pathology and Treatment of Spontaneous Occlusion of the Circle of Willis; Health Labour Sciences Research Grant for Research on Measures for Infractable Diseases. Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of moyamoya disease (spontaneous occlusion of the circle of Willis). Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2012;52(5):245-266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsushima T, Inoue T, Suzuki SO, Fujii K, Fukui M, Hasuo K. Surgical treatment of moyamoya disease in pediatric patients--comparison between the results of indirect and direct revascularization procedures. Neurosurgery. 1992;31(3):401-405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishimiya M, Matsuda H, Imabayashi E, Kuji I, Sato N. Comparison of SPM and NEUROSTAT in voxelwise statistical analysis of brain SPECT and MRI at the early stage of Alzheimer's disease. Ann Nucl Med. 2008;22(10):921-927.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeuchi R, Matsuda H, Yoshioka K, Yonekura Y. Cerebral blood flow SPET in transient global amnesia with automated ROI analysis by 3DSRT. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2004;31(4):578-589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Ogasawara K, Kobayashi M, et al. Improvement and impairment in cognitive function after carotid endarterectomy: comparison of objective and subjective assessments. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2012;52(3):154-160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiba T, Setta K, Shimada Y, et al. Comparison of effects between clopidogrel and cilostazol on cerebral perfusion in nonsurgical adult patients with symptomatically ischemic moyamoya disease: subanalysis of a prospective cohort. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2018;27(11):3373-3379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hikiami H, Goto H, Sekiya N, et al. Comparative efficacy of Keishi-bukuryo-gan and pentoxifylline on RBC deformability in patients with “oketsu” syndrome. Phytomedicine. 2003;10(6-7):459-466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakae H, Yokoi A, Kodama H, et al. Comparison of the effects on rib fracture between the traditional Japanese medicine Jidabokuippo and nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs: a randomized controlled trial. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2012;2012:837958.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujimura M, Kaneta T, Shimizu H, Tominaga T. Cerebral ischemia owing to compression of the brain by swollen temporal muscle used for encephalo-myo-synangiosis in moyamoya disease. Neurosurg Rev. 2009;32(2):245-249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machida T, Higuchi Y, Nakano S, et al. Sagittal splitting of the temporalis muscle for encephalo-myo-synangiosis to prevent ischemic complications due to a swollen temporalis muscle without inhibiting collateral developments in patients with moyamoya disease. J Neurosurg. 2018;130(6):1957-1964.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim DS, Huh PW, Kim HS, et al. Surgical treatment of moyamoya disease in adults: combined direct and indirect vs. indirect bypass surgery. Neurol Med Chir (Tokyo). 2012;52(5):333-338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Yu S, Lu J, et al. Direct bypass surgery vs. combined bypass surgery for hemorrhagic moyamoya disease: a comparison of angiographic outcomes. Front Neurol. 2018;9:1121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omote Y, Deguchi K, Tian F, et al. Clinical and pathological improvement in stroke-prone spontaneous hypertensive rats related to the pleiotropic effect of cilostazol. Stroke. 2012;43(6):1639-1646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamai Y, Takami H, Nakahata R, Ono F, Munakata A. Comparison of the effects of acetylsalicylic acid, ticlopidine and cilostazol on primary hemostasis using a quantitative bleeding time test apparatus. Haemostasis. 1999;29(5):269-276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadashiva N, Reddy YV, Arima A, Saini J, Shukla D, Pandey P. Moyamoya disease: experience with direct and indirect revascularization in 70 patients from a nonendemic region. Neurol India. 2016;64(suppl):S78-S86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baron JC, Bousser MG, Rey A, et al. Reversal of focal “misery-perfusion syndrome” by extra-intracranial arterial bypass in hemodynamic cerebral ischemia: a case study with 15O positron emission tomography. Stroke. 1981;12(4):454-459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida K, Ogasawara K, Saura H, et al. Post-carotid endarterectomy changes in cerebral glucose metabolism on (18)F-fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography associated with postoperative improvement or impairment in cognitive function. J Neurosurg. 2015;123(6):1546-1554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchino H, Kim JH, Fujima N, et al. Synergistic interactions between direct and indirect bypasses in combined procedures: the significance of indirect bypasses in moyamoya disease. Neurosurgery. 2017;80(2):201-209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Li ZY, Chen C, et al. Postoperative neovascularization, cerebral hemodynamics, and clinical prognosis between combined and indirect bypass revascularization procedures in hemorrhagic moyamoya disease. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2021;208:106869.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roder C, Haas P, Fudali M, et al. Neuropsychological impairment in adults with moyamoya angiopathy: preoperative assessment and correlation to MRI and H215O PET. Neurosurg Rev. 2020;43(6):1615-1622.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinagawa F, Kobayashi S, Fujita K. Japanese Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale–Revised. Nihon Bunka Kagakusha; 1990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koyama M. Clinical Psychology of Brain Damage, Vol 48-54. Gakuen Sha; 1985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
