<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35310360</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>In-vivo evaluation of molybdenum as bioabsorbable stent candidate.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>262</StartPage>
          <EndPage>271</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>262-271</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2021.11.005</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Biodegradable stents have tremendous theoretical potential as an alternative to bare metal stents and drug-eluting stents for the treatment of obstructive coronary artery disease. Any bioresorbable or biodegradable scaffold material needs to possess optimal mechanical properties and uniform degradation behavior that avoids local and systemic toxicity. Recently, molybdenum (Mo) has been investigated as a potential novel biodegradable material for this purpose. With its proven moderate degradation rate and excellent mechanical properties, Mo may represent an ideal source material for clinical cardiac and vascular applications. The present study was performed to evaluate the mechanical performance of metallic Mo <i>in vitro</i> and the biodegradation properties <i>in vivo</i>. The results demonstrated favorable mechanical behavior and a uniform degradation profile as desired for a new generation ultra-thin degradable endovascular stent material. Moreover, Mo implants in mouse arteries avoided the typical cellular response that contributes to restenosis. There was minimal neointimal hyperplasia over 6 months, an absence of excessive smooth muscle cell (SMC) proliferation or inflammation near the implant, and avoidance of significant harm to regenerating endothelial cells (EC). Qualitative inspection of kidney sections showed a potentially pathological remodeling of kidney Bowman's capsule and glomeruli, indicative of impaired filtering function and development of kidney disease, although quantifications of these morphological changes were not statistically significant. Together, the results suggest that the products of Mo corrosion may exert beneficial or inert effects on the activities of inflammatory and arterial cells, while exerting potentially toxic effects in the kidneys that warrant further investigation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2021 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sikora-Jasinska</LastName>
            <ForeName>Malgorzata</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Morath</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lea M</ForeName>
            <Initials>LM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kwesiga</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria P</ForeName>
            <Initials>MP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Plank</LastName>
            <ForeName>Margaret E</ForeName>
            <Initials>ME</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nelson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexia L</ForeName>
            <Initials>AL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Oliver</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexander A</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering and Physiology, Mayo Clinic Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bocks</LastName>
            <ForeName>Martin L</ForeName>
            <Initials>ML</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Case Western Reserve University School of Medicine, UH Rainbow Babies &amp; Children's Hospital, Cleveland, OH, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guillory</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roger J</ForeName>
            <Initials>RJ</Initials>
            <Suffix>2nd</Suffix>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Goldman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeremy</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Engineering, Michigan Technological University, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biocompatibility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biodegradable stent</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Degradation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molybdenum</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts to report.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35310360</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8897701</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2021.11.005</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(21)00526-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone G.W., Gao R., Kimura T., Kereiakes D.J., Ellis S.G., Onuma Y., Cheong W.-F., Jones-McMeans J., Su X., Zhang Z. 1-year outcomes with the Absorb bioresorbable scaffold in patients with coronary artery disease: a patient-level, pooled meta-analysis. Lancet. 2016;387(10025):1277–1289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26825231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang S.-H., Chae I.-H., Park J.-J., Lee H.S., Kang D.-Y., Hwang S.-S., Youn T.-J., Kim H.-S. Stent thrombosis with drug-eluting stents and bioresorbable scaffolds: evidence from a network meta-analysis of 147 trials. Cardiovasc. Interv. 2016;9(12):1203–1212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27262860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassese S., Byrne R.A., Ndrepepa G., Kufner S., Wiebe J., Repp J., Schunkert H., Fusaro M., Kimura T., Kastrati A. Everolimus-eluting bioresorbable vascular scaffolds versus everolimus-eluting metallic stents: a meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Lancet. 2016;387(10018):537–544.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26597771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jinnouchi H., Torii S., Sakamoto A., Kolodgie F.D., Virmani R., Finn A.V. Fully bioresorbable vascular scaffolds: lessons learned and future directions. Nat. Rev. Cardiol. 2019;16(5):286–304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30546115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verheye S., Wlodarczak A., Montorsi P., Torzewski J., Bennett J., Haude M., Starmer G., Buck T., Wiemer M., Nuruddin A.A.  2020. BIOSOLVE‐IV‐registry: Safety and Performance of the Magmaris Scaffold: 12‐month Outcomes of the First Cohort of 1,075 Patients, Catheterization and Cardiovascular Interventions.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32881396</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onuma Y., Serruys P.W. Rather thick, yet antithrombogenic: is the Magmaris scaffold a new hope for bioresorbable coronary scaffold? Circ. Cardiovasc. Interv. 2017;10(8)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28801542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waksman R., Lipinski M.J., Acampado E., Cheng Q., Adams L., Torii S., Gai J., Torguson R., Hellinga D.M., Westman P.C., Joner M., Zumstein P., Kolodgie F.D., Virmani R. Comparison of acute thrombogenicity for metallic and polymeric bioabsorbable scaffolds: Magmaris versus Absorb in a porcine arteriovenous shunt Model. Circ. Cardiovasc. Interv. 2017;10(8)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28801538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Birgelen C., Kok M.M., van der Heijden L.C., Danse P.W., Schotborgh C.E., Scholte M., Gin R.M.T.J., Somi S., van Houwelingen K.G., Stoel M.G., de Man F.H.A.F., Louwerenburg J.W., Hartmann M., Zocca P., Linssen G.C.M., van der Palen J., Doggen C.J.M., Löwik M.M. Very thin strut biodegradable polymer everolimus-eluting and sirolimus-eluting stents versus durable polymer zotarolimus-eluting stents in all comers with coronary artery disease (BIO-RESORT): a three-arm, randomised, non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2016;388(10060):2607–2617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27806902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bailey S.R. DES design: theoretical advantages and disadvantages of stent strut materials, design, thickness, and surface characteristics. J. Intervent. Cardiol. 2009;22:S3–S17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto A., Jinnouchi H., Torii S., Virmani R., Finn A.V. Understanding the impact of stent and scaffold material and strut design on coronary artery thrombosis from the basic and clinical points of view. Bioengineering. 2018;5(3)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6164756</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30181463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foin N., Lee R.D., Torii R., Guitierrez-Chico J.L., Mattesini A., Nijjer S., Sen S., Petraco R., Davies J.E., Di Mario C., Joner M., Virmani R., Wong P. Impact of stent strut design in metallic stents and biodegradable scaffolds. Int. J. Cardiol. 2014;177(3):800–808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25449502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin W., Qin L., Qi H., Zhang D., Zhang G., Gao R., Qiu H., Xia Y., Cao P., Wang X., Zheng W. Long-term in vivo corrosion behavior, biocompatibility and bioresorption mechanism of a bioresorbable nitrided iron scaffold. Acta Biomater. 2017;54:454–468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28315492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostaed E., Ardakani M.S., Sikora-Jasinska M., Drelich J.W. Precipitation induced room temperature superplasticity in Zn-Cu alloys. Mater. Lett. 2019;244:203–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6927668</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31871366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostaed E., Sikora-Jasinska M., Ardakani M.S., Mostaed A., Reaney I.M., Goldman J., Drelich J.W. Towards revealing key factors in mechanical instability of bioabsorbable Zn-based alloys for intended vascular stenting. Acta Biomater. 2020;105:319–335.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294534</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31982587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostaed E., Sikora-Jasinska M., Drelich J.W., Vedani M. Zinc-based alloys for degradable vascular stent applications. Acta Biomater. 2018;71:1–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5927626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29530821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venezuela J., Dargusch M.S. Addressing the slow corrosion rate of biodegradable Fe-Mn: current approaches and future trends. Curr. Opin. Solid State Mater. Sci. 2020;24(3)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen D., Qi H., Lin W., Zhang W., Bian D., Shi X., Qin L., Zhang G., Fu W., Dou K. PDLLA-Zn-nitrided Fe bioresorbable scaffold with 53-μm-thick metallic struts and tunable multistage biodegradation function. Sci. Adv. 2021;7(23)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8177708</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34088662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redlich C., Quadbeck P., Thieme M., Kieback B. Molybdenum - a biodegradable implant material for structural applications? Acta Biomater. 2020;104:241–251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31926333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redlich C., Schauer A., Scheibler J., Poehle G., Barthel P., Maennel A., Adams V., Weissgaerber T., Linke A., Quadbeck P. In vitro degradation behavior and biocompatibility of bioresorbable molybdenum. Metals. 2021;11(5):761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8705131</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34947370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu G., Zhang G.J., Jiang F., Ding X.D., Sun Y.J., Sun J., Ma E. Nanostructured high-strength molybdenum alloys with unprecedented tensile ductility. Nat. Mater. 2013;12(4):344–350.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23353630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xing H.-r., Hu P., Zhou Y.-h., Li S.-L., Zuo Y.-g., Cheng Q., Wang K.-s., Yang F., Feng P.-f., Chang T. The microstructure and texture evolution of pure molybdenum sheets under various rolling reductions. Mater. Char. 2020;165</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eck R., Pink E. Effects of working on strength and ductility of molybdenum and tungsten alloys. Int. J. Refract. Metals Hard Mater. 1992;11(6):337–341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reiser J., Hoffmann J., Jäntsch U., Klimenkov M., Bonk S., Bonnekoh C., Rieth M., Hoffmann A., Mrotzek T. Ductilisation of tungsten (W): on the shift of the brittle-to-ductile transition (BDT) to lower temperatures through cold rolling. Int. J. Refract. Metals Hard Mater. 2016;54:351–369.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwarz G., Mendel R.R., Ribbe M.W. Molybdenum cofactors, enzymes and pathways. Nature. 2009;460(7257):839–847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendel R.R. The molybdenum cofactor. J. Biol. Chem. 2013;288(19):13165–13172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arrington L.R., Davis G.K. Molybdenum toxicity in the rabbit: two figures. J. Nutr. 1953;51(2):295–304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13097245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arthur D. Interrelationships of molybdenum and copper in the diet of the Guinea pig. J. Nutr. 1965;87(1):69–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5834577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bompart G., Pécher C., Prévot D., Girolami J.-P. Mild renal failure induced by subchronic exposure to molybdenum: urinary kallikrein excretion as a marker of distal tubular effect. Toxicol. Lett. 1990;52(3):293–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1975134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fungwe T.V., Buddingh F., Demick D.S., Lox C.D., Yang M.T., Yang S.P. The role of dietary molybdenum on estrous activity, fertility, reproduction and molybdenum and copper enzyme activities of female rats. Nutr. Res. (N.Y.) 1990;10(5):515–524.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeder H.A., Mitchener M. Toxic effects of trace elements on the reproduction of mice and rats. Arch. Environ. Health. 1971;23(2):102–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5558140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller R.F., Price N.O., Engel R.W. Added dietary inorganic sulfate and its effect upon rats fed molybdenum. J. Nutr. 1956;60(4):539–547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13385719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosoff B., Spencer H. The distribution and excretion of molybdenum-99 in mice. Health Phys. 1973;25(2):173–175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4784249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vyskočil A., Viau C. Assessment of molybdenum toxicity in humans. J. Appl. Toxicol. 1999;19(3):185–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10362269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novotny J.A., Turnlund J.R. Molybdenum intake influences molybdenum kinetics in men. J. Nutr. 2007;137(1):37–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17182798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haywood S., Dincer Z., Holding J., Parry N.M. Metal (molybdenum, copper) accumulation and retention in brain, pituitary and other organs of ammonium tetrathiomolybdate-treated sheep. Br. J. Nutr. 1998;79(4):329–331.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9624223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribeiro A.M., Flores-Sahagun T.H.S., Paredes R.C. A perspective on molybdenum biocompatibility and antimicrobial activity for applications in implants. J. Mater. Sci. 2015;51(6):2806–2816.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sebestova L., Havelek R., Rezacova M., Honzicek J., Krocova Z., Vinklarek J. Study of antitumor effect of selected vanadium and molybdenum organometallic complexes in human leukemic T-cells. Chem. Biol. Interact. 2015;242:61–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26391003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lourenco M.L., Cardoso G.C., Sousa K., Donato T.A.G., Pontes F.M.L., Grandini C.R. Development of novel Ti-Mo-Mn alloys for biomedical applications. Sci. Rep. 2020;10(1):6298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei D., Anniyaer A., Koizumi Y., Aoyagi K., Nagasako M., Kato H., Chiba A. On microstructural homogenization and mechanical properties optimization of biomedical Co-Cr-Mo alloy additively manufactured by using electron beam melting. Addit. Manuf. 2019;28:215–227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simoes T.A., Bryant M.G., Brown A.P., Milne S.J., Ryan M., Neville A., Brydson R. Evidence for the dissolution of molybdenum during tribocorrosion of CoCrMo hip implants in the presence of serum protein. Acta Biomater. 2016;45:410–418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27581397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li P., Ma X., Tong T., Wang Y. Microstructural and mechanical properties of β-type Ti–Mo–Nb biomedical alloys with low elastic modulus. J. Alloys Compd. 2020;815</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guillory R.J., Oliver A.A., Davis E.K., Earley E.J., Drelich J.W., Goldman J. Preclinical in vivo evaluation and screening of zinc-based degradable metals for endovascular stents. JOM (J. Occup. Med.) 2019;71(4):1436–1446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7962665</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33731979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierson D., Edick J., Tauscher A., Pokorney E., Bowen P., Gelbaugh J., Stinson J., Getty H., Lee C.H., Drelich J., Goldman J. A simplified in vivo approach for evaluating the bioabsorbable behavior of candidate stent materials. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. B Appl. Biomater. 2012;100(1):58–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21905215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schreiber H.A., Loschko J., Karssemeijer R.A., Escolano A., Meredith M.M., Mucida D., Guermonprez P., Nussenzweig M.C. Intestinal monocytes and macrophages are required for T cell polarization in response to Citrobacter rodentium. J. Exp. Med. 2013;210(10):2025–2039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3782042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24043764</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliver A.A., Sikora-Jasinska M., Demir A.G., Guillory R.J. Recent advances and directions in the development of bioresorbable metallic cardiovascular stents: insights from recent human and in vivo studies. Acta Biomater. 2021</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pourbaix M. Atlas of electrochemical equilibria in aqueous solution. NACE. 1974;307</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saji V.S., Lee C.W. Molybdenum, molybdenum oxides, and their electrochemistry. ChemSusChem. 2012;5(7):1146–1161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22693154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrova M., Bojinov M., Zanna S., Marcus P. Mechanism of anodic oxidation of molybdenum in nearly-neutral electrolytes studied by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Electrochim. Acta. 2011;56(23):7899–7906.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maheswari N., Muralidharan G. Controlled synthesis of nanostructured molybdenum oxide electrodes for high performance supercapacitor devices. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2017;416:461–469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirata T. In-situ observation of Mo-O stretching vibrations during the reduction of MoO3 with hydrogen by diffuse reflectance FTIR spectroscopy. Appl. Surf. Sci. 1989;40(1):179–181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sen B.K., Tiwari S., Deb M.K., Pervez S. Nanogram level quantification of molybdenum (VI) by novel hyphenated SDME/DRS-FTIR in human biological fluid. Anal. Methods. 2015;7(22):9474–9481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bharat L.K., Raju G.S.R., Yu J.S. Red and green colors emitting spherical-shaped calcium molybdate nanophosphors for enhanced latent fingerprint detection. Sci. Rep. 2017;7(1):11571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599674</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28912449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pesce C. Glomerular number and size: facts and artefacts, the anatomical record. Off. Publ. Am. Assoc. Anatom. 1998;251(1):66–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9605222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett K.M., Bertram J.F., Beeman S.C., Gretz N. The emerging role of MRI in quantitative renal glomerular morphology. Am. J. Physiol. Ren. Physiol. 2013;304(10):F1252–F1257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23515719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sasaki T., Tsuboi N., Haruhara K., Okabayashi Y., Kanzaki G., Koike K., Kobayashi A., Yamamoto I., Ogura M., Yokoo T. Bowman capsule volume and related factors in adults with normal renal function. Kidney Int. Rep. 2018;3(2):314–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29725634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao Q., Shen W., Qin W., Zheng C., Zhang M., Zeng C., Wang S., Wang J., Zhu X., Liu Z. Treatment of db/db diabetic mice with triptolide: a novel therapy for diabetic nephropathy. Nephrol. Dial. Transplant. 2010;25(11):3539–3547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haruhara K., Tsuboi N., Sasaki T., Amano H., Tanaka M., Koike K., Kanzaki G., Okabayashi Y., Miyazaki Y., Ogura M., Yokoo T. Volume ratio of glomerular tufts to Bowman capsules and renal outcomes in nephrosclerosis. Am. J. Hypertens. 2018;32(1):45–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30358804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shirato I., Hosser H., Kriz W., Kimura K., Sakai T., Tomino Y. The development of focal segmental glomerulosclerosis in Masugi nephritis is based on progressive podocyte damage. Virchows Arch. 1996;429(4):255–273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8972762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal M.K., Kalimi M. Activation of mineralocorticoid agonist and antagonist specific receptors from rat kidney. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 1987;143(1):398–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3030321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosokawa S., Yoshida O. Clinical studies on molybdenum in patients requiring long-term hemodialysis. Am. Soc. Artif. Intern. Organs J. 1994;40(3):M445–M449.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8555555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi L., Cao H., Luo J., Liu P., Wang T., Hu G., Zhang C. Effects of molybdenum and cadmium on the oxidative damage and kidney apoptosis in Duck. Ecotoxicol. Environ. Saf. 2017;145:24–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28692912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tallkvist J., Oskarsson A.  In: Handbook on the Toxicology of Metals. fourth ed. Nordberg G.F., Fowler B.A., Nordberg M., editors. Academic Press; San Diego: 2015. Chapter 47 - molybdenum; pp. 1077–1089.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachdeva S., Maret W. Comparative outcomes of exposing human liver and kidney cell lines to tungstate and molybdate. Toxicol. Mech. Methods. 2021:1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34320920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu J., Su Y., Qin Y.-X., Zheng Y., Wang Y., Zhu D. Evolution of metallic cardiovascular stent materials: a comparative study among stainless steel, magnesium and zinc. Biomaterials. 2020;230:119641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31806406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliver A.A., Guillory R.J., Flom K.L., Morath L.M., Kolesar T.M., Mostaed E., Sikora-Jasinska M., Drelich J.W., Goldman J. Analysis of vascular inflammation against bioresorbable Zn–Ag-based alloys. ACS Appl. Bio Mater. 2020;3(10):6779–6789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905847</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33644704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
