<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35322906</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-474X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>82</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of developmental neuroscience : the official journal of the International Society for Developmental Neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Dev Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Dextromethorphan reduces prenatal lipopolysaccharide exposure-induced dopaminergic neuronal loss and cytokine changes in offspring.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>261</StartPage>
          <EndPage>270</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>261-270</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jdn.10180</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Maternal infection during pregnancy may affect fetal brain development and increase the risk of developing neurological and mental disorders later in life in offspring. In this study, we used low-dose lipopolysaccharide (LPS) injection to mimic mild maternal infection at a critical time window for fetal dopamine (DA) and serotonin (5-HT) neuron development. The affected offspring exhibited reduction of dopaminergic and serotonergic neurons and anxiety- and depression-related behaviors in adulthood. In the current study, we evaluated whether dextromethorphan (DM, 30 mg/kg), an over-the-counter antitussive drug with anti-inflammatory and neuroprotective properties, could reduce the adverse effects of maternal infection mimicked by LPS exposure. We discovered that DM application did not change the baseline serum interleukin-6 (IL-6) and tumor necrosis factor α (TNFα) levels in the LPS-exposed offspring. However, DM treatment could reduce the heightened immune responses induced by a postnatal LPS challenge test in prenatal LPS-exposed offspring. The neuroprotective effect of DM was only seen in DA neurons but not in 5-HT neurons. We concluded that DM treatment can partially protect the offspring against the adverse effects of LPS-induced maternal immune activation. The reduction in heightened immune responses and dopaminergic neuronal loss in LPS-exposed offspring could potentially reduce the risk of DA-related neurological and psychiatric disorders later in life.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 International Society for Developmental Neuroscience.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chia-Yu</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy and Cell Biology, School of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sabrina</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4293-7443</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Anatomy and Cell Biology, School of Medicine, National Yang Ming Chao Tung University, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Dev Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8401784</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0736-5748</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016207">Cytokines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D008070">Lipopolysaccharides</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>333DO1RDJY</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D012701">Serotonin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>7355X3ROTS</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003915">Dextromethorphan</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>VTD58H1Z2X</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D004298">Dopamine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016207" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokines</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003915" MajorTopicYN="N">Dextromethorphan</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004298" MajorTopicYN="N">Dopamine</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008070" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lipopolysaccharides</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000633" MajorTopicYN="N">toxicity</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011297" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prenatal Exposure Delayed Effects</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000139" MajorTopicYN="N">chemically induced</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012701" MajorTopicYN="N">Serotonin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IL-6</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TNF-α</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dextromethorphan</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipopolysaccharide</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">serotonin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35322906</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jdn.10180</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bransfield, R. C., Wulfman, J. S., Harvey, W. T., &amp; Usman, A. I. (2007). The association between tick-borne infections, Lyme borreliosis and autism spectrum disorders. Medical Hypotheses, 70, 967-974.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvey, P. M., Chang, Q., Lipton, J. W., &amp; Ling, Z. (2003). Prenatal exposure to the bacteriotoxin lipopolysaccharide leads to long-term losses of dopamine neurons in offspring: A potential, new model of Parkinson's disease. Frontiers in Bioscience, 8, s826-s837.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castano, A., Herrera, A. J., Cano, J., &amp; Machado, A. (1998). Lipopolysaccharide intranigral injection induces inflammatory reaction and damage in nigrostriatal dopaminergic system. Journal of Neurochemistry, 70, 1584-1592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, D. Y., Song, P. S., Hong, J. S., Chu, C. L., Pan, I. H., Chen, Y. M., Lin, C. H., Lin, S. H., &amp; Lin, C. C. (2013). Dextromethorphan inhibits activations and functions in dendritic cells. Clinical &amp; Developmental Immunology, 2013, 125643.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dammann, O., &amp; Leviton, A. (1998). Infection remote from the brain, neonatal white matter damage, and cerebral palsy in the preterm infant. Seminars in Pediatric Neurology, 5, 190-201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Einarson, A., &amp; Koren, G. (1999). Dextromethorphan. Extrapolation of findings from reproductive studies in animals to humans. Canadian Family Physician, 45, 2309-2310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Einarson, A., Lyszkiewicz, D., &amp; Koren, G. (2001). The safety of dextromethorphan in pregnancy: Results of a controlled study. Chest, 119, 466-469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fidel, P. L. Jr., Cutright, J., &amp; Steele, C. (2000). Effects of reproductive hormones on experimental vaginal candidiasis. Infection and Immunity, 68, 651-657.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fortier, M.-E., Joober, R., Luheshi, G. N., &amp; Boksa, P. (2004). Maternal exposure to bacterial endotoxin during pregnancy enhances amphetamine-induced locomotion and startle responses in adult rat offspring. Journal of Psychiatric Research, 38, 335-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, H. M., Jiang, J., Wilson, B., Zhang, W., Hong, J. S., &amp; Liu, B. (2002). Microglial activation-mediated delayed and progressive degeneration of rat nigral dopaminergic neurons: Relevance to Parkinson's disease. Journal of Neurochemistry, 81, 1285-1297.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gayle, D. A., Beloosesky, R., Desai, M., Amidi, F., Nunez, S. E., &amp; Ross, M. G. (2004). Maternal LPS induces cytokines in the amniotic fluid and corticotropin releasing hormone in the fetal rat brain. American Journal of Physiology. Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 286, R1024-R1029.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hochstrasser, T., Ullrich, C., Sperner-Unterweger, B., &amp; Humpel, C. (2011). Inflammatory stimuli reduce survival of serotonergic neurons and induce neuronal expression of indoleamine 2,3-dioxygenase in rat dorsal raphe nucleus organotypic brain slices. Neuroscience, 184, 128-138. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2011.03.070</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holladay, S. D., &amp; Smialowicz, R. J. (2000). Development of the murine and human immune system: Differential effects of immunotoxicants depend on time of exposure. Environmental Health Perspectives, 108(Suppl 3), 463-473.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holsapple, M. P., West, L. J., &amp; Landreth, K. S. (2003). Species comparison of anatomical and functional immune system development. Birth Defects Research. Part B, Developmental and Reproductive Toxicology, 68, 321-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koumans, E. H., Sternberg, M., Bruce, C., McQuillan, G., Kendrick, J., Sutton, M., &amp; Markowitz, L. E. (2007). The prevalence of bacterial vaginosis in the United States, 2001-2004; associations with symptoms, sexual behaviors, and reproductive health. Sexually Transmitted Diseases, 34, 864-869.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauder, J. M. (1990). Ontogeny of the serotonergic system in the rat: Serotonin as a developmental signal. Ann NY Acad Sci, 600, 279-313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Letterio, J. J., Geiser, A. G., Kulkarni, A. B., Roche, N. S., Sporn, M. B., &amp; Roberts, A. B. (1994). Maternal rescue of transforming growth factor-beta 1 null mice. Science, 264, 1936-1938.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, G., Cui, G., Tzeng, N.-S., Wei, S.-J., Wang, T., Block, M. L., &amp; Hong, J.-S. (2005). Femtomolar concentrations of dextromethorphan protect mesencephalic dopaminergic neurons from inflammatory damage. The FASEB Journal, 19, 489-496.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, G., Liu, Y., Tzeng, N.-s., Cui, G., Block, M. L., Wilson, B., Qin, L., Wang, T., Liu, B., Liu, J., &amp; Hong, J.-S. (2005). Protective effect of dextromethorphan against endotoxic shock in mice. Biochemical Pharmacology, 69, 233-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim, A. I., McFadden, T., Link, V. M., Han, S.-J., Karlsson, R.-M., Stacy, A., Farley, T. K., Harrison, O. J., Shih, H.-Y., Cameron, H. A., &amp; Belkaid, Y. (2021). Maternal infection promotes offspring tissue-specific immune fitness. Science, 373(6558), eabf3002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, Y.-L., Lin, S.-Y., &amp; Wang, S. (2012). Prenatal lipopolysaccharide exposure increases anxiety-like behaviors and enhances stress-induced corticosterone responses in adult rats. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 26, 459-468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, Y.-L., &amp; Wang, S. (2014). Prenatal lipopolysaccharide exposure increases depression-like behaviors and reduces hippocampal neurogenesis in adult rats. Behavioural Brain Research, 259, 24-34. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2013.10.034</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ling, Z., Chang, Q. A., Tong, C. W., Leurgans, S. E., Lipton, J. W., &amp; Carvey, P. M. (2004). Rotenone potentiates dopamine neuron loss in animals exposed to lipopolysaccharide prenatally. Experimental Neurology, 190, 373-383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ling, Z., Gayle, D. A., Ma, S. Y., Lipton, J. W., Tong, C. W., Hong, J. S., &amp; Carvey, P. M. (2002). In utero bacterial endotoxin exposure causes loss of tyrosine hydroxylase neurons in the postnatal rat midbrain. Movement Disorders, 17, 116-124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ling, Z., Zhu, Y., Tong, C., Snyder, J. A., Lipton, J. W., &amp; Carvey, P. M. (2006). Progressive dopamine neuron loss following supra-nigral lipopolysaccharide (LPS) infusion into rats exposed to LPS prenatally. Experimental Neurology, 199, 499-512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, S.-L., Li, Y.-H., Shi, G.-Y., Tang, S.-H., Jiang, S.-J., Huang, C.-W., Liu, P.-Y., Hong, J.-S., &amp; Wu, H.-L. (2009). Dextromethorphan reduces oxidative stress and inhibits atherosclerosis and neointima formation in mice. Cardiovascular Research, 82, 161-169. https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvp043</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Y., Qin, L., Li, G., Zhang, W., An, L., Liu, B., &amp; Hong, J. S. (2003). Dextromethorphan protects dopaminergic neurons against inflammation-mediated degeneration through inhibition of microglial activation. The Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, 305, 212-218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medlock, E., Kaplan, D., Cecchini, M., Ulich, T., del Castillo, J., Andresen, J. (1993) Granulocyte colony-stimulating factor crosses the placenta and stimulates fetal rat granulopoiesis. Blood 81, 916-922.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mengistie, Z., Woldeamanuel, Y., Asrat, D., &amp; Adera, A. (2014). Prevalence of bacterial vaginosis among pregnant women attending antenatal care in Tikur Anbessa University Hospital, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. BMC Research Notes, 7, 822-827.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyer, U., Feldon, J., Schedlowski, M., &amp; Yee, B. K. (2005). Towards an immuno-precipitated neurodevelopmental animal model of schizophrenia. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 29, 913-947.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin, L., Wu, X., Block, M. L., Liu, Y., Breese, G. R., Hong, J.-S., Knapp, D. J., &amp; Crews, F. T. (2007). Systemic LPS causes chronic neuroinflammation and progressive neurodegeneration. Glia, 55, 453-462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Specht, L. A., Pickel, V. M., Joh, T. H., &amp; Reis, D. J. (1981). Light-microscopic immunocytochemical localization of tyrosine hydroxylase in prenatal rat brain. I. Early ontogeny. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 199, 233-253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urakubo, A., Jarskog, L. F., Lieberman, J. A., &amp; Gilmore, J. H. (2001). Prenatal exposure to maternal infection alters cytokine expression in the placenta, amniotic fluid, and fetal brain. Schizophrenia Research, 47, 27-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, L.-M., Wu, Q., Kirk, R. A., Horn, K. P., Ebada Salem, A. H., Hoffman, J. M., Yap, J. T., Sonnen, J. A., Towner, R. A., Bozza, F. A., Rodrigues, R. S., &amp; Morton, K. A. (2018). Lipopolysaccharide endotoxemia induces amyloid-β and p-tau formation in the rat brain. American Journal of Nuclear Medicine and Molecular Imaging, 8, 86-99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, S., Yan, J. Y., Lo, Y. K., Carvey, P. M., &amp; Ling, Z. (2009). Dopaminergic and serotoninergic deficiencies in young adult rats prenatally exposed to the bacterial lipopolysaccharide. Brain Research, 1265, 196-204. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2009.02.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, W., Wang, T., Qin, L., Gao, H. M., Wilson, B., Ali, S. F., Zhang, W., Hong, J. S., &amp; Liu, B. (2004). Neuroprotective effect of dextromethorphan in the MPTP Parkinson's disease model: Role of NADPH oxidase. The FASEB Journal, 18, 589-591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu, Y., Carvey, P. M., &amp; Ling, Z. (2007). Altered glutathione homeostasis in animals prenatally exposed to lipopolysaccharide. Neurochemistry International, 50, 671-680.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
