<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" VersionID="2" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="2">35325443</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1920-7476</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>113</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Canadian journal of public health = Revue canadienne de sante publique</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Can J Public Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Rural homelessness: how the structural and social context of small-town living influences the experience of homelessness.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>407</StartPage>
          <EndPage>416</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>407-416</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17269/s41997-022-00625-9</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Homelessness is increasingly recognized as a crisis beyond Canada's largest cities where it is most visible, yet little is known about the experience and outcomes associated with rural homelessness. The aims of this study were to explore the experience of housing insecurity and its impact on the health of rural residents, identify the various factors contributing to homelessness in a rural Ontario context, and give voice to people with lived experience about their needs, challenges, and potential solutions to the housing crisis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This exploratory qualitative study used interpretive description and a critical theory lens. Interviews were conducted with people who were currently experiencing homelessness and key informants in a rural community experiencing a housing crisis. Data collection took place between August 2020 and May 2021. Analysis was inductive and concurrent.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Findings from interviews with 27 participants (16 with lived experience and 11 key informants) revealed how the structural and social context contributed to rural homelessness. Barriers to securing rental housing in a tight market were influenced by small-town dynamics and discrimination. These experiences led to feelings of hopelessness, which combined with daily stressors of managing unsuitable living conditions to contribute to deteriorating physical and mental health. Opportunities for tailoring interventions to the rural context include increasing awareness, expanding transportation, improving access to local services, and applying Housing First principles.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Interventions to prevent and manage homelessness must be tailored to the unique rural context.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s) under exclusive license to The Canadian Public Health Association.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Buck-McFadyen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ellen</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0037-104X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Trent/Fleming School of Nursing, Trent University, 1600 West Bank Drive, Peterborough, ON, K9L 0G2, Canada. ellenbuckmcfadyen@trentu.ca.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Can J Public Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372714</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0008-4263</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006703" MajorTopicYN="Y">Homeless Persons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006798" MajorTopicYN="N">Housing</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012424" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rural Population</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012931" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Environment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012940" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Problems</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">
        <AbstractText>RéSUMé: OBJECTIFS: Le sans-abrisme est de plus en plus reconnu comme une crise qui sévit aussi hors des plus grandes villes du Canada, où il est le plus visible, mais on en sait peu sur l’expérience et les résultats cliniques associés au sans-abrisme rural. Notre étude visait à explorer l’expérience de l’insécurité du logement et ses effets sur la santé des résidents ruraux, à cerner les divers facteurs contribuant au sans-abrisme en milieu rural en Ontario et à permettre à des personnes ayant une expérience vécue d’exprimer leurs besoins, leurs difficultés et des solutions possibles à la crise du logement. MéTHODE: Cette étude qualitative exploratoire a fait appel à la description interprétative et au prisme de la théorie critique. Des entretiens ont été menés avec des gens actuellement sans abri et avec des informateurs et des informatrices dans une communauté rurale aux prises avec une crise du logement. La collecte des données s’est déroulée entre août 2020 et mai 2021. Leur analyse a été inductive et concurrente. RéSULTATS: Les constatations des entretiens avec 27 participants (16 ayant une expérience vécue et 11 informateurs et informatrices) ont révélé que le contexte structurel et social contribue au sans-abrisme rural. Les obstacles à l’obtention de logements locatifs dans un marché étroit étaient influencés par la dynamique d’une petite ville et par la discrimination. Ces expériences ont mené à des sentiments de désespoir qui, combinées au stress quotidien de conditions de vie inadaptées, ont contribué à la détérioration de la santé physique et mentale. Pour adapter les interventions au contexte rural, on peut faire de la sensibilisation, développer les transports, améliorer l’accès aux services locaux et appliquer les principes de Logement d’abord. CONCLUSION: Les interventions pour prévenir et gérer le sans-abrisme doivent être adaptées aux particularités du contexte rural.</AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s) under exclusive license to The Canadian Public Health Association.</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Homelessness</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lived experience</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rural</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social stigma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The author declares no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325443</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8944177</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17269/s41997-022-00625-9</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.17269/s41997-022-00625-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali N.  Understanding hidden homelessness. Canadian Observatory on Homelessness; 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batterham D. Defining “at-risk of homelessness”: Re-connecting causes, mechanisms and risk. Housing, Theory and Society. 2017;36(1):1–24. doi: 10.1080/14036096.2017.1408678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14036096.2017.1408678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brott H, Kornbluh M, Incaudo G, Banks L, Reece J. Placing a spotlight on rural homelessness: Identifying the barriers and facilitators to successfully supporting homeless families within rural communities. Journal of Poverty. 2018;23(3):179–201. doi: 10.1080/10875549.2018.1549184.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10875549.2018.1549184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canadian Observatory on Homelessness. (2013). How many people are homeless in Canada? Retrieved June 23, 2021 from https://www.homelesshub.ca/about-homelessness/homelessness-101/how-many-people-are-homeless-canada</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carpenter-Song E, Ferron J, Kobylenski S. Social exclusion and survival for families facing homelessness in rural New England. Journal of Social Distress and the Homeless. 2016;25(1):41–52. doi: 10.1080/10530789.2016.1138603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10530789.2016.1138603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coley RL, Leventhal T, Lynch AD, Kull M. Relations between housing characteristics and the well-being of low-income children and adolescents. Developmental Psychology. 2013;49(9):1775–1789. doi: 10.1037/a0031033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0031033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3766502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23244408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn JR, Hayes MV, Hulchanski JD, Hwang SW, Potvin L. Housing as a socio-economic determinant of health: Findings of a national needs, gaps and opportunities assessment. Canadian Journal of Public Health. 2006;97(3):S11–S15. doi: 10.1007/BF03405392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03405392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17357542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forchuk C, Montgomery P, Berman H, Ward-Griffin C, Csiernik R, Gorlick C, Jensen E, Riesterer P. Gaining ground, losing ground: The paradoxes of rural homelessness. Canadian Journal of Nursing Research. 2010;42(2):138–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadermann AM, Karim ME, Norena M, Emerson SD, Hubley AM, Russell LB, Nisenbaum R, Hwang SW, Aubry T, Palepu A. The association of residential instability and hospitalizations among homeless and vulnerably housed individuals: Results from a prospective cohort study. Journal of Urban Health. 2020;97(2):239–249. doi: 10.1007/s11524-019-00406-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11524-019-00406-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101457</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S. Making the prevention of homelessness a priority: The role of social innovation. American Journal of Economics and Sociology. 2020;79(2):353–381. doi: 10.1111/ajes.12328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajes.12328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S, Barr C, Friesen A, Harris B, Hill C, Kovacs-Burns K, Pauly B, Pearce B, Turner A, Marsolais A.  Canadian definition of homelessness. 2012. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S, Dej E.  A new direction: A framework for homelessness prevention. 2017. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S, Dej E, Richter T, Redman M.  The state of homelessness in Canada 2016 (COH Research Paper #12) 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karabanow J, Naylor T, Aube C. From place to space: Exploring youth migration and homelessness in rural Nova Scotia. Journal of Rural and Community Development. 2014;9(2):112–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kauppi, C., O’Grady, B., Schiff, R., Martin, F., &amp; Ontario Municipal Social Services Association. (2017). Homelessness and hidden homelessness in rural and northern Ontario. https://www.ruralontarioinstitute.ca/file.aspx?id=ae34c456-6c9f-4c95-9888-1d9e1a81ae9a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkpatrick SI, Tarasuk V. Housing circumstances are associated with household food access among low-income urban families. Journal of Urban Health. 2011;88(2):284–296. doi: 10.1007/s11524-010-9535-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11524-010-9535-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21286826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald S-A, Gaulin D. The invisibility of rural homelessness in a Canadian context. Journal of Social Distress and Homelessness. 2019;29(2):169–183. doi: 10.1080/10530789.2019.1688540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10530789.2019.1688540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGinty EE, Barry CL. Stigma reduction to combat the addiction crisis: Developing an evidence base. New England Journal of Medicine. 2020;382(14):1291–1292. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp2000227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp2000227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meltzer R, Schwartz A. Housing affordability and health: Evidence from New York City. Housing Policy Debate. 2015;26(1):80–104. doi: 10.1080/10511482.2015.1020321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10511482.2015.1020321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mill JE, Allen MN, Morrow RA. Critical theory: Critical methodology to disciplinary foundations in nursing. Canadian Journal of Nursing Research. 2001;33(2):109–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piat M, Polvere L, Kirst M, Voronka J, Zabkiewicz D, Plante M-C, Isaak C, Nolin D, Nelson G, Goering P. Pathways into homelessness: Understanding how both individual and structural factors contribute to and sustain homelessness in Canada. Urban Studies. 2014;52(13):2366–2382. doi: 10.1177/0042098014548138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0042098014548138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raphael, D., Bryant, T., Mikkonen, J., &amp; Raphael, A. (2020). Social determinants of health: The Canadian facts (2nd ed.) https://www.thecanadianfacts.org/The_Canadian_Facts-2nd_ed.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh A, Daniel L, Baker E, Bentley R. Housing disadvantage and poor mental health: A systematic review. American Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2019;57(2):262–272. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2019.03.018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2019.03.018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31326010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics Canada. (2017a). Census profile: 2016 census. (Catalogue No. 98-316-X2016001). Ottawa. Retrieved from http://www12.statcan.gc.ca/census-recensement/2016/dp-pd/prof/index.cfm?Lang=E</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics Canada. (2017b). Population Centre and Rural Area Classification 2016. Retrieved from https://www.statcan.gc.ca/en/subjects/standard/pcrac/2016/introduction</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics Canada  . One in ten Canadian households living in core housing need in 2018. The Daily. 2020. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swope CB, Hernandez D. Housing as a determinant of health equity: A conceptual model. Social Science and Medicine. 2019;243:112571. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.112571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.112571</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31675514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorne S, Reimer Kirkham S, MacDonald-Emes J. Interpretive description: A noncategorical qualitative alternative for developing nursing knowledge. Research in Nursing and Health. 1997;20:169–177. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1098-240X(199704)20:23.3.CO;2-B.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1098-240X(199704)20:23.3.CO;2-B</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9100747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorne, S., Reimer Kirkham, S., &amp; O’Flynn-Magee, K. (2004). The analytic challenge in interpretive description. International Journal of Qualitative Methods, 3(1).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waegemakers Schiff, J., Schiff, R., &amp; Turner, A. (2016). Rural homelessness in western Canada: Lessons learned from diverse communities. Social Inclusion, 4(4). 10.17645/si.v4i4.633</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waegemakers Schiff J, Schiff R, Turner A, Bernard K. Rural homelessness in Canada: Directions for planning and research. Journal of Rural and Community Development. 2015;10(4):85–106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson J, Crawley J, Kane D. Social exclusion, health and hidden homelessness. Public Health. 2016;139:96–102. doi: 10.1016/j.puhe.2016.05.017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.puhe.2016.05.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" VersionID="2" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="2">35325443</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>28</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1920-7476</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>113</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Canadian journal of public health = Revue canadienne de sante publique</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Can J Public Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Rural homelessness: how the structural and social context of small-town living influences the experience of homelessness.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>407</StartPage>
          <EndPage>416</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>407-416</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.17269/s41997-022-00625-9</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Homelessness is increasingly recognized as a crisis beyond Canada's largest cities where it is most visible, yet little is known about the experience and outcomes associated with rural homelessness. The aims of this study were to explore the experience of housing insecurity and its impact on the health of rural residents, identify the various factors contributing to homelessness in a rural Ontario context, and give voice to people with lived experience about their needs, challenges, and potential solutions to the housing crisis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This exploratory qualitative study used interpretive description and a critical theory lens. Interviews were conducted with people who were currently experiencing homelessness and key informants in a rural community experiencing a housing crisis. Data collection took place between August 2020 and May 2021. Analysis was inductive and concurrent.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Findings from interviews with 27 participants (16 with lived experience and 11 key informants) revealed how the structural and social context contributed to rural homelessness. Barriers to securing rental housing in a tight market were influenced by small-town dynamics and discrimination. These experiences led to feelings of hopelessness, which combined with daily stressors of managing unsuitable living conditions to contribute to deteriorating physical and mental health. Opportunities for tailoring interventions to the rural context include increasing awareness, expanding transportation, improving access to local services, and applying Housing First principles.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Interventions to prevent and manage homelessness must be tailored to the unique rural context.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s) under exclusive license to The Canadian Public Health Association.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Buck-McFadyen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ellen</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0037-104X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Trent/Fleming School of Nursing, Trent University, 1600 West Bank Drive, Peterborough, ON, K9L 0G2, Canada. ellenbuckmcfadyen@trentu.ca.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Can J Public Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0372714</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0008-4263</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006703" MajorTopicYN="Y">Homeless Persons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006798" MajorTopicYN="N">Housing</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012424" MajorTopicYN="Y">Rural Population</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012931" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Environment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012940" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Problems</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">
        <AbstractText>RéSUMé: OBJECTIFS: Le sans-abrisme est de plus en plus reconnu comme une crise qui sévit aussi hors des plus grandes villes du Canada, où il est le plus visible, mais on en sait peu sur l’expérience et les résultats cliniques associés au sans-abrisme rural. Notre étude visait à explorer l’expérience de l’insécurité du logement et ses effets sur la santé des résidents ruraux, à cerner les divers facteurs contribuant au sans-abrisme en milieu rural en Ontario et à permettre à des personnes ayant une expérience vécue d’exprimer leurs besoins, leurs difficultés et des solutions possibles à la crise du logement. MéTHODE: Cette étude qualitative exploratoire a fait appel à la description interprétative et au prisme de la théorie critique. Des entretiens ont été menés avec des gens actuellement sans abri et avec des informateurs et des informatrices dans une communauté rurale aux prises avec une crise du logement. La collecte des données s’est déroulée entre août 2020 et mai 2021. Leur analyse a été inductive et concurrente. RéSULTATS: Les constatations des entretiens avec 27 participants (16 ayant une expérience vécue et 11 informateurs et informatrices) ont révélé que le contexte structurel et social contribue au sans-abrisme rural. Les obstacles à l’obtention de logements locatifs dans un marché étroit étaient influencés par la dynamique d’une petite ville et par la discrimination. Ces expériences ont mené à des sentiments de désespoir qui, combinées au stress quotidien de conditions de vie inadaptées, ont contribué à la détérioration de la santé physique et mentale. Pour adapter les interventions au contexte rural, on peut faire de la sensibilisation, développer les transports, améliorer l’accès aux services locaux et appliquer les principes de Logement d’abord. CONCLUSION: Les interventions pour prévenir et gérer le sans-abrisme doivent être adaptées aux particularités du contexte rural.</AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s) under exclusive license to The Canadian Public Health Association.</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Homelessness</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lived experience</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rural</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social stigma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The author declares no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35325443</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8944177</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17269/s41997-022-00625-9</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.17269/s41997-022-00625-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali N.  Understanding hidden homelessness. Canadian Observatory on Homelessness; 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batterham D. Defining “at-risk of homelessness”: Re-connecting causes, mechanisms and risk. Housing, Theory and Society. 2017;36(1):1–24. doi: 10.1080/14036096.2017.1408678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14036096.2017.1408678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brott H, Kornbluh M, Incaudo G, Banks L, Reece J. Placing a spotlight on rural homelessness: Identifying the barriers and facilitators to successfully supporting homeless families within rural communities. Journal of Poverty. 2018;23(3):179–201. doi: 10.1080/10875549.2018.1549184.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10875549.2018.1549184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canadian Observatory on Homelessness. (2013). How many people are homeless in Canada? Retrieved June 23, 2021 from https://www.homelesshub.ca/about-homelessness/homelessness-101/how-many-people-are-homeless-canada</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carpenter-Song E, Ferron J, Kobylenski S. Social exclusion and survival for families facing homelessness in rural New England. Journal of Social Distress and the Homeless. 2016;25(1):41–52. doi: 10.1080/10530789.2016.1138603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10530789.2016.1138603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coley RL, Leventhal T, Lynch AD, Kull M. Relations between housing characteristics and the well-being of low-income children and adolescents. Developmental Psychology. 2013;49(9):1775–1789. doi: 10.1037/a0031033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0031033</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3766502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23244408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunn JR, Hayes MV, Hulchanski JD, Hwang SW, Potvin L. Housing as a socio-economic determinant of health: Findings of a national needs, gaps and opportunities assessment. Canadian Journal of Public Health. 2006;97(3):S11–S15. doi: 10.1007/BF03405392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03405392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17357542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forchuk C, Montgomery P, Berman H, Ward-Griffin C, Csiernik R, Gorlick C, Jensen E, Riesterer P. Gaining ground, losing ground: The paradoxes of rural homelessness. Canadian Journal of Nursing Research. 2010;42(2):138–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadermann AM, Karim ME, Norena M, Emerson SD, Hubley AM, Russell LB, Nisenbaum R, Hwang SW, Aubry T, Palepu A. The association of residential instability and hospitalizations among homeless and vulnerably housed individuals: Results from a prospective cohort study. Journal of Urban Health. 2020;97(2):239–249. doi: 10.1007/s11524-019-00406-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11524-019-00406-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101457</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S. Making the prevention of homelessness a priority: The role of social innovation. American Journal of Economics and Sociology. 2020;79(2):353–381. doi: 10.1111/ajes.12328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajes.12328</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S, Barr C, Friesen A, Harris B, Hill C, Kovacs-Burns K, Pauly B, Pearce B, Turner A, Marsolais A.  Canadian definition of homelessness. 2012. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S, Dej E.  A new direction: A framework for homelessness prevention. 2017. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetz S, Dej E, Richter T, Redman M.  The state of homelessness in Canada 2016 (COH Research Paper #12) 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karabanow J, Naylor T, Aube C. From place to space: Exploring youth migration and homelessness in rural Nova Scotia. Journal of Rural and Community Development. 2014;9(2):112–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kauppi, C., O’Grady, B., Schiff, R., Martin, F., &amp; Ontario Municipal Social Services Association. (2017). Homelessness and hidden homelessness in rural and northern Ontario. https://www.ruralontarioinstitute.ca/file.aspx?id=ae34c456-6c9f-4c95-9888-1d9e1a81ae9a</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkpatrick SI, Tarasuk V. Housing circumstances are associated with household food access among low-income urban families. Journal of Urban Health. 2011;88(2):284–296. doi: 10.1007/s11524-010-9535-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11524-010-9535-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21286826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald S-A, Gaulin D. The invisibility of rural homelessness in a Canadian context. Journal of Social Distress and Homelessness. 2019;29(2):169–183. doi: 10.1080/10530789.2019.1688540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10530789.2019.1688540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGinty EE, Barry CL. Stigma reduction to combat the addiction crisis: Developing an evidence base. New England Journal of Medicine. 2020;382(14):1291–1292. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp2000227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp2000227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meltzer R, Schwartz A. Housing affordability and health: Evidence from New York City. Housing Policy Debate. 2015;26(1):80–104. doi: 10.1080/10511482.2015.1020321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10511482.2015.1020321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mill JE, Allen MN, Morrow RA. Critical theory: Critical methodology to disciplinary foundations in nursing. Canadian Journal of Nursing Research. 2001;33(2):109–127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piat M, Polvere L, Kirst M, Voronka J, Zabkiewicz D, Plante M-C, Isaak C, Nolin D, Nelson G, Goering P. Pathways into homelessness: Understanding how both individual and structural factors contribute to and sustain homelessness in Canada. Urban Studies. 2014;52(13):2366–2382. doi: 10.1177/0042098014548138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0042098014548138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raphael, D., Bryant, T., Mikkonen, J., &amp; Raphael, A. (2020). Social determinants of health: The Canadian facts (2nd ed.) https://www.thecanadianfacts.org/The_Canadian_Facts-2nd_ed.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh A, Daniel L, Baker E, Bentley R. Housing disadvantage and poor mental health: A systematic review. American Journal of Preventive Medicine. 2019;57(2):262–272. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2019.03.018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2019.03.018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31326010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics Canada. (2017a). Census profile: 2016 census. (Catalogue No. 98-316-X2016001). Ottawa. Retrieved from http://www12.statcan.gc.ca/census-recensement/2016/dp-pd/prof/index.cfm?Lang=E</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics Canada. (2017b). Population Centre and Rural Area Classification 2016. Retrieved from https://www.statcan.gc.ca/en/subjects/standard/pcrac/2016/introduction</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Statistics Canada  . One in ten Canadian households living in core housing need in 2018. The Daily. 2020. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swope CB, Hernandez D. Housing as a determinant of health equity: A conceptual model. Social Science and Medicine. 2019;243:112571. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.112571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2019.112571</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31675514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorne S, Reimer Kirkham S, MacDonald-Emes J. Interpretive description: A noncategorical qualitative alternative for developing nursing knowledge. Research in Nursing and Health. 1997;20:169–177. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1098-240X(199704)20:23.3.CO;2-B.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1098-240X(199704)20:23.3.CO;2-B</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9100747</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorne, S., Reimer Kirkham, S., &amp; O’Flynn-Magee, K. (2004). The analytic challenge in interpretive description. International Journal of Qualitative Methods, 3(1).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waegemakers Schiff, J., Schiff, R., &amp; Turner, A. (2016). Rural homelessness in western Canada: Lessons learned from diverse communities. Social Inclusion, 4(4). 10.17645/si.v4i4.633</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waegemakers Schiff J, Schiff R, Turner A, Bernard K. Rural homelessness in Canada: Directions for planning and research. Journal of Rural and Community Development. 2015;10(4):85–106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson J, Crawley J, Kane D. Social exclusion, health and hidden homelessness. Public Health. 2016;139:96–102. doi: 10.1016/j.puhe.2016.05.017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.puhe.2016.05.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
