<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35332709</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2472-1727</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Birth defects research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Birth Defects Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Stem cell-based region-specific brain organoids: Novel models to understand neurodevelopmental defects.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bdr2.2004</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The study of human brain development and neurodevelopmental defects has remained challenging so far due to unique, specific, and complex underlying processes. Recent advances in the technologies and protocols of in vitro human brain organoid development have led to immense possibilities of understanding these processes. Human brain organoids are stem-cell derived three-dimensional in vitro tissues that resemble the developing fetal brain. Major advances in stem cell techniques pioneering the development of in vitro human brain development include reprogramming human somatic cells into induced pluripotent cells (iPSCs) followed by the targeted differentiation of iPSCs into the cells of three embryonic germ cell layers. The neural progenitor cells produced by the directed differentiation of iPSCs undergo some level of self-organization to generate in vitro human brain like tissue. A three-dimensional differentiation approach applied to create region-specific brain organoids has successfully led to develop highly specialized cortical, forebrain, pallium, and subpallium in vitro human brain organoid models. These stem cell-based brain organoids are novel models to study human brain development, neurodevelopmental defects, chemical toxicity testing, and drug repurposing screening. This review focuses on the fundamentals of brain organoid development and applications. The novel applications of using cortical organoids in understanding the mechanisms of Zika virus-induced microcephaly, congenital microcephaly, and lissencephaly are also discussed.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shafique</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sidra</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9200-3652</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical and Molecular Sciences, Queen's University, Kingston, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Birth Defects Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101701004</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zika virus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain organoids</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug repurposing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lissencephaly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microcephaly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodevelopmental defects</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stem cells</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35332709</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bdr2.2004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bershteyn, M., Nowakowski, T. J., Pollen, A. A., Di Lullo, E., Nene, A., Wynshaw-Boris, A., &amp; Kriegstein, A. R. (2017). Human iPSC-derived cerebral organoids model cellular features of Lissencephaly and reveal prolonged mitosis of outer radial glia. Cell Stem Cell, 20(4), 435-449.e4. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.STEM.2016.12.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birey, F., Andersen, J., Makinson, C. D., Islam, S., Wei, W., Huber, N., … Pasca, S. P. (2017). Assembly of functionally integrated human forebrain spheroids. Nature, 545(7652), 54-59. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature22330</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bond, J., Roberts, E., Springell, K., Lizarraga, S., Scott, S., Higgins, J., … Woods, C. G. (2005). A centrosomal mechanism involving CDK5RAP2 and CENPJ controls brain size. Nature Genetics, 37(4), 353-355. https://doi.org/10.1038/NG1539</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buesen, R., Visan, A., Genschow, E., Slawik, B., Spielmann, H., &amp; Seiler, A. (2004). Trends in improving the embryonic stem cell test (EST): An overview. ALTEX, 21(1), 15-22. Retrieved from. https://www.altex.org/index.php/altex/article/view/983</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carlson, B. M. (2013). Human embryology and developmental biology (5th ed., p. 953). Philadelphia, PA: Elsevier/Saunder.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC. (2016). Zika Virus | CDC. Retrieved from https://www.cdc.gov/zika/index.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colas, J.-F., &amp; Schoenwolf, G. C. (2001). Towards a cellular and molecular understanding of neurulation. Developmental Dynamics, 221(2), 117-145. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvdy.1144</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Lullo, E., &amp; Kriegstein, A. R. (2017). The use of brain organoids to investigate neural development and disease HHS public access. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 18(10), 573-584. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn.2017.107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donovan, K. A., An, J., Nowak, R. P., Yuan, J. C., Fink, E. C., Berry, B. C., … Fischer, E. S. (2018). Thalidomide promotes degradation of SALL4, a transcription factor implicated in Duane radial ray syndrome. eLife, 7, 1-25. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.38430</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finnell, R. H., Waes, J. G., Eudy, J. D., &amp; Rosenquist, T. H. (2002). Molecular basis of environmentally induced birth defects. Annual Review of Pharmacology and Toxicology, 42(1), 181-208. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.pharmtox.42.083001.110955</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francis, F., Meyer, G., Fallet-Bianco, C., Moreno, S., Kappeler, C., Socorro, A. C., … Chelly, J. (2006). Human disorders of cortical development: From past to present. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 23(4), 877-893. https://doi.org/10.1111/J.1460-9568.2006.04649.X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hansen, D. V., Lui, J. H., Parker, P. R. L., &amp; Kriegstein, A. R. (2010). Neurogenic radial glia in the outer subventricular zone of human neocortex. Nature, 464(7288), 554-561. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature08845</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iefremova, V., Manikakis, G., Krefft, O., Jabali, A., Weynans, K., Wilkens, R., … Ladewig, J. (2017). An organoid-based model of cortical development identifies non-cell-autonomous defects in Wnt signaling contributing to Miller-Dieker syndrome. Cell Reports, 19(1), 50-59. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.CELREP.2017.03.047</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelava, I., &amp; Lancaster, M. A. (2016). Stem cell models of human brain development. Cell Stem Cell, 18(6), 736-748. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.STEM.2016.05.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lancaster, M. A., Renner, M., Martin, C. A., Wenzel, D., Bicknell, L. S., Hurles, M. E., … Knoblich, J. A. (2013). Cerebral organoids model human brain development and microcephaly. Nature, 501(7467), 373-379. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature12517</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lenz, W. (1988). A short history of thalidomide Embryopathy. Teratology, 38, 203-215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lui, J. H., Hansen, D. V., &amp; Kriegstein, A. R. (2011). Development and evolution of the human neocortex. Cell, 146(1), 18-36. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2011.06.030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller, M. T. (1991). Thalidomide embryopathy: A model for the study of congenital incomitant horizontal strabismus. Transactions of the American Ophthalmological Society, 89, 623-674.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mlakar, J., Korva, M., Tul, N., Popović, M., Poljšak-Prijatelj, M., Mraz, J., … Avšič Županc, T. (2016). Zika virus associated with microcephaly. New England Journal of Medicine, 374(10), 951-958. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMOA1600651/SUPPL_FILE/NEJMOA1600651_DISCLOSURES.PDF</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrison, T. E., &amp; Diamond, M. S. (2017). Animal models of Zika virus infection, pathogenesis, and immunity. Journal of Virology, 91(8), 1-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muffat, J., Li, Y., Yuan, B., Mitalipova, M., Omer, A., Corcoran, S., … Jaenisch, R. (2016). Efficient derivation of microglia-like cells from human pluripotent stem cells. Nature Medicine, 22(11), 1358-1367. https://doi.org/10.1038/nm.4189</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padmanabhan, R. (2006). Etiology, pathogenesis and prevention of neural tube defects. Congenital Anomalies, 46(2), 55-67. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1741-4520.2006.00104.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pagnamenta, A. T., Murray, J. E., Yoon, G., Akha, E. S., Harrison, V., Bicknell, L. S., … Knight, S. J. L. (2012). A novel nonsense CDK5RAP2 mutation in a Somali child with primary microcephaly and sensorineural hearing loss. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 158A(10), 2577-2582. https://doi.org/10.1002/AJMG.A.35558</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pallocca, G., Grinberg, M., Henry, M., Frickey, T., Hengstler, J. G., Waldmann, T., … Leist, M. (2016). Identification of transcriptome signatures and biomarkers specific for potential developmental toxicants inhibiting human neural crest cell migration. Archives of Toxicology, 90(1), 159-180. https://doi.org/10.1007/S00204-015-1658-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prabhakar, B., Lee, S., &amp; Rasmussen, T. P. (2018). Stem cells in birth defects research and developmental toxicology (Vol. 5, pp. 1-24). Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781119283249.ch1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pushpakom, S., Iorio, F., Eyers, P. A., Escott, K. J., Hopper, S., Wells, A., … Pirmohamed, M. (2018). Drug repurposing: Progress, challenges and recommendations. Nature Reviews Drug Discovery, 18(1), 41-58. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrd.2018.168</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian, X., Nguyen, H. N., Jacob, F., Song, H., &amp; Ming, G. L. (2017). Using brain organoids to understand Zika virus-induced microcephaly. Development (Cambridge), 144(6), 952-957. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.140707</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian, X., Nguyen, H. N., Song, M. M., Hadiono, C., Ogden, S. C., Hammack, C., … Ming, G. L. (2016). Brain-region-specific organoids using mini-bioreactors for modeling ZIKV exposure. Cell, 165(5), 1238-1254. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2016.04.032</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romito, A., &amp; Cobellis, G. (2016). Pluripotent stem cells: Current understanding and future directions. Stem Cells International, 2016, 1-20. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/9451492</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rungarunlert, S., Techakumphu, M., Pirity, M. K., &amp; Dinnyes, A. (2009). Embryoid body formation from embryonic and induced pluripotent stem cells: Benefits of bioreactors. World Journal of Stem Cells, 1(1), 11-21. https://doi.org/10.4252/wjsc.v1.i1.11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schardein, J. L., Keller, K. A., &amp; Schwetz, B. A. (1989). Potential human developmental toxicants and the role of animal testing in their identification and characterization. Critical Reviews in Toxicology, 19(3), 251-339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shafique, S. (2016). How Zika virus crosses the placental barrier? International Journal of Vaccines and Research, 4(3), 23-26. https://doi.org/10.19070/2572-7427-160006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shafique, S. (2018a). Preclinical developmental toxicity testing and advanced in-vitro stem cell based systems. Timely Topics Clinical Vaccine Research, 2(1), 2-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shafique, S. (2018b). Zika-induced microcephaly and neurodevelopment. Research Journal of Congenital Disease, 1(1), 1-3. Retrieved from. http://www.imedpub.com/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shafique, S. (2019). An overview and the species-specific teratogenicity keywords: World-wide effect of TD the total estimate of the babies born with phocomelia after. Research Journal of Congenital Diseases, 2(1), 1-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simunovic, M., &amp; Brivanlou, A. H. (2017). Embryoids, organoids and gastruloids: New approaches to understanding embryogenesis. Development, 144(6), 976-985. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.143529</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Somers, G. F. (1962). Thalidomide and congenital abnormalities. Lancet (London, England), 1(7235), 912-913. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(62)91943-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stiles, J., &amp; Jernigan, T. L. (2010). The basics of brain development. Neuropsychology Review, 20(4), 327-348. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11065-010-9148-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Structural and Functional Birth Defects. (2021). Retrieved from https://birthdefects.org/structural-and-functional-birth-defects/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stummann, T. C., Hareng, L., &amp; Bremer, S. (2009). Hazard assessment of methylmercury toxicity to neuronal induction in embryogenesis using human embryonic stem cells. Toxicology, 257(3), 117-126. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.TOX.2008.12.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi, K., Tanabe, K., Ohnuki, M., Narita, M., Ichisaka, T., Tomoda, K., &amp; Yamanaka, S. (2007). Induction of pluripotent stem cells from adult human fibroblasts by defined factors. Cell, 131(5), 861-872. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2007.11.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang, H., Hammack, C., Ogden, S. C., Wen, Z., Qian, X., Li, Y., … Ming, G. L. (2016). Zika virus infects human cortical neural progenitors and attenuates their growth. Cell Stem Cell, 18(5), 587-590. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.stem.2016.02.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vasudevan, A., Long, J. E., Crandall, J. E., Rubenstein, J. L. R., &amp; Bhide, P. G. (2008). Compartment-specific transcription factors orchestrate angiogenesis gradients in the embryonic brain. Nature Neuroscience, 11(4), 429-439. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn2074</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells, P. G. (2018). A new target for thalidomide. Nature Chemical Biology, 14(10), 904-905. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41589-018-0134-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu, M., Lee, E. M., Wen, Z., Cheng, Y., Huang, W. K., Qian, X., … Tang, H. (2016). Identification of small-molecule inhibitors of Zika virus infection and induced neural cell death via a drug repurposing screen. Nature Medicine, 22(10), 1101-1107. https://doi.org/10.1038/NM.4184</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
