<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35348418</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-5116</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>60</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pharmaceutical biology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pharm Biol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Phytochemical and biological activities of some Iranian medicinal plants.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>664</StartPage>
          <EndPage>689</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>664-689</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/13880209.2022.2046112</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Due to adverse effects of synthetic compounds, there is a growing interest in utilization of plant-derived natural products in the pharmaceutical and food industries. Iranian endemic medicinal plants widely used in traditional practice have attracted much attention as antibacterial and antioxidant agents.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This review attempts to compile the accessible scientific research pertained to phytochemical compounds, antibacterial and antioxidant effects of essential oils obtained from some of the most widely used and distributed medicinal plants in Iran.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This review has been compiled using references via reliable databases (Google Scholar, SID and Science Direct) from 2010 to 2020. This literature review was limited to references published in English and Persian languages.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Based on studies heretofore carried out, essential oils isolated from mentioned medicinal plants exhibited strong antioxidant activity which is attributed to their main phytochemical compounds; thymol, carvacrol, <i>p</i>-cymene and γ-terpinene. In addition, the antibacterial activities of essential oils of most plant species from Apiaceae and Asteraceae families were more susceptible against Gram-positive bacteria; <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> and <i>Bacillus cereus</i> than Gram-negative bacteria; however, essential oils of other studied plant species manifested similar behaviours against both Gram-positive and -negative bacteria.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">As there is rich ethnobotanical knowledge behind Iranian endemic medicinal plants, further scientific research is required to prove their safety and efficacy. This review revealed that there are numerous valuable medicinal plants adoptable in food and pharmaceutical industries in the near future.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Salome</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Nutrition, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Young Researchers and Elite Club, Karaj Branch, Islamic Azad University, Karaj, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qihe</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Food Science and Nutrition, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fatemi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Faezeh</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nuclear Fuel Cycle Research School, Nuclear Science and Technology Research Institute, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Asri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Younes</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Research Institute of Forests and Rangelands, Agricultural Research, Education and Extension Organization (AREEO), Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Pharm Biol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9812552</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1388-0209</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D009822">Oils, Volatile</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D064209">Phytochemicals</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019448" MajorTopicYN="N">Ethnobotany</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007492" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Iran</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009822" MajorTopicYN="Y">Oils, Volatile</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D064209" MajorTopicYN="N">Phytochemicals</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010946" MajorTopicYN="Y">Plants, Medicinal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apiaceae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Asteraceae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iranian plant species</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lamiaceae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rosaceae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemical compounds</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">natural antibacterial agents</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">traditional uses</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">volatile oils</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348418</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967204</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13880209.2022.2046112</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alavi L, Barzegar M, Jabari A, Naghdi BH.. 
2010. Effect of heat treatment on chemical composition and antioxidant property of Thymus daenensis essential oil. J Med Plants. 9(35):129–138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amorati R, Foti MC, Valgimigli L.. 
2013. Antioxidant activity of essential oils. J Agric Food Chem. 61(46):10835–10847.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24156356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Afsari Sardari F, Mosleh G, Azadi A, Mohagheghzadeh A.. 
2019. Traditional and recent evidence on five phytopharmaceuticals from Rosa damascena Herrm. Pharmacogn Res. 6:77–84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmadi F, Sadeghi S, Modarresi M, Abiri R, Mikaeli A.. 
2010. Chemical composition, in vitro anti-microbial, antifungal and antioxidant activities of the essential oil and methanolic extract of Hymenocrater longiflorus Benth., of Iran. Food Chem Toxicol. 48(5):1137–1144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20132856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmadi R, Alizadeh A, Ketabchi S.. 
2015. Antimicrobial activity of the essential oil of Thymus kotschyanus grown wild in Iran. Int J Biol Sci. 6:239–248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmadi-Dastgerdi A, Ezzatpanah H, Asgary S, Dokhani S, Rahimi E.. 
2017. Phytochemical, antioxidant and antimicrobial activity of the essential oil from flowers and leaves of Achillea millefolium subsp. millefolium. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 20(2):395–409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akbarzadeh T, Sabourian R, Saeedi M, Rezaeizadeh H, Khanavi M, Shams Ardekani MH.. 
2015. Liver tonics: review of plants used in Iranian traditional medicine. Asian Pac J Trop Biomed. 5(3):170–181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alamholo M.
2020. Investigation of chemical composition, antibacterial and antioxidant activity of Thymus daenensis and Thymus eriocalyx essential oils against human pathogenic bacteria. J Med Microbiol. 8:148–154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alfadda AA, Sallam RM.. 
2012. Reactive oxygen species in health and disease. J Biomed Biotechnol. 2012:936486.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3424049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22927725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alizadeh A.
2015. Essential oil composition, phenolic content, antioxidant, and antimicrobial activity of cultivated Satureja rechingeri Jamzad at different phenological stages. Z Naturforsch C J Biosci. 70(3–4):51–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25924231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amin GH.
1991. Iranian traditional medicinal plants. Tehran, Iran: Research Deputy of Health Ministry Publisher.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aminzare M, Amiri E, Abbasi Z, Hassanzad Azar H, Hashemi M.. 
2017. Evaluation of in vitro antioxidant characteristics of corn starch bioactive films incorporated with Bunium persicum and Zataria multiflora essential oils. Annu Res Rev Biol. 15(5):1–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amiri F, Gholipouri A, Kheirkhah M, Mirjalili MH.. 
2019. Study on ethnobotany and the effect of ecological factor on the yield of essential oil of Ziziphora clinopodioides Lam. (case study: Yazd Province). J Med Plants By Prod. 8:189–199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amiri H.
2012. Essential oils composition and antioxidant properties of three Thymus species. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2012:728065–728073.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3163135</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21876714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amiri MS, Jabbarzadeh P, Akhondi M.. 
2012. An ethnobotanical survey of medicinal plants used by indigenous people in Zangelanlo district, Northeast Iran. J Med Plants Res. 6:749–753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amiri MS, Joharchi MR.. 
2013. Ethnobotanical investigation of traditional medicinal plants commercialized in the markets of Mashhad, Iran. Avicenna J Phytomed. 3(3):254–271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4075713</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25050282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amiri MS, Joharchi MR.. 
2016. Ethnobotanical knowledge of Apiaceae family in Iran: a review. Avicenna J Phytomed. 6(6):621–635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5206921</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amirmohammadi M, Khajoenia S, Bahmani M, Rafieian-Kopaei M, Eftekhari Z, Qorbani M.. 
2014. In vivo evaluation of antiparasitic effects of Artemisia abrotanum and Salvia officinalis extracts on Syphacia obvelata, Aspiculuris tetraptera and Hymenolepis nana parasites. Asian Pac J Trop Dis. 4:S250–S254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armana M, Azizi N, Yousefzadi M.. 
2012. Cytotoxicity, antimicrobial activity and composition of the essential oil from Salvia mirzayanii Rech. f. &amp; Esfand from Iran. J Biol Active Prod Nat. 2:54–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arumugam G, Swamy MK, Sinniah UR.. 
2016. Plectranthus amboinicus (Lour.) Spreng: botanical, phytochemical, pharmacological and nutritional significance. Molecules. 21(4):369–395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6274163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27043511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asadollahi M, Firuzi O, Jamebozorgi FH, Alizadeh M, Jassbi AR.. 
2019. Ethnopharmacological studies, chemical composition, antibacterial and cytotoxic activities of essential oils of eleven Salvia in Iran. J Herb Med. 17:100250–100302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asbaghian S, Shafaghat A, Zarea K, Kasimov F, Salimi F.. 
2011. Comparison of volatile constituents, and antioxidant and antibacterial activities of the essential oils of Thymus caucasicus, T. kotschyanus and T. vulgaris. Nat Prod Commun. 6:137–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21366065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asgharipour MR, Abjahan AA, Dahmarde M.. 
2016. Variability in Ziziphora clinopodioides subsp. bungeana (Juz.) based on morphological traits and essential oils profile. Not Bot Horti Agrobot. 44(1):189–194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashrafi B, Ramak P, Ezatpour B, Talei GR.. 
2017. Investigation on chemical composition, antimicrobial, antioxidant, and cytotoxic properties of essential oil from Dracocephalum kotschyi Boiss. Afr J Tradit Complement Altern Med. 14(3):209–217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5412227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28480433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asri Y, Sadeh-Hoseinabad Ghaini F, Vaziri A, Akbarzadeh M.. 
2017. Essential oil composition from Hymenocrater calycinus (Boiss.) Benth. in Iran. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 20(3):712–719.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attaran HR, Dini S, Fatemi F, Hesaraki S, Parhizkarie M, Dadkhah A.. 
2015. Hepatoprotective evaluation of Iranian Satureja Rechingeri essential oils against oxidative injuries induced by acetaminophen in Wistar rats. Int J Rev Life Sci. 5:204–210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attaran HR, Fatemi F, Rasooli A, Dadkhah A, Mohammadi Malayeri MR, Dini S.. 
2018. Zataria multiflora essential oil prevent iron oxide nanoparticles-induced liver toxicity in rat model. J Med Plants By Prod. 7:15–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avaei A, Mohamadi Sani A, Mahmoodzadeh Vaziri B.. 
2015. Chemical composition and antimicrobial effect of the essential oil of Zataria multiflora Boiss. endemic in Khorasan-Iran. Asian Pac J Trop Dis. 5:181–185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bagherifar S, Sourestani MM, Zolfaghari M, Mottaghipisheh J, Zomborszki ZP, Csupor D.. 
2019. Variation of chemical constituents and antiradical capacity of nine Ferulago angulata populations from Iran. Chem Biodivers. 16(10):e1900302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31415713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahadori MB, Dinparast L, Zengin G.. 
2016. The genus Heracleum: a comprehensive review on its phytochemistry, pharmacology, and ethnobotanical values as a useful herb. Comprehens Rev Food Sci Food Saf. 15(6):1018–1039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33401836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahmani M, Zargaran A, Rafieian-Kopaei M, Saki K.. 
2014. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants used in the management of diabetes mellitus in the Urmia, Northwest Iran. Asian Pac J Trop Dis. 7:S348–S354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25312149</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakkali F, Averbeck S, Averbeck D, Idaomar M.. 
2008. Biological effects of essential oils—a review. Food Chem Toxicol. 46(2):446–475.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17996351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balouiri M, Sadiki M, Ibnsouda SK.. 
2016. Methods for in vitro evaluating antimicrobial activity: a review. J Pharm Anal. 6(2):71–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5762448</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basov A, Fedulova L, Baryshev M, Dzhimak S.. 
2019. Deuterium-depleted water influence on the isotope 2H/1H regulation in body and individual adaptation. Nutrients. 11(8):1903–1922.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6723318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31443167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basti AA, Gandomi H, Noori N, Khanjari A.. 
2016. Shirazi thyme (Zataria multiflora Boiss.) oils. in essential oils in food preservation. Flav Saf. 83:731–736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bazdar M, Sadeghi H, Hosseini S.. 
2018. Evaluation of oil profiles, total phenols and phenolic compounds in Prangos ferulacea leaves and flowers and their effects on antioxidant activities. Biocatal Agric Biotechnol. 14:418–423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benzie IFF, Strain JJ.. 
1996. The ferric reducing ability of plasma (FRAP) as a measure of “antioxidant power”: the FRAP assay. Anal Biochem. 239(1):70–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8660627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertrand P, Cheong Sing A, Jacqueline Smadja A.. 
2005. Assessment of antioxidant activity of cane brown sugars by ABTS and DPPH radical scavenging assays: determination of their polyphenolic and volatile constituents. J Agric Food Chem. 53(26):10074–10079.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16366697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bezić N, Šamanić I, Dunkić V, Besendorfer V, Puizina J.. 
2009. Essential oil composition and internal transcribed spacer (its) sequence variability of four south-Croatian Satureja species (Lamiaceae). Molecules. 14(3):925–938.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6253779</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19255551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bondet V, Brand-Williams W, Berset CL.. 
1997. Kinetics and mechanisms of antioxidant activity using the DPPH free radical method. LWT Food Sci Technol. 30(6):609–615.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borges A, Ferreira C, Saavedra MJ, Simões M.. 
2013. Antibacterial activity and mode of action of ferulic and gallic acids against pathogenic bacteria. Microb Drug Resist. 19(4):256–265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23480526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borges A, Simões LC, Saavedra MJ, Simões M.. 
2014. The action of selected isothiocyanates on bacterial biofilm prevention and control. Int Biodeterior Biodegrad. 86:25–33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buso P, Manfredini S, Reza Ahmadi-Ashtiani H, Sciabica S, Buzzi R, Vertuani S, Baldisserotto A.. 
2020. Iranian medicinal plants: from ethnomedicine to actual studies. Medicina. 56(3):97–150.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7143749</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32110920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caleja C, Barros L, Antonio AL, Oliveira MB, Ferreira IC.. 
2017. A comparative study between natural and synthetic antioxidants: evaluation of their performance after incorporation into biscuits. Food Chem. 216:342–346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27596429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chouhan S, Sharma K, Guleria S.. 
2017. Antimicrobial activity of some essential oils—present status and future perspectives. Medicines. 4(3):58–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28930272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrysargyris A, Mikallou M, Petropoulos S, Tzortzakis N.. 
2020. Profiling of essential oils components and polyphenols for their antioxidant activity of medicinal and aromatic plants grown in different environmental conditions. Agron. 10(5):727–755.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox SD, Mann CM, Markham JL, Bell HC, Gustafson JE, Warmington JR, Wyllie SG.. 
2000. The mode of antimicrobial action of the essential oil of Melaleuca alternifolia (tea tree oil). J Appl Microbiol. 88(1):170–175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10735256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadkhah A, Allameh A, Khalafi H, Ashrafihelan J.. 
2011. Inhibitory effects of dietary caraway essential oils on 1,2-dimethylhydrazine-induced colon carcinogenesis is mediated by liver xenobiotic metabolizing enzymes. Nutr Cancer. 63(1):46–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21108126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadkhah A, Fatemi F, Malayeri MRM, Ashtiyani MHK, Noureini SK, Rasooli A.. 
2019. Considering the effect of Rosa damascena Mill. essential oil on oxidative stress and Cox-2 gene expression in the liver of septic rats. Turk J Pharm Sci. 16(4):416–425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadkhah A, Fatemi F, Mohammadi Malayeri MR, Rasooli A.. 
2014. Cancer chemopreventive effect of dietary Zataria multiflora essential oils. Turk J Biol. 38:930–939.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadkhah A, Fatemi F, Mohammadi Malayeri MR, Torabi F, Sarbazi M, Dini S.. 
2018. Potential protective effect of pretreatment with caraway essential oil in vivo model of iron nanoparticle-induced liver injury. J Med Plants By Prod. 7:145–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dehghan H, Sarrafi Y, Salehi P.. 
2016. Antioxidant and antidiabetic activities of herbal plants from Hyrcania region. Iran J Food Drug Anal. 24(1):179–188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28911402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhifi W, Bellili S, Jazi S, Bahloul N, Mnif W.. 
2016. Essential oils' chemical characterization and investigation of some biological activities: a critical review. Medicines. 3(4):25–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5456241</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28930135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dini S, Dadkhah A, Fatemi F.. 
2015. Biological properties of Iranian Zataria multiflora essential oils: a comparative approach. Electron J Biol. 11:57–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolatkhahi M, Dolatkhahi A, Nejad JB.. 
2014. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants used in Arjan–Parishan protected area in Fars Province of Iran. Avicenna J Phytomed. 4(6):402–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4224954</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25386404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebrahimabadi AH, Djafari-Bidgoli Z, Mazoochi A, Kashi FJ, Batooli H.. 
2010. Essential oils composition, antioxidant and antimicrobial activity of the leaves and flowers of Chaerophyllum macropodum Boiss. Food Control. 21(8):1173–1178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ehsani A, Rezaeiyan A, Hashemi M, Aminzare M, Jannat B, Afshari A.. 
2019. Antibacterial activity and sensory properties of Heracleum persicum essential oil, nisin, and Lactobacillus acidophilus against Listeria monocytogenes in cheese. Vet World. 12(1):90–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6431807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30936660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ekhtelat M, Bahrani Z, Siahpoosh A, Ameri A.. 
2019. Evaluation of antibacterial effects of Mentha spicata L., Cuminum cyminum L. and Mentha longifolia L. essential oils individually and in combination with sodium benzoate against Escherichia coli O157: H7 and Listeria monocytogenes. Jundishapur J Nat Pharm Prod. 14(3):e59092–e59100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emami Bistgani ZE, Sefidkon F.. 
2019. Review on ethnobotany, phytochemical, molecular and pharmacological activity of Thymus daenensis Celak. Biocatal Agric Biotechnol. 22:101400–101430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fallah S, Mouguee S, Rostaei M, Adavi Z, Lorigooini Z.. 
2020. Chemical compositions and antioxidant activity of essential oil of wild and cultivated Dracocephalum kotschyi grown in different ecosystems: a comparative study. Ind Crops Prod. 143:111885–111894.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falsafi T, Moradi P, Mahboubi M, Rahimi E, Momtaz H, Hamedi B.. 
2015. Chemical composition and anti-Helicobacter pylori effect of Satureja bachtiarica Bunge essential oil. Phytomedicine. 22(1):173–177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25636887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Allameh A, Khalafi H, Rajaee R, Davoodian N, Rezaei M.. 
2011. Biochemical properties of γ-irradiated caraway essential oils. J Food Biochem. 35(2):650–662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Allameh A, Khalafi H, Rezaei MB, Seyhoon M.. 
2010. The effect of essential oils and hydroalcoholic extract of caraway seed on oxidative stress parameters in rats suffering from acute lung inflammation before and after γ-irradiation. J Med Aromat. 25:441–455.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Asri Y, Rasooli I, Alipoor SD, Shaterloo M.. 
2012. Chemical composition and antioxidant properties of γ-irradiated Iranian Zataria multiflora extracts. Pharm Biol. 50(2):232–238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22092051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Dadkhah A, Akbarzadeh K, Dini S, Hatami S, Rasooli A.. 
2015. Hepatoprotective effects of deuterium depleted water (DDW) adjuvant with Satureja rechingeri essential oils. Electron J Biol. 11:23–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Dadkhah A, Rezaei M, Dini S.. 
2013. Effect of γ-irradiation on the chemical composition and antioxidant properties of cumin extracts. Food Biochem. 37(4):432–439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Dini S, Ddkhah A, Reza ZM.. 
2015. Considering the antibacterial activity of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil treated with γ-irradiation in vitro and in vivo systems. Radiat Phys Chem. 106:145–150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Dini S, Rezaei MB, Dadkhah A, Dabbagh R, Naij S.. 
2014. The effect of γ-irradiation on the chemical composition and antioxidant activities of peppermint essential oil and extract. J Essent Oil Res. 26(2):97–104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatemi F, Golbodagh A, Hojihosseini R, Dadkhah A, Akbarzadeh K, Dini S, Malayeri MR.. 
2020. Anti-inflammatory effects of deuterium-depleted water plus Rosa damascena Mill. essential oil via cyclooxygenase-2 pathway in rats. Turk J Pharm Sci. 17(1):99–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7227869</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32454767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fathi Moghaddam E, Shakerian A, Sharafati Chaleshtori R, Rahimi E.. 
2020. Chemical composition and antioxidant properties and antimicrobial effects of Satureja bachtiarica Bunge. and Echinophora platyloba DC. essential oils against Listeria monocytogenes. J Medicinal Plants By- Products. 9:47–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firuzi O, Asadollahi M, Gholami M, Javidnia K.. 
2010. Composition and biological activities of essential oils from four Heracleum species. Food Chem. 122(1):117–122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gachkar L, Yadegari D, Rezaei MB, Taghizadeh M, Astaneh SA, Rasooli I.. 
2007. Chemical and biological characteristics of Cuminum cyminum and Rosmarinus officinalis essential oils. Food Chem. 102(3):898–904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gandomi H, Misaghi A, Basti AA, Bokaei S, Khosravi A, Abbasifar A, Javan AJ.. 
2009. Effect of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil on growth and aflatoxin formation by Aspergillus flavus in culture media and cheese. Food Chem Toxicol. 47(10):2397–2400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19477213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gavanji S, Mohammadi E, Larki B, Bakhtari A.. 
2014. Antimicrobial and cytotoxic evaluation of some herbal essential oils in comparison with common antibiotics in bioassay condition. Integr Med Res. 3(3):142–152.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5481736</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28664090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgiev E, Stoyanova A.. 
2006. Handbook of the specialists in aroma industry. Plovdiv: Bulgarian National Association of Essential Oils, Perfumery and Cosmetics.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi PA, Momeni M, Bahmani M.. 
2013. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants used by Kurd tribe in Dehloran and Abdanan districts, Ilam Province, Iran. Afr J Tradit Complement Altern Med. 10(2):368–385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24146463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi G, Alirezalu A, Ghosta Y, Jarrahi A, Safavi SA, Abbas-Mohammadi M, Barba FJ, Munekata PE, Domínguez R, Lorenzo JM.. 
2020. Composition, antifungal, phytotoxic, and insecticidal activities of Thymus kotschyanus essential oil. Molecules. 25(5):1152–1170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7179150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32143475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi Pirbalouti A, Izadi A, Malek Poor F, Hamedi B.. 
2016. Chemical composition, antioxidant and antibacterial activities of essential oils from Ferulago angulata. Pharm Biol. 54(11):2515–2520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi Pirbalouti A, Nourafcan H, Solyamani-Babadi E.. 
2017. Variation in chemical composition and antibacterial activity of essential oils from Bakhtiari savory (Satureja bachtiarica Bunge.). J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 20(2):474–484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi Pirbalouti AG, Dadfar S.. 
2013. Chemical constituents and antibacterial activity of essential oil of Satureja bachtiarica (Lamiaceae). Acta Pol Pharm Drug Res. 70:933–938.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24147374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi Pirbalouti AG, Koohpayeh A, Karimi I.. 
2010a. The wound healing activity of flower extracts of Punica granatum and Achillea kellalensis in Wistar rats. Acta Pol Pharm. 67(1):107–110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20210088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi Pirbalouti AG, Malekpoor F, Enteshari S, Yousefi M, Momtaz H, Hamedi B.. 
2010b. Antibacterial activity of some folklore medicinal plants used by Bakhtiari tribal in Southwest Iran. Int J Biol. 2:55–63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghasemi Pirbalouti AG, Neshat SH, Rahimi E, Hamedi B, Malekpoor F.. 
2014. Chemical composition and antibacterial activity of essential oils of Iranian herbs against Staphylococcus aureus isolated from milk. Int J Food Prop. 17(9):2063–2071.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghavam M, Manconi M, Manca ML, Bacchetta G.. 
2021. Extraction of essential oil from Dracocephalum kotschyi Boiss. (Lamiaceae), identification of two active compounds and evaluation of the antimicrobial properties. J Ethnopharmacol. 267:113513–113541.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33172599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilca M, Stoian I, Atanasiu V, Virgolici B.. 
2007. The oxidative hypothesis of senescence. J Postgrad Med. 53(3):207–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17700000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golkar P, Mosavat N, Jalali SA.. 
2020. Essential oils, chemical constituents, antioxidant, antibacterial and in vitro cytotoxic activity of different Thymus species and Zataria multiflora collected from Iran. S Afr J Bot. 130:250–258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golparvar AR, Gheisari MM, Hadipanah A, Khorrami M.. 
2018. Antibacterial, antifungal properties and chemical composition of essential oils of Satureja hortensis L. and Satureja khuzestanica Jamzad. J Med Herb. 8:243–249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadian J, Akramian M, Heydari H, Mumivand H, Asghari B.. 
2012. Composition and in vitro antibacterial activity of essential oils from four Satureja species growing in Iran. Nat Prod Res. 26(2):98–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21827283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadian J, Esmaeili H, Nadjafi F, Khadivi-Khub A.. 
2014. Essential oil characterization of Satureja rechingeri in Iran. Ind Crops Prod. 61:403–409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadipanah A, Khorami M.. 
2016. Antimicrobial activity and chemical composition of Thymus vulgaris and Thymus daenensis essential oils. Adv Pharm J. 4:101–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haghi G, Hatami A, Ghasian F, Hoseini H.. 
2010. Antioxidant activity evaluation and essential oil analysis of Chaerophyllum macropodum Boiss. from central Iran. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 13(4):489–495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haidari F, Seyed-Sadjadi N, Taha-Jalali M, Mohammed-Shahi M.. 
2011. The effect of oral administration of Carum carvi on weight, serum glucose, and lipid profile in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. Saudi Med J. 32(7):695–700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21748206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hariri A, Ouis N, Bouhadi D, Benatouche Z.. 
2018. Characterization of the quality of the steamed yoghurts enriched by dates flesh and date powder variety H'loua. Banat's J Biotechnol. IX(17):31–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hashemi MB, Niakousari M, Saharkhiz MJ, Eskandari MH.. 
2011. Influence of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil on oxidative stability of sunflower oil. Eur J Lipid Sci Technol. 113(12):1520–1526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hashemi SM, Khodaei D.. 
2020. Antimicrobial activity of Satureja khuzestanica Jamzad and Satureja bachtiarica Bunge. essential oils against Shigella flexneri and Escherichia coli in table cream containing Lactobacillus plantarum LU5. Food Sci Nutr. 8(11):5907–5915.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7684589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33282242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hazrati S, Ebadi MT, Mollaei S, Khurizadeh S.. 
2019. Evaluation of volatile and phenolic compounds, and antioxidant activity of different parts of Ferulago angulata (schlecht.) Boiss. Ind Crops Prod. 140(111589):111589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hazrati S, Govahi M, Sedaghat M, Kashkooli AB.. 
2020. A comparative study of essential oil profile, antibacterial and antioxidant activities of two cultivated Ziziphora species (Z. clinopodioides and Z. tenuior). Ind Crops Prod. 157:112942–112949.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemati A, Azarnia M, Angaji AH.. 
2010. Medicinal effects of Heracleum persicum (Golpar). Middle-East J Sci Res. 5:174–176.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heydari P, Yavari M, Adibi P, Asghari G, Ghanadian SM, Dida GO, Khamesipour F.. 
2019. Medicinal properties and active constituents of Dracocephalum kotschyi and its significance in Iran: a systematic review. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2019:1–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6526565</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyldgaard M, Mygind T, Meyer RL.. 
2012. Essential oils in food preservation: mode of action, synergies, and interactions with food matrix components. Front Microbiol. 3:12–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3265747</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22291693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ighodaro OM, Akinloye OA.. 
2018. First line defence antioxidants—superoxide dismutase (SOD), catalase (CAT) and glutathione peroxidase (GPX): their fundamental role in the entire antioxidant defence grid. Alexandria J Med. 54(4):287–293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iqbal J, Abbasi BA, Mahmood T, Kanwal S, Ali B, Shah SA, Khalil AT.. 
2017. Plant-derived anticancer agents: a green anticancer approach. Asian Pac J Trop Biomed. 7(12):1129–1150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Işcan G, Kirimer N, Kürkcüoğlu M, Başer KHC, Demirci F.. 
2002. Antimicrobial screening of Mentha piperita essential oils. J Agric Food Chem. 50(14):3943–3946.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12083863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Izadi Z, Mirazi N.. 
2020. Identification of chemical compounds and evaluation of antioxidant and antimicrobial properties of sage (Salvia officinalis L.) essential oil at different harvest times. Qom Univ Med Sci J. 14(9):1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jahantab E, Hatami E, Sayadian M, Salahi Ardakani A.. 
2018. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants of Boyer Ahmad and Dena regions in Kohgiluyeh and Boyer Ahmad province. Iran Adv Herb. 3:12–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jalas J.
1982. Flora Iranica 1982, No. 150. New York: Springer; p. 536–538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jamzad Z.
1996. Satureja rechingeri (Labiatae)—a new species from Iran. Ann Nat Mus Wien B Für Bot Zool. 1:75–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javan AJ.
2016. Combinational effects of Trachyspermum ammi and Zataria multiflora Boiss essential oils on some pathogenic food-borne bacteria. Koomesh. 17:374–383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johri RK.
2011. Cuminum cyminum and Carum carvi: an update. Pharmacogn Rev. 5(9):63–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3210012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22096320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karim MH, Karbasi A, Mohamadzadeh SH.. 
2020. Marketing strategies and export of Iranian medicinal plants. J Med Plants By Prod. 9:101–111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kavoosi G, Purfard AM.. 
2013. Scolicidal effectiveness of essential oil from Zataria multiflora and Ferula assa-foetida: disparity between phenolic monoterpenes and disulphide compounds. Comp Clin Pathol. 22(5):999–1005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazemi M, Dakhili M, Dadkhah A, Yasrebifar Z, Larijani K.. 
2011. Composition, antimicrobial and antioxidant activities of the essential oil of Artemisia kermanensis Podl., an endemic species from Iran. J Med Plants Res. 5:4481–4486.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazemi M.
2015. Chemical composition and antimicrobial, antioxidant activities and anti-inflammatory potential of Achillea millefolium L., Anethum graveolens L., and Carum copticum L. essential oils. J Herb Med. 5(4):217–222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keshavarz A, Minaiyan M, Ghannadi A, Mahzouni P.. 
2012. Effects of Carum carvi L. (caraway) extract and essential oil on TNBS-induced colitis in rats. Res Pharm Sci. 8:1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3895295</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24459470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khajehie N, Golmakani MT, Eblaghi M, Eskandari MH.. 
2017. Evaluating the effects of microwave-assisted hydrodistillation on antifungal and radical scavenging activities of Oliveria decumbens and Chaerophyllum macropodum essential oils. J Food Prot. 80(5):783–791.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28371590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khatibi SA, Misaghi A, Moosavy MH, Basti AA, Koohi MK, Khosravi P, Haghirosadat F.. 
2017. Encapsulation of Zataria multiflora Bioss. essential oil into nanoliposomes and in vitro antibacterial activity against Escherichia coli o157: H7. J Food Process Preserv. 41(3):e12955–e12965.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kheirkhahan P, Ghavami M, Sharifan A.. 
2020. Chemical composition, antioxidant activity and antimicrobial effect of Rosa damascena Mill. essential oil against Staphylococcus aureus, Escherichia coli and Salmonella typhi. J Food Biosci Technol. 10:63–74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khodaei M, Amanzadeh Y, Faramarzi MA, Hamedani MP.. 
2018. Chemical analysis and anti-bacterial effect of essential oils from three different species of Dracocephalum in Iran. Am J Essent Oil. 6:31–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khosravi AR, Shokri H, Minooeianhaghighi M.. 
2011. Inhibition of aflatoxin production and growth of Aspergillus parasiticus by Cuminum cyminum, Ziziphora clinopodioides, and Nigella sativa essential oils. Foodborne Pathog Dis. 8(12):1275–1280.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kousha A, Bayat M.. 
2012. Bactericidal and fungicidal activity of methanolic extracts of Heracleum persicum Desf. ex Fischer against some aquatic and terrestrial animal pathogens. Int J Pharmacol. 8(7):652–656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar Y, Prakash O, Tripathi H, Tandon S, Gupta MM, Rahman LU, Lal RK, Semwal M, Darokar MP, Khan F.. 
2018. Aroma Db: a database of medicinal and aromatic plant’s aroma molecules with phytochemistry and therapeutic potentials. Front Plant Sci. 13:1081–1092.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6099104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30150996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladan Moghadam AR.
2016. Chemical composition and antioxidant activity Cuminum cyminum L. essential oils. Int J Food Prop. 19(2):438–442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langroodi AM, Fathabad AE, Moulodi F, Mashak Z, Abad MA.. 
2018. Antioxidant and antimicrobial activities of aqueous and ethanolic extracts of barberry and Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil against some food-borne bacteria. J Kermanshah Univ Med Sci. 22(2):e83087–e83094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li R, Zhenquan J, Trush MA.. 
2016. Defining ROS in biology and medicine. React Oxyg Species (Apex). 1(1):9–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5921829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29707643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahammadi Purfard AM, Kavoosi G.. 
2012. Chemical composition, radical scavenging, antibacterial and antifungal activities of Zataria multiflora Bioss. essential oil and aqueous extract. J Food Hyg Saf. 32:326–332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahboubi M, Heidarytabar R, Mahdizadeh E.. 
2017. Antibacterial activity of Zataria multiflora essential oil and its main components against Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Herba Polonica. 63(3):18–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahboubi M, Kazempour N, Khamechian T, Fallah MH, Kermani MM.. 
2011. Chemical composition and antimicrobial activity of Rosa damascena Mill. essential oil. J Biol Active Prod Nat. 1(1):19–26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahboubi M, Kazempour N.. 
2016. The antibacterial activity of Satureja khuzestanica essential oil against clinical isolates of E. coli. Jundishapur J Nat Pharm Prod. 11(2):e30034–e30040.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahboubi M.
2016. Rosa damascena as holy ancient herb with novel applications. J Tradit Complement Med. 6(1):10–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737971</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26870673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmoodi A, Roomiani L, Soltani M, Basti AA, Kamali A, Taheri S.. 
2012. Chemical composition and antibacterial activity of essential oils and extracts from Rosmarinus officinalis, Zataria multiflora, Anethum graveolens and Eucalyptus globulus. Glob Veter. 9:73–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahomoodally MF, Chintamunnee V.. 
2012. Herbal medicine commonly used against infectious diseases in the tropical island of Mauritius. J Herb Med. 2(4):113–125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majidi Z, Bina F, Kahkeshani N, Rahimi R.. 
2020. Bunium persicum: a review of ethnopharmacology, phytochemistry, and biological activities. Eur J Integr Med. 5:150–176.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazandarani M, Osia N, Mosavi AK, Bayat H.. 
2013. Ecological requirements, antioxidant activity and new chemotype essential oil from Achillea millefolium L. and Achillea micrantha Wild. in North of Iran (Golestan Province). J Med Plants By Prod. 2:33–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mazidi S, Rezaei K, Golmakani MT, Sharifan A, Rezazadeh S.. 
2012. Antioxidant activity of essential oil from Black Zira (Bunium persicum Boiss.) obtained by microwave-assisted hydro distillation. J Agric Sci Technol. 14:1013–1022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehran M, Hoseini H, Hatami A, Taghizade M.. 
2016. Investigation of components of seven species of thyme essential oils and comparison of their antioxidant properties. J Med Plants. 2:134–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Memarzadeh SM, Gholami A, Pirbalouti AG, Masoum S.. 
2020. Bakhtiari savory (Satureja bachtiarica Bunge.) essential oil and its chemical profile, antioxidant activities, and leaf micromorphology under green and conventional extraction techniques. Ind Crops Prod. 154:112719–112730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikaili P, Shayegh J, Sarahroodi S, Sharifi M.. 
2012. Pharmacological properties of herbal oil extracts used in Iranian traditional medicine. Adv Environ Biol. 6:153–158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller HE.
1971. A simplified method for the evaluation of antioxidants. J Am Oil Chem Soc. 48(2):91–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirdeilami SZ, Barani H, Mazandarani M, Heshmati GA.. 
2011. Ethnopharmacological survey of medicinal plants in Maraveh Tappeh region, north of Iran. Iran J Plant Physiol. 2:325–336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirzakhani M, Ekrami M, Moini S.. 
2018. Chemical composition, total phenolic content and antimicrobial activities of Zhumeria majdae. J Food Bioprocess Eng. 1:47–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moazzami Farida SH, Ajani Y, Sadr M, Mozaffarian V.. 
2018. Ethnobotanical applications and their correspondence with phylogeny in Apiaceae–Apioideae. Res J Pharmacogn. 5:79–97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moein M, Zomorodian K, Almasi M, Pakshir K, Zarshenas MM.. 
2017. Preparation and analysis of Rosa damascena essential oil composition and antimicrobial activity assessment of related fractions. Iran J Sci Technol Trans Sci. 41(1):87–94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moghaddam M, Mehdizadeh L, Mirzaei Najafgholi H, Ghasemi Pirbalouti A.. 
2018. Chemical composition, antibacterial and antifungal activities of seed essential oil of Ferulago angulata. Int J Food Prop. 21(1):158–170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohammadi Gholami AN, Shiravand S, Ebrahimi K.. 
2018. Chemical composition, anti-fungal properties, anti-oxidant activity and cytotoxicity of Thymus daenensis Celak. essential oil. Eco-Phytochem J Med Plants. 6:56–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mojaddar Langroodi A, Tajik H, Mehdizadeh T.. 
2019. Antibacterial and antioxidant characteristics of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil and hydroalcoholic extract of Rhus coriaria L. J Food Qual Hazards Control. 6(1):16–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moridi Farimani M, Mirzania F, Sonboli A, Moghaddam FM.. 
2017. Chemical composition and antibacterial activity of Dracocephalum kotschyi essential oil obtained by microwave extraction and hydro distillation. Int J Food Prop. 20(Suppl. 1):306–315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morteza-Semnani K, Ahadi H, Hashemi Z.. 
2016. The genus Hymenocrater: a comprehensive review. Pharm Biol. 54(12):3156–3163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27363483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morteza-Semnani K, Saeedi M, Akbarzadeh M.. 
2012. Chemical composition and antimicrobial activity of the essential oil of Hymenocrater calycinus (Boiss.) Benth. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 15(5):708–714.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mottaghipisheh J, Kiss T, Tóth B, Csupor D.. 
2020. The Prangos genus: a comprehensive review on traditional use, phytochemistry, and pharmacological activities. Phytochem Rev. 19(6):1449–1470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mozafarian V.
1996. Dictionary of Iranian plant names. Tehran, Iran: Farhang Moasser Publisher.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mumivand H, Aghemiri A, Aghemiri A, Morshedloo MR, Nikoumanesh K.. 
2019. Ferulago angulata and Tetrataenium lasiopetalum: essential oils composition and antibacterial activity of the oils and extracts. Biocatal Agric Biotechnol. 22:101407–101430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naghibi F, Mosaddegh M, Mohammadi Motamed M, Ghorbani A.. 
2005. Labiatae family in folk medicine in Iran: from ethnobotany to pharmacology. Iran J Pharm Res. 4:63–79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Najafi S, Nejad BS, Deokule S, Estakhr J.. 
2010. Phytochemical screening of Bidaria khandalense (Sant.) Loranthus capitellatus Wall., Viscum articulatum Burm. f. and Vitex negundo Linn. Res J Pharm Biol Chem Sci. 1:388–393.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasab FK, Khosravi AR.. 
2014. Ethnobotanical study of medicinal plants of Sirjan in Kerman Province. J Ethnopharmacol. 154(1):190–197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24746480</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasseri M, Golmohammadzadeh S, Arouiee H, Jaafari MR, Neamati H.. 
2016. Antifungal activity of Zataria multiflora essential oil-loaded solid lipid nanoparticles in vitro condition. Iran J Basic Med Sci. 19:1231–1237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5126225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27917280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman DJ, Cragg GM.. 
2012. Natural products as sources of new drugs over the 30 years from 1981 to 2010. J Nat Prod. 75(3):311–335.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22316239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nickavar B, Adeli A, Nickavar A.. 
2014. Analyses of the essential oil from Bunium persicum fruit and its antioxidant constituents. J Oleo Sci. 63(7):741–746.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24919477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noudeh GD, Sharififar F, Noodeh AD, Moshafi MH, Afzadi MA, Behravan E, Aref M, Sakhtianchi R.. 
2010. Antitumor and antibacterial activity of four fractions from Heracleum persicum Desf. and Cinnamomum zeylanicum Blume. J Med Plant Res. 4:2176–2180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omidpanah N, Valifard M, Esmaeili M, Yousefi R, Moghadam A.. 
2015. Antioxidant and antibacterial properties of the essential oils of two Iranian medicinal plants: Zhumeria majdae and Salvia mirzayanii. J Adv Med Sci Appl Technol. 1(1):51–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oroojalian F, Kasra-Kermanshahi R, Azizi M, Bassami MR.. 
2010. Phytochemical composition of the essential oils from three Apiaceae species and their antibacterial effects on food-borne pathogens. Food Chem. 120(3):765–770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owfi R, Safaian N.. 
2017. Overview of important medicinal plants at Fars province. Iran Med Aromat Plants. 6:4–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan SY, Litscher G, Gao SH, Zhou SF, Yu ZL, Chen HQ, Zhang SF, Tang MK, Sun JN, Ko KM.. 
2014. Historical perspective of traditional indigenous medical practices: the current renaissance and conservation of herbal resources. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2014:525340–525361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4020364</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24872833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pauli A, Kubeczka KH.. 
2010. Antimicrobial properties of volatile phenylpropanes. Nat Prod Commun. 5(9):1387–1394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20922996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pezhmanmehr M, Hasani ME, Jahansouz F, Najafi AA, Sefidkon F, Mardi M, Pirseyedi M.. 
2009. Assessment of genetic diversity in some Iranian populations of Bunium persicum using RAPD and AFLP markers. Iran J Biotechnol. 7:93–100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poljsak B, Šuput D, Milisav I.. 
2013. Achieving the balance between ROS and antioxidants: when to use the synthetic antioxidants. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2013:956792–956803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3657405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23738047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prestinaci F, Pezzotti P, Pantosti A.. 
2015. Antimicrobial resistance: a global multifaceted phenomenon. Pathog Glob Health. 109(7):309–318.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4768623</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26343252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raeisi M, Tajik H, Rohani SMR, Tepe B, Kiani H, Khoshbakht R, Aski HS, Tadrisi H.. 
2016. Inhibitory effect of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil, alone and in combination with monolaurin, on listeria monocytogenes. Vet Res Forum. 7:7–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4867031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahimi V, Hekmatimoghaddam S, Jebali A, Khalili Sadrabad E, Akrami Mohajeri F.. 
2019. Chemical composition and antifungal activity of essential oil of Zataria Multiflora. J Nut Food Secur. 4:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahimmalek M, Bahreininejad B, Khorrami M, Tabatabaei BE.. 
2009. Genetic variability and geographic differentiation in Thymus daenensis subsp. daenensis, an endangered medicinal plant, as revealed by inter simple sequence repeat (ISSR) markers. Biochem Genet. 47(11–12):831–842.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahnama M, Najimi M, Ali S.. 
2012. Antibacterial effects of Myristica fragrans, Zataria multiflora Boiss., Syzygium aromaticum, and Zingiber officinale Rosci essential oils, alone and in combination with nisin on Listeria monocytogenes. Comp Clin Pathol. 21(6):1313–1316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rakotoarivelo NH, Rakotoarivony F, Ramarosandratana AV, Jeannoda VH, Kuhlman AR, Randrianasolo A, Bussmann RW.. 
2011. Medicinal plants used to treat the most frequent diseases encountered in Ambalabe rural community, Eastern Madagascar. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 11:68–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4570514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26369781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao J, Chen B, McClements DJ.. 
2019. Improving the efficacy of essential oils as antimicrobials in foods: Mechanisms of action. Annu Rev Food Sci Technol. 10:365–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30653350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rashidipour M, Ezatpour B, Talei GR, Pournia Y.. 
2016. The carvacrol level and antibacterial properties of industrial and laboratory essential oils of the wild and cultivated Satureja khuzestanica. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 19(3):519–528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasooli A, Fatemi F, Akbarzadeh K, Dini S, Bahremand S.. 
2016. Synergistic protective activity of deuterium depleted water (DDW) and Satureja rechingeri essential oil on hepatic oxidative injuries induced by acetaminophen in rats. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 19(5):1086–1101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Razzaghi-Abyaneh M, Shams-Ghahfarokhi M, Rai M.. 
2013. Antifungal plants of Iran: an insight into ecology. Chemistry and molecular biology. Heidelberg, Berlin: Springer Publisher.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rechinger K, Wendelbo P.. 
1967. Zhumeria majdae. Nytt Mag Bot. 14:39–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rechinger K.
1982. Flora Iranica, Labiatae. Akad Druke-u Verlag. 150:479–480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rezayan A, Ehsani A.. 
2015. Evaluation of the chemical compounds and antibacterial properties of the aerial parts of Persian Heracleum persicum essence. J Babol Univ Med Sci. 17:26–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roshanaei K, Dadkhah A, Fatemi F, Dini S.. 
2017. Heracleum persicum essential oil administration in CCL4 treated rat sustains antioxidant/oxidative stress statue. Adv Biores. 8:93–101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rustaie A, Keshvari R, Samadi N, Khalighi-Sigaroodi F, Ardekani MR, Khanavi M.. 
2016. Essential oil composition and antimicrobial activity of the oil and extracts of Bunium persicum (Boiss.) B. Fedtsch.: wild and cultivated fruits. Pharm Sci. 22(4):296–301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadat-Hosseini M, Farajpour M, Boroomand N, Solaimani-Sardou F.. 
2017. Ethnopharmacological studies of indigenous medicinal plants in the south of Kerman, Iran. J Ethnopharmacol. 199:194–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28167292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saei-Dehkordi S, Fallah AA, Heidari-Nasirabadi M, Moradi M.. 
2012. Chemical composition, antioxidative capacity and interactive antimicrobial potency of Satureja khuzestanica Jamzad essential oil and antimicrobial agents against selected food-related microorganisms. J Food Sci Technol. 47(8):1579–1585.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saeidi M, Asili J, Emami SA, Moshtaghi N, Malekzadeh-Shafaroudi S.. 
2019. Comparative volatile composition, antioxidant and cytotoxic evaluation of the essential oil of Zhumeria majdae from south of Iran. Iran J Basic Med Sci. 1:80–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437462</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944712</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Safa O, Soltanipoor MA, Rastegar S, Kazemi M, Dehkordi KN, Ghannadi A.. 
2013. An ethnobotanical survey on Hormozgan Province. Iran J Phytomed. 3:64–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4075690</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25050260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahari Moghadam A, Mehrafarin A, Naghdi Badi H.. 
2017. Chemical composition and antioxidant activity Achillea millefolium L. essential oils. Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 20(1):293–297.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saharkhiz M, Motamedi M, Zomorodian K, Pakshir K, Miri R, Hemyari K.. 
2012. Chemical composition, antifungal and antibiofilm activities of the essential oil of Mentha piperita L. ISRN Pharm. 2012:718645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3532871</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23304561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saharkhiz MJ, Zomorodian K, Taban A, Pakshir K, Heshmati K, Rahimi MJ.. 
2016. Chemical composition and antimicrobial activities of three Satureja species against food-borne pathogens. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 19(8):1984–1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saidi M.
2014. Antioxidant activities and chemical composition of essential oils from Satureja khuzestanica, Oliveria decumbens and Thymus daenensis. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 17(3):513–521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sajed H, Sahebkar A, Iranshahi M.. 
2013. Zataria multiflora Boiss. (Shirazi thyme)—an ancient condiment with modern pharmaceutical uses. J Ethnopharmacol. 145(3):686–698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23266333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sayhoon M, Rajaie R, Hosseini SL, Nasiri SS, Sarabi M.. 
2013. Investigation of antibacterial activity of essential oil of gamma irradiated caraway seeds (Carum carvi L.). J Nucl Sci Technol. 1:60–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharafati Chaleshtori F, Saholi M, Sharafati Chaleshtori R.. 
2018. Chemical composition, antioxidant and antibacterial activity of Bunium persicum, Eucalyptus globulus, and Rose Water on multidrug-resistant Listeria species. J Evid Based Integr Med. 23:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871051</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29405759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidi Damyeh MS, Niakousari M, Saharkhiz MJ.. 
2016. Ultrasound pretreatment impact on Prangos ferulacea Lindl. and Satureja macrosiphonia Bornm. essential oil extraction and comparing their physicochemical and biological properties. Ind Crops Prod. 87:105–115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidi Damyeh MS, Niakousari M.. 
2016. Impact of ohmic-assisted hydrodistillation on kinetics data, physicochemical and biological properties of Prangos ferulacea Lindle. essential oil: comparison with conventional hydrodistillation. Innov Food Sci Emerg Technol. 33:387–396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senatore F, Urrunaga Soria E, Urrunaga Soria R, Della Porta G, De Feo V.. 
1998. Essential oils from two Peruvian Satureja species. Flavour Fragr J. 13(1):1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shafaghat A, Shafaghatlonba M.. 
2011. Comparison of biological activity and chemical constituents of the essential oils from leaves of Thymus caucasicus, T. kotschyanus and T. vulgaris. J Essent Oil-Bear. 14(6):786–791.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahabi N, Tajik H, Moradi M, Forough M, Ezati P.. 
2017. Physical, antimicrobial and antibiofilm properties of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil nanoemulsion. Int J Food Sci Technol. 52(7):1645–1652.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahbazi Y, Shavisi N, Karami N, Kakaei S.. 
2015. Chemical composition and in vitro antibacterial activity of Ferulago angulata (Schlecht.) Boiss essential oil. Pharm Sci. 21(1):6–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahbazi Y, Shavisi N, Modarresi M, Karami N.. 
2016. Chemical composition, antibacterial and antioxidant activities of essential oils from the aerial parts of Ferulago angulata (Schlecht.) Boiss and Ferulago bernardii Tomk. &amp; M. Pimen from different parts of Iran. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 19(7):1627–1638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahbazi Y.
2015. Chemical composition and in vitro antibacterial effect of Ziziphora clinopodioides essential oil. Pharm Sci. 21(2):51–56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahbazi Y.
2017. Chemical compositions, antioxidant and antimicrobial properties of Ziziphora clinopodioides Lam. essential oils collected from different parts of Iran. J Food Sci Technol. 54(11):3491–3503.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5629158</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shakib P, Taherikalani M, Ramazanzadeh R.. 
2018. Chemical composition, genotoxicity and antimicrobial activities of Dracocephalum kotschyi Boiss. against OXA-48 producing Klebsiella pneumoniae isolated from major hospitals of Kurdistan Province. Microbiol Res J Int. 24(3):1–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharififar F, Derakhshanfar A, Dehghan-Nudeh G, Abbasi N, Abbasi R, Gharaei RR, Koohpayeh A.. 
2011. In vivo antioxidant activity of Zataria multiflora Boiss. essential oil. Pak J Pharm Sci. 24:221–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21454174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shariatifar N, Mostaghim T, Afshar A, Mohammadpourfard I, Sayadi M, Rezaei M.. 
2017. Antibacterial properties of essential oil of Heracleum persicum (Golpar) and food-borne pathogens. Int J Enteric Pathog. 5(2):41–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma P, Jha AB, Dubey RS, Pessarakli M.. 
2012. Reactive oxygen species, oxidative damage, and antioxidative defense mechanism in plants under stressful conditions. J Bot. 2012:217037–217063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheibani M, Nayernouri T, Dehpour A.. 
2018. Herbal medicines and other traditional remedies in Iran—a tragedy unfolds. Arch Iran Med. 21(7):312–314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30041530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheikholeslami S, Mousavi SE, Ashtiani HR, Doust SR, Rezayat SM.. 
2016. Antibacterial activity of silver nanoparticles and their combination with Zataria multiflora essential oil and methanol extract. Jundishapur J Microbiol. 9(10):e36070.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5136444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27942360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srinivasan K.
2018. Cumin (Cuminum cyminum) and black cumin (Nigella sativa) seeds: traditional uses, chemical constituents, and nutraceutical effects. J Food Saf. 2(1):1–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevanovic ZD, Sieniawska E, Glowniak K, Obradovic N, Pajic-Lijakovic I.. 
2020. Natural macromolecules as carriers for essential oils: from extraction to biomedical application. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 8:563–587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7330110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32671026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swamy MK, Akhtar MS, Sinniah UR.. 
2016. Antimicrobial properties of plant essential oils against human pathogens and their mode of action: an updated review. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2016:3012462–3012483.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5206475</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28090211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taherpour AA, Khaef S, Yari A, Nikeafshar S, Fathi M, Ghambari S.. 
2017. Chemical composition analysis of the essential oil of Mentha piperita L. from Kermanshah, Iran by hydrodistillation and HS/SPME methods. J Anal Sci Technol. 8(1):1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taherpour AA, Maroofi H, Changizi M, Shoushtari RV, Larijani K, Kazempour A.. 
2011. Chemical compositions of the essential oil and calculation the biophysicochemical coefficients of the components of Hymenocrater longiflorus Benth. of Iran. Nat Sci. 3(2):104–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tavakoli HR, Mashak Z, Moradi B, Sodagari HR.. 
2015. Antimicrobial activities of the combined use of Cuminum cyminum L. essential oil, nisin and storage temperature against Salmonella typhimurium and Staphylococcus aureus in vitro. Jundishapur J Microbiol. 8(4):e24838–e24845.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4449852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26034554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veeresham C.
2012. Natural products derived from plants as a source of drugs. J Adv Pharm Technol Res. 3(4):200–201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3560124</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23378939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yazdani M, Jookar Kashi F, Dashti Zadeh Z.. 
2019. Evaluation of antimicrobial and antioxidant activity of essential oil of Mentha piperita L. Iran J Med Microbiol. 13(3):210–219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yousefi K, Hamedeyazdan S, Hodaei D, Lotfipour F, Baradaran B, Orangi M, Fathiazad F.. 
2017. An in vitro ethnopharmacological study on Prangos ferulacea: a wound healing agent. Bioimpacts. 7(2):75–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5524988</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28752071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zinoviadou KG, Koutsoumanis KP, Biliaderis CG.. 
2009. Physico-chemical properties of whey protein isolate films containing oregano oil and their antimicrobial action against spoilage flora of fresh beef. Meat Sci. 82(3):338–345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20416718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zolfaghari MR, Jalali Yazdi A, Fatemi F.. 
2015. Effect of γ-irradiation on the antibacterial activities of Cuminum cyminum L. essential oils in vitro and in in vivo systems. J Essent Oil-Bear Plants. 18:582–591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zomorodian K, Ghadiri P, Saharkhiz MJ, Moein MR, Mehriar P, Bahrani F, Golzar T, Pakshir K, Fani MM.. 
2015. Antimicrobial activity of seven essential oils from Iranian aromatic plants against common causes of oral infections. Jundishapur J Microbiol. 8(2):e17766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4353034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25793100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zomorodian K, Moein M, Pakshir K, Karami F, Sabahi Z.. 
2017. Chemical composition and antimicrobial activities of the essential oil from Salvia mirzayanii leaves. Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 22(4):770–776.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5871294</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28689440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
