<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35342963</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4598</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>65</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Muscle &amp; nerve</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Muscle Nerve</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Serum thyroid-stimulating hormone is an independent risk factor of recurrent Guillain-Barré syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>688</StartPage>
          <EndPage>692</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>688-692</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mus.27539</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION/AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Guillain-Barré syndrome (GBS) is generally considered to be monophasic, but some patients have recurrences. The purpose of this study was to clarify the possible link between thyroid parameters and recurrent GBS (RGBS) patients in China.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this retrospective study we enrolled patients who were admitted to the Department of Neurology of The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University from 2014 to 2020 and fulfilled the diagnostic criteria of GBS or Miller Fisher syndrome. We evaluated clinical characteristics; cerebrospinal fluid parameters; and serum levels of thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH), free thyroxine, and free triiodothyronine in 320 individuals, including 302 with monophasic GBS and 18 with recurrent GBS.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Serum levels of TSH in monophasic GBS patients were significantly lower than those in RGBS patients (P &lt; .001), whereas FT3 levels were higher in the monophasic GBS group (P = .022). Age at onset, incidence of antecedent illness, time from onset to nadir, proportion with acute inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy, and Hughes Functional Grading Scale score at nadir were statistically significant between monophasic GBS patients and RGBS patients (P &lt; .05). The multivariate regression analysis revealed that antecedent illness, AIDP, and high TSH were independent risk factors for RGBS. Our receiver-operating characteristic curve analysis showed that the risk of recurrence in GBS patients increases when the TSH concentration is higher than 3.87 μIU/mL.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results demonstrate an association between TSH and RGBS. Oxidative stress is one of the possible interpretations for this association.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Luo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhiya</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tao</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2473-997X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Muscle Nerve</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7803146</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0148-639X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>9002-71-5</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D013972">Thyrotropin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020275" MajorTopicYN="Y">Guillain-Barre Syndrome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019846" MajorTopicYN="Y">Miller Fisher Syndrome</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013972" MajorTopicYN="N">Thyrotropin</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Guillain-Barré syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">free thyroxine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">free triiodothyronine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recurrence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyroid-stimulating hormone</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35342963</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mus.27539</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakerley BR, Yuki N. Infectious and noninfectious triggers in Guillain-Barré syndrome. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2013;9:627-639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grand′ Maison F, Feasby TE, Hahn AF, et al. Recurrent Guillain-Barré syndrome. Clinical and laboratory features. Brain. 1992;115:1093-1106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das A, Kalita J, Misra UK. Recurrent Guillain Barré syndrome. Electromyogr Clin Neurophysiol. 2004;44:95-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishii J, Yuki N, Kawamoto M, Yoshimura H, Kusunoki S, Kohara N. Recurrent Guillain-Barré syndrome, Miller Fisher syndrome and Bickerstaff brainstem encephalitis. J Neurol Sci. 2016;364:59-64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malek E, Salameh J. Guillain-Barré syndrome. Semin Neurol. 2019;39:589-595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tu Y, Gong X, Zeng G, et al. Differences in thyroid function and autoantibodies in the development of Guillain-Barré syndrome vs chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculoneuropathy. Front Neurol. 2020;11:1018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van der Meché FG, Van Doorn PA, Meulstee J, et al. Diagnostic and classification criteria for the Guillain-Barré syndrome. Eur Neurol. 2001;45:133-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakerley BR, Uncini A, Yuki N. Guillain-Barré and Miller Fisher syndromes---new diagnostic classification. Nat Rev Neurol. 2014;10:537-444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruts L, Drenthen J, Jacobs BC, van Doorn PA, on behalf of the Dutch GBS Study Group. Distinguishing acute-onset CIDP from fluctuating Guillain-Barré syndrome: a prospective study. Neurology. 2010;74:1680-1686.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes RA, Newsom-Davis JM, Perkin GD, et al. Controlled trial prednisolone in acute polyneuropathy. Lancet. 1978;2:750-753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ho TW, Mishu B, Li CY, et al. Guillain-Barré syndrome in northern China. Relationship to Campylobacter jejuni infection and anti-glycolipid antibodies. Brain. 1995;118:597-605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang Y, Ying Z, Chen Z, et al. Thyroid hormone level is associated with the frequency and severity of Guillain-Barré syndrome. Int J Neurosci. 2017;127:893-899.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang M, Ma Z, Qin H, Yao Z. Thyroid hormone potentially benefits multiple sclerosis via facilitating remyelination. Mol Neurobiol. 2016;53:4406-4416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ausó E, Lavado-Autric R, Cuevas E, et al. A moderate and transient deficiency of maternal thyroid function at the beginning of fetal neocorticogenesis alters neuronal migration. Endocrinology. 2004;145:4037-4047.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang M, Zhan XL, Ma ZY, Chen XS, Cai QY, Yao ZX. Thyroid hormone alleviates demyelination induced by cuprizone through its role in remyelination during the remission period. Exp Biol Med (Maywood). 2015;240:1183-1196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long Y, Zheng Y, Chen M, et al. Serum thyroid-stimulating hormone and anti-thyroglobulin antibody are independently associated with lesions in spinal cord in central nervous system demyelinating diseases. PLoS One. 2014;9:e100672.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao W, Zeng H, Zhang X, et al. A high thyroid stimulating hormone level is associated with diabetic peripheral neuropathy in type 2 diabetes patients. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2016;115:122-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torun AN, Kulaksizoglu S, Kulaksizoglu M, Pamuk BO, Isbilen E, Tutuncu NB. Serum total antioxidant status and lipid peroxidation marker malondialdehyde levels in overt and subclinical hypothyroidism. Clin Endocrinol. 2009;70:469-474.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cebeci E, Alibaz-Oner F, Usta M, Yurdakul S, Erguney M. Evaluation of oxidative stress, the activities of paraoxonase and arylesterase in patients with subclinical hypothyroidism. J Invest Med. 2012;60:23-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dib M, Garrel C, Favier A, Robin V, Desnuelle C. Can malondialdehyde be used as a biological marker of progression in neurodegenerative disease. J Neurol. 2002;249:367-374.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith KJ, Kapoor R, Felts PA. Demyelination: the role of reactive oxygen and nitrogen species. Brain Pathol. 1999;9:69-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodella U, Scorzeto M, Duregotti E, et al. An animal model of Miller Fisher syndrome: mitochondrial hydrogen peroxide is produced by the autoimmune attack of nerve terminals and activates Schwann cells. Neurobiol Dis. 2016;96:95-104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pandolfi C, Filippi C. Guillain-Barré syndrome associated with hypothyroidism. Report of a case. Minerva Med. 1989;80:1129-1131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali A, Malik WT, Raja U, Khan FA, Javaid I. Thyroid storm, a mimicker of Guillain-Barre syndrome: a case report. Cureus. 2020;12:e9918.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Comi C. Fas-mediated T-cell apoptosis in chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy. J Peripher Nerv Syst. 2011;16(Suppl 1):45-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
