<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35348903</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-2199</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>29</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Amino acids</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Amino Acids</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Integrated transcriptomic and proteomic analyses for the characterization of parathyroid oxyphil cells in uremic patients.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00726-022-03126-8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Chief cells are the predominant cells in parathyroid glands of healthy adults; however, parathyroid oxyphil cells, whose function is unknown, increase dramatically in patients with secondary hyperparathyroidism (SHPT). Calcitriol and calcimimetics are the most powerful treatments for SHPT, while the mechanisms leading to calcitriol or calcimimetic resistance in oxyphil cell-predominant SHPT are unknown. Here we used transcriptomic and proteomic techniques to characterize oxyphil cells by comparing the differences between chief and oxyphil cell nodules of parathyroid glands in uremic patients. Compared to chief cell nodules, the most marked expression increases in oxyphil cell nodules were for mitochondrion-associated proteins. The mitochondria number and mitochondrial DNA content were also significantly increased in oxyphil cell nodules. Moreover, oxyphil cell nodules expressed parathyroid-specific factors, and exhibited lower levels of proliferation-related proteins but higher synthesis and secretion level of parathyroid hormone (PTH). The protein expression of SHPT-regulating factors, including vitamin-D receptor, calcium-sensing receptor and Klotho, were significantly downregulated in oxyphil cell nodules. Therefore, oxyphil cells characterized by enrich mitochondria in uremic patients showed higher synthesis and secretion of PTH but lower expression of SHPT regulators than chief cells, which may contribute to the pathophysiology of SHPT and the treatment resistance to calcitriol and calcimimetics.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Austria, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jianping</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9371-6192</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>You</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huaizhou</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mengjing</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Minmin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. chenjing1998@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. chenjing1998@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Austria</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Amino Acids</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9200312</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0939-4451</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcimimetics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcitriol</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondrion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parathyroid oxyphil cell</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptomic</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>21</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348903</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-022-03126-8</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00726-022-03126-8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anders S, Pyl PT, Huber W (2015) HTSeq–a Python framework to work with high-throughput sequencing data. Bioinformatics 31(2):166–169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basile C, Lomonte C (2017) The function of the parathyroid oxyphil cells in uremia: still a mystery? Kidney Int 92(5):1046–1048</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29055426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bienaimé F, Prié D, Friedlander G, Souberbielle JC (2011) Vitamin D metabolism and activity in the parathyroid gland. Mol Cell Endocrinol 347(1–2):30–41</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21664247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Block GA, Martin KJ, de Francisco AL, Turner SA, Avram MM, Suranyi MG, Hercz G, Cunningham J, Abu-Alfa AK, Messa P, Coyne DW, Locatelli F, Cohen RM, Evenepoel P, Moe SM, Fournier A, Braun J, McCary LC, Zani VJ, Olson KA, Drüeke TB, Goodman WG (2004) Cinacalcet for secondary hyperparathyroidism in patients receiving hemodialysis. N Engl J Med 350(15):1516–1525</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolger AM, Lohse M, Usadel B (2014) Trimmomatic: a flexible trimmer for Illumina sequence data. Bioinformatics 30(15):2114–2120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24695404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">24695404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borràs M, Torregrossa V, Oliveras A, Almirall J, Ma Paz M, Betriu A, Martin M, Muray S, Fibla J, Fernández E (2003) BB genotype of the vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism postpones parathyroidectomy in hemodialysis patients. J Nephrol 16(1):116–120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12649542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canalejo A, Almadén Y, Torregrosa V, Gomez-Villamandos JC, Ramos B, Campistol JM, Felsenfeld AJ, Rodríguez M (2000) The in vitro effect of calcitriol on parathyroid cell proliferation and apoptosis. J Am Soc Nephrol 11(10):1865–1872</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11004217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie AC (1967) The parathyroid oxyphil cells. J Clin Pathol 20(4):591–602</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4880406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">473518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conesa A, Götz S, García-Gómez JM, Terol J, Talón M, Robles M (2005) Blast2GO: a universal tool for annotation, visualization and analysis in functional genomics research. Bioinformatics 21(18):3674–3676</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham J, Locatelli F, Rodriguez M (2011) Secondary hyperparathyroidism: pathogenesis, disease progression, and therapeutic options. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 6(4):913–921</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21454719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delhomme N, Padioleau I, Furlong EE, Steinmetz LM (2012) easyRNASeq: a bioconductor package for processing RNA-Seq data. Bioinformatics 28(19):2532–2533</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22847932</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3463124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan Y, Liu W, Bi R, Densmore MJ, Sato T, Mannstadt M, Yuan Q, Zhou X, Olauson H, Larsson TE, Toka HR, Pollak MR, Brown EM, Lanske B (2018) Interrelated role of Klotho and calcium-sensing receptor in parathyroid hormone synthesis and parathyroid hyperplasia. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 115(16):E3749-e3758</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29618612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5910831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galitzer H, Ben-Dov IZ, Silver J, Naveh-Many T (2010) Parathyroid cell resistance to fibroblast growth factor 23 in secondary hyperparathyroidism of chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 77(3):211–218</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghazalpour A, Bennett B, Petyuk VA, Orozco L, Hagopian R, Mungrue IN, Farber CR, Sinsheimer J, Kang HM, Furlotte N, Park CC, Wen PZ, Brewer H, Weitz K, Camp DG 2nd, Pan C, Yordanova R, Neuhaus I, Tilford C, Siemers N, Gargalovic P, Eskin E, Kirchgessner T, Smith DJ, Smith RD, Lusis AJ (2011) Comparative analysis of proteome and transcriptome variation in mouse. PLoS Genet 7(6):e1001393</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21695224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3111477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Z, Gu H, Hu J, Hu S, Wang X, Liu X, Jiao X, Liu X (2018) Quantitative proteomics identify an association between extracellular matrix degradation and immunopathology of genotype VII Newcastle disease virus in the spleen in chickens. J Proteomics 181:201–212</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29684681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang S, Chen L, Te R, Qiao J, Wang J, Zhang W (2013) Complementary iTRAQ proteomics and RNA-seq transcriptomics reveal multiple levels of regulation in response to nitrogen starvation in Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803. Mol Biosyst 9(10):2565–2574</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23942477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kan S, Zhang W, Mao J, Wang M, Ni L, Zhang M, Zhang Q, Chen J (2018) NF-κB activation contributes to parathyroid cell proliferation in chronic kidney disease. J Nephrol 31(6):941–951</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30171599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanehisa M, Goto S, Sato Y, Furumichi M, Tanabe M (2012) KEGG for integration and interpretation of large-scale molecular data sets. Nucleic Acids Res 40(Database issue):D109–D114</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karthikkeyan G, Subbannayya Y, Najar MA, Mohanty V, Pinto SM, Arunachalam C, Prasad TSK, Murthy KR (2018) Human optic nerve: an enhanced proteomic expression profile. OMICS 22(10):642–652</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30346883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kasdon EJ, Rosen S, Cohen RB, Silen W (1981) Surgical pathology of hyperparathyroidism. Usefulness of fat stain and problems in interpretation. Am J Surg Pathol 5(4):381–384</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6168205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazama JJ, Sato F, Omori K, Hama H, Yamamoto S, Maruyama H, Narita I, Gejyo F, Yamashita T, Fukumoto S, Fukagawa M (2005) Pretreatment serum FGF-23 levels predict the efficacy of calcitriol therapy in dialysis patients. Kidney Int 67(3):1120–1125</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15698453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim D, Langmead B, Salzberg SL (2015) HISAT: a fast spliced aligner with low memory requirements. Nat Methods 12(4):357–360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4655817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4655817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komaba H, Fukagawa M (2010) FGF23-parathyroid interaction: implications in chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 77(4):292–298</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komaba H, Nakanishi S, Fujimori A, Tanaka M, Shin J, Shibuya K, Nishioka M, Hasegawa H, Kurosawa T, Fukagawa M (2010) Cinacalcet effectively reduces parathyroid hormone secretion and gland volume regardless of pretreatment gland size in patients with secondary hyperparathyroidism. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 5(12):2305–2314</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2994093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li S, Mao J, Wang M, Zhang M, Ni L, Tao Y, Huang B, Chen J (2018) Comparative proteomic analysis of chief and oxyphil cell nodules in refractory uremic hyperparathyroidism by iTRAQ coupled LC-MS/MS. J Proteomics 179:42–52</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindberg JS, Culleton B, Wong G, Borah MF, Clark RV, Shapiro WB, Roger SD, Husserl FE, Klassen PS, Guo MD, Albizem MB, Coburn JW (2005) Cinacalcet HCl, an oral calcimimetic agent for the treatment of secondary hyperparathyroidism in hemodialysis and peritoneal dialysis: a randomized, double-blind, multicenter study. J Am Soc Nephrol 16(3):800–807</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Li H, Su J, Xu S, Zhu F, Ai J, Hu Z, Zhou M, Tian J, Su Z, Yang P, Nie J (2019) Numb depletion promotes Drp1-mediated mitochondrial fission and exacerbates mitochondrial fragmentation and dysfunction in acute kidney injury. Antioxid Redox Signal 30(15):1797–1816</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29890853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lomonte C, Martino R, Selvaggiolo M, Bona RM, Cazzato F, Milano R, Chiarulli G, Basile C (2003) Calcitriol pulse therapy and histology of parathyroid glands in hemodialysis patients. J Nephrol 16(5):716–720</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14733419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lomonte C, Vernaglione L, Chimienti D, Bruno A, Cocola S, Teutonico A, Cazzato F, Basile C (2008) Does vitamin D receptor and calcium receptor activation therapy play a role in the histopathologic alterations of parathyroid glands in refractory uremic hyperparathyroidism? Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3(3):794–799</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322048</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2386693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma J, Chen T, Wu S, Yang C, Bai M, Shu K, Li K, Zhang G, Jin Z, He F, Hermjakob H, Zhu Y (2019) iProX: an integrated proteome resource. Nucleic Acids Res 47(D1):D1211–D1217</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malberti F, Marcelli D, Conte F, Limido A, Spotti D, Locatelli F (2001) Parathyroidectomy in patients on renal replacement therapy: an epidemiologic study. J Am Soc Nephrol 12(6):1242–1248</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11373348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mei H, Sun S, Bai Y, Chen Y, Chai R, Li H (2015) Reduced mtDNA copy number increases the sensitivity of tumor cells to chemotherapeutic drugs. Cell Death Dis 6(4):e1710</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25837486</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4650546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Messa P, Macário F, Yaqoob M, Bouman K, Braun J, von Albertini B, Brink H, Maduell F, Graf H, Frazão JM, Bos WJ, Torregrosa V, Saha H, Reichel H, Wilkie M, Zani VJ, Molemans B, Carter D, Locatelli F (2008) The OPTIMA study: assessing a new cinacalcet (Sensipar/Mimpara) treatment algorithm for secondary hyperparathyroidism. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3(1):36–45</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18178780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2390975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemeth EF, Heaton WH, Miller M, Fox J, Balandrin MF, Van Wagenen BC, Colloton M, Karbon W, Scherrer J, Shatzen E, Rishton G, Scully S, Qi M, Harris R, Lacey D, Martin D (2004) Pharmacodynamics of the type II calcimimetic compound cinacalcet HCl. J Pharmacol Exp Ther 308(2):627–635</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14593085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nonaka D (2011) Study of parathyroid transcription factor Gcm2 expression in parathyroid lesions. Am J Surg Pathol 35(1):145–151</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raggi P, Kleerekoper M (2008) Contribution of bone and mineral abnormalities to cardiovascular disease in patients with chronic kidney disease. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3(3):836–843</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter CS, Haughey BH, Miller B, Brown AJ (2012) Differential gene expression by oxyphil and chief cells of human parathyroid glands. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 97(8):E1499-1505</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22585091</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3591682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter C, Miller B, Coyne DW, Gupta D, Zheng S, Brown AJ, Slatopolsky E (2017) Paricalcitol and cinacalcet have disparate actions on parathyroid oxyphil cell content in patients with chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 92(5):1217–1222</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28750928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts A, Trapnell C, Donaghey J, Rinn JL, Pachter L (2011) Improving RNA-Seq expression estimates by correcting for fragment bias. Genome Biol 12(3):R22</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3129672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez M, Canalejo A, Garfia B, Aguilera E, Almaden Y (2002) Pathogenesis of refractory secondary hyperparathyroidism. Kidney Int Suppl 80:155–160</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rottembourg J, Menegaux F (2019) Are oxyphil cells responsible for the ineffectiveness of cinacalcet hydrochloride in haemodialysis patients? Clin Kidney J 12(3):433–436</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sumida K, Nakamura M, Ubara Y, Marui Y, Tanaka K, Takaichi K, Tomikawa S, Inoshita N, Ohashi K (2011) Histopathological alterations of the parathyroid glands in haemodialysis patients with secondary hyperparathyroidism refractory to cinacalcet hydrochloride. J Clin Pathol 64(9):756–760</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21565858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka Y, Funahashi H, Imai T, Seo H, Tominaga Y, Takagi H (1996) Oxyphil cell function in secondary parathyroid hyperplasia. Nephron 73(4):580–586</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8856255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trapnell C, Williams BA, Pertea G, Mortazavi A, Kwan G, van Baren MJ, Salzberg SL, Wold BJ, Pachter L (2010) Transcript assembly and quantification by RNA-Seq reveals unannotated transcripts and isoform switching during cell differentiation. Nat Biotechnol 28(5):511–515</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3146043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3146043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vulpio C, Maresca G, Distasio E, Cacaci S, Panocchia N, Luciani G, Bossola M (2011) Switch from calcitriol to paricalcitol in secondary hyperparathyroidism of hemodialysis patients: Responsiveness is related to parathyroid gland size. Hemodial Int 15(1):69–78</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21223484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ZQ, Xu XY, Gong QQ, Xie C, Fan W, Yang JL, Lin QS, Zheng SJ (2014) Root proteome of rice studied by iTRAQ provides integrated insight into aluminum stress tolerance mechanisms in plants. J Proteomics 98:189–205</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24412201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L, Cao H, Chen C, Yue C, Hao X, Yang Y, Wang X (2016) Complementary transcriptomic and proteomic analyses of a chlorophyll-deficient tea plant cultivar reveal multiple metabolic pathway changes. J Proteomics 130:160–169</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu G, Nie L, Zhang W (2008) Integrative analyses of posttranscriptional regulation in the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae using transcriptomic and proteomic data. Curr Microbiol 57(1):18–22</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18363056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35348903</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-2199</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>29</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Amino acids</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Amino Acids</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Integrated transcriptomic and proteomic analyses for the characterization of parathyroid oxyphil cells in uremic patients.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00726-022-03126-8</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Chief cells are the predominant cells in parathyroid glands of healthy adults; however, parathyroid oxyphil cells, whose function is unknown, increase dramatically in patients with secondary hyperparathyroidism (SHPT). Calcitriol and calcimimetics are the most powerful treatments for SHPT, while the mechanisms leading to calcitriol or calcimimetic resistance in oxyphil cell-predominant SHPT are unknown. Here we used transcriptomic and proteomic techniques to characterize oxyphil cells by comparing the differences between chief and oxyphil cell nodules of parathyroid glands in uremic patients. Compared to chief cell nodules, the most marked expression increases in oxyphil cell nodules were for mitochondrion-associated proteins. The mitochondria number and mitochondrial DNA content were also significantly increased in oxyphil cell nodules. Moreover, oxyphil cell nodules expressed parathyroid-specific factors, and exhibited lower levels of proliferation-related proteins but higher synthesis and secretion level of parathyroid hormone (PTH). The protein expression of SHPT-regulating factors, including vitamin-D receptor, calcium-sensing receptor and Klotho, were significantly downregulated in oxyphil cell nodules. Therefore, oxyphil cells characterized by enrich mitochondria in uremic patients showed higher synthesis and secretion of PTH but lower expression of SHPT regulators than chief cells, which may contribute to the pathophysiology of SHPT and the treatment resistance to calcitriol and calcimimetics.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Austria, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jianping</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9371-6192</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>You</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huaizhou</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mengjing</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Minmin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. chenjing1998@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Clinical Research Center for Aging and Medicine, Huashan Hospital, Shanghai Medical College, Fudan University, Shanghai, China. chenjing1998@fudan.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Austria</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Amino Acids</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9200312</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0939-4451</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcimimetics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcitriol</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mitochondrion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parathyroid oxyphil cell</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Proteomic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcriptomic</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>21</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348903</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00726-022-03126-8</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00726-022-03126-8</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anders S, Pyl PT, Huber W (2015) HTSeq–a Python framework to work with high-throughput sequencing data. Bioinformatics 31(2):166–169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basile C, Lomonte C (2017) The function of the parathyroid oxyphil cells in uremia: still a mystery? Kidney Int 92(5):1046–1048</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29055426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bienaimé F, Prié D, Friedlander G, Souberbielle JC (2011) Vitamin D metabolism and activity in the parathyroid gland. Mol Cell Endocrinol 347(1–2):30–41</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21664247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Block GA, Martin KJ, de Francisco AL, Turner SA, Avram MM, Suranyi MG, Hercz G, Cunningham J, Abu-Alfa AK, Messa P, Coyne DW, Locatelli F, Cohen RM, Evenepoel P, Moe SM, Fournier A, Braun J, McCary LC, Zani VJ, Olson KA, Drüeke TB, Goodman WG (2004) Cinacalcet for secondary hyperparathyroidism in patients receiving hemodialysis. N Engl J Med 350(15):1516–1525</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15071126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolger AM, Lohse M, Usadel B (2014) Trimmomatic: a flexible trimmer for Illumina sequence data. Bioinformatics 30(15):2114–2120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24695404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">24695404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borràs M, Torregrossa V, Oliveras A, Almirall J, Ma Paz M, Betriu A, Martin M, Muray S, Fibla J, Fernández E (2003) BB genotype of the vitamin D receptor gene polymorphism postpones parathyroidectomy in hemodialysis patients. J Nephrol 16(1):116–120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12649542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canalejo A, Almadén Y, Torregrosa V, Gomez-Villamandos JC, Ramos B, Campistol JM, Felsenfeld AJ, Rodríguez M (2000) The in vitro effect of calcitriol on parathyroid cell proliferation and apoptosis. J Am Soc Nephrol 11(10):1865–1872</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11004217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie AC (1967) The parathyroid oxyphil cells. J Clin Pathol 20(4):591–602</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4880406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">473518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conesa A, Götz S, García-Gómez JM, Terol J, Talón M, Robles M (2005) Blast2GO: a universal tool for annotation, visualization and analysis in functional genomics research. Bioinformatics 21(18):3674–3676</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham J, Locatelli F, Rodriguez M (2011) Secondary hyperparathyroidism: pathogenesis, disease progression, and therapeutic options. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 6(4):913–921</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21454719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delhomme N, Padioleau I, Furlong EE, Steinmetz LM (2012) easyRNASeq: a bioconductor package for processing RNA-Seq data. Bioinformatics 28(19):2532–2533</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22847932</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3463124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan Y, Liu W, Bi R, Densmore MJ, Sato T, Mannstadt M, Yuan Q, Zhou X, Olauson H, Larsson TE, Toka HR, Pollak MR, Brown EM, Lanske B (2018) Interrelated role of Klotho and calcium-sensing receptor in parathyroid hormone synthesis and parathyroid hyperplasia. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 115(16):E3749-e3758</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29618612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5910831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galitzer H, Ben-Dov IZ, Silver J, Naveh-Many T (2010) Parathyroid cell resistance to fibroblast growth factor 23 in secondary hyperparathyroidism of chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 77(3):211–218</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghazalpour A, Bennett B, Petyuk VA, Orozco L, Hagopian R, Mungrue IN, Farber CR, Sinsheimer J, Kang HM, Furlotte N, Park CC, Wen PZ, Brewer H, Weitz K, Camp DG 2nd, Pan C, Yordanova R, Neuhaus I, Tilford C, Siemers N, Gargalovic P, Eskin E, Kirchgessner T, Smith DJ, Smith RD, Lusis AJ (2011) Comparative analysis of proteome and transcriptome variation in mouse. PLoS Genet 7(6):e1001393</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21695224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3111477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Z, Gu H, Hu J, Hu S, Wang X, Liu X, Jiao X, Liu X (2018) Quantitative proteomics identify an association between extracellular matrix degradation and immunopathology of genotype VII Newcastle disease virus in the spleen in chickens. J Proteomics 181:201–212</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29684681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang S, Chen L, Te R, Qiao J, Wang J, Zhang W (2013) Complementary iTRAQ proteomics and RNA-seq transcriptomics reveal multiple levels of regulation in response to nitrogen starvation in Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803. Mol Biosyst 9(10):2565–2574</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23942477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kan S, Zhang W, Mao J, Wang M, Ni L, Zhang M, Zhang Q, Chen J (2018) NF-κB activation contributes to parathyroid cell proliferation in chronic kidney disease. J Nephrol 31(6):941–951</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30171599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanehisa M, Goto S, Sato Y, Furumichi M, Tanabe M (2012) KEGG for integration and interpretation of large-scale molecular data sets. Nucleic Acids Res 40(Database issue):D109–D114</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karthikkeyan G, Subbannayya Y, Najar MA, Mohanty V, Pinto SM, Arunachalam C, Prasad TSK, Murthy KR (2018) Human optic nerve: an enhanced proteomic expression profile. OMICS 22(10):642–652</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30346883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kasdon EJ, Rosen S, Cohen RB, Silen W (1981) Surgical pathology of hyperparathyroidism. Usefulness of fat stain and problems in interpretation. Am J Surg Pathol 5(4):381–384</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6168205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazama JJ, Sato F, Omori K, Hama H, Yamamoto S, Maruyama H, Narita I, Gejyo F, Yamashita T, Fukumoto S, Fukagawa M (2005) Pretreatment serum FGF-23 levels predict the efficacy of calcitriol therapy in dialysis patients. Kidney Int 67(3):1120–1125</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15698453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim D, Langmead B, Salzberg SL (2015) HISAT: a fast spliced aligner with low memory requirements. Nat Methods 12(4):357–360</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4655817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4655817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komaba H, Fukagawa M (2010) FGF23-parathyroid interaction: implications in chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 77(4):292–298</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komaba H, Nakanishi S, Fujimori A, Tanaka M, Shin J, Shibuya K, Nishioka M, Hasegawa H, Kurosawa T, Fukagawa M (2010) Cinacalcet effectively reduces parathyroid hormone secretion and gland volume regardless of pretreatment gland size in patients with secondary hyperparathyroidism. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 5(12):2305–2314</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20798251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2994093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li S, Mao J, Wang M, Zhang M, Ni L, Tao Y, Huang B, Chen J (2018) Comparative proteomic analysis of chief and oxyphil cell nodules in refractory uremic hyperparathyroidism by iTRAQ coupled LC-MS/MS. J Proteomics 179:42–52</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindberg JS, Culleton B, Wong G, Borah MF, Clark RV, Shapiro WB, Roger SD, Husserl FE, Klassen PS, Guo MD, Albizem MB, Coburn JW (2005) Cinacalcet HCl, an oral calcimimetic agent for the treatment of secondary hyperparathyroidism in hemodialysis and peritoneal dialysis: a randomized, double-blind, multicenter study. J Am Soc Nephrol 16(3):800–807</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15689407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Li H, Su J, Xu S, Zhu F, Ai J, Hu Z, Zhou M, Tian J, Su Z, Yang P, Nie J (2019) Numb depletion promotes Drp1-mediated mitochondrial fission and exacerbates mitochondrial fragmentation and dysfunction in acute kidney injury. Antioxid Redox Signal 30(15):1797–1816</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29890853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lomonte C, Martino R, Selvaggiolo M, Bona RM, Cazzato F, Milano R, Chiarulli G, Basile C (2003) Calcitriol pulse therapy and histology of parathyroid glands in hemodialysis patients. J Nephrol 16(5):716–720</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14733419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lomonte C, Vernaglione L, Chimienti D, Bruno A, Cocola S, Teutonico A, Cazzato F, Basile C (2008) Does vitamin D receptor and calcium receptor activation therapy play a role in the histopathologic alterations of parathyroid glands in refractory uremic hyperparathyroidism? Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3(3):794–799</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322048</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2386693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma J, Chen T, Wu S, Yang C, Bai M, Shu K, Li K, Zhang G, Jin Z, He F, Hermjakob H, Zhu Y (2019) iProX: an integrated proteome resource. Nucleic Acids Res 47(D1):D1211–D1217</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malberti F, Marcelli D, Conte F, Limido A, Spotti D, Locatelli F (2001) Parathyroidectomy in patients on renal replacement therapy: an epidemiologic study. J Am Soc Nephrol 12(6):1242–1248</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11373348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mei H, Sun S, Bai Y, Chen Y, Chai R, Li H (2015) Reduced mtDNA copy number increases the sensitivity of tumor cells to chemotherapeutic drugs. Cell Death Dis 6(4):e1710</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25837486</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4650546</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Messa P, Macário F, Yaqoob M, Bouman K, Braun J, von Albertini B, Brink H, Maduell F, Graf H, Frazão JM, Bos WJ, Torregrosa V, Saha H, Reichel H, Wilkie M, Zani VJ, Molemans B, Carter D, Locatelli F (2008) The OPTIMA study: assessing a new cinacalcet (Sensipar/Mimpara) treatment algorithm for secondary hyperparathyroidism. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3(1):36–45</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18178780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2390975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemeth EF, Heaton WH, Miller M, Fox J, Balandrin MF, Van Wagenen BC, Colloton M, Karbon W, Scherrer J, Shatzen E, Rishton G, Scully S, Qi M, Harris R, Lacey D, Martin D (2004) Pharmacodynamics of the type II calcimimetic compound cinacalcet HCl. J Pharmacol Exp Ther 308(2):627–635</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14593085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nonaka D (2011) Study of parathyroid transcription factor Gcm2 expression in parathyroid lesions. Am J Surg Pathol 35(1):145–151</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21164298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raggi P, Kleerekoper M (2008) Contribution of bone and mineral abnormalities to cardiovascular disease in patients with chronic kidney disease. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 3(3):836–843</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18322050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter CS, Haughey BH, Miller B, Brown AJ (2012) Differential gene expression by oxyphil and chief cells of human parathyroid glands. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 97(8):E1499-1505</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22585091</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3591682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter C, Miller B, Coyne DW, Gupta D, Zheng S, Brown AJ, Slatopolsky E (2017) Paricalcitol and cinacalcet have disparate actions on parathyroid oxyphil cell content in patients with chronic kidney disease. Kidney Int 92(5):1217–1222</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28750928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts A, Trapnell C, Donaghey J, Rinn JL, Pachter L (2011) Improving RNA-Seq expression estimates by correcting for fragment bias. Genome Biol 12(3):R22</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3129672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez M, Canalejo A, Garfia B, Aguilera E, Almaden Y (2002) Pathogenesis of refractory secondary hyperparathyroidism. Kidney Int Suppl 80:155–160</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rottembourg J, Menegaux F (2019) Are oxyphil cells responsible for the ineffectiveness of cinacalcet hydrochloride in haemodialysis patients? Clin Kidney J 12(3):433–436</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31198545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sumida K, Nakamura M, Ubara Y, Marui Y, Tanaka K, Takaichi K, Tomikawa S, Inoshita N, Ohashi K (2011) Histopathological alterations of the parathyroid glands in haemodialysis patients with secondary hyperparathyroidism refractory to cinacalcet hydrochloride. J Clin Pathol 64(9):756–760</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21565858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka Y, Funahashi H, Imai T, Seo H, Tominaga Y, Takagi H (1996) Oxyphil cell function in secondary parathyroid hyperplasia. Nephron 73(4):580–586</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8856255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trapnell C, Williams BA, Pertea G, Mortazavi A, Kwan G, van Baren MJ, Salzberg SL, Wold BJ, Pachter L (2010) Transcript assembly and quantification by RNA-Seq reveals unannotated transcripts and isoform switching during cell differentiation. Nat Biotechnol 28(5):511–515</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3146043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3146043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vulpio C, Maresca G, Distasio E, Cacaci S, Panocchia N, Luciani G, Bossola M (2011) Switch from calcitriol to paricalcitol in secondary hyperparathyroidism of hemodialysis patients: Responsiveness is related to parathyroid gland size. Hemodial Int 15(1):69–78</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21223484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang ZQ, Xu XY, Gong QQ, Xie C, Fan W, Yang JL, Lin QS, Zheng SJ (2014) Root proteome of rice studied by iTRAQ provides integrated insight into aluminum stress tolerance mechanisms in plants. J Proteomics 98:189–205</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24412201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L, Cao H, Chen C, Yue C, Hao X, Yang Y, Wang X (2016) Complementary transcriptomic and proteomic analyses of a chlorophyll-deficient tea plant cultivar reveal multiple metabolic pathway changes. J Proteomics 130:160–169</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu G, Nie L, Zhang W (2008) Integrative analyses of posttranscriptional regulation in the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae using transcriptomic and proteomic data. Curr Microbiol 57(1):18–22</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18363056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
