<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35348993</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-7365</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>37</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Metabolic brain disease</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Metab Brain Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Review of neuropsychological outcomes in isolated methylmalonic acidemia: recommendations for assessing impact of treatments.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1317</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1335</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1317-1335</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11011-022-00954-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Methylmalonic acidemia (MMA) due to methylmalonyl-CoA mutase deficiency (OMIM #251,000) is an autosomal recessive disorder of organic acid metabolism associated with life-threatening acute metabolic decompensations and significant neuropsychological deficits. "Isolated" MMA refers to the presence of excess methylmalonic acid without homocysteine elevation. Belonging to this class of disorders are those that involve complete deficiency (mut<sup>0</sup>) and partial deficiency (mut<sup>-</sup>) of the methylmalonyl-CoA mutase enzyme and other disorders causing excess methylmalonic acid excretion. These other disorders include enzymatic subtypes related to cobalamin A defect (cblA) (OMIM #25,110), cobalamin B defect (cblB) (OMIM #251,110) and related conditions. Neuropsychological attributes associated with isolated MMA have become more relevant as survival rates increased following improved diagnostic and treatment strategies. Children with this disorder still are at risk for developmental delay, cognitive difficulties and progressive declines in functioning. Mean IQ for all types apart from cblA defect enzymatic subtype is rarely above 85 and much lower for mut<sup>0</sup> enzymatic subtype. Identifying psychological domains responsive to improvements in biochemical status is important. This review suggests that processing speed, working memory, language, attention, and quality of life may be sensitive to fluctuations in metabolite levels while IQ and motor skills may be less amenable to change. Due to slower developmental trajectories, Growth Scale Values, Projected Retained Ability Scores and other indices of change need to be incorporated into clinical trial study protocols. Neuropsychologists are uniquely qualified to provide a differentiated picture of cognitive, behavioral and emotional consequences of MMA and analyze benefits or shortcomings of novel treatments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Waisbren</LastName>
            <ForeName>Susan E</ForeName>
            <Initials>SE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0013-700X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Boston Children's Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. susan.waisbren@childrens.harvard.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Metab Brain Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8610370</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0885-7490</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>8LL8S712J7</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D008764">Methylmalonic Acid</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 5.4.99.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D008765">Methylmalonyl-CoA Mutase</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>P6YC3EG204</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014805">Vitamin B 12</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C537358">Methylmalonic acidemia</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">Amino Acid Metabolism, Inborn Errors</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008764" MajorTopicYN="N">Methylmalonic Acid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Methylmalonyl-CoA Mutase</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="N">Mutation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014805" MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin B 12</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Methylmalonic acidemia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychological</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological outcomes research</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>22</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35348993</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11011-022-00954-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11011-022-00954-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almási T, Guey LT, Lukacs C, Csetneki K, Vokó Z, Zelei T (2019) Systematic literature review and meta-analysis on the epidemiology of methylmalonic acidemia (MMA) with a focus on MMA caused by methylmalonyl-CoA mutase (Mut) deficiency. Orphanet J Rare Dis 14(1):84. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-019-1063-z</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-019-1063-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31023387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6485056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amaral AU, Cecatto C, Castilho RF, Wajner M (2016) 2-Methylcitric acid impairs glutamate metabolism and induces permeability transition in brain mitochondria. J Neurochem 137(1):62–75. https://doi.org/10.1111/jnc.13544</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.13544</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26800654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basner M, Hermosillo E, Nasrini J, Saxena S, Dinges DF, Moore TM, Gur RC (2020) Cognition test battery: Adjusting for practice and stimulus set effects for varying administration intervals in high performing individuals. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2020 Jul;42(5):516–529. https://doi.org/10.1080/13803395.2020.1773765 . Epub 2020 Jun 15. Erratum in: J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2020 Jun 24:1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgarter ER, Viardot C (1995) Long-term follow-up of 77 patients with isolated methylmalonic acidaemia. J Inherit Metab Dis 18(2):138–142. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00711749</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00711749</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7564229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner MR, Hörster F, Dionisi-Vici C, Haliloglu G, Karall D, Chapman KA, Huemer M, Hochuli M, Assoun M, Ballhausen D, Burlina A, Fowler B, Grünert SC, Grünewald S, Honzik T, Merinero B, Pérez-Cerdá C, Scholl-Bürgi S, Skovby F, Wijburg F, MacDonald A, Martinelli D, Sass JO, Valayannopoulos V, Chakrapani A (2014) Proposed guidelines for the diagnosis and management of methylmalonic and propionic acidemia. Orphanet J Rare Dis 2(9):130. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-014-0130-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-014-0130-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayley N, Alyward GP (2019) Bayley scales of infant and toddler development—fourth edition: administration manual. Pearson Corp Inc, New York, NY</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beglinger LJ, Gaydos B, Tangphao-Daniels O, Duff K, Kareken DA, Crawford J, Fastenau PS, Siemers ER (2005) Practice effects and the use of alternate forms in serial neuropsychological testing. Arch Clin Neuropsychol 20(4):517–529. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.acn.2004.12.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.acn.2004.12.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15896564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budimirovic DB, Berry-Kravis E, Erickson CA, Hall SS, Hessl D, Reiss AL, King MK, Abbeduto L, Kaufmann WE (2017) Updated report on tools to measure outcomes of clinical trials in fragile X syndrome. J Neurodev Disord 12(9):14. https://doi.org/10.1186/s11689-017-9193-x.PMID:28616097;PMCID:PMC5467057</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s11689-017-9193-x.PMID:28616097;PMCID:PMC5467057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busch RM, Lineweaver TT, Ferguson L, Haut JS (2015) Reliable change indices and standardized regression-based change score norms for evaluating neuropsychological change in children with epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav 47: 45–54</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabrera-Pastor A, Taoro-Gonzalez L, Felipo V (2016) Hyperammonemia alters glycinergic neurotransmission and modulation of the glutamate-nitric oxide-cGMP pathway by extracellular glycine in cerebellum in vivo. J Neurochem 137(4):539–548. https://doi.org/10.1111/jnc.13579</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jnc.13579</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26875688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakrapani A, Sivakumar P, McKiernan PJ, Leonard JV (2002) Metabolic stroke in methylmalonic acidemia five years after liver transplantation. J Pediatr 140(2):261–263. https://doi.org/10.1067/mpd.2002.121698</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1067/mpd.2002.121698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11865284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chapman KA, Gramer G, Viall S, Summar ML (2018) Incidence of maple syrup urine disease, propionic acidemia, and methylmalonic aciduria from newborn screening data. Mol Genet Metab Rep 5(15):106–109. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgmr.2018.03.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgmr.2018.03.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen K, Didsbury M, van Zwieten A, Howell M, Kim S, Tong A, Howard K, Nassar N, Barton B, Lah S, Lorenzo J, Strippoli G, Palmer S, Teixeira-Pinto A, Mackie F, McTaggart S, Walker A, Kara T, Craig JC, Wong G (2018) Neurocognitive and educational outcomes in children and adolescents with CKD: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 13(3):387–397. https://doi.org/10.2215/CJN.09650917</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.09650917</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29472306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5967677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen PW, Hwu WL, Ho MC, Lee NC, Chien YH, Ni YH, Lee PH (2010) Stabilization of blood methylmalonic acid level in methylmalonic acidemia after liver transplantation. Pediatr Transplant 14(3):337–341. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3046.2009.01227.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-3046.2009.01227.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19686300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu TH, Chien YH, Lin HY, Liao HC, Ho HJ, Lai CJ, Chiang CC, Lin NC, Yang CF, Hwu WL, Lee NC, Lin SP, Liu CS, Hu RH, Ho MC, Niu DM (2019) Methylmalonic acidemia/propionic acidemia - the biochemical presentation and comparing the outcome between liver transplantation versus non-liver transplantation groups. Orphanet J Rare Dis 14(1):73. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-019-1045-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-019-1045-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30940196</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6444613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coelho D, Suormala T, Stucki M, Lerner-Ellis JP, Rosenblatt DS, Newbold RF, Baumgartner MR, Fowler B (2008) Gene identification for the cblD defect of vitamin B12 metabolism. N Engl J Med 358(14):1454–1464. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa072200</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa072200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18385497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cosson MA, Benoist JF, Touati G, Déchaux M, Royer N, Grandin L, Jais JP, Boddaert N, Barbier V, Desguerre I, Campeau PM, Rabier D, Valayannopoulos V, Niaudet P, de Lonlay P (2009) Long-term outcome in methylmalonic aciduria: a series of 30 French patients. Mol Genet Metab 97(3):172–178. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgme.2009.03.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgme.2009.03.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19375370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costanzo M, Caterino M, Cevenini A, Jung V, Chhuon C, Lipecka J, Fedele R, Guerrera IC, Ruoppolo M (2020) Proteomics reveals that methylmalonyl-CoA mutase modulates cell architecture and increases susceptibility to stress. Int J Mol Sci 21(14):4998. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21144998</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms21144998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7403994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeRoche K, Welsh M (2008) Twenty-five years of research on neurocognitive outcomes in early-treated phenylketonuria: intelligence and executive function. Dev Neuropsychol 33(4):474–504. https://doi.org/10.1080/87565640802101482</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/87565640802101482</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18568900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dionisi-Vici C, Deodato F, Röschinger W, Rhead W, Wilcken B (2006) 'Classical' organic acidurias, propionic aciduria, methylmalonic aciduria and isovaleric aciduria: long-term outcome and effects of expanded newborn screening using tandem mass spectrometry. J Inherit Metab Dis 29(2–3):383–9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10545-006-0278-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duff K, Westervelt HJ, McCaffrey RJ, Haase RF (2001) Practice effects, test-retest stability, and dual baseline assessments with the California Verbal Learning Test in an HIV sample. Arch Clin Neuropsychol 16(5):461–476</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14590160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliott CD (2007) Differential abilities scale, second edition. San Antonio, TX: Harcourt Assessment</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falleti MG, Maruff P, Collie A, Darby DG (2006) Practice effects associated with the repeated assessment of cognitive function using the CogState battery at 10-minute, one week and one month test-retest intervals. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol 28(7):1095–1112. https://doi.org/10.1080/13803390500205718</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13803390500205718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16840238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farmer CA, Kaat AJ, Thurm A, Anselm I, Akshoomoff N, Bennett A, Berry L, Bruchey A, Barshop BA, Berry-Kravis E, Bianconi S, Cecil KM, Davis RJ, Ficicioglu C, Porter FD, Wainer A, Goin-Kochel RP, Leonczyk C, Guthrie W, Koeberl D, Love-Nichols J, Mamak E, Mercimek-Andrews S, Thomas RP, Spiridigliozzi GA, Sullivan N, Sutton VR, Udhnani MD, Waisbren SE, Miller JS (2020) Person ability scores as an alternative to norm-referenced scores as outcome measures in studies of neurodevelopmental disorders. Am J Intellect Dev Disabil 125(6):475–480. https://doi.org/10.1352/1944-7558-125.6.475</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1352/1944-7558-125.6.475</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33211814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fenton WA, Gravel RA, Rosenblatt DS (2001) Disorders of propionate and methylmalonate metabolism. In Scriver CR, Beaudet AL, Sly WS, Valle, D (eds) The metabolic and molecular bases of inherited disease. 2165–2193</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feuchtbaum L, Carter J, Dowray S, Currier RJ, Lorey F (2012) Birth prevalence of disorders detectable through newborn screening by race/ethnicity. Genet Med 14(11):937–945. https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2012.76</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/gim.2012.76</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22766612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fray PJ, Robbins TW (1996) CANTAB battery: proposed utility in neurotoxicology. Neurotoxicol Teratol. 18(4):499–504. https://doi.org/10.1016/0892-0362(96)00027-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gershon RC, Wagster MV, Hendrie HC, Fox NA, Cook KF, Nowinski CJ (2013) NIH toolbox for assessment of neurological and behavioral function. Neurology 80(11 Suppl 3):S2-6. https://doi.org/10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182872e5f</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182872e5f</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23479538</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3662335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haijes HA, Jans JJM, Tas SY, Verhoeven-Duif NM, van Hasselt PM (2019) Pathophysiology of propionic and methylmalonic acidemias. Part 1: Complications. J Inherit Metab Dis. 42(5):730–744. https://doi.org/10.1002/jimd.12129</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haijes HA, Molema F, Langeveld M, Janssen MC, Bosch AM, van Spronsen F, Mulder MF, Verhoeven-Duif NM, Jans JJM, van der Ploeg AT, Wagenmakers MA, Rubio-Gozalbo ME, Brouwers MCGJ, de Vries MC, Langendonk JG, Williams M, van Hasselt PM (2020) Retrospective evaluation of the Dutch pre-newborn screening cohort for propionic acidemia and isolated methylmalonic acidemia: What to aim, expect, and evaluate from newborn screening? J Inherit Metab Dis 43(3):424–437. https://doi.org/10.1002/jimd.12193</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han B, Nie W, Sun M, Liu Y, Cao Z (2020) Clinical presentation, molecular analysis and follow-up of patients with mut methylmalonic acidemia in Shandong province. China Pediatr Neonatol 61(2):148–154. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pedneo.2019.07.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pedneo.2019.07.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31466887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heringer J, Valayannopoulos V, Lund AM, Wijburg FA, Freisinger P, Barić I, Baumgartner MR, Burgard P, Burlina AB, Chapman KA, I Saladelafont EC, Karall D, Mühlhausen C, Riches V, Schiff M, Sykut-Cegielska J, Walter JH, Zeman J, Chabrol B, Kölker S; additional individual contributors of the E-IMD consortium (2016) Impact of age at onset and newborn screening on outcome in organic acidurias. J Inherit Metab Dis 39(3):341–353. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10545-015-9907-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heuberger K, Bailey HJ, Burda P, Chaikuad A, Krysztofinska E, Suormala T, Bürer C, Lutz S, Fowler B, Froese DS, Yue WW, Baumgartner MR (2019) Genetic, structural, and functional analysis of pathogenic variations causing methylmalonyl-CoA epimerase deficiency. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Basis Dis 1865(6):1265–1272. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbadis.2019.01.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howieson D (2019) Current limitations of neuropsychological tests and assessment procedures. Clin Neuropsychol 33(2):200–208. https://doi.org/10.1080/13854046.2018.1552762</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13854046.2018.1552762</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30608020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hörster F, Baumgartner MR, Viardot C, Suormala T, Burgard P, Fowler B, Hoffmann GF, Garbade SF, Kölker S, Baumgartner ER (2007) Long-term outcome in methylmalonic acidurias is influenced by the underlying defect (mut0, mut-, cblA, cblB). Pediatr Res 62(2):225–230. https://doi.org/10.1203/PDR.0b013e3180a0325f</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1203/PDR.0b013e3180a0325f</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17597648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hörster F, Garbade SF, Zwickler T, Aydin HI, Bodamer OA, Burlina AB, Das AM, De Klerk JBC, Dionisi-Vici C, Geb S, Gökcay G, Guffon N, Maier EM, Morava E, Walter JH, Schwahn B, Wijburg FA, Lindner M, Grünewald S, Baumgartner MR, Kölker S (2009) Prediction of outcome in isolated methylmalonic acidurias: combined use of clinical and biochemical parameters. J Inherit Metab Dis 32(5):630. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10545-009-1189-6 . Epub 2009 Jul 31. Erratum in: J Inherit Metab Dis. 2009 Dec;32(6):762–3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hörster F, Tuncel AT, Gleich F, Plessl T, Froese SD, Garbade SF, Kölker S, Baumgartner MR; Additional Contributors from E-IMD (2021) Delineating the clinical spectrum of isolated methylmalonic acidurias: cblA and mut. J Inherit Metab Dis 44(1):193–214. https://doi.org/10.1002/jimd.12297</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang YZ, Sun LY (2019) The value of liver transplantation for methylmalonic acidemia. Front Pediatr. 2019 Mar 21;7:87. https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2019.00087 . Erratum in: Front Pediatr. 2020 Apr 02;8:126</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang L, Liu Y, Shen M, Liu Y, He R, Song J, Jin Y, Li M, Zhang Y, Dong H, Liu X, Yan H, Qin J, Zheng H, Chen Y, Li D, Wei H, Zhang H, Sun L, Zhu Z, Liang D, Yang Y (2020) A study on a cohort of 301 Chinese patients with isolated methylmalonic acidemia. J Inherit Metab Dis 43(3):409–423. https://doi.org/10.1002/jimd.12183</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jimd.12183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31622506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan P, Ficicioglu C, Mazur AT, Palmieri MJ, Berry GT (2006) Liver transplantation is not curative for methylmalonic acidopathy caused by methylmalonyl-CoA mutase deficiency. Mol Genet Metabol 88:322–326. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgme.2006.04.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymgme.2006.04.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khanna A, Gish R, Winter SC, Nyhan WL, Barshop BA (2016) Successful domino liver transplantation from a patient with methylmalonic acidemia. JIMD Rep 25:87–94. https://doi.org/10.1007/89042015480</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/89042015480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26219882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ktena YP, Paul SM, Hauser NS, Sloan JL, Gropman A, Manoli I, Venditti CP (2015) Delineating the spectrum of impairments, disabilities, and rehabilitation needs in methylmalonic acidemia (MMA). Am J Med Genet A 167A(9):2075–2084. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.37127</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.37127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25959030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">9017244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kronenberger WG, Harrington M, Yee KS (2021) Projected retained ability score (PRAS): a new methodology for quantifying absolute change in norm-based psychological test scores over time. Assessment. 2021 Mar;28(2):367–379. https://doi.org/10.1177/1073191119872250</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kölker S, Burgard P, Sauer SW, Okun JG (2013) Current concepts in organic acidurias: understanding intra- and extracerebral disease manifestation. J Inherit Metab Dis 36(4):635–644. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10545-013-9600-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10545-013-9600-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23512157</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kölker S, Garcia-Cazorla A, Valayannopoulos V, Lund AM, Burlina AB, Sykut-Cegielska J, Wijburg FA, Teles EL, Zeman J, Dionisi-Vici C, Barić I, Karall D, Augoustides-Savvopoulou P, Aksglaede L, Arnoux JB, Avram P, Baumgartner MR, Blasco-Alonso J, Chabrol B, Chakrapani A, Chapman K, I Saladelafont EC, Couce ML, de Meirleir L, Dobbelaere D, Dvorakova V, Furlan F, Gleich F, Gradowska W, Grünewald S, Jalan A, Häberle J, Haege G, Lachmann R, Laemmle A, Langereis E, de Lonlay P, Martinelli D, Matsumoto S, Mühlhausen C, de Baulny HO, Ortez C, Peña-Quintana L, Ramadža DP, Rodrigues E, Scholl-Bürgi S, Sokal E, Staufner C, Summar ML, Thompson N, Vara R, Pinera IV, Walter JH, Williams M, Burgard P (2015) The phenotypic spectrum of organic acidurias and urea cycle disorders. Part 1: the initial presentation. J Inherit Metab Dis 38(6):1041–57. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10545-015-9839-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledley FD, Levy HL, Shih VE, Benjamin R, Mahoney MJ (1984) Benign methylmalonic aciduria. N Engl J Med 311(16):1015–1018. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM198410183111604</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198410183111604</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6148691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonard JV (1995) The management and outcome of propionic and methylmalonic acidaemia. J Inherit Metab Dis 18(4):430–434. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00710054</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00710054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7494401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li D, McDonald CM, Elfring GL, Souza M, McIntosh J, Kim DH, Wei LJ (2020) Assessment of treatment effect with multiple outcomes in 2 clinical trials of patients with Duchenne muscular dystrophy. JAMA Netw Open 3(2):e1921306. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.21306</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.21306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058550</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7202370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manoli I, Sloan JL, Venditti CP (2005) Isolated methylmalonic acidemia. 2005 Aug 16 [updated 2016 Dec 1]. In: Adam MP, Ardinger HH, Pagon RA, Wallace SE, Bean LJH, Gripp KW, Mirzaa GM, Amemiya A, editors. GeneReviews<sup>®</sup> [Internet]. Seattle (WA): University of Washington, Seattle; 1993–2022. PMID: 20301409</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manoli I, Myles JG, Sloan JL, Shchelochkov OA, Venditti CP (2016) A critical reappraisal of dietary practices in methylmalonic acidemia raises concerns about the safety of medical foods. Part 1: isolated methylmalonic acidemias. Genet Med. 2016 Apr;18(4):386–95. https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2015.102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marcotte K, Graham NL, Fraser KC, Meltzer JA, Tang-Wai DF, Chow TW, Freedman M, Leonard C, Black SE, Rochon E (2017) White matter disruption and connected speech in non-fluent and semantic variants of primary progressive aphasia. Dementia and Geriatric Cognitive Disorders Extra 7(1):52–73. https://doi.org/10.1159/000456710</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000456710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28611820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5465709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsui SM, Mahoney MJ, Rosenberg LE (1983) The natural history of the inherited methylmalonic acidemias. N Engl J Med 308:857–861. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM198304143081501</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198304143081501</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6132336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McArdle JJ, Grimm KJ, Hamagami F, Bowles RP, Meredith W (2009) Modeling life-span growth curves of cognition using longitudinal data with multiple samples and changing scales of measurement. Psychol Methods 14(2):126–149. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0015857</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0015857</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19485625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2831479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molema F, Williams M, Langendonk J, Darwish-Murad S, van de Wetering J, Jacobs E, Onkenhout W, Brusse E, van der Eerden A, Wagenmakers M (2020) Neurotoxicity including posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome after initiation of calcineurin inhibitors in transplanted methylmalonic acidemia patients: Two case reports and review of the literature. JIMD Rep 51(1):89–104. https://doi.org/10.1002/jmd2.12088</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmd2.12088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32071844</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7012740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melo DR, Kowaltowski AJ, Wajner M, Castilho RF (2011) Mitochondrial energy metabolism in neurodegeneration associated with methylmalonic acidemia. J Bioenerg Biomembr 43(1):39–46. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10863-011-9330-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10863-011-9330-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21271280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morioka D, Kasahara M, Horikawa R, Yokoyama S, Fukuda A, Nakagawa A (2007) Efficacy of living donor liver transplantation for patients with methylmalonic acidemia. Am J Transplant 7(12):2782–2787. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-6143.2007.01986.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-6143.2007.01986.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mueller KD, Koscik RL, Hermann BP, Johnson SC, Turkstra LS (2018) Declines in connected language are associated with very early mild cognitive impairment: results from the wisconsin registry for alzheimer’s prevention. Front Aging Neurosci 9(9):437. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2017.00437</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2017.00437</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29375365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5767238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolaides P, Leonard J, Surtees R (1998) Neurological outcome of methylmalonic acidaemia. Arch Dis Child 78(6):508–512. https://doi.org/10.1136/adc.78.6.508</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/adc.78.6.508</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9713004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1717592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niemi AK, Kim IK, Krueger CE, Cowan TM, Baugh N, Farrell R, Bonham CA, Concepcion W, Esquivel CO, Enns GM (2015) Treatment of methylmalonic acidemia by liver or combined liver-kidney transplantation. J Pediatr 166(6):1455–61.e1. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.01.051</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.01.051</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nizon M, Ottolenghi C, Valayannopoulos V, Arnoux JB, Barbier V, Habarou F, Desguerre I, Boddaert N, Bonnefont JP, Acquaviva C, Benoist JF, Rabier D, Touati G, de Lonlay P (2013) Long-term neurological outcome of a cohort of 80 patients with classical organic acidurias. Orphanet J Rare Dis 23(8):148. https://doi.org/10.1186/1750-1172-8-148</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-8-148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nyhan WL, Gargus JJ, Boyle K, Selby R, Koch R (2002) Progressive neurologic disability in methylmalonic acidemia despite transplantation of the liver. Eur J Pediatr 161(7):377–379. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00431-002-0970-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00431-002-0970-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Shea CJ, Sloan JL, Wiggs EA, Pao M, Gropman A, Baker EH, Manoli I, Venditti CP, Snow J (2012) Neurocognitive phenotype of isolated methylmalonic acidemia. Pediatrics 129(6):e1541–e1551. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2011-1715</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2011-1715</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22614770</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3362903</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pascoal C, Brasil S, Francisco R, Marques-da-Silva D, Rafalko A, Jaeken J, Videira PA, Barros L, Dos Reis FV (2018) Patient and observer reported outcome measures to evaluate health-related quality of life in inherited metabolic diseases: a scoping review. Orphanet J Rare Dis 13(1):215. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-018-0953-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-018-0953-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30486833</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6263554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Payne JM, Hearps SJC, Walsh KS, Paltin I, Barton B, Ullrich NJ, Haebich KM, Coghill D, Gioia GA, Cantor A, Cutter G, Tonsgard JH, Viskochil D, Rey-Casserly C, Schorry EK, Ackerson JD, Klesse L, Fisher MJ, Gutmann DH, Rosser T, Packer RJ, Korf B, Acosta MT, North KN; NF Clinical Trials Consortium (2019) Reproducibility of cognitive endpoints in clinical trials: lessons from neurofibromatosis type 1. Ann Clin Transl Neurol 6(12):2555–2565. https://doi.org/10.1002/acn3.50952</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pillai NR, Stroup BM, Poliner A, Rossetti L, Rawls B, Shayota BJ, Soler-Alfonso C, Tunuguntala HP, Goss J, Craigen W, Scaglia F, Sutton VR, Himes RW, Burrage LC (2019) Liver transplantation in propionic and methylmalonic acidemia: A single center study with literature review. Mol Genet Metab 128(4):431–443. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgme.2019.11.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prada CE, Al Jasmi F, Kirk EP, Hopp M, Jones O, Leslie ND, Burrow TA (2011) Cardiac disease in methylmalonic acidemia. J Pediatr 159(5):862–864. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.06.005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.06.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21784454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proctor EC, Turton N, Boan EJ, Bennett E, Philips S, Heaton RA, Hargreaves IP (2020) The effect of methylmalonic acid treatment on human neuronal cell coenzyme Q<sub>10</sub> status and mitochondrial function. Int J Mol Sci 21(23):9137. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21239137</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms21239137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7730949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds CR, Kamphaus RW (2015) Behavior assessment system for children, Third Edition. Bloomington, MN: Pearson</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ristl R, Urach S, Rosenkranz G, Posch M (2019) Methods for the analysis of multiple endpoints in small populations: A review. J Biopharm Stat 29(1):1–29. https://doi.org/10.1080/10543406.2018.1489402</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10543406.2018.1489402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29985752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto R, Nakamura K, Kido J, Matsumoto S, Mitsubuchi H, Inomata Y, Endo F (2016) Improvement in the prognosis and development of patients with methylmalonic acidemia after living donor liver transplant. Pediatr Transplant 20(8):1081–1086. https://doi.org/10.1111/petr.12804</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/petr.12804</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27670840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro E, Bernstein J, Adams HR, Barbier AJ, Buracchio T, Como P, Delaney KA, Eichler F, Goldsmith JC, Hogan M, Kovacs S, Mink JW, Odenkirchen J, Parisi MA, Skrinar A, Waisbren SE, Mulberg AE (2016) Neurocognitive clinical outcome assessments for inborn errors of metabolism and other rare conditions. Mol Genet Metab 118(2):65–9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ymgme.2016.04.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheikhmoonesi F, Shafaat A, Moarefian S, Zaman T (2013) Affective disorder as the first manifestation of methylmalonic acidemia: a case report. Iran J Pediatr 23(2):245–6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shevell MI, Matiaszuk N, Ledley FD, Rosenblatt DS (1993) Varying neurological phenotypes among mut0 and Mut- patients with methylmalonylCoA mutase deficiency. Am J Med Genet 45(5):619–624. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.1320450521</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.1320450521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7681251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sloan JL, Manoli I, Venditti CP (2015) Liver or combined liver-kidney transplantation for patients with isolated methylmalonic acidemia: who and when? J Pediatr 166(6):1346–1350. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.03.026</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2015.03.026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25882873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith PJ, Need AC, Cirulli ET, Chiba-Falek O, Attix DK (2013) A comparison of the Cambridge automated neuropsychological test battery (CANTAB) with “traditional” neuropsychological testing instruments. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol 35(3):319–328. https://doi.org/10.1080/13803395.2013.771618</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13803395.2013.771618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23444947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sniderman LC, Lambert M, Giguère R, Auray-Blais C, Lemieux B, Laframboise R, Rosenblatt DS, Treacy EP (1999) Outcome of individuals with low-moderate methylmalonic aciduria detected through a neonatal screening program. J Pediatr 134(6):675–680</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0022-3476(99)70280-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spada M, Calvo PL, Brunati A, Peruzzi L, Dell’Olio D, Romagnoli R, Porta F (2015) Early liver transplantation for neonatal-onset methylmalonic acidemia. Pediatrics 136(1):e252–e256. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2015-0175</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2015-0175</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26077484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sparrow SS, Cicchetti DV, Saulnier CA (2016) Vineland adaptive behavior scales, Third edition (Vineland-3). NCS Pearson, Bloomington</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Splinter K, Niemi AK, Cox R, Platt J, Shah M, Enns GM, Kasahara M, Bernstein JA (2016) Impaired health-related quality of life in children and families affected by methylmalonic acidemia. J Genet Couns 25(5):936–944. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10897-015-9921-x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10897-015-9921-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26667650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tandon PK, Kakkis ED (2021) The multi-domain responder index: a novel analysis tool to capture a broader assessment of clinical benefit in heterogeneous complex rare diseases. Orphanet J Rare Dis 16(1):183. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13023-021-01805-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-021-01805-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33874971</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8054393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas MS, Annaz D, Ansari D, Scerif G, Jarrold C, Karmiloff-Smith A (2009) Using developmental trajectories to understand developmental disorders. J Speech Lang Hear Res 52(2):336–358. https://doi.org/10.1044/1092-4388(2009/07-0144)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1044/1092-4388(2009/07-0144)</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19252129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vakil E (2012) Neuropsychological assessment: principles, rationale, and challenges. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol 34(2):135–150. https://doi.org/10.1080/13803395.2011.623121</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13803395.2011.623121</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22087572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Meer SB, Poggi F, Spada M, Bonnefont JP, Ogier H, Hubert P, Depondt E, Rapoport D, Rabier D, Charpentier C et al (1994) Clinical outcome of long-term management of patients with vitamin B12-unresponsive methylmalonic acidemia. J Pediatr 125(6 Pt 1):903–908. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0022-3476(05)82005-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0022-3476(05)82005-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7996362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varvogli L, Repetto GM, Waisbren SE, Levy HL (2000) High cognitive outcome in an adolescent with Mut- methylmalonic acidemia. Am J Med Genet 96(2):192–195</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1096-8628(20000403)96:2&lt;192::AID-AJMG14&gt;3.0.CO;2-J</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watkins D, Rosenblatt DS (2011) Inborn errors of cobalamin absorption and metabolism. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet 157C(1):33–44. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.c.30288</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.c.30288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21312325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wechsler D (2011) Wechsler abbreviated scale of intelligence, second edition (WASI-II), San Antonio, TX: NCS Pearson</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wechsler D (2008) Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale--Fourth Edition (WAIS-IV), Bloomington, MN: NCS Pearson</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wechsler D (2014) Wechsler intelligence scale for children -fifth edition (WISC-V), Bloomington, MN: NCS Pearson</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wechsler D (2012) Wechsler preschool and primary scale of intelligence-fourth edition (WPPSI-IV), Bloomington MN: NCS Pearson</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinfurt KP (2019) Clarifying the meaning of clinically meaningful benefit in clinical research: noticeable change vs valuable change. JAMA 322(24):2381–2382. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2019.18496</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.18496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31790549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L, Guo B, Li X, Liu X, Wei X, Guo L (2020) Brain MRI features of methylmalonic acidemia in children: the relationship between neuropsychological scores and MRI findings. Sci Rep 10(1):13099. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-70113-y</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-70113-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32753589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7403351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu Y, Shuai R, Liang L, Qiu W, Shen L, Wu S, Wei H, Chen Y, Yang C, Xu P, Chen X, Zou H, Feng J, Niu T, Hu H, Ye J, Zhang H, Lu D, Gong Z, Zhan X, Ji W, Gu X, Han L (2021) Different mutations in the MMUT gene are associated with the effect of vitamin B12 in a cohort of 266 Chinese patients with mut-type methylmalonic acidemia: A retrospective study. Mol Genet Genomic Med 9(11):e1822. https://doi.org/10.1002/mgg3.1822</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeltner NA, Landolt MA, Baumgartner MR, Lageder S, Ouitmann J, Sommer R, Karall D, Mühlhausen C, Schlune A, Scholl-Bürgi S, Huemer M (2017) Living with intoxication-type inborn errors of metabolism: A qualitative analysis of interviews with paediatric patients and their parents. JIMD Rep 31:1–9. https://doi.org/10.1007/8904_2016_545</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/8904_2016_545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26983835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang C, Wang X, Hao S, Zhang Q, Zheng L, Zhou B, Liu F, Feng X, Chen X, Ma P, Chen C, Cao Z, Ma X (2020) Mutation analysis, treatment and prenatal diagnosis of Chinese cases of methylmalonic acidemia. Sci Rep 10(1):12509. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-69565-z</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-69565-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32719376</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7385101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou X, Cui Y, Han J (2018) Methylmalonic acidemia: Current status and research priorities. Intractable Rare Dis Res 7(2):73–78. https://doi.org/10.5582/irdr.2018.01026</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5582/irdr.2018.01026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29862147</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5982627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
