<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35355493</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>03</Month>
        <Day>31</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2702-3648</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>31</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of osteopathic medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Osteopath Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Prevention of external auditory canal exostosis in the Colorado whitewater community.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1515/jom-2021-0252</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="CONTEXT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">External auditory canal exostoses (EACE) are bony formations that develop insidiously in the auditory meatus from chronic exposure to cold water and, in severe cases, require surgery. This condition has been understudied in the whitewater kayakers and not yet studied in the riverboarding population. Precautions such as earplugs are thought to prevent the formation of EACE because they mechanically block cold water from contacting the sensitive skin in the external auditory canal; however, earplugs are not commonly utilized by athletes. Inquiring about hobbies and the use of protective equipment can be done during osteopathic physicians' preventive care visits.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This article aims to determine the prevalence of EACE in Colorado whitewater athletes and their attitudes about wearing ear protection before and after an educational intervention directed at increasing awareness and prevention of EACE.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In July 2020, participants of this cross-sectional study completed a 10-min survey that collected demographics, whitewater experience, and perceptions of EACE, followed by an educational intervention. Participant ears were photographed utilizing a digital otoscope to assess EACE, and severity ratings were categorized into one of four occlusion levels: none (0%), mild (&lt;25%), moderate (25-75%), or severe (&gt;75%). Spearman correlation coefficients and Wilcoxon signed-rank tests were utilized to assess changes in attitudes before and after the educational intervention.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eighty-one participants (mean [SD] age = 36.3 [12.6] years, 25.9% female) completed the study: 74 kayakers and seven riverboarders. After the intervention, 60.5% (49/81) (p&lt;0.001) reported greater understanding of EACE and 75.0% (60/80) were more likely to wear ear protection (p&lt;0.001). Most (58.0%, 47/81) never wore ear protection. Of the 61 (75.0%) participants with at least one ear severity rating, most (55.7%, 34/61) had moderate EACE, 29.5% (18/61) had no to mild EACE, and 14.8% (9/61) had severe EACE (p&lt;0.001). Impaired hearing was the biggest barrier to utilizing ear protection (51.6%, 33/64).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results suggested that the educational intervention improved understanding of EACE and may increase utilization of ear protection in this population. Such prevention efforts may lead to better health of whitewater paddlers by reducing the incidence of EACE. Encouraging osteopathic physicians to inquire about hobbies and protective equipment during primary care preventive visits is essential to help keep athletes in the river doing what they love for longer, contributing to a healthier and happier whole person.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Annalise E. Wille et al., published by De Gruyter, Berlin/Boston.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wille</LastName>
            <ForeName>Annalise E</ForeName>
            <Initials>AE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9758-6850</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>A.T. Still University School of Osteopathic Medicine, Mesa, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pazdernik</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vanessa K</ForeName>
            <Initials>VK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Research Support, A.T. Still University, Kirksville, MO, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sassounian</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicole</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>A.T. Still University School of Osteopathic Medicine, Mesa, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Glaser</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kelli</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3613-7140</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rocky Vista University School of Osteopathic Medicine, Parker, CO, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Osteopath Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101776472</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2702-3648</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EACE</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exostosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">external auditory canal exostosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whitewater</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">whitewater kayaking</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35355493</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/jom-2021-0252</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">jom-2021-0252</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DiBartolomeo, JR. Exostoses of the external auditory canal. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol Suppl 1979;88:2–20. https://doi.org/10.1177/00034894790880s601.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kennedy, GE. The relationship between auditory exostoses and cold water: a latitudinal analysis. Am J Phys Anthropol 1986;71:401–15. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajpa.1330710403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobo, DR. Exostoses of the external auditory canal. World J Otorhinolaryngol 2015;5:14–20. https://doi.org/10.5319/wjo.v5.i1.14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harrison, DF. The relationship of osteomata of the external auditory meatus to swimming. Ann R Coll Surg Engl 1962;31:187–201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore, RD, Schuman, TA, Scott, TA, Mann, SE, Davidson, MA, Labadie, RF. Exostoses of the external auditory canal in white-water kayakers. Laryngoscope 2010;120:582–90. https://doi.org/10.1002/lary.20781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper, A, Tong, R, Neil, R, Owens, D, Tomkinson, A. External auditory canal exostoses in white water kayakers. Br J Sports Med 2010;44:144–7. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsm.2008.048157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris, S, Martin, T, Mccahon, D, Bennett, S. Awareness and attitudes towards external auditory canal exostosis and its preventability in surfers in the UK: cross-sectional study. J Laryngol Otol 2016;130:628–34. https://doi.org/10.1017/s0022215116008082.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander, V, Lau, A, Beaumont, E, Hope, A. The effects of surfing behaviour on the development of external auditory canal exostosis. Eur Arch Oto-Rhino-Laryngol 2015;272:1643–9. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00405-014-2950-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hurst, W, Bailey, M, Hurst, B. Prevalence of external auditory canal exostoses in Australian surfboard riders. J Laryngol Otol 2004;118:348–51. https://doi.org/10.1258/002221504323086525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert, C, Marin, S, Esvan, M, Godey, B. Impact of ear protection on occurrence of exostosis in surfers: an observational prospective study of 242 ears. Eur Arch Oto-Rhino-Laryngol 2021;278:4775–81. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00405-021-06609-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabiani, M, Barbara, M, Filipo, R. External ear canal exostosis and aquatic sports. ORL J Otorhinolaryngol Relat Spec 1984;46:159–64. https://doi.org/10.1159/000275702.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Timofeev, I, Notkina, N, Smith, IM. Exostoses of the external auditory canal: a long-term follow-up study of surgical treatment. Clin Otolaryngol Allied Sci 2004;29:588–94. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2273.2004.00865.x.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Umeda, Y, Nakajima, M, Yoshioka, H. Surfer’s ear in Japan. Laryngoscope 1989;99:639–41. https://doi.org/10.1288/00005537-198906000-00012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy, VM, Abdelrahman, T, Lau, A, Flanagan, PM. Surfers’ awareness of the preventability of “surfer’s ear” and use of water precautions. J Laryngol Otol 2011;125:551–3. https://doi.org/10.1017/s0022215111000041.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srinivasan, J, Reddy, VM, Flanagan, PM. Audiological implications of earplugs used for the prevention of aural exostoses. Eur Arch Oto-Rhino-Laryngol 2012;269:787–90. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00405-011-1730-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simas, V, Hing, W, Pope, R, Climstein, M. Australian surfers’ awareness of ’surfer’s ear. BMJ Open Sport Exerc Med 2020;6: e000641. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjsem-2019-000641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
